<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131692" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Labour costs main focus of German metal wage talks.</title>
<headline>Labour costs main focus of German metal wage talks.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German metal employers on Monday went on the offensive over labour costs as they squared up to meet engineering trade union IG Metall in a first discussion over the union's 1997 wage demand.</p>
<p>Engineering employers group Gesamtmetall insisted that an overall reduction in non-wage labour costs, which it says are crippling German competitiveness and are responsible for the huge redundancies in the sector, was an absolute priority.</p>
<p>&quot;It is critical that we arrive at a reduction in non-wage labour costs and an overall stability in costs,&quot; Gestamtmetall president Werner Stumpfe said in an article published in the &quot;Handelsblatt&quot; newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>He argued that the loss since 1991 of around one million jobs in the industry, which currently employs some 3.5 million, was largely the result of wage bargaining errors that have been widely viewed as offering too high a level of wage rises.</p>
<p>But Stumpfe displayed a noticeably less hardline approach to implementation of a new law introduced this month aimed at allowing employers to cut sick pay allowances to 80 percent of salary from the current 100 percent payment.</p>
<p>The new law on sick pay should be reflected in the wage deal about to be negotiated, he insisted.</p>
<p>But such a position is in stark contrast to Stumpfe's initial advice to metal and engineering employers that they put the cuts into effect immediately.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall was forced to retract that recommendation, after some firms, including Daimler-Benz AG which acted on the recommendation, were hit by mass protests involving more than 100,000 workers around the country.</p>
<p>IG Metall is going into the talks demanding that employers declare once and for all their position on the sick pay issue. If no agreement is reached, a second day of nationwide protest across the sector is planned to go ahead on Thursday.</p>
<p>It is also demanding concrete job protection measures as part of the 1997 wage agreement, and has set aside more than half of its 1997 wage demand for such measures.</p>
<p>That would pave the way for a headline increase in wages barely higher than inflation -- a rise that Gesamtmetall has said it could discuss if accompanied by measures that would significantly cut non-wage costs.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall has said that an IG Metall offer to accept sick payments based purely on a worker's basic pay -- instead of an amount including an average amount of overtime -- would not bring in a sufficient cost reduction.</p>
<p>It estimates that would only save around a quarter of the costs that a 20 percent sick payment reduction would. That in turn has been calculated as saving German industry some 12 billion marks a year.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
