<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13176" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-No legal action over rebel-Australia Opp'n.</title>
<headline>RTRS-No legal action over rebel-Australia Opp'n.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian opposition leader Kim Beazley said on Sunday he was not seeking legal action over the defection of a Labor senator that has muddied the balance of power in the upper house Senate.</p>
<p>But Beazley told Nine Network television Senator Mal Colston's decision to quit the Labor party and serve out his term as an independent complicated parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;It's put a question mark, obviously, a new question mark over all legislative processes ... it's a most unlovely performance,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Melbourne's The Sunday Age newspaper reported on Sunday Labor was considering pushing for a police investigation into whether Colston had broken the law if he had quit Labor and pledged support for government legislation in return for a prestigious Senate post.</p>
<p>Colston announced his resignation from the Labor Party last week, freeing him from voting in line with Labor policy in the Senate, where the Liberal-National government does not have a majority.  </p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard's conservative government needs the support of at least two non-government senators and there has been strong speculation Colston agreed to back key government reforms in return for government backing for his successful bid for the Senate deputy presidency.</p>
<p>Colston has not commented in detail on his likely voting pattern, saying only he would be guided by his Labor principles and by the government's mandate to implement certain policies.</p>
<p>Asked about the possibility of legal action, Beazley said: &quot;No, I think that's over the top.&quot;  </p>
<p>Beazley also said the government's planned charter of budget honesty, requiring updated Treasury economic and fiscal forcasts to be released ahead of an election, would delay detailed policy announcements until weeks before polling day.</p>
<p>&quot;What it will do in terms of debate is put opposition and government in a position whereby they'd be most foolish to announce their fully-costed and definite plans for the next three-year period until that final release of estimates is down,&quot; Beazley said.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
