<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132094" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Wabao to make 3-for-10 interim payout.</title>
<headline>Wabao to make 3-for-10 interim payout.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poultry and chicken feed processor Shenzhen Wabao Group Co Ltd said on Monday it plans to distribute its three-for-10 interim bonus shares this week.</p>
<p>Wabao said in a notice published in the official Securities Times that it has set the final date to register for the dividend at October 23 and its A shares will go ex-dividend on October 24.</p>
<p>Bonus shares distributed to holders of A shares will be listed on October 28, Wabao said.</p>
<p>Wabao said it would have expanded total share capital of 311.14 million shares following the distribution.</p>
<p>The firm said in an interim report that its net profits in the first half of 1996 skyrocketed 507.46 percent over the previous year's same period level of 11.87 million yuan.</p>
<p>Under Chinese accounting standards, the company chalked up after-tax profits of 72.10 million yuan in the first half of this year, the report said.</p>
<p>A company spokesman told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin that nearly 90 percent of the firm's first-half earnings in 1996 stemmed from returns on securities investment.  </p>
<p>Wabao said the higher earnings were also due to the firm's moves to expand the scale of its operations and to solid sales of its Shenzhen-based property projects.</p>
<p>The company recently said it had set up a joint venture with the U.S.-based Photran Co Ltd to produce liquid crystal displays.</p>
<p>A Wabao spokesman said the Shenzhen-listed company has a 51 percent stake in the venture, Shenzhen Fortune Conductive Glass Co Ltd, which has registered capitalization of US$5 million.</p>
<p>The remaining 49 percent stake in the Shenzhen-based joint venture is held by Photran, the official said.</p>
<p>He said the project should generate after-tax profits of US$2 million annually upon full operation.</p>
<p>He said the venture's products are widely used in the mobile telephone and computer sectors.</p>
<p>Wabao, which has class A shares listed in Shenzhen, is mainly involved in exporting poultry and processing chicken feed. The firm, which also has interests in property development, plans to further diversify over the next few years, the official said.</p>
<p>Wabao reported after-tax profits of 8.73 million yuan for 1995, down sharply from 56.67 million yuan racked up in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
