<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132083" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan business urges government to move on reforms.</title>
<headline>Japan business urges government to move on reforms.</headline>
<byline>Linda Sieg</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese business leaders gave a cautious welcome to the conservative Liberal Democratic Party's robust showing in Sunday's election but urged the new government to enact reforms to ensure future economic success.</p>
<p>Worries persisted, however, over whether meaningful measures would emerge given the prospect of a coalition government and the LDP's image as keepers of the status quo.</p>
<p>The general election -- the first since the LDP lost its monopoly on power three years ago -- put the party in the driver's seat but without the clear majority many pollsters had thought possible.</p>
<p>&quot;Our nation now confronts a crucial moment on the eve of the 21st century,&quot; said Jiro Nemoto, chairman of Nikkeiren, the employers' federation. &quot;We want the new administration to...exert leadership in resolutely enacting the structural reforms we have been seeking.&quot;</p>
<p>The main business lobby, Keidanren, echoed that sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the new administration...will be stable and take strong initiatives,&quot; said Keidanren Chairman Shoichiro Toyoda, urging bold moves on government streamlining, tax reform and the budget.</p>
<p>The LDP fell 12 seats short of the 251 it needed to govern alone in the 500-seat Lower House of parliament and was expected to ask its two minority partners in the outgoing government, the tiny Sakigake party and the Social Democrats, to stay in the ruling camp.</p>
<p>It was also expected to court the new Democratic Party -- a recently formed group of reformist lawmakers -- while also drawing on defectors from the main opposition Shinshinto (New Frontier Party).</p>
<p>Some optimists had hoped an LDP majority would help Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, who is expected to head the next government, end policy drift and enact the deregulation big business wants and economists say is vital to ensure Japan's corporations succeed in global competition.</p>
<p>There were lingering hopes that some efforts would be made.</p>
<p>&quot;Until now the coalition cabinet has emphasised consensus so it lacked leadership,&quot; said Toshiaki Kakimoto, managing director of the Japan Research Institute. &quot;This time the LDP has increased its votes, so we hope they can take responsibility and have the power to implement (policies).&quot;</p>
<p>That, however, hardly implies drastic moves on matters like deregulation, tax reform and provisions for a rapidly ageing population that will burden public coffers, sceptics said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two types of reform: liberalisation versus tinkering with the existing system to make things better,&quot; said Chris Calderwood, chief economist at BZW Securities in Tokyo. &quot;I think the LDP is in the second camp.&quot;</p>
<p>Shorter term, the need for the LDP to scramble for coalition partners clouds the outlook for some concrete steps business and share market players are keen to see implemented.</p>
<p>Among those are corporate tax cuts, reform of the anti-monopoly law to allow holding companies, and revisions of real estate rules to promote property market liquidity.</p>
<p>An LDP-led coalition will likely go ahead with a planned rise in the three-percent sales tax to five percent from next April, but it remained unclear whether Japan would introduce a stimulative supplementary budget for the current fiscal year to March 1997 to prop up the economy's tentative recovery.</p>
<p>The economy is gradually emerging from a prolonged slump which followed the bursting of a late-1980s economic &quot;bubble&quot;, but the recovery is patchy and has owed much to government stimulus spending and record-low interest rates.</p>
<p>Should the LDP join hands with the fledgling Democratic Party in a coalition, its pre-election pledges of a five trillion yen ($44 billion) extra budget could well be scaled back.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Democrats join in, maybe we will have to review the content of the supplementary budget,&quot; Yoshimasa Hayashi, an LDP Upper House member, told Reuters. &quot;They said we have enough public financing, so maybe they are going to say lower the size of the budget.&quot; ($1=113 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
