<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132187" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd leader in Turkey for U.S. talks.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd leader in Turkey for U.S. talks.</headline>
<dateline>SILOPI, Turkey 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqi Kurdish leader Massoud Barzani arrived in Turkey on Monday for talks with a U.S. envoy to end Kurdish factional fighting in northern Iraq that damaged U.S. interests in the volatile region.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) leader Barzani crossed the Habur border post at 10 a.m. (0700 GMT) and headed for a Turkish army building in the nearby town of Silopi.</p>
<p>The Kurdish warlord, previously backed by Baghdad in factional fighting, arrived in a convoy of landcruisers accompanied by armed guards.</p>
<p>Turkish troops threw a tight ring of security around the army building where Barzani was to meet U.S. envoy Robert Pelletreau later in the day.</p>
<p>Pelletreau, assistant secretary of state for near eastern affairs, was also due to meet Barzani's adversary Jalal Talabani, head of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK), in Turkey on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Fighting between the two factions since August has raised the profile of President Saddam Hussein in northern Iraq and effectively ended the U.S. military, aid and intelligence presence in the mountainous region.</p>
<p>The rival Kurds exchanged artillery fire on Sunday for control of the strategic Dukan Dam.</p>
<p>Barzani tipped the balance of power in his favour in late August by joining with Iraqi troops and tanks to take Arbil, Iraqi Kurdistan's former administrative centre. However, he now says that deal is off.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SILOPI, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
