<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132156" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- Chuan Leekpai and Chavalit Yongchaiyudh, leaders of Democrat and the New Aspiration parties, have exchanged campaign salvoes on the eve of the election candidacy registration which starts today. The leader of Chart Pattana party Chatichai Choonhavan upped his leverage by presenting himself as a crucial variable in the two rivals' widening polarity. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Only 27,000 illegal alien workers from a total of 700,000 have so far been registered with immigration offices. The National Security Council says as of October 15 just under four percent of aliens had been registered by their employers. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Heavy rain has lashed the southern province of Prachuab Khiri Khan, triggering flash floods and a widespread blackout for several hours. Five villages were hard hit on Sunday after water run-off from the mountains worsened the flood situation. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The proposed merger between Nithipat Capital Plc and financially-ailing Bangkok Bank of Commmerce (BBC), with the former to take over the bank's management, is seen to be be worthwhile for the parties concerned in the long run. The Bank of Thailand has suggested that the price of BBC's common shares to be sold to Nithipat Capital by the Fund for the Rehabilitation and Development of Financial Institutions, the majority shareholder in the bank, be set at par value. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Shinawatra International and the Laotian government have quietly inked a telecom deal under which Laos transfers all telecommunication activities including a basic telephone network to Lao Telecommunication. Under the contract signed on October 8, Laos would transfer all telecom activities including its basic telephone network of 20,000 numbers to Lao Telecommunication, except satellite activities. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
