<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13218" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's second &quot;Battle of Okinawa&quot; looms.</title>
<headline>Japan's second &quot;Battle of Okinawa&quot; looms.</headline>
<byline>Eugene Moosa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The second &quot;Battle of Okinawa&quot; opens this week when Japan's Supreme Court decides if local authorities can deny land to U.S. military bases followed by an historic referendum on whether Okinawans want the bases.</p>
<p>Parliamentarians and political commentators say the events over the next two weeks could split Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's coalition and even trigger general elections,</p>
<p>The row over U.S. forces' concentration on Okinawa also has the potential to threaten U.S. security arrangements in Asia.</p>
<p>The bitter year-long controversy, which comes to a head first on Wednesday with the court ruling and 10 days later with the referendum, was triggered by the rape of an Okinawan schoolgirl by three U.S. servicemen last September.</p>
<p>The servicemen were convicted and sentenced to up to 10 years in jail. A local court is expected to rule on September 12 on their appeal.</p>
<p>Public outcry over the rape set off the present chain reaction.</p>
<p>The first skirmish takes place in Tokyo at the Supreme Court when the Grand Bench of 15 judges, headed by Chief Justice Toru Miyoshi, rules whether local authorities must appropriate land for U.S. bases on the orders of Tokyo.</p>
<p>The next round is a September 8 Okinawa referendum on a non-binding resolution demanding the central government scale down, but not immediately close, U.S. bases on the island.</p>
<p>In both cases, the issue is the lopsided U.S. presence on the island, about 1,000 miles (1,600 km) south of Tokyo.</p>
<p>The island's 1.2 million people are host to a vast array of marine camps and air force bases that make up 75 percent of U.S. military facilities in Japan. About two-thirds of the 47,000 U.S. troops in Japan are also based on the sub-tropical island which is a popular holiday resort for Japanese.</p>
<p>Many Okinawans argue that with only one per cent of Japan's land and one per cent of its population, they carry an unfair burden.</p>
<p>Strategically located in easy range of China, Taiwan, and North Korea, about half of the 100,000 U.S. forces in Asia are based in Japan and a significant realignment or cutback in their presence would be a military planner's nightmare.</p>
<p>The U.S. presence is a legacy of the last great battle of World War Two, the Battle of Okinawa.</p>
<p>A third of the islanders, about 140,000 people, were killed in the battle, many forced to commit mass suicide by fanatical Japanese soldiers in the last days of the war.</p>
<p>After its defeat, Japan ceded Okinawa to U.S. military rule which lasted until 1972.</p>
<p>In those years, the Okinawa economy never caught up with the rest of Japan, and the prefecture is now the poorest in Japan, with a per capita income half that of Tokyo.</p>
<p>Okinawa Governor Masahide Ota, who wants all U.S. forces out by 2015, has brought the matter to a head by refusing to sign orders needed to extend leases of private land for U.S. bases.</p>
<p>Ota has said an April agreement worked out by Hashimoto and President Bill Clinton at a Tokyo summit to reduce the amount of land occupied by U.S. bases by one-fifth does not go far enough.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Supreme Court is expected to uphold lower court rulings in favour of the central government, because accepted international law gives treaties, such as the U.S.-Japan Security Treaty which forms the basis of land appropriations, precedence over domestic laws.</p>
<p>But while the Supreme Court ruling will pass judgment on the legality of Ota's actions, the referendum's results could easily offset the political effects of the court action.</p>
<p>No one expects Okinawans to return a &quot;no&quot; vote. The key figures will be the size of the &quot;yes&quot; vote and voter turnout.</p>
<p>If Ota defies a court ruling for land  appropriations, Hashimoto's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) has floated the idea of a parliamentary law allowing the central government to overule local governments on land use for military bases.</p>
<p>But both the Social Democratic Party and Sakigake, the LDP's coalition partners, baulk at such action. Some senior members have threatened to walk out of the coalition -- a move which would force Hashimoto to call elections.</p>
<p>The rest of Japan is doing nothing to help the central government and Okinawa get out of the impasse.</p>
<p>Efforts to find alternative sites for some U.S. forces on mainland Japan have been roundly rejected so far by other local authorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
