<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132151" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan dailies chastise parties, no-show voters.</title>
<headline>Japan dailies chastise parties, no-show voters.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's major newspapers urged the Liberal Democratic Party on Monday to keep its campaign promises and upbraided political parties and no-show voters for a record poor turnout.</p>
<p>&quot;The LDP should not get too full of itself,&quot; said the liberal daily Asahi Shimbun in an editorial comment on Sunday's general election, in which Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's conservative LDP won the most seats but failed to get a majority.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only did it fail to win a majority under an electoral system that favoured the ruling party, it was overall political stability -- rather than specific policies -- that the voters chose,&quot; the Asahi said.</p>
<p>The LDP emerged as the biggest winner in Sunday's vote, but its 239 seats were 12 short of the 251 it needed to govern alone in the 500-seat Lower House. It was expected to form a coalition.</p>
<p>The LDP should quickly carry out its election pledges to drastically deregulate the financial system, telecommunications and transportation and trim bloated government agencies, said the Nihon Keizai Shimbun, Japan's leading business daily.</p>
<p>&quot;The LDP must not forget its campaign pledge to voters to carry out administrative reform,&quot; said the newspaper's editorial. &quot;If it reneges, it had better be prepared for a harsh backlash in the next elections.&quot;</p>
<p>The conservative daily Yomiuri Shimbun also told the LDP to be realistic about the lukewarm vote of support it received.</p>
<p>&quot;This election result was not so much a positive evaluation of the LDP, but a call for a coalition that makes clear its political responsibilities instead of procrastinating on key issues,&quot; the daily said in its editorial.</p>
<p>The Yomiuri noted that nearly half of the 500 lawmakers elected on Sunday were born after World War Two, raising the &quot;hope that those who will bear political responsibility for the 21st century can bring fresh winds of change&quot;.</p>
<p>On the turnout of 59 percent, the lowest figure since the war, the moderate daily Mainichi Shimbun assigned equal blame to parties with vague policies and to apathetic voters.</p>
<p>&quot;Voters could see that the consumption tax debate which unfolded with great fanfare and the calls for cutting numbers of ministries were merely vote-getting tactics,&quot; said the Mainichi.</p>
<p>&quot;Voters who stayed away from the polls should, now that the election is over, think again about the clear and present dangers approaching as the gears of the Japanese system spin out of control,&quot; the daily said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
