<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132176" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FEATURE - Pressures grow for mergers of oil giants in Asia.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Pressures grow for mergers of oil giants in Asia.</headline>
<byline>Neil Fullick</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mega-mergers between oil majors are the flavour of 1996 in Europe and North America and pressures are growing that could even lead to similar deals in Asia, analysts say.</p>
<p>The benefits of merging may not seem so obvious to majors operating in Asia, as they have been elsewhere, because demand forecasts for the region are so bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;The difference between Asia-Pacific and mature markets is very much the way in which most of the major corporations view their futures,&quot; said a strategist for an oil major.</p>
<p>&quot;They are viewing Asia-Pacific with fantastic growth potential. So there is more reluctance and less of a drive to get into bed with others.&quot;</p>
<p>But some analysts said Asian refining margins are increasingly weak, smaller but growing oil companies are taking market share and state oil companies are becoming more and more aggressive as energy deregulation sweeps the region.</p>
<p>These may be the elements, they say, that will eventually prompt mergers between majors even in Asia -- the region which many executives view as the future for their companies.</p>
<p>Cooperation on exploration and production projects is common in the global oil community. Mergers with state oil companies as a gateway to individual markets are also a regular feature.</p>
<p>Multi-billion dollar mergers between integrated majors are less common.</p>
<p>MERGERS THIS YEAR</p>
<p>But this year, Mobil Corp of the United States and British Petroleum Co Plc agreed to merge their downstream operations in Europe into a $5 billion joint venture.</p>
<p>Texaco Inc and Shell Oil Co confirmed this month that they were talking about a possible merger of their downstream operations in the United States.</p>
<p>The merger would take 15 percent of the huge U.S. market and control assets of $17 billion. It would be in partnership with Saudi Arabia, through a Texaco/Saudi joint venture, so guaranteeing crude supplies from the world's biggest crude exporter.</p>
<p>Stuart Saint, vice president of consultants Arthur D. Little Inc, said &quot;The joint ventures in the USA and Europe are driven by weak profitability, flat demand and a desire to cut costs. In Asia, the situation is different except in Japan where there may be increasing recognition that weak margins are here to stay and improving profitability is essential.&quot;</p>
<p>Japanese oil groups have already started merging some operations, most noticeably in distribution, in a bid to cut costs in the post-deregulation era.</p>
<p>Some analysts say mergers between entire companies are not far off in Japan.</p>
<p>A government survey this month showed profits at 12 leading companies slumped 54.1 percent to 28 billion yen ($249.1 million) in the April-September half year.</p>
<p>Japan's refinery runs were 83 percent in August, up from 75.6 percent in July -- levels many refineries outside Japan would find unacceptable.</p>
<p>But analysts say elsewhere in Asia, refinery margins are under pressure and could remain so heading into the next century as supply overtakes demand. In the much longer term, demand is expected to become a stronger factor and outpace supply.</p>
<p>Since mid-year basic refinery margins for swing producer Singapore have fallen several dollars into the red at times and currently stand around 50 cents into losses.</p>
<p>Traders said margins were negative in the growing South Korea refining industry, but refiners there are concerned more with maintaining market share than producing maximum profits.</p>
<p>EXPLORATION, PRODUCTION SUCCESS HAS NOT MATCHED EXPECTATIONS</p>
<p>At the same time, exploration and production successes have not matched expectations, said Trevor MacMurray, senior director at business consultants McKinsey &amp; Co.</p>
<p>&quot;The realism of getting a good return from investments is setting in. A few years ago people were quite euphoric about prospects here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts estimate more than $40 billion would be needed in refinery investments in the next 15 years to meet projected demand growth of six percent per year.</p>
<p>But many Asian grassroots refinery projects involving majors are stalled, most noticeably in China. Domestic policy changes and haggles over allowing foreign access to China's domestic markets have delayed five projects involving majors.</p>
<p>&quot;In China, many companies have spent a lot of money and have been left frustrated,&quot; said one analyst, who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>Another rising pressure on majors is the number of expanding companies and state-oil companies that are exploiting niche areas of the market.</p>
<p>McKinsey's MacMurray pointed to Tosco Corp and  Koch Oil in refining and marketing, Enron Corp in gas and India's Reliance Industries Ltd.</p>
<p>State groups like Petronas Carigali Bhd of Malaysia, Petroleum Authority of Thailand (PTT) and Chinese Petroleum Corp (CPC) of Taiwan are increasingly aggressive in exploration, production and marketing.</p>
<p>But despite these growing pressures, an Asian merger of the downstream operations or upstream operations of two majors is not seen anytime soon.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still very much a drive to invest and grow in the region. I don't see there being any rush to merge. There is too much potential,&quot; said one industry executive.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see oil majors willing to give up what are seen as major growth potential areas and what most are probably selling to their corporate managers as the future of the company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition, the Asian market is fragmented. Markets are at different stages of development, some are still closed while others are at varying degrees of deregulation.</p>
<p>So while majors might see cooperation as beneficial in individual markets it would not be so easy to identify a region wide multi-billion dollar fit with another major. ($1=112.4 Yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
