<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13212" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korea's Chun, Roh face court judgment.</title>
<headline>South Korea's Chun, Roh face court judgment.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a trial that dug up the dirtiest secrets of South Korea's former military strongmen, a court on Monday is expected to sentence one-time president Chun Doo Hwan and his successor Roh Tae-woo.</p>
<p>State prosecutors have demanded death for Chun and life in jail for Roh on charges of treason, mutiny and corruption.</p>
<p>Few South Koreans, however, will be holding their breath for the outcome.</p>
<p>Guilty verdicts are widely considered a foregone conclusion, but regardless of the sentencing the two former military generals are expected to be offered clemency by current president Kim Young-sam.</p>
<p>Moon Chung-in, a professor of politics at Yonsei University, said there was &quot;zero possibility&quot; of any death sentence being carried out. &quot;By carrying out the death sentence, nobody will gain,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Kim Young-sam would be shown to have an iron fist and no human heart.&quot;</p>
<p>Moon said it was more likely that Kim would grant clemency before he steps down next year. That would mollify the rightwing of his ruling party whose support he needs to help pick his presidential successor.</p>
<p>Chun and Roh are expected to appeal any sentence by the Seoul District Criminal Court.</p>
<p>A three-judge panel will also pass judgmnt on former military associates of Chun and Roh and senior officials who served during their administrations.</p>
<p>Also in court will be a line-up of South Korea's top business tycoons, including the chairmen of the mighty Samsung and Daewoo groups, charged with buying business favours by showering Chun and Roh with cash.</p>
<p>Most Koreans believe the tycoons will get off with the equivalent of a rap across the knuckles because of their key role in the economy.</p>
<p>Cameras will be removed from the court during their sentencing in a move commentators say is to protect their overseas corporate image.</p>
<p>The businessmen have admitted paying off the presidential Blue House, saying it was common practice at the time, but deny they received favours in return.</p>
<p>Treason and mutiny charges stem from a 1979 coup that propelled then military general Chun to power and a massacre in 1980 in the southwestern city of Kwangju when troops crushed an uprising against martial law.</p>
<p>Hundreds of civilians were killed, according to official accounts, although survivors say the death toll was higher.</p>
<p>The lengthy trial first electrified, then bored South Koreans when it became clear that the evidence would not drag in President Kim, whose campaign to &quot;right the wrongs of history&quot; lay behind the prosecution and who denied ever taking tainted money.</p>
<p>Koreans were gripped by initial images of the two ex-presidents stripped of their dignity in pale blue prison smocks and plastic slippers like common criminals.</p>
<p>Roh, the suave former statesman who presided triumphantly over the 1988 Seoul Olympics, and the ramrod straight Chun gave little away under cross examination, frequently saying &quot;I don't know&quot; or &quot;I can't remember&quot;.</p>
<p>Prosecutors tried to prove that military action that launched Chun's political career was illegal and sought to piece together the events that led to the Kwangju tragedy, which still haunts the nation.</p>
<p>Chun defended his seizure of power by saying it prevented turmoil that would have invited attack from North Korea after the assasination of president Park Chung Hee.</p>
<p>He denied giving the order to open fire to crack paratroopers who stormed Kwangju.</p>
<p>Prosecutors exposed breathtaking corruption as tycoons detailed how they toted sackloads of cash to the Blue House in deals brokered by presidential aides.</p>
<p>Roh has confessed to amassing a 500 billion won (around $600 million) slush fund in his 1988-93 term in office, while prosecutors allege Chun built a hidden fortune of 700 billion won (about $850 million) during his 1980-88 tenure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
