<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132161" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- Feverish negotiations are going on between the camps of Vice President Joseph Estrada and Sen Edgardo Angara for a possible team-up in the 1998 elections. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- A U.S.Department of Defence report has confirmed the presence of hazardous military wastes, including cancer-causing asbestos, at the former Clark air base (INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- A woman was shot dead and eight Moro National Liberation Front members were wounded on the eve of special elections in Parang, Sulu on Sunday (MANILA STANDARD)</p>
<p>- The Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF) &quot;lost command&quot; is massing its forces in various areas in Mindanao in preparation for a large-scale offensive, the military said. (THE PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- The government expects additional tax revenues of at least 2.5 billion pesos a year from the planned restructuring of the automotive industry (INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- The Trade Union Congress of the Philippines is seeking a 45-peso across the board increase in wages (BUSINESSWORLD)</p>
<p>- The government's projection of an average 8.6 percent inflation rate by end-1996 is harder to achieve with the recent oil price increase and the spate of price adjustments to come, economist Benjamin Diokno said. (THE BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- The Philippine National Oil Co-Petrochemical Development Corp will have to deal with Congress to push its right to take the lead in the construction of the country's first naphtha cracker facility. (THE BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
