<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13216" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore premier sees slowdown for 3-6 months.</title>
<headline>Singapore premier sees slowdown for 3-6 months.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong said on Sunday he was unsure how long the current economic slowdown in the city-state would last but thought it might continue for three to six months.</p>
<p>Goh also said he feared the slowdown in the retail sector might last longer than the slump in the key electronics sector.  </p>
<p>On August 12, Singapore announced a sharp decline in economic growth for the second quarter to seven percent from 10.9 percent in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>Officials said the slowdown was largely due to a slump in its key electronics industry, which accounts for around half the country's industrial output and almost 60 percent of its non-oil exports.</p>
<p>Goh told a news conference he was cautiously optimistic over the prospects for the economy but was unsure how long the slowdown would continue. &quot;It is difficult to say how long it will last ... Three months, six months, that is possible.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The downturn is felt in the electronics industry, which of course then would have some influence on maybe the financial sector,&quot; Goh said.</p>
<p>&quot;The downturn has come very suddenly and more sharply than people expected. We are dealing with a very volatile industry.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;My worry, of course, is over the retail sector. For the retail sector we are undergoing a restructuring change,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect the retail sector to be rather slow moving for quite some time. I think that will last longer than the slowdown in the electronics industry.&quot;  </p>
<p>Goh said part of the reason for the current &quot;shaking-out&quot; in Singapore's retail sector was that shops were spreading across the island and were no longer concentrated in just a few areas.</p>
<p>Retailers also faced the challenge of Singaporeans shopping outside the country because of the high value of the Singapore dollar, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Singaporeas now buy quite a bit from outside the country: Hong Kong, London, Malaysia because of the strong dollar,&quot; he said. ($1 = S$1.41) -- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
