<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132138" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Japan troubles show need for strong government - Lee.</title>
<headline>Japan troubles show need for strong government - Lee.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore patriarch Lee Kuan Yew said Japan's economic problems in recent years reflect lack of a strong government, the Straits Times reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted Lee, Singapore's Senior Minister, as saying in an off-the-cuff speech on Sunday that Japan's economy faltered after the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) lost decisive control of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;For 37, 38 years, the LDP had a decisive majority and governed Japan in a decisive way. They could take hard measures, tough policies and decisions, and carry the economy forward,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>But he said Japan now lacked political stability and &quot;they cannot take decisive measures to get the people to accept hard decisions and to get the economy going again&quot;.</p>
<p>The LDP ruled Japan for 38 years until an election in 1993. While it came back into government in mid-1994, that was as part of a coalition, and in a general election over the weekend it failed to win an outright majority.</p>
<p>Lee was using Japan as an example of why strong and decisive governments, like that of Singapore's People's Action Party (PAP), can help economies improve.</p>
<p>The newspaper quoted him as saying, &quot;Remember: do not complain that you have a strong government in the People's Action Party. You will start knowing what life would be like when you end up with a weak government that cannot act and the economy is in trouble and the country is in trouble.&quot;</p>
<p>Singapore is experiencing an economic slowdown at the moment with exports lagging, but Lee said due to good economic management, &quot;we have no unemployment, no hardship, nobody has felt the pinch&quot;.</p>
<p>The PAP has controlled Singapore's government since 1959.</p>
<p>Lee also pointed to Thailand, saying the country would enjoy 40 to 50 percent more economic growth if it had a strong government instead of a succession of coalition governments which are &quot;in the nature of things weak and unstable&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
