<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132155" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: BOJ policy to keep emphasis on recovery-governor.</title>
<headline>BOJ policy to keep emphasis on recovery-governor.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Japan's (BOJ) monetary policy will continue to emphasise making Japan's economic recovery more solid, BOJ governor Yasuo Matsushita said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;In managing monetary policy for the time being, it is appropriate for us to keep the emphasis on making the basis for an economic recovery more solid and to carefully watch developments in economic and financial conditions,&quot; Matsushita said in a statement to the central bank's regional branch managers.  </p>
<p>&quot;The economy is continuing its gradual recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He explained the pace of the recovery remains gradual from the pressures of structural adjustment facing the economy.</p>
<p>Matsushita explained housing investment remains at high levels while corporate capital investment is showing signs of improvement with it spreading to companies of various industries and of all sizes.</p>
<p>Private consumption is generally on a gradual recovery trend, he said. Industrial production is on a gradual upward trend although inventory adjustment is still going on in some industries such as semiconductors.  </p>
<p>Falls in prices are gradually coming to a halt, Matsushita said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the high level of public works spending is expected to decline in the coming months.</p>
<p>&quot;For our economy to move on to a solid self-sustainable recovery track, it is important for the favourable economic cyclical mechanism centering on private demand to strengthen further,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the same time, Matsushita stressed the importance of scrapping or easing regulations that hinder the growth of the economy.</p>
<p>Matsushita spoke at the opening of a 2-day meeting of 33 domestic BOJ branch managers and BOJ representatives from London, New York, and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Such meetings are usually held quarterly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
