<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132192" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Jordan will propose plans worth 3.70 billion dinars ($5.22 billion) at the Cairo Middle East economic summit in November. Plans cover projects in industry, minerals, communications, tourism and water sectors.</p>
<p>- French President Chirac to get warm welcome when he delivers speech to parliament on Thursday. Opposition groups appreciate the positive statements from Paris on the Middle East.</p>
<p>- Kabariti calls for 100,000 dinars to support sports clubs for refugees.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Central tender agency says it will issue tender within two days for new loading platform worth 25 million dinars ($35.3 million) at Jordan's Aqaba port.</p>
<p>- Doctors say they won some of their rights in talks with the government. Committee will meet today to cancel decision to stop work.</p>
<p>- Speaker of Austrian parliament arrives in Jordan on Wednesday for three-day visit.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Minister of Supply Munir Sobar says government considering cancelling import duties on sugar, rice and other commodities which the private sector may want to import, including corn and fodder.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Arab Organisation for Human Rights in Jordan alleges human rights violations, including curbs on freedom of expression. Ex-detainees claim torture.</p>
<p>- Central Bank governor Fariz says small Arab capital markets encourage capital flight.</p>
<p>- Jordanian economist says inflation will rise to eight percent because of food price increases.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
