<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132175" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Fuji Bank to set aside reserves on Tobishima loans.</title>
<headline>Fuji Bank to set aside reserves on Tobishima loans.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fuji Bank Ltd on Monday said that it plans to set aside loan loss reserves against its loans to construction firm Tobishima Corp in its earnings for the year to March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>However, it declined to comment on the amount it would set aside. Despite the charge, Fuji maintains its earnings and dividend forecast for the current business year, a Fuji spokesman said.</p>
<p>Tobishima said on Friday that it had drawn up a new restructuring plan to try to solve its financial difficulties, under which it would ask its creditors, including Fuji Bank, to reduce their claims against Tobishima for the debts owed by its group companies from about 740 billion yen to 100 billion yen.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun economic daily said on Saturday that Fuji is expected to set aside loan loss reserves worth 100 billion yen to 150 billion yen in its 1996/97 earnings.</p>
<p>The paper said the bank is expected to sell assets to cover the charge. The Fuji spokesman said the bank could not comment on the report. Fuji said in May that it expected to post a parent current profit of 70 billion yen and pay a 8.5 yen dividend for 1996/97. It posted a parent current loss of 500.09 billion yen and paid a 6.5 yen dividend in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
