<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132150" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan LDP set to lure opposition defectors--report.</title>
<headline>Japan LDP set to lure opposition defectors--report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of 10 legislators is preparing to quit Japan's main opposition party and help the Liberal Democratic Party gain a majority in parliament, a newspaper said on Monday.</p>
<p>Ten members of Shinshinto (New Frontier Party), which came in a distant second to the LDP in Sunday's general elections, will meet in Tokyo on Monday to formalise their plan to quit the party and work with the LDP, the mass-circulation Yomiuri Shimbun said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's LDP emerged as the biggest winner in Sunday's polls, but its tally of 239 seats was 12 short of the 251 it needed to govern alone in the 500-seat Lower House.</p>
<p>In the outgoing coalition government, the LDP was the dominant partner in an alliance with the Social Democratic Party and Sakigake, a small LDP splinter group. The LDP said after the poll it would seek to form a new coalition.</p>
<p>The defectors' group is headed by Hiroshi Kumagai, a former chief cabinet secretary and ally-turned-critic of Shinshinto head Ichiro Ozawa, the Yomiuri said.</p>
<p>Kumagai's office said it was unable to confirm the whereabouts or plans of the group.</p>
<p>The main opposition Shinshinto dropped four seats to 156 and there are doubts over the future of the party and its leader Ozawa, an LDP defector from 1993, political analysts said.</p>
<p>Analysts said about 10 conservative independent candidates were also exploring ways to join with the LDP, either by formally joining the party or by cooperating as an informal ally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
