<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13219" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: RUBBER-Indonesia seen diversifying into Japan.</title>
<headline>RUBBER-Indonesia seen diversifying into Japan.</headline>
<byline>Gde Anugrah Arka</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia, the world's second largest rubber producer, is likely to make further inroads into the Japanese market and reduce its dependence on exports to the United States, industry officials and traders said.</p>
<p>Rubber is one of Indonesia's most important export commodities, with some 12.5 million people involved in the production, processing and marketing of some 1.54 million tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>The United States is Indonesia's favoured destination for rubber exports, but trade sources said it would be unwise to depend too heavily on one market, especially since Washington has plans to offload a huge amount of rubber stocks.</p>
<p>The U.S. Defense National Stockpile Center said recently it plans to start selling up to 60,000 tonnes of surplus natural rubber, both ribbed smoked sheets and technically specified blocks, early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The details are not clear yet, but it's clear that putting all our eggs in one basket is quite risky,&quot; the executive director of the Indonesia Rubber Association, A.F.S. Budiman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>If the United States sells the surplus in one go when prices are weak, it may push prices further down, Budiman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever the details will be, the news has reminded us that we have to diversify and focus more on the fast growing Japanese market,&quot; one dealer in the western Sumatran city of Padang said.</p>
<p>&quot;Five of the biggest Padang firms are expected to ship some 10,000 tonnes of rubber in August. As far as I know, all of these are bound to the U.S. This is very risky,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States is Indonesia's most important market. It bought 47 percent of the country's total exports of 1.32 million tonnes of both technically specified blocks and ribbed smoke sheets in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Firms are likely to intensify efforts such as sending more offers to Japan to further capture the market thanks to a tendency to shift to Indonesia and cut dependence on Thai rubber,&quot; one dealer in Jakarta said.</p>
<p>Japanese firms had reduced rubber imports from the world's largest producer Thailand to 255,499 tonnes in the first half of this year against 288,713 tonnes in the same period last year.</p>
<p>On the other hand, imports from Indonesia jumped sharply to 60,612 tonnes in the same period from 21,330 tonnes.</p>
<p>Dealers said the expected stronger efforts by Indonesian rubber exporters could undermine Thailand's rank as the most important rubber supplier to Japan's tyre firms.</p>
<p>Japan is already the second biggest market for Indonesian rubber, dealers said.</p>
<p>Japan's shift to Indonesia partly reflected Thailand's delayed shipments in May and cancellation of its shipments of its benchmark Ribbed Smoke Sheets (RSS) rubber to Japan in 1994, dealers said.</p>
<p>Indonesia was also likely to further exploit growing rubber demand in Japan on relatively weak prices of its benchmark tyre-grade Standard Indonesia Rubber 20 (SIR20), they said.</p>
<p>Japan's total rubber demand for tyres is expected to hit a record of 1.043 million tonnes in 1996, exceeding the previous record of 1.035 million tonnes in 1995, according to the Japan Automobile Tyre Manufacturers Assocition.</p>
<p>SIR20 has recently traded between 54.00-55.00 U.S. cents/lb October/November deliveries on Friday against 56.75-58.00 cents a year ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
