<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13215" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia begins probe into Tenaga - paper.</title>
<headline>Malaysia begins probe into Tenaga - paper.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Anti-Corruption Agency (ACA) has begun an investigation into alleged malpractices and abuse of power in state electric utility Tenaga Nasional Bhd, the New Sunday Times newspaper said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Times quoted ACA deputy director-general Mohamed Zawawi as saying the probe would follow up allegations raised in a Tenaga internal audit report.</p>
<p>&quot;The probe commenced early last week after the agency was given a copy of the report, which is being studied by the investigating team,&quot; Zawawi said.</p>
<p>The voluminous report, excerpts of which have been shown to Reuters and obtained by local newspapers, raised questions over Tenaga's tendering process, administrative procedures and management of the utility's subsidiaries.</p>
<p>The report also exposed alleged surveillance and telephone tapping of certain employees.</p>
<p>The New Straits Times quoted Zawawi as saying the agency would soon complete a probe into allegations surrounding a logging contract by Tenaga and detailed in the audit report.</p>
<p>The report was leaked to the media after a 12-15 hour blackout on August 3 in Peninsula Malaysia that embarrassed politicians and Tenaga officials.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
