<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132224" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Daimler auto sector must remain unified - Feuerstein.</title>
<headline>Daimler auto sector must remain unified - Feuerstein.</headline>
<dateline>STUTTGART 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of Daimler-Benz AG's works council, Karl Feuerstein, said on Monday that the industrial group's automotive business must remain a single entity in any restructuring of the group.</p>
<p>Feuerstein also said that any supervisory board decision on a restructuring of Daimler would probably not be taken at the next scheduled board meeting on November 6 and would perhaps not be taken until 1997.  </p>
<p>Daimler =2</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Feuerstein, deputy head of the supervisory board, said Daimler's automotive unit must under no circumstances be split up within the Daimler group.</p>
<p>&quot;We will measure all proposals according to this demand,&quot; Feuerstein said.</p>
<p>&quot;We must discuss this comprehensively in the supervisory board,&quot; Feuerstein said, adding that the board must not let itself be put under time pressure.</p>
<p>A row has been brewing within Daimler over a proposal by chief executive Juergen Schrempp to integrate Mercedes into Daimler.</p>
<p>Sources close to Daimler have said that six out of seven management board members at Daimler approved the plan. Only Mercedes-Benz chief executive Helmut Werner opposes it, the sources said.</p>
<p>The four-member presidency of the supervisory board, consisting of two employee representatives and two from the shareholders' side, will discuss the plans for a management restructuring at a meeting on Tuesday, Feuerstein said.</p>
<p>Sources close to the company said shareholder representatives on the supervisory board, including the chief executive of Deutsche Bank AG, Hilmar Kopper, would meet on Monday to discuss the changes.</p>
<p>Feuerstein said he did not oppose a new structure in principle but added that the automotive business must not be split up. He did not say how he envisaged this happening as part of a reorganisation.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
