<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132298" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norsk Hydro's net profits slump in Q3.</title>
<headline>Norsk Hydro's net profits slump in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diversified industrial giant Norsk Hydro ASA said on Monday lower prices for aluminium and petrochemicals were mainly responsible for a 45 percent slump in net profits in the third quarter compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>Norway's largest listed company booked profits after tax of 909 million crowns ($139.2 million) for the three-month period against 1.66 billion crowns in the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Hydro said its tax provisions were also higher in the quarter due to increased earnings from offshore oil and gas activities.</p>
<p>Third-quarter operating income of 2.15 billion crowns was 21 percent down from 2.72 billion and included a writedown of 400 million crowns because of a downward revision of estimates for remaining oil and gas reserves in the Frigg area of the North Sea.</p>
<p>The writedown was in addition to a 755 million crown writedown for the Lille-Frigg field taken in the second quarter 1995.</p>
<p>Excluding the writedown, operating income was six percent down from last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline was due to significantly lower earnings for light metals and petrochemicals,&quot; a statement from the company said. &quot;Oil and gas showed a marked improvement in operating income, while results for agriculture showed a moderate reduction compared to the previous year.&quot;</p>
<p>For the first nine months, Hydro posted a net income of 4.19 billion crowns, 27 percent down from 5.77 billion crowns booked a year earlier. Pre-tax profits for the period amounted to 8.40 billion crowns against 9.02 billion.</p>
<p>The results fell slightly short of expectations and Hydro's share price slipped three crowns to 303 crowns in early trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the negative impact of the pre-notified writedown of NOK 400 million related to the Frigg area, operating income for oil and gas was nearly NOK 500 million above that in the third quarter of 1995. Improved margins both for refining and retail marketing helped,&quot; Hydro said in its Profile newsletter.</p>
<p>Operating income for oil and gas amounted to 1.35 billion crowns in the fbthird quarter, a rise of 57 percent from 859 million crowns a year ago.</p>
<p>Meanwhile operating income from the agriculture division slid nine percent to 526 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had a financial strain this year tied to the start up of an ammonia plant in Trinidad after a maintenance shutdown and an upgrade,&quot; said Leiv Nergaard, Hydro's executive vice president and chief financial officer.</p>
<p>Third-quarter operating income for light metals slumped more than 80 percent to 158 million crowns against 943 million crowns due to lower aluminium prices, weaker margins in general for semi-fabricated products and reduced electricity production.</p>
<p>The division's income was also dented by unrealised losses of 119 million related to the group's aluminium trading activities.</p>
<p>&quot;A significant part of this loss represents the reversal of previously recorded unrealised gainsas well as other writedowns resulting from mark to market measurements of future contracts,&quot; Hydro said.</p>
<p>It added that it expected the poor market conditions to continue for the remainder of the year leading to a weak result for aluminium operations in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The company said the global market for vinylchloride monomer (VCM) and polyvinyl chloride (PVC) cocntinued to be characterised by weak demand and low prices in the third quarter, although market levels increased slightly towards the end of the period.</p>
<p>Hydro's operating income from petrochemicals tumbled 66 percent to 118 million crowns from 348 million crowns in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The cyclical developments are still lagging in some parts of Europe. We don't expect any rapid increase in the growth rate,&quot; Nergaard said.</p>
<p>--Tanya Pang, Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41 ($ = 6.530 Norwegian Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
