<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132295" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: OPEL PLANS TO ENTER POLISH MINICAR MARKET - PAPER.</title>
<headline>OPEL PLANS TO ENTER POLISH MINICAR MARKET - PAPER.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Adam Opel AG will start production at its Polish plant with a small family car but will follow through shortly with a launch of a new mini car, Opel's chief executive David Herman told Rzeczpospolita newspaper.</p>
<p>Reczpospolita quoted Herman as saying that Opel, the German subsidiary of General Motors, wanted to launch a new model that would be smaller and 20 percent cheaper than its Corsa sub-compact and would compete with Fiat's Cinquecento minicar.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to attack Poland's Cinquecento market,&quot; Herman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cars that sell the best in Poland are the small and cheap ones and we are working on such cars right now,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Herman said Opel expected to sell its new models in Poland and to export them to other East and Central European countries.</p>
<p>Opel launched the construction of its Polish 470-million mark plant last month and expects first family cars based on its current Astra model to roll off its assembly lines in 1998.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
