<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132268" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: DT has no comment on IPO range reports.</title>
<headline>DT has no comment on IPO range reports.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom AG, the German telecommunications giant, on Monday declined to comment on newspaper reports that the price range for its huge share listing has been set at 25 marks to 30 marks.</p>
<p>Germany's mass daily Bild newspaper and the Financial Times of London both reported in their Monday editions that Telekom and its banks had agreed on this range over the weekend, putting the target at the high end of analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>More than three million Germans have signed up for the issue, making it likely that as much as 70 percent of the shares could now be placed in Germany, the Financial Times added.</p>
<p>Around 15 percent of the issue is expected to be placed in the United States and 10 percent would be targeted at institutional investors in Britain, the paper added.</p>
<p>Neither Deutsche Telekom nor Deutsche Bank, the lead manager of the issue, would comment on the reports, saying the information would be released later in the day.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom will hold a news conference at 0800 GMT to discuss the final details in its sales prospectus and kick off the bookbuilding phase of its listing.</p>
<p>During bookbuilding, prospective investors will make bids for Telekom shares within a price range set by the company and its banks.</p>
<p>The final share price will be set on the weekend of November 16 and 17. Trading in the shares will begin on November 18 in Germany and New York and a day later in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Trading on the so-called &quot;grey market&quot;, telephone trade in options for Telekom shares, will begin in Frankfurt on Monday once the price range has been announced.</p>
<p>-- William Boston, Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
