<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132290" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares slightly weaker, seen consolidating.</title>
<headline>German shares slightly weaker, seen consolidating.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were slightly weaker in early bourse dealings on Monday and were unable to hold advances made in electronic trade, which was boosted after data showed some slowing in German money supply growth.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 leading shares slipped 2.55 points, or 0.09 percent, to 2,732.27.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which reflects all-day computer dealings in the DAX, had jumped to a new record of 2,745.82 points after the German central bank said money supply growth in September was an annualised 8.4 percent compared to 8.7 in August.</p>
<p>Dealers said some players were taking profit and the market was in a consolidation phase after new record high levels were reached last week. &quot;The market could fall a little bit further in the short term,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Preferred shares in software manufacturer SAP AG lost over two percent, to trade down six marks at 278 marks. Traders said they saw some profit-taking on the stock.</p>
<p>Drugs manufacturer Schering climbed over one percent after an upbeat analysts' meeting on Friday. Dealers said the company had confirmed that its dividend would be two marks per share.</p>
<p>National telecommunications monopoly Deutsche Telekom announced a price range of between 25 and 30 marks, in line with most forecasts, for the some 500 million shares in its initial public offering next month.</p>
<p>Dealers said Telekom shares were fetching between 37 and 39 marks in unofficial or so-called &quot;grey trade&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
