<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132219" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Some economists say Ireland should stay out of EMU.</title>
<headline>Some economists say Ireland should stay out of EMU.</headline>
<byline>Carmel Linnane</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ireland would be better off to stay out of a European single currency and wait for its closest trading partner, Britain, to join before committing itself, some economists believe.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Ireland should hold and wait until Britain goes in,&quot; Professor Peter Neary, economist with University College Dublin told Reuters.</p>
<p>Neary said increasingly he was less convinced about EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is being pushed on political grounds and politics is taking precedence over economics.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is essential to extract the economics and focus on them,&quot; Neary said.</p>
<p>For Ireland one of the major concerns is the effect on competitiveness if Britain stays on the outside of a single currency and sterling plummets, both Neary and Davy stockbrokers economist Jim O'Leary said.</p>
<p>Some economists argue that the impact of a depreciating sterling will not be large as only 30 percent of Ireland's exports now go to Britain.</p>
<p>But Neary argues that the exporters hardest hit will be primarily small, indigenous firms.</p>
<p>&quot;The main question then is what type of firms will suffer. I believe they will be disproportionately small, disproportionately Irish-owned and disproportionally labour intensive,&quot; Neary said.</p>
<p>He said the effect on multinational exports, which account for 50 percent of total Irish exports, will be far less as they are &quot;almost certainly less cost sensitive, they have bigger margins and they are integrated into international production networks&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;My bottom line is what you need ideally in an economy is flexibility and the Irish economy, in terms of its labour market institutions, we know is very inflexible. It is not obvious that the thing to do about that is to throw away the little bit of flexibility we have,&quot; Neary said.</p>
<p>Davy stockbrokers' O'Leary told an economic workshop over the weekend that significant movements in the real exchange rate were apt to be more protracted within EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only is there the commonly-recognised risk of sharp appreciations in Ireland's real exchange rate, but there is the much less frequently discussed risk of a sharp real depreciation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both Neary and O'Leary also disputed the notion that entering EMU may lead to lower interest rates for Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;Are we sure we will get lower interest rates?,&quot; Neary said. &quot;People assume that if we join EMU we will get a Euro interest rate which will be similar to the Deutschmark interest rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Neary said that all depends on how well the European Central Bank works.</p>
<p>Both economists believe the European Central Bank (ECB) may end up being forced to raise interest rates in a move to establish its credentials and effectiveness as an inflation-fighting central bank.</p>
<p>Neary said also questions how the ECB will work if it is faced with a crisis where perhaps a large country like France is hit by a shock.</p>
<p>&quot;Where countries have existing high debt and are being tempted, like France and Italy, to qualify for the Maastricht obligations in ways that may not be dealing with their longer-term budgetary problems they are going to find it even harder to live with post-EMU budgetary obligations,&quot; Neary said.</p>
<p>&quot;That may raise issues on the stability of EMU itself but from an Irish point of veiw it means our scope for any independent policy is further constrained.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
