<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132214" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: FEATURE-Morocco battles pollution threat.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Morocco battles pollution threat.</headline>
<byline>John Baggaley</byline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Within its mediaeval ochre walls, amid white buildings and green spaces there is little hint of the dangers facing the Moroccan capital Rabat or the rest of the north African country's environment.</p>
<p>But insidiously destroying its fabric, ruining Morocco's coast, and threatening its countryside, economy and health, pollution is being targeted as a relentless enemy that must be defeated.</p>
<p>Environment Minister Nouredine Ben Omar Alami says pollution is costing 20 billion dirhams ($2.3 billion) a year and could largely be beaten by spending 4.6 billion dirhams a year which would bring annual economic benefits of 14.2 billion dirhams.</p>
<p>His ministry, set up four years ago in recognition of the problem, has since then had an army of specialists within it and from other ministries working on a strategy for the years 2005-2025 to achieve this.</p>
<p>So far, its main task has been to assess the size of the problem. Some of the findings are alarming.</p>
<p>&quot;Rock near the main discharge station (on the coast) is burnt, eroded and denude of all form of life,&quot; says Abdelghani Chafik of the Fisheries Ministry, referring to waste pumped into the sea by edible oil, leather and phosphates industries.</p>
<p>While the phosphates earn foreign currency, local fishermen suffer, shellfish mutate, and waste and pollution threaten beaches which should be a magnet for the average three million, but falling, number of tourists visiting Morocco each year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Medina (Rabat's old city) is heading for squalor...its historic attraction rapidly crumbling,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>In the centre of Rabat, home to more than 750,000 people &quot;the lead and dust content (of the air) in places is 200 percent higher than World Health Organisation recommendations.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubbish is evident on parts of Morocco's 3,500 km (2,190 miles) of coast and passing ships empty their waste to make the Mediterranean the world's most polluted sea.</p>
<p>Stand by old quarries near Casablanca, the country's main financial centre, and watch 2,000 tonnes of waste a day being &quot;disposed of pell-mell&quot;, tipped from a height of 30 ft (10 metres) to land where it will.</p>
<p>Pollution of the water table from the quarries extends 300 metres from some sites, say the specialists.</p>
<p>They have for the first time pinpointed endangered plants and animals, targeted 10 factories for help and reform in the most industrialised area, surveyed waste produced by the 27 million population, and set priorities to change its ways.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end, the adoption of the most compelling principle, 'the pollutor pays', will have to be envisaged for later...&quot; minister Alami told a seminar on the environment this month.</p>
<p>One specialist told the same meeting: &quot;Each year in Morocco 3.9 million tonnes of solid household waste are produced in urban areas. Of the 85 percent which is collected, only two percent is recycled...the rest is dumped without control...&quot;</p>
<p>Morocco's two percent recycling figure compared, he said, with 35 percent in France and 50 percent for Belgium.</p>
<p>In Oued Sebou Basin near the ancient city of Fez, pollution from olive processing is such that production of drinking water has reached &quot;a critical state&quot;, said Mohamed Oublkace.</p>
<p>Morocco is the world's seventh major producer of olive oil, but at a cost. Waste from the oil plants, averaging 70,000 cubic metres a year, is such that during the olive season &quot;the capacities of drinking water treatment plants&quot; are submerged.</p>
<p>&quot;...during the olive season, production of drinking water by the station, in the best cases, only covers 50 percent of drinking water needs..,&quot; said Mohamed Saadllah.</p>
<p>From January 1993 to March last year pollution had forced a total stoppage at the plant 10 times for a total of 84 days.</p>
<p>Around five million people live in Oued Sebou Basin. And Oublkace said: &quot;Three years after the identification and recommendations for priority action...few real steps to combat pollution on the ground have been taken.&quot;</p>
<p>Among a battery of fresh recommendations are new laws to follow the 1995 legislation to control dumping that affects water supply, new methods, education, and money.</p>
<p>The figures are impressive. As examples, the ministry says it will cost 908 million dirhams ($104 million) for a first stage in setting up a plant to eliminate heavy metal from used industrial water in Medina and Doukkarat, 17 million dirhams to reduce pollution from the state-owned phosphates company, 22 million to do the same for one packaging company.</p>
<p>At stake, says the environment ministry is the health of its people, the future of its natural resources, its economic wellbeing, its fishing and tourist industries and &quot;one of the most important concentration of monk seals in the world.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
