<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132258" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Arthuis says to continue French bank reform.</title>
<headline>Arthuis says to continue French bank reform.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said on Monday he would continue to reform the French banking sector and highlighted rules discriminating between commercial banks and others in prudential controls and opening hours.</p>
<p>&quot;French banks are not in a very favourable position at the moment vis a vis their international competitors,&quot; Arthuis said in an interview with financial daily L'Agefi.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan to continue reform to harmonise the ground rules for competition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Arthuis said two areas of primary concern were the status of certain financial institutions and a 1937 law on opening hours.  </p>
<p>&quot;Numerous inflexibilities in terms of labour and the pricing of banking services are constraining the sector's ability to adapt&quot; Arthuis was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Efforts to improve profitability are also hampered by the fact that the market is home to players with different statutes and requirements on returns over shareholder funds which help the commercial position, profit and margins of some,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;These reforms will of course provide the time needed to prepare,&quot; he said. &quot;I also want to see developments on the 1937 decree which concerns only the commerical banks of the AFB (banking association),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;These rules penalise this side of the banking sector versus rivals who can also open their branches on Saturdays: it is also bad for employment and fails to live up to customer demands for a more accessible service,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tax treatment of the banking sector will also have to be examined in depth,&quot; he said . -- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
