<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132285" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Latin American firms see opening in EU beef scare.</title>
<headline>Latin American firms see opening in EU beef scare.</headline>
<byline>Dominique Vidalon</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Meat producers from Latin America on Monday launched a publicity blitz at Europe's largest food industry fair to capitalise on their &quot;natural&quot; meat products from cattle fed on open pasture and free of mad cow disease.</p>
<p>Firms from Argentina and Uruguay said they had no history of bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), or mad cow disease, which has undermined the industry in Europe and heightened concern over how cattle are fed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hoping to benefit from that high-quality image in the future,&quot; Juan Manuel Alzaga, sales manager of Frigorifico Rioplatense, Argentina's number four frozen and fresh meat exporter, told Reuters at the SIAL food industry fair in Paris.</p>
<p>Alzaga said his firm aimed to step up its presence in difficult markets such as Russia and the Far East.</p>
<p>Argentina exports around 20 percent of its beef production but hopes to double that figure within five years, he said.</p>
<p>Producers also hope to boost meat sales to the European Union but the EU market has been very difficult to penetrate.</p>
<p>Latin American firms have had a hard time marketing their products in a region where meat consumption and prices have fallen sharply since March, when Britain announced a possible link between BSE and a fatal brain-wasting disease in humans.</p>
<p>Beef consumption in the EU is down by 11 to 12 percent and prices are 15 percent lower than a year ago, EU officials say.</p>
<p>Foreign producers see obvious advantages in flaunting their image as suppliers of &quot;mad-cow-free&quot; beef, even though some of the lost consumer appetite for beef may be unlikely to return.</p>
<p>But the Latin American exporters complain that they face another big hurdle since imports of their meat into the EU are restricted by strict quota rules.</p>
<p>Some hoped that the EU might eventually have to increase the quotas as new members join the 15-nation bloc.</p>
<p>Uruguay, for instance, found in Sweden a new outlet for its sheep meat and beef when that country joined the EU in 1995.</p>
<p>A country where meat accounts for 15 percent of total exports, Uruguay is currently trying to convince European authorities to raise its quota for beef and sheep meat.</p>
<p>Alfredo Rodriguez Sere, vice president of the Instituto Nacional de Carnes (National Meat Institute), said executives from Uruguay's meat industry would meet EU authorities in Brussels at the end of end October to discuss the issue.</p>
<p>Uruguay planned to back up its demand for a higher sheep meat quota by showing that sheep meat consumption was on the rise in Europe as consumers shunned beef, he said.</p>
<p>Evidence published in July indicating BSE could spread to sheep if they ate tainted feed in laboratories has failed to dent lamb and mutton consumption significantly in Europe.</p>
<p>Uruguay has traditionally produced sheep for their wool. But it is now particularly anxious to step up exports of sheep meat as wool prices are relatively low on world markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="URU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
