<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132278" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 21.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Monday.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- A senior Irish policeman was appointed on Sunday to lead an investigation into allegations of corruption in the force in County Cork, southern Ireland.</p>
<p>-  Irish deputy prime minister Dick Spring on Sunday sent the strongest signal yet that he would like to see the present rainbow coalition seesk re-election as a government.  </p>
<p>- Irish shoppers face a spate of overcharging during the &quot;traumatic transition&quot; to a new Euro single currency in two years'time, the director of the EU consumer organisation BEUC, Jim Murray, said on Sunday.</p>
<p>- Ireland's food and drink exports have fallen by about five percent in volume terms in the first six months of 1996 compared with the first six months of 1995, according to figures published by the Irish Food Board on Sunday.  </p>
<p>- European Monetary Union raises grave concerns for the Irish economy and joining without Britain could spell disaster for the finance sector in particular, an economic workshop was told in County Kerry at the weekend.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- The Irish minister for Agriculture Ivan Yates said he is absolutely convinced that the increased number of BSE cases in Ireland this year is directly related to animals fed on meat and bonemeal after the ban on such products was introduced in 1990.  </p>
<p>- A female Irish aid worker was detained by Ethopian border guards after she accidently strayed into Ethopia from Somalia.</p>
<p>- Irish state industrial development authority, IDA Ireland, is set to achieve record levels of jobs creation for the second successive year, with up to 8,000 net jobs created in 1996.</p>
<p>- Leading Irish economists have called on the government to abandon the idea of cutting income tax rates and instead concentrate on increasing allowances.</p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
