<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132202" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- U.S. envoy Ross threatens to return immediately to U.S. if meaningful progress not made in Israel, PLO negotiations.</p>
<p>- U.S. a month ago warned Israel: A freeze in peace talks with Syria could bring escalation and deterioration.</p>
<p>- Senior treasury officials: military industries has to lay off 500 more workers.</p>
<p>- Interior minister calls for bringing 4,000 more Ethiopian Jews to Israel &quot;at one go&quot;.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- IDB Development buys Hapoalim's surplus stake in Clal for 137 million shekels ($45.6 million).</p>
<p>- Transportation minister says religious Jewish investors from U.S. offer to buy state airlines El Al running on a six-day a week basis due to the Jewish sabbath.</p>
<p>- Bank Leumi denies surrender to political dictate over appointment of new chairman for Africa-Israel.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- State witness aided in revealing Murdoch company case.</p>
<p>- Protests against Hebron redeployment begin to heat up.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Netanyahu's office says French President Chirac will be received warmly.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH</p>
<p>- Israel rejects the French attempt to get involved in peace negotiations.</p>
<p>- Gathering of rightwing rabbis says Hebron redeployment is suicide; Hebrew University professor says danger to Netanyahu's life from Jewish extremists over the Hebron deal if implemented.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu turns 47 today.</p>
<p>- State airline El Al will fly to Europe on Jewish sabbath.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Hindujas joins with Bezeq Telecommunications in India project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
