<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132244" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>-- Portuguese retailer Jeronimo Martins recently opened the biggest sports shop in Britain, in the city of Leeds, part of its Lillywhites chain.</p>
<p>-- Portuguese state airport company ANA - Aeroportos e Navegacao Aerea has revised downwards its forecast for traffic through Portuguese airports this year. It has revised growth in the number of passengers to three percent from a previous estimate of eight percent.</p>
<p>-- The privatisation of the state's remaining 13.2 percent stake in Banco Totta e Acores could take place in November, the Finance Ministry said.</p>
<p>-- Banco Mello Comercial should post profits of between 200 and 300 million escudos in 1996.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>-- A study by consultants AC Nielsen forecasts the closure of some 10,000 grocer's shops in Portugal by the year 2000 as supermarkets and hypermarkets take an increasing share of the retail business.</p>
<p>-- Opposition Social Democrat leader Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa wants a referendum on changes to Portugal's abortion law.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>-- Portugal rejected an attempt by Italy to form an alliance with Portugal and Spain to try to delay the launch date of the European single currency, the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
