<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132212" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Qatar's ousted emir to return soon - minister.</title>
<headline>Qatar's ousted emir to return soon - minister.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's deposed emir is expected to return home soon from self-imposed exile following an agreement over missing funds, a cabinet minister said in remarks published on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;God willing, his royal highness Sheikh Khalifa bin Hamad al-Thani, the father (of all Qataris), is returning to Qatar soon,&quot; Justice Minister Najeeb Mohammad al-Nuaimi told al-Khaleej newspaper in the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>&quot;Qatar is his hometown, and he is always welcome to return without any conditions. Our gates are also open to his entourage&quot;.</p>
<p>Qatar on Sunday announced it had ended a row over billions of dollars missing from state coffers since Sheikh Khalifa was toppled by his son, Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani, in a bloodless palace coup last year.</p>
<p>A justice ministry statement quoted by Qatar's official news agency said the government was dropping all lawsuits against the deposed emir in return for settling accounts at the centre of their dispute.</p>
<p>Nuaimi said he could not specify the amount of the disputed funds because they would be determined by the settlement.</p>
<p>&quot;But what is important is that their amount is not as large as was carried by the Arab and foreign media.&quot;</p>
<p>Unofficial estimates said the sum controlled by Sheikh Khalifa since his ouster by his eldest son in a bloodless palace coup in June 1995 ranged from $3 billion to $7 billion.</p>
<p>Authorities in Britain, France and Switzerland blocked bank accounts controlled by the former emir earlier this year at the request of the new government in Doha.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
