<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132237" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy budget should not be watered down - Ciampi.</title>
<headline>Italy budget should not be watered down - Ciampi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's tough 1997 budget must not be watered down in its passage through parliament, Treasury and Budget Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said in an article in the Turin daily La Stampa on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;This government must not just get along somehow from day to day, it must fly high,&quot; Ciampi was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no sense in this administration just busying itself with minor issues, we are now linked to Maastricht,&quot; he said, adding that the budget should emerge from the lower house of parliament reinforced rather than weakened.</p>
<p>The lower Chamber of Deputies has until November 17 to approve the budget after which it goes to the Senate where the government has a comfortable majority.</p>
<p>Communist Refoundation leader Fausto Bertinotti, whose party holds the balance of power in the Chamber, criticised the government's plans to modify certain tax proposals contained in the draft budget in comments at the weekend widely seen as threatening the budget's passage.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi, however, said on Sunday his government would not hit the poor in the budget, saying the effect of proposed tax rises for lower earners would be compensated by allowances and deductions.</p>
<p>The centre-right Freedom Alliance has presented some 1,000 amendments to the budget and promised &quot;intransigent opposition&quot; to the government's 62.5 trillion lire austerity package. The separatist Northern League has said it would present 1,800 amendments.</p>
<p>The budget commission has until October 28 to examine all the proposed amendments before passing the draft law to the full Chamber of Deputies for debate. The budget must be approved by December 31.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
