<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132243" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ENI opens lower, near max offer price.</title>
<headline>ENI opens lower, near max offer price.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Italian energy giant ENI opened slightly lower in Milan, close to the maximum price to be offered for institutions in the second tranche share placement.</p>
<p>ENI stock was 0.31 percent easier at 7,475 lire at 0814 GMT after opening at 7,465. The Italian Treasury announced on Saturday that the top price to be offered to institutions will be 7,425 lire per share.</p>
<p>The actual price is to be announced next weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes sense for ENI shares to move towards that level,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>Another dealer said the market may have been expecting a higher range, given Friday's levels. &quot;The price has been well received but anyone hoping to speculate on a rise will be disappointed with this level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Treasury said private investors would be offered a 3.5 percent discount to the price paid by institutions.</p>
<p>The second tranche placement of about 700 million shares would bring the Treasury's stake in ENI to 76 percent from 85 percent.</p>
<p>Market expectations are for a share offer price of around 7,200-7,300 lire, putting a value of 5.8 trillion lire on the share offer.</p>
<p>Analysts said the offer was likely to be priced attractively enough to encourage a strong response from investors and to trigger an over-allotment option.</p>
<p>The Treasury is set to announce the actual price of the share offer on October 26 and trading is set to start in the new shares on Monday October 28.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129689</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
