<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132255" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: INSTANT VIEW - German Sept M3 money supply.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - German Sept M3 money supply.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are comments from economists on the September German M3 money supply data measuring an annualised, seasonally adjusted rate of 8.4 pct.</p>
<p>Economists had predicted the rate would show a small slowdown in growth, measuring between 8.2 and 8.5 percent, after ticking up to 8.7 percent in August from 8.6 percent in July.</p>
<p>Mathias Haffner, economist at BZW in Frankfurt:</p>
<p>&quot; The M3 figures were no big surprise. Lower bank lending to the private sector is a surprise, though. We can't take any long-term trend from these figures. M3 is not really the main theme for the market at the moment.&quot;  </p>
<p>Gerhard Grebe, chief economist at Bank Julius Baer:</p>
<p>&quot;The development is excellent, weaker credit growth is encouraging, but it's no surprise and pretty much what I expected.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I still think it's going to be difficult to reach the M3 corridor. This doesn't raise expectations of further rate cuts,&quot; said Grebe.</p>
<p>Hans-Juergen Metzler, economist at Deutsche Bank Research, speaking on Reuters Financial Television:</p>
<p>&quot;It's exactly in line with our forecast. This is a rebound in the right direction.&quot;  </p>
<p>Metzler said: &quot;There is quite a good chance of a further reduction in M3 growth, but we still expect it to exceed the target at around 7-7.5. I can't expect a reduction in the repo for the time being, especially with last Friday's relatively strong numbers for the business climate.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In August, capital formation was disappointing, now there is a rebound. The long end looks more attractive. &quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There won't be a reduction in the repo for some time. The reason is a rebounding economy: strong Ifo sets Buba up for wait-and-see approach. Recovery in economy is likely to continue.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;After M3 the markets will be friendly. More important is the impact of the U.S., however. Fed fund rates could come down and then the German rates would come down too. Rally will continue - but not for too long.&quot;</p>
<p>Petra Koehler, economist at Dresdner Bank, speaking on Reuters Financial Television: &quot;We have quite a sound economic recovery in Germany now and we don't expect the Bundesbank to cut the repo.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are no expectations of a cut in the repo anymore. Sound recovery in the economy, new order figures, production, the Ifo report -- they all looked good. The long end of the yield curve looks more attractive than the short end.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is important. There could possibly be a rise in interest rates ahead since the U.S. economy is very robust,&quot; said Koehler.</p>
<p>Michael Claus, CS First Boston, speaking on Reuters Financial Televsion: &quot;M3 was better than expected. If anything, it will increase chances for a cut in the repo.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;More than by M3, Buba will be guided by European developments. Yet the M3 number increases the chance for a cut. That cut should be by at least 20, maybe 30 basis points.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Even if there is tightening in the U.S., the Buba will still cut, only later. As for the German market: Expect flattening of the yield curve from the long end.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
