<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132200" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- President Mubarak tells judicary Egypt is going through a boom period in large projects that will create jobs and raise living standards. Our efforts to waive Egypt's debts took five years and led to the scrapping of debts worth $24.5 billion and their $28 billion service payments. All doors are open for private sector investment and development, the government will only keep strategic and essential industries. The economic conference will allow us to show foreigners our investment opportunities.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Ganzouri meets with 14 ministers, decides on: setting up committees to find quick solutions to the status of joint venture; drafting a plan to set up a cotton fund which will keep prices steady and cover the difference between the government's buying price and its actual export price.</p>
<p>- Hebron negotiations to resume today, another crisis delays reaching an accord.</p>
<p>- French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette to visit today to prepare for Presdient Chirac's visit.</p>
<p>- Navy Commander Ahmed Selim tells news conference that Badr 96 military manouveres acertained the strenght of our armed forces, October 21 is a great day in the history of the Egyptian navy because forces sank Israel's Eilat destroyer in 1967.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Mubarak to the judiciary: Egypt's judges are the pillars of truth and there can be no democracy or stability without justice. An armed forces committee to be set up to gather the documents of the October war. Egypt must hold the economic conference because it is obliged to do so infront of the international community.</p>
<p>- Ganzouri and ministers decide on reassessing energy prices to encourage widescale investment projects.</p>
<p>- Zamalek beats Aluminium with difficulty (local football league)</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Mubarak while inaugurating the court complex in Abbasiya: we have several national projects in Sinai and we will bring water to the New Valley.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Moussa says the goal of the peace process is to set up a Palestinian state.</p>
<p>- Flash floods are expected in Sinai and the Red Sea on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
