<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132203" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-French President Chirac brings up Lebanon in his talks with Syrian President Assad.</p>
<p>-Prime Minister Hariri says the consultative committee of nations to help finance postwar rebuilding in Lebanon will meet on December 16 in Washington.</p>
<p>-Hizbollah chief Nasrallah says: &quot;The country is on the edge of a volcano and what is needed is an emergency plan to stop the deterioration&quot;.</p>
<p>-Hizbollah says the five-nation ceasefire agreement monitoring committee has failed in its mandate.</p>
<p>-Five guerrilla attacks on targets of the Israeli-backed South Lebanon Army (SLA) militia.</p>
<p>-Transportation Minister Miskawi says that the northern Tripoli port will have a role in the regional economy.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-Lebanon gets $20 million loan from Kuwaiti Development Fund for coastal highway in Beirut.</p>
<p>-Lebanese treasury bill subscriptions reach 15,637 billion Lebanese pounds by October 10.</p>
<p>-Speaker of the outgoing parliament Nabih Berri to be re-elected on Tuesday by a majority of MPs' votes to head the new national assembly.</p>
<p>-German parliamentary delegation in Beirut.</p>
<p>-Maronite Patriarch Sfeir urges authorities to investigate the alleged financial scandals in public institutions.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-The unofficial consultations by President Hrawi over the formation of the new cabinet begin this week.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-President Assad tells Chirac: &quot;Lebanon is out of its calamity and what hurts it hurts Syria&quot;.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Hariri says U.S. President Bill Clinton promised him to reconsider the U.S. travel ban on Lebanon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
