<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132209" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Cyprus - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Greek Cypriot press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ALITHIA</p>
<p>- Problems in right-wing Democratic Rally will be discussed at its political committee which convenes in 10 days time.</p>
<p>- U.S. President Bill Clinton reaffirms his commitment for a solution to the Cyprus problem.</p>
<p>HARAVGHI</p>
<p>- Cyprus's electricity authority modifies terms of the tender for the construction of a new power station at Vassiliko to suit a specific company.</p>
<p>- The government will push for the deregulation of interest rates in 1996.</p>
<p>PHILELEPHTHEROS</p>
<p>- Britain's envoy on Cyprus David Hannay sets a target of April or May for a meeting between President Glafcos Clerides and Turkish Cypriot leader Rauf Denktash paralell to secret proximity talks.</p>
<p>- Large landowners got relaxations to building coefficient legislation while regulations have tightened for others, says the chairman of small communities.</p>
<p>- Demonstration at the Ledra Palace checkpoint discourages tourists from visiting the north.</p>
<p>SIMERINI</p>
<p>- British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind is to convey a clear message during his visit that Britain wants to give the Cyprus problem a new push.</p>
<p>- Unions are on a collision course with the government over draft legislation banning strikes in essential services.</p>
<p>- Postmen declare a 24-hour strike.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
