<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132280" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Partek sees net up, overall profit down. [CORRECTED 06:48 GMT]</title>
<headline>Partek sees net up, overall profit down. [CORRECTED 06:48 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish construction group Partek Oy said on Monday it expected profits on disposals to lift net profit clearly in 1996 (corrects from 1995), but nearer the operating level its earnings would be clearly lower.</p>
<p>&quot;The net profit will be much bigger than last year's because of the profits on disposals,&quot; the company said in a statement with its January-August results. In 1995 its net profit was 149.4 million markka.</p>
<p>&quot;The result for the entire year will be clearly lower than last year's,&quot; it said. Profit after financial items in 1995 was 270 million markka.  </p>
<p>The company earlier this year sold its shareholding in concrete company Euroc to Aker of Norway for 1.6 billion markka, realising a profit of about 500 million.</p>
<p>Total sales at its minerals and insulation divisions were expected to rise, with precast concrete sales remaining flat but demand for its cargo-handling equipment division cargotec looked likely to stay depressed, Partek said.</p>
<p>&quot;The considerable reduction in interest-bearing debts will lower financial costs substantially compared with 1995,&quot; it said. @</p>
<p>&quot;Measures that will strengthen cargotec's structure and change the direction of profit development are now the priority,&quot; it said, but added that their effect on its earnings this year would be slight.</p>
<p>It said continued restructuring of its precast concrete operations and write-offs on real estate outside its core business would create costs of between 50 and 100 million markka this year. -- Helsinki newsroom +35 89 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
