<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132284" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FEATURE - Rome studies return of ancient obelisk to Ethiopia.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Rome studies return of ancient obelisk to Ethiopia.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of Ethiopia's most treasured artefacts, an ancient obelisk from Axum, has stood in Rome for 60 years.</p>
<p>Now, what has become an 80-foot thorn in the side of Italy's relations with its former colony may be about to go back.</p>
<p>Uprooted by occupying troops of fascist dictator Benito Mussolini and shipped to Italy as a war trophy in 1937, the monolith has languished in the shadows of such archaeological gems as the Colosseum and the ancient Roman Forum.</p>
<p>&quot;It clearly doesn't belong here,&quot; said Grum Abay Teshome, counsellor at the Ethiopian Embassy in Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;The way it was brought here dehumanises Ethiopia. It was looted from its sacred place and it has to be given back.&quot;</p>
<p>Grum is optimistic, more than ever before, that this will happen -- buoyed by a decision by Italy's Foreign Ministry to set up a committee to study how the obelisk could be returned.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe we'll see something in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rino Serri, an Italian deputy foreign minister, said the government would try to make good on two bilateral treaties, one signed in 1947 and the other in 1958, to return the obelisk to Ethiopia which for various reasons were never honoured.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to close this question. Treaties have to be respected,&quot; said Serri, who visited Ethiopia's capital Addis Ababa last month to discuss the fate of the obelisk.</p>
<p>Covered with relief carvings and believed to be nearly 2,000 years old, it once stood in the historic city of Axum in northern Ethiopia.</p>
<p>It is the second tallest of many obelisks built in ancient Axum which academics say are the most important examples of stonecarving and engineering south of Egypt.</p>
<p>Serri said the committee would begin work soon and was expected to take three to four months to prepare a report on the feasibility of returning the obelisk to Axum.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two schools of thought: one is that they brought it here so it has to be possible to bring it back.</p>
<p>&quot;The other is that after 60 years in a different climate, with all the pollution, it could just break into pieces if we tried to move it,&quot; Serri said.</p>
<p>Axum, now a popular tourist destination, was the capital of an empire which controlled trade between the Red Sea and the upper Nile. It enjoyed particular prosperity and expansion in the second to ninth centuries. In the fourth century, the civilisation embraced Christianity.</p>
<p>&quot;The Axum civilisation is the source of our culture and the obelisk is a symbol of this,&quot; said Grum, who passes the monument every morning on his way to work.</p>
<p>&quot;It annoys me that there is nothing written on the obelisk. All other monuments in Rome have a plaque describing the historic importance. There is nothing that shows its significance as a work of art of Ethiopia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mussolini invaded Ethiopia in 1935. When Addis Ababa fell a year later, Ethiopia formed part of Italian East Africa with Eritrea and Italian Somaliland until its liberation by the World War Two Allies in 1941.</p>
<p>Mussolini had the obelisk erected on October 28, 1937, the 15th anniversary of his March on Rome, in front of the building which was to have housed his Ministry for an Italian Africa.</p>
<p>The building is now the headquarters of the U.N.'s Food and Agriculture Organisation.</p>
<p>Grum said the high turnover of Italian governments, 54 since the end of the war, had contributed to the fact that the obelisk had not yet been returned.</p>
<p>&quot;A new foreign minister would come in, study the issue and just when he was ready to sign, the government would change.&quot;</p>
<p>Grum said a reluctance on the part of Ethiopia to demand the obelisk had also been a factor.</p>
<p>&quot;Various governments and regimes in Ethiopia might not have pushed very hard given that Italy was a great economic power, it was giving a lot of economic aid.</p>
<p>&quot;Relations have always been good, but this issue has always been in the back of peoples' minds,&quot; he said. &quot;The time is ripe to resolve it. There seems to be a conviction that the obelisk should no longer be a thorny issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Mussolini sympathisers have voiced opposition to giving it back.</p>
<p>&quot;I am against its return and I'm sure the relatives of soldiers fallen in Africa will also mobilise themselves,&quot; said Teodoro Buontempo, a member of the hard-right National Alliance who sits in parliament and on Rome's city council.</p>
<p>&quot;It should stay here as a symbol of the good Italy did in Ethiopia. They continue to benefit from the schools and hospitals we built,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Grum said the obelisk was being awaited anxiously in Ethiopia. &quot;It will be welcomed enthusiastically. Happiness and satisfaction will be with every Ethiopian.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
