<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13220" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Intria buys into two construction firms.</title>
<headline>Intria buys into two construction firms.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intria Bhd is proposing to acquire stakes in ACP Industries Bhd and FCW Holdings Bhd to consolidate its position in Malaysia's booming construction sector, the company said in a weekend statement.</p>
<p>Intria, formerly known as Acidchem (M) Bhd, recently acquired a 40 percent stake in British construction company Costain Group Plc and the latest moves were expected to strengthen its presence in the sector, the company said.</p>
<p>FCW is a local member of the Swiss-based ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG consortium, which has been awarded the contract to design and build the 13.6 billion ringgit ($5.5 billion) Bakun Dam and its transmission lines in the Borneo state of Sarawak.</p>
<p>ACP, which makes precast concrete pipes and other precast products, would complement the infrastructure and construction activities of the group, Intria said in a statement.</p>
<p>Intria is to acquire a 23.4 percent stake in ACP for 130.9 million ringgit, or 14 ringgit a share, from Abdul Rashid bin Abdul Manaf. It would be satisfied by the issuance of 49.38 million new Intria shares at 2.65 ringgit each.  </p>
<p>Intria is buying a 30.1 percent stake in FCW from Ivory Quest Sdn Bhd for 364 million ringgit, or 6.50 ringgit per share, to be satisfied by the issuance of 137.36 million new Intria shares at 2.65 ringgit each.</p>
<p>ACP shares closed 10 cents up on Friday to 15.10 ringgit. FCW dropped five cents to 6.45 ringgit. Intria shares, suspended since August 19, were last traded at 6.70 ringgit.</p>
<p>Intria also announced a proposed bonus issue of up to 546.66 million new shares at one ringgit each, taking into account the exercise of Intria warrants outstanding prior to the date fixed for determining the entitlement to the proposed bonus issue.</p>
<p>Intria said the proposed bonus issue would give three new ordinary shares for every two held.</p>
<p>Intria paid 159 million ringgit in early July for its stake in Costain, which reported a pre-tax loss of 37.8 million sterling in 1995.</p>
<p>Analysts said Intria, which shed its oleochemical business two years ago to concentrate on construction in Malaysia and overseas, was getting technical expertise and credibility by acquiring the long-established Costain.  </p>
<p>Intria is bidding on bridge and highway contracts in Brazil and Uruguay. It is also eyeing infrastructure projects in Australia, the analysts said.</p>
<p>Intria reported pre-tax profits of 5.69 million ringgit ($2.28 million) and turnover of 100.25 million ringgit in the half-year ended December 31, 1995 and has about three to four billion ringgit in contracts.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.49 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom 603-201-4813</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
