<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13223" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korea student round-up raises new Red scare.</title>
<headline>South Korea student round-up raises new Red scare.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rebel heroes in the 1980s, South Korea's student leaders are now being rounded up as communist stooges of North Korea in a new Red scare.</p>
<p>Their radical organisation is being swept off Seoul's Yonsei University along with a mountain of rubble, smashed desks and empty tear gas shells after pitched battles with riot police there last week.</p>
<p>Other elite campuses, too, are cracking down on what President Kim Young-sam has branded guerrilla warfare and what state prosecutors have condemned as terrorism.</p>
<p>Indulgent university authorities have tolerated leftist agitation for years. So why the sudden panic?</p>
<p>Government officials say student goals have changed, that leftist firebrands who battled for democracy in the late 1980s are now trying to smash it down under cover of a campaign for unification of capitalist South and communist North.</p>
<p>Violence at Yonsei began when police moved against a Pyongyang-inspired festival in support of a single Korea.</p>
<p>The festival marked the 51st anniversary of the division of the Korean peninsula following World War Two. Rallies were also staged in North Korea to mark the date.</p>
<p>While South Korean students have long flirted with Pyongyang's quirky brand of communism, a hardened core now appears to be growing better organised and armed.</p>
<p>Its pro-Pyongyang activities are becoming more brazen: two South Korean students who slipped into North Korea went on hunger strike in protest against the Yonsei crackdown.</p>
<p>North and South Korea have been technically at war since their 1950-53 conflict ended with a truce.</p>
<p>Critics believe President Kim is playing a political game. Nearing his final year in office, they say Kim is pandering to a public scared of Pyongyang and its military might to boost his standing and avoid becoming a lame duck.</p>
<p>Kim also needs rightwing support as he selects a candidate to replace him in presidential elections next year.</p>
<p>The massive assault on Yonsei last Tuesday appeared designed to achieve more than just dislodge several thousand students from their classroom strongholds.</p>
<p>The raid involving helicopters and black-hooded combat troops was given blanket coverage on television networks.</p>
<p>Although the students were armed with rocks, steel pipes and molotov cocktails -- and fought savagely enough to fatally wound a young riot policeman -- they were also exhausted and running out of food after a long siege.</p>
<p>Students were rounded up, roped together and clubbed. Some of the worst beatings were meted out to women.</p>
<p>Opposition figures complained of excessive force. After all, they noted, the unification festival has been a fixture of Yonsei campus life for years.</p>
<p>But student-bashing has played well with the public. The government has released opinion polls showing ordinary Koreans were solidly behind the crackdown.</p>
<p>Among the public there was a sense of anger, and dismay, at the sight of fist-waving students chanting slogans and singing songs penned by North Korean propagandists.</p>
<p>Some of South Korea's brightest young people unquestioningly accept North Korea's blueprint for unification that would leave the governments of North and South intact.</p>
<p>So far, 369 students have been formally arrested and police have issued wanted notices for top leaders of the Korean Federation of University Student Councils.</p>
<p>Many rank and file students insist they are not communists, just exercising their democratic right to express an opinion on reunification -- a goal espoused by Seoul as well as Pyongyang.</p>
<p>They are also demanding the withdrawal of 37,000 U.S. troops based in South Korea to deter a Northern attack.</p>
<p>President Kim has ordered university boards to stop coddling student leaders by, for instance, offering them passing grades even if they skip classes.</p>
<p>Among other moves being considered: withdrawing the federation's money-spinning campus franchises on soft drink vending machines.</p>
<p>Some analysts say Kim is polishing his anti-Communist credentials as protection. If Pyongyang accepts a proposal for peace talks put forward by Seoul and Washington, he could find himself in the politically uncomfortable position of making compromises with the enemy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
