<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132207" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel, PLO delay formal Hebron talks.</title>
<headline>Israel, PLO delay formal Hebron talks.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel and the PLO decided to continue informal talks on a Hebron redeployment and delay formal talks that were scheduled to resume in Israel's Red Sea resort of Eilat on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Saeb Erekat and Dan Shomron decided at the end of the talks in the early morning hours that the talks will continue without going down to Eilat,&quot; Israeli delegation spokesman Moshe Fogel told Reuters, referring to PLO team leader Erekat and Israeli chief negotiator Shomron.</p>
<p>A PLO official in Gaza, who spoke on condition he not be named, confirmed the decision.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Dennis Ross, who has been mediating the talks that are in their third week, met Palestinian President Yasser Arafat in Gaza for nearly two hours until 2 a.m. (0000 GMT) on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I believed we narrowed the differences. I believe we have made progress. We still have work to do,&quot; Ross told reporters as he stood beside Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still differences. I'm convinced that this is a very serious process. We are going to keep working at it and I hope to see results soon.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat asked Ross to thank President Bill Clinton for his support of the peace process.</p>
<p>After Ross left, Arafat, asked if a deal was in hand, said: &quot;Not yet.&quot;</p>
<p>A PLO official, also speaking after Ross left Gaza, said the U.S. envoy planned to leave for Washington later on Monday. U.S. embassy spokesman Richard Scorza said he could not confirm the report.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't have any information right now,&quot; Scorza said.</p>
<p>Israel Radio said the decision to delay formal talks was made when negotiators realised there were tougher problems on civil affairs relating to the partial Israeli withdrawal from the West Bank town of Hebron than first thought.</p>
<p>Fogel said: &quot;I think you have to see it in this context: the security parts of the redeployment are at a somewhat more advanced stage than civil affairs aspects but I don't think it has anything to do with going down to Eilat.&quot;</p>
<p>The radio said Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, meanwhile, began briefing cabinet ministers on understandings reached so far ahead of a cabinet vote on the deal to be called once agreement was reached.</p>
<p>Israel's previous government signed a deal that included the Hebron redeployment with the Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) a year ago. The redeployment, set for March, was delayed after Islamic suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in February and March.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, who took office in June, put the partial withdrawal on hold demanding changes to enhance security for some 400 Jewish settlers living amidst 100,000 Palestinians in Hebron.</p>
<p>Palestinians say there can be no substantive changes to the signed deal.</p>
<p>The talks were announced at a Washington summit called after 60 Palestinains and 15 Israelis were killed in clashes last month touched off by Israeli policies in Arab East Jerusalem, claimed by both sides.</p>
<p>Palestinians and Arab states see Netanyahu's handling of the Hebron deal as a litmus test of his commitment to the Middle East peace process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
