<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132294" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: War reduces Sri Lanka to low-budget tourism.</title>
<headline>War reduces Sri Lanka to low-budget tourism.</headline>
<byline>Mohan Samarasinghe</byline>
<dateline>KANDALAMA, Sri Lanka 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nestling amid huge trees fanned by cool breezes from the nearby lake, the Culture Club resort looks as if it comes straight from a picturebook of Sri Lanka's past.</p>
<p>Visitors are greeted by traditional drums, ushered to their rustic-looking cottages in bullock carts and treated to flute music during sunset cocktails on the verandah.</p>
<p>The Culture Club is one of many idyllic resorts scattered throughout Sri Lanka, all waiting impatiently for foreign tourists.</p>
<p>They may have to wait some while longer.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka's tourist industry, once the tropical island's top foreign exchange earner, has been badly hit by the civil war, now in its 14th year, pitting government forces and Tamil rebels seeking a separate homeland.</p>
<p>&quot;We're all scrambling for the business and prices are tumbling as a result,&quot; said Dirk Flamer-Caldera, a director at Connaissance de Ceylan Ltd, which owns the Culture Club at Kandalama, 140 km (85 miles) northeast of Colombo.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess beggars can't be choosers.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year, the industry earned $224 million, lagging behind the garment industry, expatriate remittances and tea exports as a foreign exchange earner. Its ranking could slip further this year.</p>
<p>Unable to attract a high-spending clientele, Sri Lankan hoteliers have brought down their prices to rock-bottom levels. A double room that averaged about $80 per day five years ago, now goes for as little as $23, said Flamer-Caldera.</p>
<p>Flamer-Caldera's hotel sells a room for $40 on a group rate, down from the $90 rate which was regarded as necessary to make a profit when the hotel opened a little over two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Look around you. We can easily sell this hotel for $100 a night, but only if the situation is good,&quot; said Herman Gonsal, the Culture Club's general manager.</p>
<p>Tourism officials are quick to point out that the war is contained in the north and east of Sri Lanka, well away from tourist attractions such as the southern beaches, the central hill country and the ancient kingdoms in the north central region.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the war is limited to a specific area, the perception is that this is a country at war,&quot; said Vipula Wanigasekera, director of marketing at the Ceylon Tourist Board.</p>
<p>Tourism minister Dharmasiri Senanayake has said the government will soon launch a $4 million global advertising campaign to press home the message that the war is contained.</p>
<p>Wanigasekera said tourist arrivals plummeted soon after the guerrillas blew up Colombo's Central Bank in January, killing nearly 100 people and destroying part of the city's financial district. No tourists were involved in the blast.</p>
<p>Then in July, a time when foreign tourists are thinking about winter vacations, the rebels exploded bombs in a crowded commuter train in a Colombo suburb, killing 57 passengers.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems as if the war is slowly coming to Colombo. That affects tourism,&quot; Gonsal said.</p>
<p>Tourist Board figures show arrivals for the first seven months of this year fell 30 percent from a year earlier. And industry sources say winter bookings do not change the picture much. Sri Lanka had a little over 400,000 arrivals in 1995.</p>
<p>Hoteliers say the industry's woes are not limited to the headcount.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem right now is not with the numbers. We have tourists coming but at ridiculous prices,&quot; said Flamer-Caldera.</p>
<p>The industry has responded to the low incomes and bleak forcasts by laying off staff, closing down sections of hotels and holding back on expansion projects.</p>
<p>Connaissance has suspended the construction of a 100-room hotel in the hill district of Kandy. Directly affected are some 200 construction workers and about 300 members of staff who were to be employed by the hotel.</p>
<p>Wanigasekera said he hoped the government's publicity campaign would reverse the trend. &quot;We want to stress that Sri Lanka still has great war-free destinations with a diversity of attractions.&quot;</p>
<p>At least the tourists at Kandalama seem to back that argument. Hannie Deville-Zuidmeer of the Netherlands said: &quot;So far it has been quite possible to forget about Sri Lanka's war and enjoy my holiday.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANDALAMA, Sri Lanka"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
