<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132265" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- Over 80 percent of young people in Sweden are opposed to phasing out the country's nuclear power programme by 2010, and the government's planned early start to the shut-down is also called to question.</p>
<p>- Non-Swedish diplomats in New York tip Sweden as favourite to take one of the two vacant places on the United Nations Security Council. The vote on for the places will take place later on Monday.</p>
<p>- The government communications committee is looking into the possibility of increasing tax on diesel oil and diesel powered vehicles.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Goran Persson says he regards the internal debate in the ruling Social Democratic party regarding nuclear power as over.</p>
<p>- Construction and real estate group Skanska believes it can save a total of 45 million crowns by connecting all its employees to one computer network.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- One in every two direct mail campaigns fails, a new survey shows. Swedish companies spend five billion crowns annually on direct mail.</p>
<p>- The British TI Group does not intend to increase its bid for Swedish polymer maker Forsheda even though British fund managers Henderson have turned the offer down. Henderson's stance would prevent TI from obtaining the 90 percent of Forsheda which would allow it to buy the remainder.</p>
<p>- Profits of listed companies are expected to return to the record levels of 1995 as early as next year when 30 of the largest companies on the Stockholm bourse are expected to earn a total of 145 billion crowns.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
