<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132291" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Emerging market investors focus on Russia, Bulgaria.</title>
<headline>Emerging market investors focus on Russia, Bulgaria.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Brothers</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market investors will watch for rumblings from Moscow this week while keep an eye on Bulgaria, holding presidential elections, and Mexico, preparing for a series of corporate results.</p>
<p>Most foreign investors agree that the ousting of Alexander Lebed as Russia's security chief last week should bring at least temporary calm to the Kremlin, and will be looking for stability in the markets despite thin, nervous debt trading on Friday.</p>
<p>Attention will now turn to the launch of the country's debut Eurobond, expected to be a possible $500 million issue with a five-year maturity.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't expect these events to delay the Eurobond, in fact it smooths the passage, because it takes away the (mud) slinging within the government,&quot; said Michael Jordan, BankAmerica's vice president of emerging markets.</p>
<p>Market players are likely to talk up the chance of a launch any time between now and early November, though with roadshows yet to come, this week looks a little early for such news.</p>
<p>&quot;The tempo of the rumours has been steadily increasing,&quot; noted an east European strategist at a European bank here.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in eastern Europe, investors will be keeping an anxious eye on Bulgaria. Heading into presidential elections on October 27, Sofia has yet to receive word on whether the IMF will release the delayed second tranche of a standby loan.</p>
<p>An IMF delegation is expected to arrive in Sofia this week or next and players will be waiting for any announcement on whether the country is taking new action on structural adjustment, privatisation or the closure of state enterprises.</p>
<p>&quot;Those people who follow the market closely will be reading the tealeaves,&quot; said one east European debt analyst here.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think the debt market will stay where it is right now -- those who are jittery have already left and those who remain are waiting to hear good news.&quot;</p>
<p>Away from Europe, Mexico is also likely to steal the headlines as the October 28 deadline approaches for companies to post their September quarter earnings results.</p>
<p>Joe McHatton, Latin America analyst at Kleinwort Benson, said he was looking for a poor third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;My guess is that the stock market will not like the results, and we might see a bit of a slide,&quot; he said, adding the Mexican stocks were about 13 percent overvalued.</p>
<p>&quot;The market could be down about 5.0 percent a couple of weeks from now,&quot; he said, but added that most of the Latin markets were reasonably valued.</p>
<p>Recent softness in the Mexican peso could, however, offset any stock market weakness prompted by poor corporate results.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico's poorer earnings probably relate to the peso being strong, impacting on export earnings,&quot; he said. &quot;If the peso declines there will be an earnings improvement ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>The peso dropped four percent last week, but most analysts said the weakness was part of the market's normal volatilty.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in the peso...does not in our view herald a new peso crisis and we still expect to see a year-end US dollar/peso exchange rate below 8.00 pesos,&quot; said David Atkinson, local currency analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Argentine stock and bond markets have been worried by allegations of corruption from former economy minister Domingo Cavallo, and investors are hoping there will be no long term impact there.</p>
<p>In Brazil, progress will continue slowly on an amendment reforming the country's civil service, allowing for the dismissal of workers and setting a ceiling on pay, after a lower house committee voted in favour last week .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
