<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132276" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Prime minister Romano Prodi, facing opposition from key hard-left allies over proposed income tax modifications, says the 1997 budget will not hit lower earners (all).</p>
<p>* Opposition leader Silvio Berlusconi, commenting over clashes within the ruling coalition over the 1997 budget, says &quot;It looks like a comic story, but the future of the country is at stake&quot; (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* Finance minister Vincenzo Visco denies the special tax for Europe will hit car, motorcycle and mobile phone owners as reported by newspapers. &quot;The Eurotax will not hit consumer spending&quot; (Repubblica, Corriere della Sera).</p>
<p>* Treasury minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi says the 1997 budget should come out from Parliament &quot;strengthened, not diluted&quot; (La Stampa).</p>
<p>* Analysts say the price for the second tranche sale of Eni (7,425 lire per share), which was fixed by the Treasury on Saturday, &quot;is higher than expected but there will be a rush&quot; (Repubblica).</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39266129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
