<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13228" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: FEATURE - China barrow puller turns company chief.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - China barrow puller turns company chief.</headline>
<byline>Mark O'Neill</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chen Zhongyuan used to pull a barrow loaded with sewing machines along the streets of Shanghai to the delapidated department store where she worked because the store had no cars.</p>
<p>Now she is president of the garment and commercial group Shanghai Kai Kai (Group) Co Ltd that is building a multi-storey department store and office building on the site of her former dingy workplace.</p>
<p>The Kai Kai Plaza, involving an investment of 550 million yuan ($66.3 million), is the symbol of the group's rapid growth in sales to 517 million yuan in 1995 from 200,000 yuan in 1987, when she joined the group.</p>
<p>&quot;My model is Marks &amp; Spencer with its 250 outlets worldwide,&quot; said the 50-year-old Chen in an interview, referring to the British-based retailer. &quot;We want to emulate its product quality, good service and cultivation of its St Michael brand name.&quot;</p>
<p>The Kai Kai brand is famous in China for shirts and woollen sweaters, made in seven factories in Zhejiang and Jiangsu provinces where labour costs are cheaper than in Shanghai.</p>
<p>Official surveys show that, despite an inflow of foreign makes, Kai Kai was the best-selling brand of shirt in the country in 1994 and 1995, with a total market share of nearly six percent.</p>
<p>The group sells its goods through retail shops in Shanghai and more than 20 cities nationwide. It also owns another shop in Shanghai selling airconditioners and has office, apartment and commercial real estate projects in Shanghai.</p>
<p>Chen plans to expand the Kai Kai brand into suits, leather shoes and leather clothes, with the group designing the goods and contracting the work, like Marks &amp; Spencer, to outside factories.</p>
<p>Kai Kai's success is in a cut-throat sector - textiles - one of the pillars of the Shanghai economy but now in crisis, with plants shedding tens of thousands of workers and shifting production to inland areas of China where labour costs are lower.</p>
<p>Chen is one of a new breed of Communist executives produced by the &quot;Chinese socialist market economy&quot;, running a large and complex company in a fiercely competitive market -- not for herself or shareholders but for the state.</p>
<p>With loyalty to both the Party and the market, they are a cross between an entrepreneur and a Communist.</p>
<p>Many earn salaries much lower than their counterparts in private, collective and joint venture companies who operate more independently of the state.</p>
<p>Chen said that, especially since 1995, she had been well rewarded for an exhausting seven-day work-week which leaves her little time to spend with her husband, a radiotherapist, and 25-year-old daughter. But she declined to reveal her income.</p>
<p>She lives in a 106 square-metre (1,140 sq ft) apartment with three bedrooms given to her by the city government and has hired a maid who helps to look after her 70-year-old father.</p>
<p>&quot;My motivation is not money,&quot; she said. &quot;For those of us who lived through the Cultural Revolution, this is a precious opportunity. I know people more able than I but they do not have this opportunity.... I want to do what I can to make this a famous brand and a famous company.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to turn this company from the single shop of 30 square metres and sales of 200,000 yuan it was in 1987 to a group with three to five billion yuan in sales,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Kai Kai was established in 1937 producing and selling shirts and woollen sweaters. It remained a small-scale operation, with a factory and shop on the same site, until 1987 when Chen and an associate came to run it.</p>
<p>It became a share-holding company in 1993, with a majority of shares held by the state and institutional investors.</p>
<p>Like millions of her generation, Chen was a victim of the leftist Cultural Revolution.</p>
<p>The daughter of two professors, she wanted to study geology and achieved excellent results at secondary school.</p>
<p>But, because of the poor class origins of her parents -- intellectuals were viewed during the Cultural Revolution as having bad class backgrounds -- she was sent instead to a commercial college for a year. Despite again achieving good marks, she was assigned in 1965 to work as a shop assistant at one of the city's worst department stores.</p>
<p>She moved in 1987 to Kai Kai as a deputy manager and was promoted to her current post five years later after helping the company achieve rapid growth.</p>
<p>Pointing to scars on her hands, she said they were a result of working close to the entrance on freezing winter days and refilling the face powder cartons bought by customers.</p>
<p>Since the store had no car, she had to pull the goods bought from other factories through the streets of Shanghai on a barrow.</p>
<p>(Conversion $1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
