<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132292" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norsk Hydro's net profits slump in Q3.</title>
<headline>Norsk Hydro's net profits slump in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diversified industrial giant Norsk Hydro ASA said on Monday lower prices for aluminium and petrochemicals were mainly responsible for a 45 percent slump in net profits in the third quarter compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>Norway's largest listed company booked profits after tax of 909 million crowns ($139 million) for the three-month period against 1.66 billion crowns in the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Hydro said its tax provisions were also higher in the quarter due to increased earnings from offshore oil and gas activities.</p>
<p>Third-quarter operating income of 2.15 billion crowns was 21 percent down from 2.72 billion and included a writedown of 400 million crowns because of a downward revision of estimates for remaining oil and gas reserves in the Frigg area of the North Sea.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline was due to significantly lower earnings for light metals and petrochemicals,&quot; a statement from the company said. &quot;Oil and gas showed a marked improvement in operating income, while results for agriculture showed a moderate reduction compared to the previous year.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
