<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132223" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: D.Telekom IPO at 25-30 DM/shr.</title>
<headline>D.Telekom IPO at 25-30 DM/shr.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Deutsche Telekom said on Monday that the price range for shares in its initial public offering next month, Europe's biggest, would be between 25 and 30 marks each, towards the top end of market expectations.</p>
<p>Telekom is issuing 500 million shares through a capital increase, with a so-called &quot;greenshoe&quot; option to sell a further 75 million. The flotation, Europe's largest ever initial public offering, could raise up to 15 billion marks ($9.73 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;We are firmly convinced that this price range very closely corresponds to the market's expectations,&quot; chief executive Ron Sommer told a news conference.</p>
<p>The price announcement marks another step towards the share placement next month. A final price for the share issue will be set during the weekend of November 16-17.</p>
<p>Bookbuilding, during which investors can place orders for stock, begins on Tuesday and will continue until November 14. Trading will begin on November 18 in Frankfurt and New York, and a day later in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Between 62 and 67 percent of the share offering will be sold within Germany, where small private investors are being offered a price discount of 0.50 marks per share on up to 300 shares. But they must place their orders before November 6.</p>
<p>Around three million Germans took advantage of a telephone hotline to register for the preferential issue terms.</p>
<p>Finance director Joachim Kroeske said that the placement of shares abroad would raise between 4.75 and 5.7 billion marks.</p>
<p>&quot;With the allocation of one-third of the tranche abroad we will underline the internationality of our flotation,&quot; Telekom finance director Joachim Kroeske told journalists.</p>
<p>Between 13 and 18 percent of the issue will be placed in the U.S., Canada and Latin America.</p>
<p>A further eight to 12 percent will go to Britain, between five and eight percent to the rest of Europe and a similar amount to the Asia-Pacific and the rest of the world.</p>
<p>Kroeske said that all investors would be treated equally if the issue is oversubscribed. &quot;Every investor -- regardless of where he subscribes -- will be treated equally. There will be no favouritism,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Telephone trade in the &quot;grey market&quot; for pre-listing trade kicked off on Monday with brokers quoting prices for Telekom shares after their issue well above the offer range.</p>
<p>At 0900 GMT broker Ballmaier &amp; Schultz was quoting a bid/offer range of 36.50/37.50 marks, with Munich broker Uto Baader quoting the same range. ($1=1.5423 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
