<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132283" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FEATURE - Portugal wrestles with the demon behind the wheel.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Portugal wrestles with the demon behind the wheel.</headline>
<byline>Samantha McArthur</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Orson Welles said he was only frightened twice in his life -- once when he broke his legs, and once when he took a taxi in Lisbon.</p>
<p>The actor had good reason to fear Portuguese roads. They have the highest death rate in western Europe.</p>
<p>The number of deaths per 1,000 tonnes of fuel consumed is nearly twice that of Italy and Belgium, two other European countries with a reputation for hair-raising driving.</p>
<p>Last year 2,165 people were killed in 50,000 car accidents, up from 1,964 the previous year, in a country with a population of just 10 million.</p>
<p>Police warn tourists who are brave enough to hire a car to expect the inexplicable.</p>
<p>It is not uncommon to see trucks overtaking a line of cars on a bend at the brow of a hill, or to be forced off the road on to the hard shoulder which often serves as an extra lane.</p>
<p>Politicians describe the accident rate as a national disgrace and have launched repeated prevention campaigns which have so far failed to make a dent on the statistics.</p>
<p>&quot;The average Portuguese is a nice guy, quite a gentleman, but behind the wheel he becomes a fiend, using his car as a tool to assert himself,&quot; said traffic police chief Matos da Silva, who has spent 20 years dealing with demon drivers.</p>
<p>Outside the Lisbon police station where he works a sign saying &quot;Slow, School Ahead&quot; lies crushed on the pavement like a broken lollipop in the wake of a passing driver.</p>
<p>Law professor Germano Marques da Silva, who drafted a new highway code two years ago, says the Portuguese can no longer blame their old cars and pot-holed roads since increased wealth and European Union funds have brought motorways and Mercedes to replace the 20-year-old Fiat 600s.</p>
<p>&quot;The roads haven't kept up with Portugal's car fever in recent years but that isn't the real problem. It's lack of good manners and education. To drive defensively requires maturity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Matos da Silva agrees: &quot;Our driving test is quite demanding and the schools teach good technical skills, but they don't instil an ethical approach to driving.&quot;</p>
<p>The Portuguese are not necessarily less mature or ethical than other Europeans but they are more likely to feel they will get away with a death-defying U-turn.</p>
<p>Whereas in the rest of western Europe a police car patrols an average stretch of 35 to 45 km (22 to 28 miles), in Portugal it must cover an average 130 km (80 miles).</p>
<p>&quot;We're not worse drivers than the Italians. It's just that we have fewer policemen,&quot; said Marques da Silva.</p>
<p>One senior police officer who did not wish to be identified said the Portuguese sense of impunity had its roots in the 1974 revolution which overthrew decades of right-wing dictatorship.</p>
<p>&quot;At that time people were so drunk on liberty they called us &quot;fascists' if we booked them for speeding.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the complexities of the Portuguese courts, where cases involving traffic offences might be held up for years and then swept away by an amnesty, had deepened drivers' sense that they were untouchable.</p>
<p>The 1994 highway code has cut back much of this bureacracy and introduced stiffer penalties but experts say it will take time to change deep-seated attitudes.</p>
<p>They cite the success of neighbouring Spain which dramatically reduced its accident rate recently by creating tougher penalties and running a campaign which put scenes from the day's bloodiest accidents on prime-time television.</p>
<p>&quot;People said shock tactics wouldn't work here,&quot; Marques da Silva said. &quot;They said the Portuguese didn't like blood and guts and would switch off their televisions, so we got a nice campaign with actors which didn't offend -- and didn't work.&quot;</p>
<p>Secretary of State for the Interior Armando Vara, who recently launched a new accident prevention campaign, favours shock tactics but thinks higher police visibility is the key to the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that will get people to fundamentally alter their behaviour is the knowledge that someone just around the corner will be watching what they are up to,&quot; he told the daily newspaper Publico.</p>
<p>Jorge Almeida Santos, a psychologist at the University of the Minho in northern Portugal, believes the cultural and psychological reasons why the Portuguese drive badly are often used as an excuse.</p>
<p>&quot;Blaming the drivers -- an amorphous mass that doesn't answer back -- is easy. The driver is the scapegoat for poor road management and insufficient policing.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
