<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132234" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- Some 80 percent of fathers now use their right to a four-week paternity leave. Only four percent took such a leave in 1993. Family Minister Grete Berget says the increase is fantastic and proves that the government's policy of making fathers assume more responsibility at home is working.</p>
<p>-Rimi supermarket chain open on Sundays despite protests by union.</p>
<p>-Rosenborg win 1996 elite division soccer championships.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- British Petroleum Norway will pay tax for the first time in 1997, after working on the Norwegian continental shelf for 20 years. High oil prices give BP Norway a taxable income on several hundred million crowns this year.</p>
<p>- Norway's largest newspaper Verdens Gang (VG) has stabilised it's circulation after slipping for 18 months. The circulation in August was 367,389 copies.</p>
<p>- A strong growth in Internet users has prompted state-owned telecompany Telenor's division Telenor Online to invest 150 million crowns in technology to improve capacity and the quality of Internet access. Telenor expects to have 150,000-200,000 Internet customers next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
