<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132270" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Monday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Four out of ten Austrian youths under the age of 18 would cast their vote in elections, a new study shows. Only some 20 percent of them would not want to vote at all.</p>
<p>- Beleaguered Chancellor and Social Democrat party leader Franz Vranitzky says he will push for reforms at a party conference to be held within the coming four weeks.</p>
<p>- Doctors heavily criticise Health Minister Christa Krammer's plans to have specialist doctors on call only during nights and weekends at Austria's hospital.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Vienna Social Democrats continue search for a coalition partner after losing absolute majority in the Austrian capital in last week's municipal elections.</p>
<p>- State-owned telecoms monopoly Post &amp; Telekom Austria poised to give major telephone book printing order to one of its subsidiaries, Omnimedia, without calling for a public tender.</p>
<p>- Austrian firms get ready for increased trade with Bosnia, expected to pick up next year.</p>
<p>- Analysts see ATX index breaking through key support at 1,100 points this week.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Social Democrats' chief whip Peter Kostelka promises to step up campaign for new jobs in attempt to turn around his party's sagging fortunes.</p>
<p>- Opinion poll shows a majority of Viennese would prefer a coalition of Social Democrats, Greens and Liberal Forum party for the Vienna state government.</p>
<p>- Austrian shopowners grudgingly agree to Economics Minister Johann Farnleitner's proposal for a reduction of overall opening hours to 60 hours a week from 66 hours currently.</p>
<p>SALZBURGER NACHRICHTEN</p>
<p>- Finnish Amer group expects its Austrian unit Atomic, a maker of skis and other sporting goods, to turn in a profit next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
