<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132215" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for October 18, 1996</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London shook off gloomy sentiment spilling over from the New York raws market an ended barely firmer. December finished 10 cents higher at $318.30 per tonne. March also ended 10 cents stronger at $315.50 per tonne. In New York raw sugar futures ended lower across the board with the spot-March contract loosing 13 points to close at 10.64 cents/lb. May ended 11 points lower at 10.65 cents/lb. The deferreds lost between two and six points. The decline came in response to predictions of another surplus in 1996/97. The market was not concerned about hurricane Lilly although recent reports indicate that there has been some damage to sugar cane. However, even before the storm nobody had assumed that the country would reach its production target for 1996/97 of 5.2 to 5.3 million tonnes up from 4.5 million tonnes in 1995/96. However, it cannot be excluded that the damage will have some impact on prices on Monday.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>CUBA - Official sources said that hurricane Lilly damaged crops ranging from sugar cane to citrus fruits. Some 66,700 ha of cane were reportedly damaged in Havana province, nearly three quarters of the total cane sown in the province. In Mantanzas province, authorities said 146,900 ha of cane had been affected. The 1996/97 harvest is due to start in December, with authorities seeking production of more than 5 million tonnes, following 4.5 million tonnes in 1995/96. This last harvest halted a steady decline in the sector since the early 1990s and Cuba is desperate to continue the recuperation of the sector.</p>
<p>ISO - The ISO confirmed that there will be another surplus in 1996/97. It said world sugar production in 1996/97 (October/September) could total 123.8 million tonnes, raw value, just 200,000 tonnes higher than in 1995/96. This, according to the ISO, will lead to a global sugar surplus of 2.5 million tonnes, the second year of consecutive surplus and half the level of the previous crop year. The increase in demand projected at 121.3 million tonnes after 118.6 million tonnes in 1995/96, will account for the sharply reduced surplus, the ISO said. Consequently, world sugar prices should drift lower towards the long-term average of 10 cents/lb, it was added. But the bearish potential of the global balance could still be limited by a number of restraining factors, the ISO said. These included the continuing tightness on the standard quality white sugar market, fears of a possible reduction of Brazilian supply from next year's crop and the expectation of higher demand in the world market from Ukraine, it emphasized.</p>
<p>PHILIPPINES - The Philippines have been over-importing in 1995/96. According to Wilson Gamboa, chief of the Sugar Regulatory Administration (SRA), the country imported 1.23 million tonnes, tel quel, in September/July 1995/96, resulting in an excess of 423,000 tonnes. He said over-importation of sugar in the country was an abuse of trade liberalization. Imports grew sharply after the Philippines offered a 35 per cent discount on tariffs to exporters from neighbouring countries. The tariff discount on imported refined sugar was part of the country's commitment under the ASEAN free trade area (AFTA). Most of the imported refined sugar which swamped the local market came from Thailand.</p>
<p>AUSTRALIA - Australia's sugar exports go from strength to strength. At 729,413 tonnes sugar shipments in August hit the highest level ever recorded in this month. This brought cumulative exports in the first quarter of 1996/97 (June/August) up to 1.56 million tonnes against 1.25 million tonnes in 1995/96 and 1.48 million tonnes in 1994/95. Total exports in 1995/96 reached 4.17 million tonnes against 4.48 million tonnes in 1994/95. Major countries of destination in June/August 1996 were Canada with 268,693 tonnes against 206,102 tonnes, South Korea with 235,875 tonnes against 233,848 tonnes and Malaysia with 232,950 tonnes compared to 206,476 tonnes. New on the list of Australia's sugar customers in August was Morocco with a shipment of 29,400 tonnes raws. Australian white sugar exports show signs of stabilizing after tremendous growth over the past years. Total white sugar exports in the first quarter of 1996 amounted to 41,186 tonnes against 42,333 tonnes in the like period the previous year. Major countries of destination in June/August 1996 were Sri Lanka with 19,500 tonnes against 5,489 tonnes and Hong Kong with 8,299 tonnes, up from 7,987 tonnes.</p>
<p>BRAZIL - Sugar production in Brazil obviously reached its peak in the July/August period and overall production in September showed a sharp drop to 1.87 million tonnes, down from 2.35 million tonnes in August and 2.40 million tonnes in September 1995. This brought cumulative production in the first five months of 1996/97 (May/September) up to 9.08 million tonnes against 8.09 million tonnes in the like period the previous year. Total production in 1995/96 amounted to 13.64 million tonnes against 12.60 million tonnes in 1994/95. Production in the North/Northeast reached 377,708 tonnes, tel quel, 11.7 per cent of the crop plan figure of 3.24 million tonnes while the Center/South so far produced 7.09 million tonnes against the plan figure of 10.53 million tonnes. Total alcohol production in May/September amounted to 9.71 billion litres of which 9.27 billion litres in the Center/South and 0.44 billion litres in the North/Northeast. The production of hydrous alcohol reached 7.76 billion litres while the production of anhydrous alcohol amounted to 2.95 billion litres.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
