<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132306" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan finance firm insolvency sparks jitters.</title>
<headline>Japan finance firm insolvency sparks jitters.</headline>
<byline>Kayako Watanabe</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Japanese financing company filed for liquidation on Tuesday with massive debt liabilities of more than $8.8 billion, spurring worries about the health of other firms in the financial industry.</p>
<p>The liability figure, which includes debt which Nichiei Finance has guaranteed, makes this the largest such insolvency case in Japan in the post-war period, one research firm said.</p>
<p>Like Japan's failed housing loan firms, or &quot;jusen&quot;, Nichiei Finance has been hit by plummetting property prices since the bursting of Japan's 1980s &quot;bubble economy&quot; of inflated land and asset prices.</p>
<p>The company, which is in the business of property-related financing and is classed in Japan as a non-bank financial institution, said it had applied to a Yokohama court for creditor protection under Japan's bankruptcy laws and would try to save what it could of the business with the court's help.</p>
<p>The news of the filing revived fears about the health of the Japanese financial industry, pushing down the stock prices of other such institutions.</p>
<p>As of the end of September, Nichiei's outstanding borrowings totalled 170.89 billion yen ($1.52 billion) and the debts it had guaranteed totalled 820.65 billion yen ($7.32 billion), making a total of around one trillion yen ($8.9 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;That makes the case the largest insolvency in the post-war era,&quot; an official at research institute Teikoku Databank Ltd, which specialises in bankruptcy data, said.</p>
<p>The previous record was Muramoto Construction Co Ltd, which filed for court protection in November 1993 with debts of 590 billion yen ($5.26 billion), the Teikoku official said.</p>
<p>But a Nichiei Finance executive said of the debts which Nichiei Finance had guaranteed, only about 100 billion yen ($892 million) was estimated to be non-performing.</p>
<p>The executive said the company wanted to pay back as much as possible of the 170.89 billion yen ($1.52 billion) it had borrowed from financial institutions. He also said major creditor banks would be asked to forgive loans to Nichiei.</p>
<p>Nichiei Finance had tried to restructure itself with help from its main creditor banks and Nichiei Co Ltd, one of its major shareholders, but the value of its assets had fallen rapidly because of the real estate slump, he said.</p>
<p>On the stock market, shares of other non-bank institutions tumbled. &quot;Investors are afraid the Nichiei Finance liquidation will set off a chain reaction of liquidations in the non-bank sector, and no one wants to buy those shares,&quot; a trader at a second-tier brokerage said.</p>
<p>But the Finance Ministry and one banking analyst said such fears of a ripple effect were unfounded.</p>
<p>Yoshinobu Yamada, analyst of Merrill Lynch Japan Inc, said Nichiei Finance's move would have no impact on the Japanese banking sector.</p>
<p>The ministry official said banks already had a good grasp of the amount of their bad loans to non-banks, and there was no worry the amount of overall bad loans would grow drastically.</p>
<p>Nichiei, a lumber firm which owns a 50.3 percent stake in Nichiei Finance, said on Tuesday it would post a 12.3 billion yen ($109 million) extraordinary loss in its earnings in the six months to September 30, 1996, due to the filing for liquidation by Nichiei Finance.</p>
<p>Nichiei said it would post a parent net loss of 10.70 billion yen ($95.5 million) for the fiscal year ending next March. Formerly it expected to post a full-year parent net profit of 700 million against its 1995/96 profit of 201 million yen ($1.79 million).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
