<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13232" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Violations down as north Lebanon votes.</title>
<headline>Violations down as north Lebanon votes.</headline>
<byline>Zeina Soufan</byline>
<dateline>TRIPOLI, Lebanon 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Lebanon voted on Sunday in the second round of Lebanon's parliamentary elections and observers reported a sharp drop in electoral abuses after charges of widespread vote-rigging in the first round.</p>
<p>Troops patrolled this Sunni Moslem port city during the voting but only minor incidents of violence were reported.</p>
<p>Fears of a repeat of abuses which marred the first round, when the pro-Syrian government rolled out a powerful electoral machine to crush a challenge by nationalist Christians, failed to materialise.</p>
<p>Some 580,000 voters were eligible to elect 28 deputies to the 128-member parliament. Mount Lebanon, the Christian heartland, elected 35 deputies last Sunday and Beirut, south Lebanon and the Bekaa valley vote on the next three Sundays.</p>
<p>As the polls closed, officials said about 50 percent of voters cast their ballots in Tripoli and other towns compared with 31 percent in north Lebanon in 1992 when most Christians and many Moslems boycotted the election.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some violations but in general it is much calmer than Mount Lebanon,&quot; Paul Salem, head of the Lebanese Association for the Democracy of Elections (LADE), said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe the violations are directed against anyone in particular, because none of the lists of candidates forms a clear front for or against the government,&quot; Salem told Reuters.</p>
<p>LADE said police were illegally in some election booths and authorities had given candidates voter lists at the last minute, some of them flawed.</p>
<p>Mikhail Daher, a Maronite Christian candidate opposed to Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri, said many people found their names were not on voting lists and officials had summoned voters to tell them who to vote for.</p>
<p>Daher said he telephoned Hariri to protest at the &quot;scandalous&quot; the way the vote was being run.</p>
<p>Last week losing opposition candidates demanded the resignation of President Elias Hrawi and Interior Minister Michel al-Murr, who is organising the polls, charging widespread abuses after government supporters won 32 of 35 seats in Mount Lebanon.</p>
<p>Newspapers dubbed the vote in the north, where four government ministers and 26 parliamentary deputies were seeking election, the most confusing round of the five-stage election.</p>
<p>The five rival tickets based on local alliances and personal rivalries offered no clear choice between the government and opposition.</p>
<p>Almost all candidates were friends of Syria, whose 35,000 troops give it a powerful say in Lebanese affairs and a close interest in the vote.</p>
<p>Supporters of Hariri, who is trying to build a national political base and is running in Beirut next week, ran on several tickets, sometimes beside his political enemies.</p>
<p>The most prominent list headed by two foes of Hariri -- Omar Karami, a former prime minister and Sunni Moslem, and Suleiman Franjieh, a Maronite Christian and former minister -- included three Hariri supporters.</p>
<p>The main rival list, headed by Karami's cousin Ahmed Karami, also included three Hariri supporters beside three of the Sunni Moslem fundamentalist group Gama'a Islamiyeh which opposes him.</p>
<p>The Gama'a is allied with the pro-Iranian Shi'ite Moslem Hizbollah which Hariri has denounced as &quot;extremist&quot; and vowed to crush in the election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRIPOLI, Lebanon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
