<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132367" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Manufactured Home seen extending offer.</title>
<headline>Manufactured Home seen extending offer.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manufactured Home Communities Inc is expected to extend again its tender offer of $26 a share for Chateau Properties Inc, which is set to expire at midnight Wednesday, analysts said.</p>
<p>In fact, some analysts believe Chateau shareholders expect a higher cash price for the mobile home park operator. These analysts suspect MHC, run by investor Sam Zell, will eventually sweeten the offer.  </p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised if they (MHC) will extend it again,&quot; said Tony Howard, director of research for First of Michigan. &quot;We still believe a higher offer is forthcoming.&quot;</p>
<p>David Helfand, MHC's chief executive, said the company is still committed to the transaction and wants to meet with Chateau.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't comment on it, but an extension is clearly one of the options,&quot; Helfand said, adding that raising the bid is also &quot;clearly an option&quot;.</p>
<p>Chateau has said it remains committed to a &quot;merger of equals&quot; with ROC Communities Inc.  </p>
<p>Last month the two companies revised their agreement under which each Chateau share will represent 1.0316 shares of the resulting combined company.</p>
<p>On October 2, MHC extended its offer of $26 a share until midnight October 23. It said it would be willing to consider &quot;an enhanced offer to shareholders&quot; if Chateau agreed to meet with MHC the week the letter was written. They did not meet.</p>
<p>As of October 1, MHC said it controlled about 51 percent of Chateau's outstanding shares -- a number that suprised analysts as low at the time. The MHC offer is subject to shareholders tendering at least two-thirds of the outstanding shares.  </p>
<p>The original tender offer was made in September and boosted Chateau's stock to $27 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I would have to think that a lot of the previous shareholders of Chateau sold when it was over $26, and new shareholders are hoping it gets into a bidding war,&quot; said Art Havener, an analyst with A.G. Edwards.</p>
<p>&quot;Many probably bought over $26.... I think we're going to hear more and more from Sam (Zell),&quot; Havener said.</p>
<p>Burl East, an analyst for EVEREN Securities, projected Zell and MHC could afford an offer of $27 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I ultimately don't know what they're going to do, but they do have room to move,&quot; East said.</p>
<p>First of Michigan's Howard said, however, it may take $28 or $30 a share to win. MHC is currently the largest player in the mobile home park industry, but a Chateau/ROC merger would be bigger.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a real incentive for Chateau not to continue on with the ROC bid,&quot; Howard said. &quot;I think everyone is doing like we've done and taken the wait-and-see.&quot;</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
