<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132316" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds end stronger, outperform on CPI data.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds end stronger, outperform on CPI data.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed stronger on Tuesday, sharply outperforming their U.S. counterparts, amid weaker-than-expected inflation data and expectations of a Bank of Canada rate cut, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The story continues to be unequivocally positive in Canada,&quot; said Anita Lauria, an economist with Salomon Brothers. &quot;Today we just got the latest installment in that trend.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$0.50 to C$110.90 to yield 7.083 percent. The U.S. 30-year benchmark fell 18/32 to yield 6.85 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds narrowed to an 11-year low of 23 basis points from 32 basis points at Monday's close.</p>
<p>Canada's unadjusted September consumer price index less food and energy prices, the so-called core CPI, rose just 1.2 percent year-on-year, Statistics Canada said Tuesday. Economists had forecast core CPI of 1.3 percent.</p>
<p>The report shows inflation is near the bottom of the Bank's 1.0-3.0 percent target range. Dealers said the report, combined with weak retail sales data on Monday, has led many to conclude the Bank of Canada will soon cut rates.  </p>
<p>Canadian T-bill prices strengthened following the CPI data, as the market priced in another cut by the Bank of Canada, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Evidence today told us there's really no price pressures whatsoever in Canada,&quot; said Lauria. &quot;Another easing could come at any time.&quot;</p>
<p>In other prices, the Government of Canada 7.0 percent of 2006 rose C$0.24 to C$104.20 to yield 6.427 percent. The U.S. 10-year benchmark fell 12/32 to yield 6.57 percent.</p>
<p>The negative spread between the 10-year bonds widened to 14 basis points from 6 basis points at Monday's close.  </p>
<p>Canada's 10-year bond on Monday closed with a yield below the U.S. bond for the first time since 1985.</p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded at 3.21 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.12 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
