<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132340" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BCE unit to hold 14.2 pct of cable group.</title>
<headline>BCE unit to hold 14.2 pct of cable group.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>BCE Inc unit Bell Canada International (BCI) said on Tuesday that if a series of transactions were completed, it would hold a 14.2 percent interest in a new concern, Cable &amp; Wireless Communications.</p>
<p>C&amp;W Communications, a new group led by Cable &amp; Wireless Plc, is to be formed through the merger of Mercury Communications Ltd and three U.K. cable telephony companies -- Bell Cablemedia Plc, Videotron Holdings Plc and the NYNEX Corp's Cablecomms Group.</p>
<p>The merger stems from Bell Cablemedia's bid, announced earlier on Tuesday, for Videotron Holdings Plc.  </p>
<p>BCI said C&amp;W Communications will be created from a series of conditional transactions. Cable &amp; Wireless Plc currently owns 80 percent of Mercury and holds a minority interest in Bell Cablemedia. BCI owns 20 percent of Mercury and 42 percent of Bell Cablemedia, which in turn has a 26 percent interest in Videotron Holdings.</p>
<p>To form the new company, Cable &amp; Wireless Plc will invest additional funds in Bell Cablemedia, which will then buy 100 percent of Videotron Holdings. Cable &amp; Wireless will also buy an additional 5.2 percent stake in Mercury from BCI, for which BCI will realize a cash premium to cost of 150 million stg.  </p>
<p>The expanded Bell Cablemedia, NYNEX Cablecomms and Mercury will then merge into a new company as the largest telephony operator in the United Kingdom, BCI said.</p>
<p>Assuming full acceptance of the offers, Cable &amp; Wireless Plc will own 52.6 percent of the new company, NYNEX Corp will own 18.5 percent and BCI will hold 14.2 percent. Plans are that the new company will be listed on the London and New York stock exchanges.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
