<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132359" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LDC debt sinks in N.Y. on frenzied dealer selling.</title>
<headline>LDC debt sinks in N.Y. on frenzied dealer selling.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin American debt prices plummeted Tuesday after overseas and U.S. investors unloaded Brady bonds and sparked a frenzy of dealer selling, traders said.</p>
<p>Argentine and Brazilian Bradies dropped dramatically when an investor in Brazil, coupled with U.S. funds, bailed out of positions that had experienced strong returns so far this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The air was let out of the balloon,&quot; one Brady bond trader said. &quot;We got up there fast and strong and the bid disappeared.&quot;  </p>
<p>By the end of Tuesday trade, Argentine FRBs had sunk 1-5/8 to 80-1/2, while Brazilian C bonds had dropped 1-1/4 to 69-1/2.</p>
<p>&quot;There was heavy trading concentrated in C bonds and FRBs,&quot; said Marcelo Fleury, vice president at Garband Corp, adding that he saw room for fresh bids below 70 on C bonds.</p>
<p>The sell-off reportedly began in Brazil, as players took fright when the Brazilian government reported exports in the third week of October totalled $844 million, down from $1.56 billion in the same week last month.  </p>
<p>Argentine paper suffered amid rumors of a cabinet shake-up that might mean the resignation of either Interior Minister Carlos Corach, Justice Minister Elas Jassan or presidential chief of staff Alberto Kohan. All three have been the target of corruption allegations by former economy minister Domingo Cavallo.</p>
<p>The three have denied any wrongdoing. An Argentine presidential spokesman denied this afternoon that any cabinet minister was set to resign.  </p>
<p>Overall, the Brady market seemed to view all news as destabilizing, though fundamentals have not changed dramatically in past days, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now everything is being interepreted negatively,&quot; said Ingrid Iversen, debt strategist at UBS Securities. &quot;People are not expecting to see any recovery (in prices) any time soon.&quot;</p>
<p>The instability crescendoed into a blow-out as dealers sought to avoid being caught long.  </p>
<p>&quot;Dealers were just stuck with paper and they kept hitting each other,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The real accounts dont want to step in until later in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
