<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132369" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cyprus Amax sees no delay from collapse.</title>
<headline>Cyprus Amax sees no delay from collapse.</headline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus Amax Minerals Co said Tuesday the collapse of a tunnel structure over the conveyor at Chile's El Abra early this month is not expected to significantly delay reaching commercial production levels.</p>
<p>Cyprus Amax said it is evaluating the extent of damage to the conveyor system.</p>
<p>The company said it expects 1996 copper production will approximate 750 million pounds and, depending on the timing of commercial production at El Abra, could approach 800 million pounds.  </p>
<p>Third quarter copper production totalled 195 million pounds for the quarter, 20 million pounds higher than in 1995 primarily due to a 67 percent increase in Cerro Verde's production, a 15 percent increase in Bagdad's production and a 10 percent increase in Miami's production, Cyprus Amax said.</p>
<p>During the third quarter, the company said, it sold 195 million pounds of produced copper, which is 17 million pounds higher than in the 1995 third quarter. Cost of sales increased $0.26 per pound from the 1995 period to $0.82 per pound for the third quarter of 1996, reflecting lower molybdenum by- product credits.</p>
<p>Third quarter net cash costs, before molybdenum credits, improved $0.07 compared with the 1995 third quarter, because of lower unit costs at Cerro Verde and Miami. Reflecting lower molybdenum prices, by-product credits were $0.12 per pound lower. Total third quarter net cash costs were 71 cents per pound, Cyprus Amax said. -- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
