<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132368" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TWA crash lawsuits draw criticism.</title>
<headline>TWA crash lawsuits draw criticism.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>A prominent aviation attorney was harshly criticized by other lawyers on Tuesday for suing over the TWA Flight 800 explosion before the government determined what caused the disaster.</p>
<p>Lee Kreindler, lead attorney for plaintiffs in the 1988 bombing of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie, Scotland, filed two lawsuits in Brooklyn federal court on Monday claiming the airline and the maker of the plane were liable because a mechanical malfunction most likely caused the July 17 TWA explosion.</p>
<p>The lawsuits alleged that Trans World Airlines and the Boeing Co. were at fault for the explosion over Long Island that killed all 230 aboard.</p>
<p>The cases were brought by the family of a husband and wife killed in the explosion.</p>
<p>Although the lawsuits focused on mechanical problems, they also contained a claim asking that the defendants be held liable if it is found that the explosion was caused by a bomb.</p>
<p>The National Transportation Board and the Federal Bureau of Investigation said they need more evidence before they can determine whether a bomb, a missile or a malfunction caused the explosion aboard the Paris-bound Boeing 747.</p>
<p>Other lawyers advising victims of the TWA explosion said the lawsuits were premature because no cause was determined. They said there was no legal advantage to filing the case so soon and accused Kreindler of taking the action in an effort to attract more clients.</p>
<p>&quot;This was done merely to generate publicity,&quot; said Kenneth Nolan of Speiser, Krause, Madole &amp; Nolan.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a big flashy kind of thing for him to draw the conclusion it's mechanical failure, when thousands of investigators are still uncertain,&quot; said Aaron Broder, another lawyer.</p>
<p>&quot;He attracts a lot more cases this way and there's a bandwagon effect,&quot; Broder said.</p>
<p>Kreindler said there was nothing frivolous about the lawsuits and that they had been filed only after his office had completed its internal investigations and shared its findings with the NTSB.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a need to bring lawsuits as soon as reasonably possible to get the litigation going. There's a limit to what we can do just relying on public information,&quot; he said adding that the Lockerbie litigation has continued for more than 7 and 1/2 years.</p>
<p>He said information gathered by his office could help the government determine the cause of the explosion.</p>
<p>&quot;I think ventilation is a good thing and we can talk about things the board and FBI can't talk about. Let's get it out there so everybody knows what's going on,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Michel Baumeister of Baumeister &amp; Samuels said he did not believe that Kreindler could have any new information because the government holds all the hard evidence.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Kreindler has no greater insight or information than any of us who specialize in this field,&quot; Baumeister said. &quot;There is no doubt malfunction may be the cause but at this time it is still a serious contender among the three possible theories.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's irresponsible for any lawyer to hold himself out at this point as having the answer because it holds out false expectation that the lawyer cannot back up,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
