<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13230" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu to meet Arafat for first time.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu to meet Arafat for first time.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu will meet Palestinian President Yasser Arafat within two weeks, Israel Television said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;As of now, President (Ezer) Weizman, Prime Minister Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai will meet within two weeks with Yasser Arafat,&quot; Israel's state-run television said.</p>
<p>It said that Netanyahu would most likely meet Arafat before the Israeli prime minister travels to the United States on September 10.</p>
<p>The television said Netanyahu's meeting with Arafat would indicate to the Americans his readiness to pursue peace with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>It said the meetings had been agreed during talks between PLO official Abu Mazen and Netanyahu adviser Dore Gold.</p>
<p>Since his May election Netanyahu has refused to meet Arafat, saying he would do so only when he deemed it necessary for Israel's security.</p>
<p>The television said that Defence Minister Mordechai would meet Arafat to discuss security issues, including a redeployment of Israeli troops from the West Bank city of Hebron.</p>
<p>Israel was due to redeploy in Hebron, the last major West Bank city still under Israeli control, in late March but delayed for security reasons. Some 400 Jews live among more than 100,000 Palestinians in Hebron.</p>
<p>The Israeli president earlier in the day said he would invite the Palestinian leader to his home but set no date.</p>
<p>Weizman said Arafat had sent him a letter &quot;in which he spelled out his troubles and problems and said 'I hope we will meet soon'.&quot;</p>
<p>Weizman made the announcement at a hurriedly called news conference with Netanyahu only hours after a newspaper said the outspoken president had threatened to meet Arafat over the right-wing leader's objections.</p>
<p>&quot;After an exchange of opinions, we agreed that the meeting would be held -- no date was set -- in my house, which is the most appropriate place,&quot; Weizman said after consulting Netanyahu at the president's Jerusalem office.</p>
<p>Israel Television said the talks between Weizman and Arafat would take place in the central Israeli village of Caesarea after the Netanyahu-Arafat meeting.</p>
<p>Weizman said he met Netanyahu last Tuesday and showed him Arafat's letter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
