<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132363" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Sumitomo copper scandal still dogs US minds.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Sumitomo copper scandal still dogs US minds.</headline>
<byline>Huw Jones</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. involvement in the huge Sumitomo copper scandal is unlikely to disappear soon as a major Wall Street broker was named on Tuesday as the victim of a forgery which helped to rack up losses of $2.6 billion.</p>
<p>Tokyo prosecutors arrested Yasuo Hamanaka, Sumitomo's former star trader, once dubbed Mr Five Percent because of his rumored control of this much of the world's red metal supplies.  </p>
<p>Hamanaka was being held on suspicion of forging the signature of a Sumitomo board member on two letters in 1994 which gave him authority to handle metal deals and cash deposited with Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>James Wiggins, a spokesman for Merrill, said the U.S. broker conducted all its business with Sumitomo in good faith, and in an entirely proper manner.</p>
<p>Sumitomo officials said on Tuesday their enquiries dug up no proof that Hamanaka had rigged the copper market or evidence Sumitomo could bring a complaint against a foreign trading company.  </p>
<p>&quot;In any event, we do not believe we would have any liability in connection with transactions conducted with them,&quot; Wiggins said.</p>
<p>U.S. regulatory watchdog Commodity Futures Trading Commission kept tight lipped on Hamanaka's arrest, saying that its own probe into the world's copper market was continuing with help from Japanese and British authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We are communicating and working together,&quot; said CFTC spokesman John Phillips.  </p>
<p>Despite Sumitomo's reiteration Tuesday there was no evidence of market rigging, lawsuits alleging that Sumitomo and Hamanaka fixed copper price appeared to be gathering pace.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there is evidence that Sumitomo and Hamanaka manipulated the copper market,&quot; said lawyer Chris Lovell of Lovell &amp; Skirnick law firm in New York.  </p>
<p>Back in July after the Sumitomo scandal broke, four lawsuits were filed, accusing Sumitomo, Hamanaka and two U.S. brokers who handled Sumitomo business, Global Minerals and Metals, and Birch Brokerage, of rigging copper prices by gathering large amounts of copper stocks in warehouses in Long Beach, Calif.</p>
<p>&quot;People from overseas and fund managers have expressed an interest in joining the lawsuits,&quot; Lovell said.</p>
<p>The lawsuits will be rolled into one class action to be refiled in New York in early January, despite some skepticism among other brokers about the likely success in court.  </p>
<p>Global Minerals have already dismissed the lawsuits, and the company's spokesman Elliot Sloane declined on Tuesday to comment on Hamanaka's arrest.</p>
<p>Last June Global and one of its senior officials were subpoenaed by the U.S. district attorney's office in Manhattan to give details about its dealings with Sumitomo.</p>
<p>&quot;We have complied with all requests for information and we are waiting for their next move,&quot; Sloane said. &quot;We continue to work with Sumitomo.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
