<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132308" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Boeing bullish on fighter jet. [CORRECTED 24/10]</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Boeing bullish on fighter jet. [CORRECTED 24/10]</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>KENT, Wash. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Co defense and space group President Gerald King said he thought the company had a &quot;better than 50-50&quot; chance of surviving to the next round of the military's Joint Strike Fighter program.</p>
<p>He said in an interview he was &quot;not quite as bullish&quot; about the company's chances of surviving into the next round of competition to win a contract to develop a so-called Evolved Expendable Launch Vehicle for the U.S. Air Force. (corrects program from &quot;...develop the next-generation space shuttle launch  vehicle.&quot;) </p>
<p>In the joint strike program, Boeing is competing with McDonnell Douglas Corp and Lockheed Martin Corp to win a contract to build about 3,000 jets in the next century for the U.S. Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps and the British Royal Navy.</p>
<p>The Pentagon will eliminate one of the bidding companies next month in a &quot;downselect.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is high on our priority, so we put a lot of effort into coming up with what we think is the right solution,&quot; King said in an interview. </p>
<p>He said he thought Boeing had a good chance because of the high degree of commonality in its design, which should allow it to come up with a lower price for the single modular aircraft with three different configurations.</p>
<p>&quot;I think our chances our better than 50-50 of going to the next phase because I think we've come forward with a very innovative solution,&quot; he said.  &quot;The customer is almost obligated to give us an opportunity to demonstrate that we can in fact deliver what we've committed to.&quot; </p>
<p>But he said he was concerned the Pentagon might favor the other bidders, particularly McDonnell Douglas, on the theory that a broad national &quot;industrial base&quot; needs to be maintained.</p>
<p>He said such an argument would make &quot;absolutely no sense&quot; because the United States already has excess capacity to build commercial and military aircraft.</p>
<p>If Boeing were eliminated the company would be &quot;available&quot; to partner with the surviving contractors, King said.</p>
<p>On the space shuttle program, the U.S. National Aeronautics and Space Administration is expected to select two finalists in December from among Boeing, McDonnell Douglas, Lockheed Martin and Alliant Techsystems Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though I think we have the best solution, I think the competition is extremely tough, with Lockheed Martin and McDonnell Douglas having present launch systems that they can evolve from,&quot; King said.</p>
<p>				   -- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KENT, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
