<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132360" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cardoso reelection to aid Brazil economy - Dornbusch.</title>
<headline>Cardoso reelection to aid Brazil economy - Dornbusch.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The best hope for Brazil's economy would be the reelection of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso so he could commit the country to thorough reform, a private U.S. economist said here.</p>
<p>Rudiger Dornbusch, economics professor at MIT, said Brazil would likely experience stunted growth as a result of its current mix of fiscal and monetary policy until the implementation of reforms currently stalled in Congress.  </p>
<p>&quot;The best scenario is that the president gets his second term, wins his election and on day one he says the next two years will be spent on serious reform so that by the 2000, Brazil is ready to grow like Asia,&quot; Dornbusch said.</p>
<p>Speaking at an event sponsored by the Commercial Bank of New York, Dornbusch said Brazil would experience &quot;uncomfortably little growth&quot; until the country implements reform because of the  monetary and fiscal policy mix.</p>
<p>Dornbusch said economic reforms would likely be on hold for two years until the presidential election.</p>
<p>The real appreciation of Brazil's currency, which was totally appropriate at the outset of the stabilization plan, was inappropriate now and formed an obstacle to economic growth, although no crisis was imminent, Dornbusch said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not predicting a maxi-devaluation, nor recommending one,&quot; Dornbusch said. &quot;I do not think there is a crisis at the door even if Brazil is selling off today.</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
