<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132300" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - OCT 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - FRANCE - OCT 21.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers. LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- European stock exchanges and Paris bourse hit year highs in wake of Wall Street buoyancy.</p>
<p>-- Schneider in preliminary talks to sell minority stake in public works subsidiary Spie Batignolles to British Amec .</p>
<p>-- UDF, junior coalition partner, loses battle for dropping of government plans to increase petrol duties and reduction in value added tax (VAT).</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- A French &quot;white knight&quot; may bid for Thomson  subsidiary Thomson Multimedia this week. A takeover by Daewoo until now looked unchallenged.</p>
<p>-- Credit Lyonnais chairman Jean Peyrelevade in an interview calls for a democratic control of the future European central bank, says cheques may no longer be free in France after EMU is implemented.</p>
<p>-- Textile group Michel Thierry in talks with U.S group Milliken.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis says in inteview that government reform of bank sector will continue, notably on the status of financial institutions and differences in opening hours under a 1937 law. Also insists that new French pension funds should pay out in annuities rather than lump sums.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Toshiba chairman Taizo Nishimuro says in an interview the computer group intends to develop multimedia product range, may seek European partnerships on top of U.S. and Asian alliances.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- Moulinex chairman Pierre Blayau confirms plans to cut 2,100 jobs, partly through early retirements, work week reshuffling.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Former EU commission head Jacques Delors says European leaders make European Monetary Union unpopular by citing it as reason for budget austerity policy.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
