<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132375" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity ends up strongly on cold, natgas.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity ends up strongly on cold, natgas.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures surged higher on Tuesday, driven up by heating demand from unseasonably cold weather and strengthening natural gas prices, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's cold in the west and it's cold in the east and (natural) gas was certainly higher,&quot; said one Houston-based power futures broker.</p>
<p>At least one futures broker called for electricity futures to continue to move up Wednesday, citing fundamentals as pushing prices to new highs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still in a bullish market,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Electricity physicals prices were also said to be higher through much of the U.S., again driven by the cold weather and higher gas prices.</p>
<p>November Palo Verde (PV) ended up $1.21 at a new life-of-contract high of $18.60 per megawatt hour (MWH), while December PV settled $1.00 higher at $18.85 after reaching as high as $18.90 per MWh.</p>
<p>January PV also hit a new contract high of $18.10, then settled 90 cents higher at $18.05 per MWh.</p>
<p>Remaining PV deferreds all closed between 10 and 85 cents higher.</p>
<p>November California-Oregon Border (COB) climbed 80 cents to settle at $19.50 after hitting a new contract high of $19.60, while December COB closed up 80 cents at $20.60 per MWh.</p>
<p>Remaining COB futures were steady to 65 cents higher.</p>
<p>NYMEX said an estimated total of 342 COB and 254 PV contracts traded on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Chris Reese, New York Power Desk 212-859-1627</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
