<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132379" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures end up sharply, shorts bail.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures end up sharply, shorts bail.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended higher across the board on Tuesday in a moderate session, with shorts rushing to cover ahead of November's Friday expiry after reports of further gains in the cash, trade sources said.</p>
<p>November surged 14.3 cents to close at $2.625 per million British thermal units. December settled 12.5 cents higher at $2.733. Other deferreds ended up by 0.9 to 9.9 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we could see more upside based on technicals, but I'm looking for a place to sell it. I certainly wouldn't want to own it here,&quot; said one East Coast trader, noting firmer physical prices on some cold weather set off the stampede.  </p>
<p>Most agreed shorts, facing colder Midwest weather this week and increased spot margins after today, opted to bail before November goes off the board.</p>
<p>But opinions were mixed about market direction near-term. While most conceded the market will remain vulnerable to cold weather spikes as storage operators protect stocks early in the heating season, they said any sign of milder temperatures could trigger swift retreats.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said December's close above key resistance at the $2.725 Oct 9 high should lead to a test of the $2.80 area and possibly a test of the contract high at $2.865. Support was seen first in the mid-$2.50s.</p>
<p>Cash sources said Gulf Coast prices firmed about 10 cents Tuesday to about the $2.50 level. Midcon pipes were up 10 cents or more to about $2.40. New York city gate gas also gained about 10 cents to the low-$2.90s. November city gate quotes were in the NYMEX plus 65-cent area.</p>
<p>The 12-month Henry Hub strip climbed 3.8 cents to $2.283. NYMEX said 62,508 Hub contracts traded, up from Monday's revised tally of 29,525. NYMEX November Hub natgas expires October 25.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Alberta natgas settled two cents higher at $1.095, while deferreds were untraded.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 28 Alberta contracts traded, up from Monday's total of 10. NYMEX November Alberta natgas expires Tuesday, October 29.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Permian natgas jumped 16.5 cents to finish at $2.38. NYMEX said 15 Permian contracts changed hands versus no trading on Monday. NYMEX November Permian natgas expires Tuesday, October 29.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, November closed 14 cents higher at $2.43, while deferreds ended up by 1.5 to 10 cents. The East/West spread widened by 0.3 cent to 19.5 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 306 lots traded, up from Monday's total of 286. KCBT November natgas expires Monday, October 28.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
