<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132303" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks open firmer after Dow record.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks open firmer after Dow record.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares climbed from the opening bell on Monday after the Dow closed at a new record high on Friday, its 31st record close this year following another round of solid corporate earnings reports.</p>
<p>At 10.30 a.m. (0030 GMT), the All Ordinaries index was 8.6 points firmer at 2,363.6.</p>
<p>The December share price index was up seven points at 2,391 and at a 27.4 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said benefiting the most from early buying was bellwether stock BHP which was aided by a firmer copper price as well as the Dow's rise on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;BHP is the standout this morning. There has been plenty of volume early and it is carrying the market at the moment,&quot; a dealer at a Brisbane-based brokerage said.</p>
<p>The dealer said resource issues were still favoured over industrials but that most blue chip industrial issues had also opened modestly firmer.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates are still a factor affecting industrial issues whereas resources are making up lost ground now that metal prices seem to have stabilised,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Amongst industrial issues, media group News Corp was well supported early after its ADRs rose on Wall Street on Friday.</p>
<p>Market attention was focused on engineering group ANI ahead of its annual meeting in Sydney this morning.</p>
<p>ANI directors are divided over the handling of the company's investment in the troubled Holter Environmental Systems in the early 1990s which has cost ANI more than A$200 million (US$159 million) in losses and writedowns.</p>
<p>Also active early was Foster's Brewing group whose shares opened weaker after it said that its 40 percent owned Canadian brewer, Molson had agreed to discuss a new licensing agreement with U.S. brewer Coors, after an arbitration panel ruling that terminated their previous agreement.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.795)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
