<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132336" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FEATURE - Exhibition celebrates Central Park's creator.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Exhibition celebrates Central Park's creator.</headline>
<byline>Robert Melnbardis</byline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imagine New York City without Central Park or Montreal without Parc du Mont-Royal overlooking the city. This would be the face of urban North America without the pioneering contributions of Frederick Law Olmsted.</p>
<p>The architect of these famed urban parks and about 500 other landscapes is celebrated in &quot;Viewing Olmsted: Photographs by Robert Burley, Lee Friedlander, and Geoffrey James,&quot; which opened this month at the Canadian Center for Architecture (CCA) with 160 photographs of Olmsted's work.</p>
<p>The exhibition is the product of seven years' work by the photographers, curator David Harris and historian Cynthia Zaitzevsky. It captures the vision that Olmsted (1822-1903) brought to his parks, private estates and cemeteries -- open spaces that invite the visitor to wander and explore.</p>
<p>Two galleries at the CCA are dedicated to Central Park (built between 1857 and 1878) and Brooklyn's Prospect Park (1865-95). One focuses on the &quot;Emerald Necklace&quot; of the Boston Park System built between 1878 and 1910, while another presents Mont-Royal (1873-81), Louisville's Cherokee Park (1889-91) and others.</p>
<p>Another gallery is set aside for Olmsted's work on cemeteries, suburban landscapes and private estates, such as William Rockefeller's Rockwood Hall in Tarrytown, New York, and George Vanderbilt's Biltmore in Asheville, North Carolina.</p>
<p>Phyllis Lambert, founder and director of the CCA, said the exhibition is designed to show how Olmsted's landscapes are a quintessentially American conception of nature in the heart of the city. &quot;The cities have changed so much around these parks, and yet the parks have this extraordinary impact on our lives,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>One photograph by Canadian Robert Burley features Prospect Park's Terrace Bridge, designed by British-born architect Calvert Vaux, who collaborated with Olmstead on Central Park and other major projects. In the foreground of the color photo is a shopping cart filled with what appears to be a vagabond's belongings -- a reminder that the homeless too are an integral part of the urban landscape.</p>
<p>In providing a present-day view of Olmsted's parks, the exhibition also illustrates the importance of protecting such green space from encroachment by concrete, asphalt, glass and steel. It took decades for Olmsted's parks to mature, and along the way they were threatened by developers, tinkered with by ambitious landscapers or simply suffered from neglect.</p>
<p>&quot;In the 1960s, Central Park was in a state of advanced entropy -- everything was being trampled to death,&quot; said Geoffrey James, the British photographer who proposed the Olmsted project to Lambert years ago. Today, 135-year-old Central Park is among the most protected of Olmsted's parks. Its environmental importance has been confirmed in scientific reports and private citizens and corporations have raised millions of dollars to restore it.</p>
<p>But the battle to preserve Olmsted's legacy continues. Over the years, protectors of Mont-Royal, the only mountain park Olmsted created, have fended off developers who wanted to build massive communications towers or turn it into a commercial ski hill. Local residents opposed to a recently opened McDonalds outlet just off the northeast edge of Mont-Royal have picketed the restaurant, calling it an affront to the natural environment.</p>
<p>The opening of the CCA's Olmsted exhibition coincided with the World Conservation Congress, a gathering in Montreal of 2,000 international conservation specialists who will discuss measures to protect the planet's biodiversity. Lambert said the theme fits well with the notion that Olmsted's parks have changed urban society for the better and must be preserved.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is what can we do now that will help them continue to have that impact for another 100 years,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
