<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132371" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon earnings slip, shares slump.</title>
<headline>Salomon earnings slip, shares slump.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The string of strong third quarter earnings from Wall Street's brokerage firms snapped on Tuesday with a surprisingly weak report from Salomon Inc.</p>
<p>Until Salomon's report, brokers had generally performed as expected, falling short of the record incomes generated in the second quarter but bettering by far efforts of a year ago.  </p>
<p>Salomon, however, failed to match even its 1995 performance, posting net income of $112 million or $0.85 per fully diluted share, down from $263 million or $2.10 per share a year ago. Analysts had expected Salomon to earn $1.19 per share, according to First Call's consensus estimate.</p>
<p>Shares in Salomon received a drubbing after the report, falling 3-1/4 to 45-3/8 on the day, but Wall Street analysts said a recent run-up in the shares ahead of today's report likely accounted for the sharpness of the sell-off.  </p>
<p>Analysts were reluctant to draw too many conclusions from the quarter, because Salomon's earnings are largely linked to its trading activities for its own account, and therefore extremely volatile.</p>
<p>However, one aspect of the quarter did raise eyebrows: a weak showing at the firm's Phibro unit, which comprises Salomon's commodities trading and refinery operations. The unit posted a $7 million profit in the third quarter, down from $68 million a year ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm never shocked when Salomon shows either a sharp increase or decline,&quot; said Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette analyst Joan Solotar. &quot;But one surprise was that refining margins were up worldwide and profits at Phibro were down.&quot;</p>
<p>During a conference call with analysts, Salomon declined to spell out the reasons for the profit decline, but the firm did announce its exit from coal, coke and fertilizer trading.</p>
<p>On a bottom-line basis, Salomon's negative net revenues in equity sales and trading of $26 million had an even larger impact than the Phibro results. In the 1995 quarter, the firm's revenues there amounted to $196 million.  </p>
<p>Analysts said most of the decline was attributable to a &quot;mark-to-market&quot; loss in the firm's proprietary equity arbitrage portfolio, an item that is all but impossible to forecast and not indicative of any underlying business trend.</p>
<p>The good news for Salomon was that underlying businesses such as investment banking showed improvement.</p>
<p>&quot;(Salomon's) long-term arbitrage portfolio and Phibro's trading results will continue to report widely varying results from quarter to quarter,&quot; Brown Brothers analyst Raphael Soifer said in a research note, &quot;but the firm's underlying performance continues to improve.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon's third quarter investment banking revenues rose to $187 million in the quarter from $128 million last year.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, 212-859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
