<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132304" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open weak, Delifrance shines.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open weak, Delifrance shines.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore shares opened weak on Monday as the foreign tranches of many blue-chip counters came under pressure, while buying interest was focused on new issues.</p>
<p>The benchmark Straits Times Industrials Index was down 10.62 points at 0210 GMT to 2,053.90 points. Turnover was 40.07 million shares with gainers ahead of losers 60 to 48.</p>
<p>Delifrance Asia, which made its debut on Monday, led the actives, opening sharply above its offer price of Singapore $0.78 and trading to a high of S$0.965. It was at S$0.935 at 0214 GMT on active volume of 13.9 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The talk is about it reaching S$1.00. There's a lot of institutional interest in the stock,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Labroy Marine continued to see interest after some late buying by syndicates on Friday lifted it from a flat debut, said a dealer at a local brokerage.</p>
<p>The foreign tranches of DBS, Fraser &amp; Neave and SIA Ltd headed the losers, shedding between S$0.40 and S$0.20. Malaysian over-the-counter shares such as Samanda Holdings and Land &amp; General dominated the gainers.</p>
<p>Dealers said Singapore's trade data, due at midday, were unlikely to have much impact as the market had discounted a decline of 3-4 percent in non-oil exports for September.</p>
<p>US1 =S$1.41</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
