<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132310" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 311 OF OCTOBER 22, 1996.</title>
<headline>OFFICIAL JOURNAL CONTENTS - OJ C 311 OF OCTOBER 22, 1996.</headline>
<text>
<p>*</p>
<p>(Note - contents are displayed in reverse order to that in the printed Journal)</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>Phare - digital orthophoto mass production Notice of invitation to tender issued by the European Commission on behalf of the Government of Lithuania for a project financed in the framework of the Phare Programme Project title and number: Orthophoto production line for land-reform project in Lithuania - LI940501.02 (Official Journal of the European Communities No C 290, 3. 10. 1996, p. 18) (96/C 311/11)</p>
<p>Collection and synthesis of data related to water management in Greece, Spain, France, Italy, Portugal, Cyprus and Malta Open procedure (96/C 311/10)</p>
<p>Tabletop lecterns Open procedure (96/C 311/09)</p>
<p>EUROPEAN ECONOMIC INTEREST GROUPING Notices published pursuant to Council Regulation (EEC) No 2137/85 of 25 July 1985 (1) - Formation (96/C 311/08)</p>
<p>Outcome of the invitation to tender (Community food aid) (96/C 311/07)</p>
<p>NOTICE OF OPEN COMPETITION (96/C 311/06)</p>
<p>Approval of State aid pursuant to Articles 92 and 93 of the EC Treaty Cases where the Commission does not raise objections Aid No N 511/95 - United Kingdom (96/C 311/05)</p>
<p>STATE AID C 24/96 (ex NN 48/96) France (96/C 311/04)</p>
<p>STATE AID C 31/96 (ex NN 46/96) Italy (Sardinia) (96/C 311/03)</p>
<p>LIST OF DOCUMENTS FORWARDED BY THE COMMISSION TO THE COUNCIL DURING THE PERIOD 7 TO 11. 10. 1996 (96/C 311/02)</p>
<p>Ecu (1) 21 October 1996 (96/C 311/01) END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
