<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13242" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks extend losses over Iraq worries.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks extend losses over Iraq worries.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian stocks slipped further on Sunday with renewed fears of a deterioration in ties with Iraq that would harm industrial firms exports to its key neighbouring market, dealers.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market 60-share index shed 0.19 percent to 139.27 percent from 139.54 points on Saturday -- and still was below the key 140-point psychological barrier.</p>
<p>A total of 249,995 shares changed hands in an low 373,479 dinar turnover in the cash-squeezed market, with no demand from foreign investors or any noticeable institutional buyers.  </p>
<p>Many of Jordan's industrial firms still rely substantially on the Iraqi market, one of the country's key export outlets despite U.N. imposed sanctions against Baghdad since the 1990 Gulf crisis.</p>
<p>The stockmarket, already suffering from lack of cash liquidity and little institutional support, has fallen by just under one percent since the two days of rioting last week.</p>
<p>The riots, the worst since 1989 unrest, were fuelled by the government's decision this month to almost double prices of bread in line with IMF-agreed economic reforms.  </p>
<p>Government accusations that Baghdad had exploited economic hardship to forment its most serious unrest civil disturbances for years have raised investors worries that Jordanian businesses will lose an anticipated share of the U.N. approved oil-for food deal contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been weak from the start and the situation now calming in the south did not have a positive impact on the market with the Iraq worries now weighing down on the market,&quot; said one broker.  </p>
<p>The market first broke the 140-point barrier at the end of June and has since slid to levels not reached since 1993. But it began a gradual pickup in trade at the start of last week.</p>
<p>Businessmen said while the troubles added uncertainty over the country's long term economic outlook, the government's tough handling so far shows determination to push on with radical IMF-backed economic reforms.</p>
<p>The Pearl Investable Index -- an independent index of the 45 best-performing shares from the official market -- dropped 0.19 percent to 79.80 points. It was 16.44 percent down on last year.</p>
<p>Along with lack of institutional support, the market has suffered since the start of the year from a liquidity crunch blamed on high interest rates by the state to protect the dinar.</p>
<p>Large investors and institutions have avoided the market, with the official index falling between 12-13 percent this year, with most of the trading dominated by floor traders.</p>
<p>Industrials dominated on a 194,060 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.08 percent, banks had a 112,422 dinar turnover and an index drop of 0.38 percent while services had a 64,186 dinar turnover and an index drop of 0.36 percent.</p>
<p>A total of 145,976 shares worth 89,209 dinars changed hands in weak trade in the parallel market.</p>
<p>--  Amman newsroom takes queries on +962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
