<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132483" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: South Dakota Senate race seen neck-and-neck.</title>
<headline>South Dakota Senate race seen neck-and-neck.</headline>
<byline>Greg Frost</byline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The increasingly nasty-sounding campaign between South Dakota Republican Sen. Larry Pressler and his Democratic opponent looks set to remain a nail-biter right up until the election.</p>
<p>Political analysts said Pressler's re-election effort has stumbled in recent weeks over allegations of possible abuse of campaign funds, but lack of reliable polling has made it tough to tell if either candidate holds an edge.</p>
<p>The tight race pits Pressler, a Vietnam veteran and a one-time presidential candidate, against U.S. Representative Tim Johnson, the only congressman from rural South Dakota.</p>
<p>Democratic sources said this could be one of their best chances of unseating a Republican incumbent in the Senate, but it will not be easy.</p>
<p>Although South Dakota has produced such Democratic luminaries as former presidential candidate George McGovern and Senate Minority Leader Tom Daschle, the state is located at the heart of America's High Plains and, as such, tends to lean Republican with its conservative neighbors.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been neck-and-neck for the entire campaign,&quot; said Jennifer Duffy, an analyst for the Cook Political Report in Washington. &quot;Unfortunately, there's an absence of independent polling in South Dakota, which is real problematic for those of us who have to follow the race.&quot;</p>
<p>Both campaigns recently released internal polls that show them leading the opponent by 10 points. The Pressler campaign said its tracking poll showed Pressler with a &quot;consistent lead&quot; over Johnson in his bid for a fourth term in the Senate.</p>
<p>But earlier this month, Pressler was hit by allegations that he violated federal election rules by using campaign funds to pay for personal expenses.</p>
<p>The report, published in the PoliticsNow online service and picked up by South Dakota newspapers and television stations, detailed the senator's lavish campaign spending at posh restaurants and luxury hotels around the country.</p>
<p>Other inquiries showed Pressler recorded more unspecified spending than any U.S. Senate candidate and that he had the largest amount of spending where he was reimbursed personally for the expenditures.</p>
<p>&quot;Sen. Pressler's campaign has attempted to portray him as a farm boy, a boy-next-door type,&quot; said Bob Burns, director of the political science department at South Dakota State University. &quot;The campaign spending report suggests that he leads quite a different lifestyle... That's why it was so damaging.</p>
<p>The Johnson campaign has so far been slow to pick up on the allegations, choosing instead to let the media run with the story. Johnson has campaigned on the theme that Pressler is out of touch with South Dakota voters.</p>
<p>Pressler, in turn, has charged that Johnson is &quot;too liberal&quot; for the state. The Republican has also accused his opponent of assailing his character, referring to speculation cited in the book &quot;Washington Babylon&quot; that Pressler is gay.</p>
<p>Former Democratic Sen. James Abourezk invited the book's author, Alexander Cockburn, to speak in South Dakota earlier this year, sparking a litany of protest from Pressler, who accused Johnson and the Democrats of trying to smear him. Johnson has denied the charge.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
