<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132475" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US newspapers seen enjoying benefits of austerity.</title>
<headline>US newspapers seen enjoying benefits of austerity.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. newspaper industry is enjoying a lift in quarterly profits from austerity measures meant to defend against rising raw-material prices, and the benefits are expected to extend into 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;All the cost cuts put in place six to nine months ago -- the smaller news holes, the narrow margins and staff reductions -- are going right to the bottom line,&quot; said media analyst Rita Zanella of Gruntal &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Prices for newsprint, the raw material used in newspapers, peaked at $743 a ton in January after a swift rise that dragged down industry profitability.  </p>
<p>Publishers reacted by conserving newsprint. Some reduced their news holes -- the pages dedicated to news stories -- or eliminated unprofitable subscribers. Other newspapers trimmed the white margins on each page. Some jobs were lost, too.</p>
<p>But newsprint prices now average about $550 and are forecast to average between $550 and $600 through the end of 1997, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Costs look pretty good,&quot; said Prudential Securities analyst James Marsh.  </p>
<p>The drop in newsprint prices gave both Times Mirror and Tribune Co a big lift in the third quarter because of their inventory accounting, Marsh said.</p>
<p>Times Mirror reported earnings of $0.43 a share, compared with a loss of $2.98 in the third quarter last year and $0.07 more than the consenus of Wall Street forecasts.</p>
<p>Tribune posted earnings of $1.00 a share, $0.21 more than the 1995 third quarter and $0.15 more than the consensus forecast.</p>
<p>For other big companies, such as Knight-Ridder, the benefits will come later this year and in early 1997, Marsh said.</p>
<p>Gannett Co, the biggest U.S. publisher which recently added broadcast properties, reported earnings of $0.82 a share, up from $0.64 a year ago and in line with the consensus forecast.</p>
<p>Marsh said several newspaper companies had stronger revenues than expected, reflecting healthy rises in classified advertising.</p>
<p>-- Michael Connor 212-859-1713</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
