<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132438" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jason motor vehicle, industrial segments gain.</title>
<headline>Jason motor vehicle, industrial segments gain.</headline>
<dateline>MILWAUKEE, Wis. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jason Inc said Tuesday a rise in its third quarter earnings was due to strong performance in both its motor vehicle and industrial segments.</p>
<p>It reported earnings for the third quarter of $0.11 a share, up from $0.07 a year earlier.</p>
<p>Jason said motor vehicle segment sales and earnings rose due to a seven percent increase in U.S. automotive production during the quarter, as well as increased sales of its new Marabond moldable fiber insulation.  </p>
<p>Jason said its Milsco Manufacturing unit, which supplies seats and accessories to Harley-Davidson Inc, also contributed strongly to results in this segment.</p>
<p>Jason said its industrial products divisions all had strong performances in the quarter, reflecting a healthy U.S. economy and good operating control.</p>
<p>Results in the power generation segment declined due to continuing softness in the U.S. market and pricing pressure on foreign jobs, it said.</p>
<p>Jason said it did not expect the power generation market to improve for several quarters.</p>
<p>The company said its previously announced acquisition of a 51 percent stake in Suroflex GmbH, a German automotive insulation maker, is expected to close by the end of October.</p>
<p>Jason said the response from European automotive manufacturers to its planned purchase of a majority stake in Suroflex had been &quot;extremely positive.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILWAUKEE, Wis."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
