<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13245" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel budget deficit surpasses yearly target.</title>
<headline>Israel budget deficit surpasses yearly target.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel said that until the end of August the government's budget deficit will surpass the 7.6 billion shekel target for all of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a source of real uncertainty in the economy,&quot; Frenkel said at an economic seminar in Tel Aviv.</p>
<p>The government posted a deficit of 6.5 billion shekels in the first seven months of the year. It will report its deficit for August in the first week of September.</p>
<p>Frenkel has said he cannot loosen his grip on monetary policy until the government tightens fiscal policy in an effort to lower inflation. On Monday the central bank is due to announce interest rates for September.</p>
<p>He noted that the government had already set a multi-year target for the budget deficit and said it needs to do the same for inflation but does not have to be overly ambitious.</p>
<p>&quot;Lowering inflation by one percent (each year) is reasonable and the government must not set targets that are a step backward,&quot; the central bank governor said.</p>
<p>He added that after setting these targets, the government must hold six-month reviews and present a report showing where the targets stand so as not to be surprised at the end of year.</p>
<p>Frenkel also indirectly criticised a government programme under which it issues special high-yielding bonds for pension funds. Because of these special bonds, pension funds have little incentive to invest in the capital market.</p>
<p>&quot;If most of the institutional savings does not go via the capital markets but via a lateral market then we cannot be surprised that we have a sleepy market where every small thing creates a storm,&quot; Frenkel said, referring to the weakness in the stock and bond markets.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.16 shekels)</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroomk, 972-3-537-2211 SAS TCC</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
