<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132433" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Borg-Warner TO SELL North American transmission unit.</title>
<headline>Borg-Warner TO SELL North American transmission unit.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Borg-Warner Automotive Inc said on Tuesday that it has reached an agreement to sell its North American manual transmission business to Transmisiones Y Equipos Mecanicos SA de CV.</p>
<p>Financial terms were not disclosed, but Borg-Warner said it expected to take a one-time charge of $35 million, or $1.50 a share in the fourth quarter as a result of the sale.  </p>
<p>Borg-Warner later said the purchase price is $20 million at closing, which is expected by the end of 1996 and about $20 million during the transition period, which is exected to be about 18 months.</p>
<p>The expected fourth-quarter charge includes costs associated with the sale of assets, costs necessary to supply existing customers while the business is transferred to its new location and costs related to restructuring Borg-Warner's Muncie, Indiana operation, Borg-Warner said.  </p>
<p>Muncie is where the transmission unit, the last existing independent producer of manual transmissions in the United States, was located. The purchaser is located in Queretero, Mexico and is a joint venture between Mexican conglomerate Desc Sociedad de Fomento Industrial SA de CV and Toledo, Ohio-based Dana Corp.</p>
<p>About 800 jobs at the Muncie facility will be lost, a spokeswoman for Borg-Warner said. Part of the proceeds from the sale will be reinvested in the plant's remaining four-wheel drive transfer case manufacturing operation, Borg-Warner, an automotive components manufacturer said.</p>
<p>Some proceeds will initially be used to pay down debt, the company said.</p>
<p>Borg-Warner said in January it was putting the money-losing transmission business up for sale. The unit is expected to lose $18 million, or $0.50 a share in 1996, Borg-Warner said. It will discuss the impact of the sale on 1997 earnings during its conference call with analysts following third quarter earnings, which are expected to be released Wednesday, Borg-Warner said.</p>
<p>Borg-Warner shares closed up 1/2 at 35-1/2 Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Reuters Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
