<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132577" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Strong demand marks U.S. drugmakers' Q3.</title>
<headline>Strong demand marks U.S. drugmakers' Q3.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of major U.S. pharmaceutical companies reported third quarter results on Tuesday either in-line or above Wall Street expectations, driven by strong demand for high-margin new drugs.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers Co Squibb Co and Warner-Lambert Co topped consensus earnings forecasts with their quarterly numbers, while American Home Products and Eli Lilly and Co matched expectations.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the firms, and others in the group, have benefitted from the launching of new drugs that generally carry higher prices and profit margins.</p>
<p>Last week companies including Merck and Co Inc, Pfizer Inc and Schering-Plough Corp beat Wall Street expectations with their third quarter results.</p>
<p>Managed health care has also helped boost unit growth by increasing patient compliance with drug regimes and opting for preventive drug therapies in an effort to avoid expensive surgeries and hospital stays, industry analysts said.  </p>
<p>The drug group's results &quot;have been driven by unit growth prospects in the United States that have jumped up with managed heath care in this tide of new products,&quot; said Rodman and Renshaw's James Keeney.</p>
<p>&quot;The dominant underylying theme is strong demand for products,&quot; said Gruntal and Co's David Saks.</p>
<p>New York-based Bristol-Myers reported third quarter earnings of $1.50 a share, up from $1.36 a year ago and topping the First Call consensus estimate of $1.48 a share.  </p>
<p>It fought off a 72 percent drop in its U.S. sales of the Capoten heart drug, which lost its patent in February, with strong sales from the anti-cancer drug Taxol and the cholesterol-lowering drug, Pravachol.</p>
<p>Pravachol's sales jumped 35 percent in the quarter to $261 million, boosted by a recent study showing the drug can reduce the risk of a first heart attack.</p>
<p>Cost cutting programs at American Home Products and Warner-Lambert are starting to bear fruit, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In both cases their gross margins and operating margins were well ahead of our expectations,&quot; said Cowen and Co's Stephen Scala.</p>
<p>Morris Plains, N.J.-based Warner-Lambert reported third quarter earnings of $0.56 compared to $0.48 a year ago. The 1995 number excludes a one-time gain of $0.31 from the sale of the company's PRO toothbrush business.</p>
<p>It beat First Call consensus of $0.54 a share.</p>
<p>American Home matched First Call consensus with earnings of $0.77 a share. Among the products that drove its earnings was its anti-obesity drug Redux, approved in the U.S. in April.  </p>
<p>Eli Lilly and Co, based in Indianapolis, Ind., reported quarterly earnings of $0.64 per share, in line with forecasts, before a $0.12 a share one-time gain on the sale of U.S. marketing rights for two antibiotics.</p>
<p>Lilly's Prozac anti-depressant sales rose 10 percent in the third quarter over year-ago levels and reached $1.75 billion for the first nine months of the year.</p>
<p>It said its gross profit margin declined in the third quarter, partly due to increased marketing costs for new products. One of those is the anti-schizophrenia drug Zyprexa, which was approved in the U.S. this month, and is expected to lift Lilly's sales in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Lilly was up 1/2 at 69-1/4 in late trading. Bristol-Myers gained two to 106, Warner-Lambert slipped 7/8 to 65-1/4 and American Home dipped 5/8 to 65-3/4.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1733</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
