<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13250" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan will not send scholarship students to Iraq.</title>
<headline>Jordan will not send scholarship students to Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan, which has blamed Iraq for domestic bread riots, will not let Jordanians study in Baghdad this year under an Iraqi university scholarship programme, officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not send any students on the Iraqi scholarship programme to study in Iraq this academic year,&quot; a senior official, who requested anonymity, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;But those who want to go and study on their own means can do so,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The scholarships, part of decades-old bilateral cooperation, allowed between 300 and 400 Jordanian students a year to study at Iraqi universities. More than 4,000 Jordanians are currently studying in Iraq.</p>
<p>King Hussein has said Jordanians who studied in Iraq or where sympathetic to Iraqi President Saddam Hussein were involved in this month's riots following a doubling of bread prices.</p>
<p>However, government attempts to blame the riots on Iraq have been treated with scepticism by many politicians and ordinary people who say the protests were sparked by rising poverty and umeployment.</p>
<p>The riots shook the southern town of Karak, once a bastion of pro-Iraqi ideology, on August 16 and spread to nearby towns before reaching a poor district of Amman. They were the most serious civil disturbances since 1989 riots that also followed price rises.</p>
<p>Jordanian officials have accused Saddam's Baath Party of cultivating Jordanian and other Arab students over the years through scholarships.</p>
<p>Information Minister Marwan Muasher said on Saturday Jordan had undisclosed proof of official Iraqi involvement in the riots and would put pro-Iraqi activists on trial soon. Amman also told three Iraqi embassy employees to leave.</p>
<p>Iraqi state radio last week denied any role by Baghdad in the unrest. The Jordanian Arab Socialist Baath Party, a pro-Iraqi organisation with one deputy in the 80-seat lower house of parliament, also denied it was involved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
