<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132575" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures finish lower amid supply.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures finish lower amid supply.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures finished lower, undermined by Treasury's auction of two- and five-year notes this week.</p>
<p>December T-bond futures slid to a fresh session low of 110-19/32 in the last minutes of trading, pressured by hefty selling from Wall Street firms late, traders said.</p>
<p>Buyers were said to be nervous amid this week's supply and because December T-bonds failed to hold in the 111-00 handle. Traders said they saw no great shakes from the two-year note auction itself, but said once it was out of the way jitters set in before the five-year sale on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Treasury sold $18.28 billion two-year notes today at a high yield of 5.930 percent, with a bid-to-cover ratio of 2.62 and non-competitive bids of $1.01 billion.</p>
<p>Treasury will auction $12.50 billion five-year notes Wednesday.</p>
<p>Mike Boss, futures analyst with Aubrey G. Lanston, said the Treasury calendar and hefty municipal bond supply this week kept a lid on the market.</p>
<p>He also cited strong oil prices, talk foreign demand for Treasuries may be waning and mixed data.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to stray too far from home,&quot; Boss said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The buyers are bought and they're just sitting there,&quot; Boss said.</p>
<p>Still, Dec T-bonds did not challenge key support at 110-15/32, the 200-day moving average and the intersection of a 1-1/2-month bull trendline. A move below that point would have been a negative technical signal for the market, traders said.</p>
<p>U.S. adjusted chain store sales rose 0.8 percent in the second week of October versus September, according to the Redbook Retail Sales Index released late in the session. Traders said it had minimal impact on the already weak market.  </p>
<p>December T-bonds finished down 14/32 at 110-20/32, 10-year notes dropped 7/32 to 108-9/32, muni-bonds fell 7/32 to 113-31/32 and March Eurodollars finished off two basis points at 94.29. March T-bills ended down two basis points at 94.81.</p>
<p>--Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750</p>
<p>/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
