<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132566" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Boeing, Rockwell deal on track.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Boeing, Rockwell deal on track.</headline>
<byline>Martin Wolk</byline>
<dateline>KENT, Wash. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boeing Co defense and space group President Gerald King said the company's planned acquisition of Rockwell International Corp's defense and space business was on track to close in early December.</p>
<p>In an interview, King also said he expected the defense and space group to remain &quot;a significant part of the Boeing Co&quot; with 30 to 40 percent of the company's total revenues &quot;over time.&quot;  </p>
<p>King said he expected federal regulators to complete an antitrust review of the planned Rockwell deal early next month. The proposal also needs to be approved by Rockwell shareholders at a meeting set for Dec. 4 and should close within a few days after that, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Something could always happen to the merger to keep it from going through, I suppose, even though it looks like a slam dunk in comparison with some of the other things that have been done in this industry,&quot; King said.  </p>
<p>Last year defense and space revenues of $5.58 billion were 29 percent of the company's $19.52 billion in revenues, with commercial aircraft sales accounting for the rest.</p>
<p>This year defense and space revenues are expected to be nearly flat, while overall company revenues rise to about $22.6 billion, reflecting growth in commercial jet deliveries, said analyst Peter Jacobs of Ragen MacKenzie.</p>
<p>The Rockwell acquisition will add about $2.6 billion in revenue to the defense and space group next year, and King said the company has no immediate plans for further acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking only to make this one work first,&quot; he said. &quot;If there's a next step, we'll think about that later.&quot;</p>
<p>King said the defense and space group continues to pursue commercial opportunities, including the Sea Launch program, which he said was on track for initial satellite launch in mid-1998.</p>
<p>King also said the company and its partner, Textron Inc's Bell Helicopter division, are offering a nine-passenger civilian version of their V-22 Osprey tiltrotor aircraft that will be available in 2001.</p>
<p>				 -- Seattle bureau 206-386-4848</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KENT, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
