<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13257" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Drop in violations reported in Lebanese election.</title>
<headline>Drop in violations reported in Lebanese election.</headline>
<byline>Sultan Sleiman</byline>
<dateline>TRIPOLI, Lebanon 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Lebanon voted on Sunday in the second round of Lebanon's parliamentary elections and observers reported a sharp drop in electoral abuses after charges of widespread vote-rigging in the first round.</p>
<p>Troops in armoured vehicles patrolled this predominantly Sunni Moslem port city as voting began. Officials said rival campaign workers scuffled outside a polling station and a man was badly hurt in a fight in the far north region of Akkar, but there were no other reports of violence.</p>
<p>Some 580,000 voters were eligible to elect 28 deputies to the 128-member parliament. Mount Lebanon, the Christian heartland, elected 35 deputies last Sunday and Beirut, south Lebanon and the Bekaa valley vote on the next four Sundays.</p>
<p>Last week losing Christian opposition candidates demanded the resignation of President Elias Hrawi and Interior Minister Michel al-Murr, charging widespread abuses after supporters of the pro-Syrian government won 32 of 35 seats in Mount Lebanon.</p>
<p>Officials said 20 percent of votes in North Lebanon were cast by 2 p.m. (1100 GMT) compared with a total 31 percent vote there in 1992 when most Christians and many Moslems boycotted the poll.</p>
<p>Fears of a repeat of last week's electoral abuses failed to materialise.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some breaches but in general it is much calmer than Mount Lebanon,&quot; Paul Salem, secretary-general of the Lebanese Association for the Democracy of Elections (LADE), told Reuters in Tripoli.</p>
<p>LADE said police were positioned illegally inside some election booths and authorities gave candidates voter lists at the last minute.</p>
<p>Maronite Christian candidate Mikhail Daher said many people found their names were not on voting lists and officials were summoning voters and telling them who to vote for.</p>
<p>Daher said he telephoned Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri to protest at the &quot;scandalous&quot; the way the vote was being run.</p>
<p>Newspapers have dubbed the vote in the north, where four government ministers and 26 parliamentary deputies are seeking election, the most confusing round of the five-stage election.</p>
<p>Five rival tickets are based on local alliances and personal rivalries and offer no clear choice between the government and opposition.</p>
<p>Almost all candidates are friends of Syria, whose 35,000 troops give it a powerful say in Lebanese affairs and a close interest in the vote.</p>
<p>Supporters of Hariri, who is trying to build a national political base and is running in Beirut, were running on different tickets, sometimes side-by-side with his enemies.</p>
<p>The most prominent list was headed by two foes of Hariri: Omar Karami, a former prime minister and Sunni Moslem, and Suleiman Franjieh, a Maronite Christian and former minister. But their list included three Hariri supporters.</p>
<p>The main rival list of Karami's cousin Ahmed Karami also included three Hariri supporters beside three of the Sunni Moslem fundamentalist group Gama'a Islamiyeh which opposes him.</p>
<p>The Gama'a is allied with the pro-Iranian Shi'ite Moslem Hizbollah which Hariri has denounced as &quot;extremist&quot; and vowed to crush in the election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRIPOLI, Lebanon"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
