<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13251" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel moves caravans into West Bank settlements.</title>
<headline>Israel moves caravans into West Bank settlements.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel began moving caravans into the West Bank on Sunday in the first expansion of Jewish settlements under Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Israel radio said the caravans would be used as classrooms and not as living quarters. Palestinian Minister of Higher Education Hanan Ashrawi condemned the move as a &quot;direct affront on the peace process&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;These mobile units are not just temporary structures, they are preparation for further expansion for further settlement activities and as such they violate any possibility of a genuine peace in the future,&quot; Ashrawi told reporters in self-ruled Gaza.</p>
<p>The first 11 of nearly 300 caravans were rolled into place in two West Bank settlements in accordance with Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai's decision earlier this month to approve their placement, Israel radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government took a decision and it will carry it out,&quot; Shlomo Dror, spokesman for Israel's coordinator of activities in the West Bank and Gaza, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The move was the government's first action on settlements since Netanyahu in August lifted a freeze on settlement building in occupied lands imposed by the previous government which made peace deals with the Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO).</p>
<p>Peace Now, Israel's leading peace movement, said settlement expansion would only deepen a crisis with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>&quot;Moving mobile homes in the territories is incompatible with the peace process,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Palestinians say Netanyahu's expansion of settlements while stalling on peace moves raises doubts about the future of PLO-Israel peace accords.</p>
<p>Palestinians, who hope to eventually establish an independent state in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, regard the 130,000 Jews living amidst nearly two million Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza as an obstacle to peace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
