<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132599" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pogo to record new Gulf of Mexico reserves.</title>
<headline>Pogo to record new Gulf of Mexico reserves.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pogo Producing Co said Tuesday it will record significant new proven Gulf of Mexico reserves by year end.</p>
<p>The company also said field development on the Tantawan discovery structure in the Gulf of Thailand is near completion and first production is expected very early in 1997.</p>
<p>Pogo and its Thailand partners, Rutherford-Moran Oil Corp and Maersk Olie og Gas As, have resumed drilling with a new five-well delination program at the Benchamas discovery area and are seeking a formal production licence for the area.  </p>
<p>&quot;Pogo's big plans for 1996 will extend through 1997,&quot; chief executive Paul G. Van Wagenen said. The company's 1996 capital and exploration budget, raised to $180 million in July, is &quot;our most ambitious budget in 14 years and reflects a 73 percent increase&quot; over 1995's spending.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have spent all of it by year-end 1996, yet we will finish the year wishing we had done more!&quot;</p>
<p>Although development drilling and workovers have been slower than expected this year, &quot;We will spend about $80 million in the Gulf of Mexico in 1996, up from $38 million in 1995,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Exploration drilling explains the increased expenditures, which will add new reserves to our year-end calculations, it explained.</p>
<p>&quot;We were just sorry we were unable to reach consensus with our Gulf of Mexico joint venture partners on all of the development drilling and reworking we had hoped to accomplish this year, which would have significantly boosted our 1996 natural gas production volumes,&quot; Van Wagenen said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope and expect to remedy that situation next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Pogo said it has drilled 19 total wells offshore to-date in 1996, including six exploration wells. Four out of six exploration wells and all 13 development wells drilled have been completed as producers.</p>
<p>It said four more offshore wells are now drilling in the Gulf of Mexico with seven wells yet to be drilled in the fourth quarter. -- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
