<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13258" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Dubai gold market subdued, recovery not seen soon.</title>
<headline>Dubai gold market subdued, recovery not seen soon.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold traders in Dubai on Sunday remained pessimistic about the market's short-term prospects but hoped Indian physical demand would strengthen ahead of the festival and wedding season.</p>
<p>&quot;The market remains subdued. But the approach of seasonal demand in India with the Hindu festivals in October and the weddings might trigger buying in September,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>He and others said some speculative buying had raised Indian demand slightly but stressed that only solid physical demand from the subcontinent would put the market back on track.</p>
<p>Dubai is the main feeder market into India which is the world's single largest gold market. The Gulf Arab emirate provides some 80 percent of annual Indian demand of 477 tonnes.</p>
<p>Indian physical demand is expected to rise by the end of August and September once the monsoon season ends.</p>
<p>It usually preludes a round of festivals and weddings in India that lifts gold bullion and jewellery demand.</p>
<p>Traders said the local benchmark price of the Ten Tola bar was steady at about 5,367 dirhams ($1,462.40).</p>
<p>A TT bar is 3.746 ounces of 24 carat gold.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment the market seems to have no chance of picking up. There will only be speculative buying. We expect it to recover after about two months,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The punishing Gulf summer has dulled Dubai's main gold souk.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is in a holiday mood,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Buying from visiting Gulf Arabs and other tourists has declined dramatically and Indian subcontinent customers return home to escape the heat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
