<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13255" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: RESEARCH ALERT-Strong buy on Makhteshim.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT-Strong buy on Makhteshim.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Brothers said it was upgrading its rating for Israel's Makhteshim Chemical Works Ltd to a strong buy from buy and has increased its earnings per share (EPS) estimate for 1996 and 1997.</p>
<p>In a report on the agrochemical manufacturer, Salomon said that strong second quarter results prompted it to raise its EPS forecast from $0.46 to $0.53 and from $0.51 to $0.61 for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Makhteshim is currently trading at 9.1 times expected 1996 EPS and 8.4 times 1997 forecast earnings. Similar international companies are currently trading at 15.1 and 12.6 times 1996 and 1997 estimates respectively,&quot; Salomon said. &quot;The Israeli benchmark, the Mishtanim Index, is at 12 times forecast 1996 EPS. As a result, we upgrade Makhteshim to Strong Buy from Buy.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon said Makhteshim's acquisition of 49 percent of a major Spanish agrochemicals manufacturer and distributor may add $16 to $20 million to 1997's sales.</p>
<p>The company and its subsidiary Agan Chemical Manufacturers Ltd have also announced new distribution and subcontracting production alliances in the United States which Salomon believes could expand 1997 sales by more than $30 million.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the U.S. market presents excellent opportunities for both companies, as it remains the largest and most profitable agrochemicals market in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that $30 million in new U.S. contracts will affect Makhteshim's revenues from the fourth quarter of 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>Makhteshim is the world's largest generic agrochemicals manufacturer and marketer of chemical ingredients used in crop protection. It is a subsidiary of Koor Industries Ltd.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
