<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132590" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. adj retail sales up 0.8 pct in Oct -- Redbook.</title>
<headline>U.S. adj retail sales up 0.8 pct in Oct -- Redbook.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. seasonally adjusted retail sales rose 0.8 percent in the first two weeks of fiscal October versus September, according to the Lynch, Jones &amp; Ryan Inc Redbook retail sales index.</p>
<p>The index rose 7.6 percent when compared with the same month a year ago, the report said.  Adjusted retail sales rose 7.5 percent in the week ended October 19, compared with the same week a year ago, it said.  </p>
<p>Companies using the National Retail Federation calendar benefited by comparing the Columbus Day week with a non-holiday week last year, said Howard Eilenberg, a retail analyst of Redbook Research.</p>
<p>&quot;The comparisons are relatively easy against a very weak October a year ago,&quot; said Eilenberg in an interview with Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Eilenberg noted that discounters made a little bit of a comeback from last week, adding that one of the major retailers reported an upturn in soft goods and apparel.</p>
<p>&quot;Soft goods and apparel now seem to be leading the other merchandise categories,&quot; said Eilenberg, adding that's been the case in the department stores and chain stores.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time, we are beginning to see apparels move in the discount stores,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Eilenberg also said the rest of October should show positive results in retail sales.</p>
<p>-- Jeff Coelho, 212-859-1562</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
