<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132567" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end sharply higher, funds cover.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end sharply higher, funds cover.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures ended sharply higher Tuesday, helped by fund shortcovering as a six-week decline looked to be bottoming out, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The weekly momentums on December gold and silver and January platinum have all turned positive,&quot; Dorsey, Wright and Associates president Thomas Dorsey of Virginia said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are beginning to see some gold stocks turn to positive weekly momentum also (in the Philadelphia Stock Exchange's gold and silver sector index) and that suggests a short term bounce.&quot;  </p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended up $2.20 an ounce at $386.10, after trading up to a four week high at $386.50, on high estimated gold futures volume of 48,000 lots.</p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold ended quoted $383.90/384.40, its highest level since September 9, compared to the London Tuesday afternoon fix at $383.35 and the New York close Monday at $381.75/382.25.</p>
<p>COMEX December silver closed up 5.3 cents at $4.990 an ounce, after seeing an intraday high at $5.000.</p>
<p>NYMEX January platinum ended up $2.70 at $391.00, after seeing a ten day high at $391.30.</p>
<p>NYMEX December palladium gained $2.35 to $120.75, its highest level since October 7.</p>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange's gold and silver sector index ended was up 2.49 points at 119.13 near the close, a two week high for the index.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some fund buying and shortcovering on a breach of a downtrend line suggesting the six week old decline may be over and a breach of the 40 day moving average in December gold futures,&quot; Refco analyst Tim Porter said.</p>
<p>But it will take evidence of significant fund shortcovering to turn the downtrend around convincingly, analysts said. Resistance in December gold is now seen around $387.50 an ounce.</p>
<p>&quot;There also appears to be a correlation between the equity market and the gold market in the short term, with gold benefitting from down days in the stockmarket like today recently,&quot; Imperial Bank's California-based chief bullion dealer Jeff Singer said.</p>
<p>COMEX warehouse stocks of gold and silver have been falling steadily in recent weeks also, with silver stocks seeing 10-year lows last week.</p>
<p>Wilmington Trust silver stocks also slipped further in the latest week to 58.223,976 ounces.</p>
<p>The decline in stocks is seen related to U.S. exports to Asia where Indian demand is seen rising seasonally.</p>
<p>India is the world's largest consumer of gold and demand is driven by three factors - wedding seasons, harvests and festivals.</p>
<p>Dealers said Indian gold demand would get a boost from the Hindu festival of Dassera on Monday and from the festival of Diwali on November 10-11. In the week ended last Saturday, gold prices rose 25 rupees per 10 grammes to 5,150 rupees on the Bombay gold market.</p>
<p>Finally, there may be a correlation between U.S. presidential election years and the gold market.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last two election years, the precious metals sector has bottomed out in December of the election year and then reversed back up,&quot; Dorsey said.</p>
<p>--Clive Mckeef, New York Commodities 212-859-1641; email: clive.mckeef@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
