<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13259" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait prisoners in hunger strike over conditions.</title>
<headline>Kuwait prisoners in hunger strike over conditions.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some 600 inmates at Kuwait's central prison have begun a hunger strike to press for better living conditions and fewer restrictions at its visiting area, a deputy said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike started yesterday (Saturday) and is still going on. About 600 inmates are on strike,&quot; said Ali al-Baghli, spokesman for parliament's human rights committee.</p>
<p>Baghli was commenting on remarks by an inmate who called anonymously to an international news organisation claiming that all 1,487 inmates at Kuwait's main prison were on hunger strike. All kinds of prisoners were involved, he said.</p>
<p>Interior ministry officials declined comment.</p>
<p>&quot;They are demanding better living conditions and they want to be allowed to receive visitors without a barrier (grill),&quot; said Baghli. &quot;The barrier in the visiting area was installed after a Pakistani prisoner escaped from the visiting area.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Officials are trying to meet the strikers' demands,&quot; said Baghli, noting that prison officials were preparing enhanced monitoring measures that would allow for the removal of the metal grill within a month.</p>
<p>In January jail inmates burned down a prison hospital in a pre-dawn riot before security forces quelled the disturbances. The riot was caused by anger among drug addicts in the prison over a narcotics crackdown.</p>
<p>Baghli said the grill was installed to prevent drug smuggling to inmates by visitors.</p>
<p>&quot;The January events will be repeated if the authorities do not meet our demands. Our strike is peaceful so far,&quot; said the inmate, who said he represented fellow prisoners.</p>
<p>The caller said they wanted better sanitary facilities, workshops, food and better treatment by prison staff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
