<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132581" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends sharply higher on cert stocks.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends sharply higher on cert stocks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures settled higher on Tuesday, led by a sharp advance in the spot contract, amid persistent concerns about near-term supplies, floor sources said.</p>
<p>Prices rose from the outset, fueled by a steep, 24,000-bag drop in exchange-deliverable coffee. The drawdown, which caught many traders by surprise, reduced CSCE certified stocks to just 5,583 60-kg bags as of October 18.</p>
<p>&quot;People are nervous that there is not that much coffee available,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Steve Platt. &quot;The certified stock report put stocks at an extremely low level.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, no coffee was reported pending certification, greatly diminishing chances for an equally sharp build next week, traders said.</p>
<p>The spot December contract surged to a session high of 118.75 cents a lb, before ending at 117.60 cents, up 4.60 cents on the day. Second-month March finished 2.55 cents higher at 106.60, while the back months closed 1.35 to 1.85 firmer.</p>
<p>The near-term supply crunch sparked keen buying interest in the December/March switch, which swelled to 11.00 cents compared with 8.95 cents at the close Monday.</p>
<p>Traders said mounting concerns about Colombian supplies as a trucking strike there reached its ninth day also contributed to the market's bullish mood. But they noted there remains some uncertainty about the status of the action.</p>
<p>The head of Colombia's National Coffee Growers Federation said Tuesday that the work stoppage had paralyzed the nation's coffee industry and forced delays in the shipment of about 250,000 60-kilo bags of coffee for October delivery.</p>
<p>But the Colombian government declared the strike illegal last week, and they reported Monday that truck drivers were gradually returning to work to avert the threat of having their licences revoked.</p>
<p>Traders said the December contract is likely to continue to trend higher, testing resistance near 120.00. But the market's gains could be short-lived, they said, as the flow of new-crop coffee from Latin America is expected to build stockpiles in the coming months.</p>
<p>Volume was heavy, at an estimated 11,120 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
