<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132579" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stone Container sees increased demand.</title>
<headline>Stone Container sees increased demand.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stone Container Corp said Tuesday that it expects demand will rise across its product lines, which will help to improve pricing.</p>
<p>&quot;In light of these improving industry conditions, we announced price increases for both container board and market pulp effective October 1,&quot; Roger Stone, chairman, said in a statement. &quot;Looking ahead, we are confident that demand will continue to rise across our product lines, and that price restorations will occur as conditions continue to improve.&quot;  </p>
<p>Earlier, Stone Container reported a third quarter loss after charges of $0.53 a share on a primary basis, compared with a year-ago loss after charges of $0.45 a share on a fully diluted basis.</p>
<p>Stone said weak prices for core products hurt third quarter results. However, he said pulp and paper pricing is recovering, and that demand for many of the company's core products strengthened during the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Containerboard activity was particularly good during the quarter,&quot; Stone said. &quot;Shipments are climbing, exports are very strong and inventories are at manageable levels. Market pulp inventories have also dropped sharply since the beginning of the year, and demand is also on the rise.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the newsprint business is still challenging, but inventories are down and a recovery will begin soon.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
