<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132511" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stock index futures finish lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. stock index futures finish lower.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stock index futures finished lower, still pressured by profit taking on recent gains and weak technology stocks.</p>
<p>December Standard and Poor's 500 futures slipped thorugh support at 710.00 to hit a session nadir of 708.30, the lowest price in a week.</p>
<p>Traders said the market had become ripe for a correction after December pushed to an all-time high at 718.70 Monday and then closed lower.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a big push up on Friday and on Monday we had higher highs and we just couldn't hold it,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders called activity light early in the day, but said interest picked up on the afternoon decline. Chicago Mercantile Exchange estimated overall S&amp;P 500 futures volume Tuesday at 79,000 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in a little corrective phase, but I really don't see a lot to it,&quot; another S&amp;P 500 futures trader said. He said a band of resistance from 705.00 to 706.00 should keep a floor under the market, if indeed Tuesday's weakness was a correction.</p>
<p>He cited some fund selling on the decline, and said locals had been active.  </p>
<p>Some traders said Tuesday's declines were a welcome sign after Monday's run to new highs. They said mild losses pave the way for the uptrend to resume.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that depending on where we open tomorrow this might be a bear trap,&quot; another S&amp;P 500 futures trader said. &quot;There're a lot of new shorts between 710.50 and 708.50 and I think those are really vulnerable if we go up to the 710.50 level tomorrow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Also, once Treasury's five-year note auction is out of the way, Treasury bonds could lead stocks higher, some traders said.  </p>
<p>December S&amp;Ps finished down 5.30 points at 709.10, new composites were off 2.70 at 377.20, KBT value lines were 4.10 points lower at 647.50, Nikkei 225s fell 20.0 at 21,175, and Nasdaq 100s eased 11.00 at 741.75. -Derivatives desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
