<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132570" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures end higher on short-covering.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures end higher on short-covering.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most IMM currency futures ended up and near session highs after a shortcovering rally hit the pits late in the day, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>They said some retail accounts were holding short mark and Swiss franc positions and were forced to cover positions once the dollar touched off sell-stop orders.</p>
<p>Buy-stop orders were heavy at $0.6565 to $0.6575 in December marks after sell orders were touched at 1.5280 spot marks in the cash market.</p>
<p>&quot;We hit a lot of stops in the mark at $0.6575 and the contract went up almost to even,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>They said volume was extremely heavy on the upside, as shorts unwilling to cover during light gains in the first half of trade, scrambled to cover positions. Many traders were looking to sell positions at the day's highs, which initially rested at $0.6550 in December marks.</p>
<p>One analyst said the first sign of trouble for the dollar came when Mexican peso futures started slipping. One large U.S. firm offered 300 December pesos in the all-or-nothing pit in the first hour of pit trade.</p>
<p>He said 4,000 peso futures traded by 1000 CDT/1500 GMT.  </p>
<p>He also said December pesos's settlement at $0.123425 was near a high-volume area.</p>
<p>&quot;There were a lot of people putting positions -- both long and short -- at $0.123400,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another currency analyst said there were concerns that Mexican legislation related to petrochemicals could negatively affect export business.</p>
<p>&quot;The peso started weakening, and then the dollar fell,&quot; one trader said. &quot;We are kind of married to the peso now.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. stocks and bonds also widened losses.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's been a long time since the U.S. dollar and U.S. assets went south on the same day,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>December Canadian dollars set a contract high at $0.7465, against the old contract high set in October 1995 at $0.7460. However, the contract ended off its highs, as the U.S. dollar lost ground, traders said.</p>
<p>At the end of pit trade, December yen was up $0.000029 at $0.008966, marks up $0.0045 at $0.6583, Swiss francs up $0.0064 at $0.8025, sterling $0.0066 higher at $1.5978, Can dollars were up $0.0005 at $0.7455, the Aussie dollar was off $0.0035 at $0.7923. The peso down $0.001050 at $0.123425.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
