<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132588" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House may rein in dlr gains post election.</title>
<headline>White House may rein in dlr gains post election.</headline>
<byline>Donna Sells</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Complaints by U.S. firms about the strength of the dollar seem to have fallen on Washington's deaf ears, but the White House may listen after the November election and act to contain the rally, U.S. experts said.</p>
<p>Any indication the White House is backing away from its strong dollar policy could spell doom before November 5.</p>
<p>&quot;If that happened, the bond market would sell off, interest rates would go up and the stock market would crash,&quot; said Chris Iggo, international economist at Barclays Bank Plc. &quot;It's not a wise decision three weeks ahead of the election.&quot;  </p>
<p>But after the election, the administration might focus again on reducing the U.S. trade deficit and enhancing U.S. firms' competitiveness. The White House might then hint in a guarded fashion that the dollar may be too strong, Iggo said.</p>
<p>Computer giant Digital Equipment Corp is the latest to sound off about damage wrought by the strong dollar.</p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer Vincent Mullarkey Tuesday said fluctuations in the U.S. dollar resulted, year over year, in a loss of more than $70 million in the first quarter. Digital joins a string of dissatisfied firms, including International Business Machines Corp and the Big Three automakers.  </p>
<p>Despite the growing chorus of discontent, U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin apparently has not wavered in his support for a strong dollar. The U.S. currency hit 112.91 yen on Monday, its highest level in 33 months.</p>
<p>Political as well as economic considerations may underlie his attitude.</p>
<p>J.P. Morgan currency strategist Ron Leven pointed out that the primary complainers -- corporate boards and major shareholders -- are typically Republicans.</p>
<p>&quot;If they're unhappy, it shouldn't really politically bother (U.S. President Bill) Clinton that much,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>As for the economic angle, Leven said a sharp drop in the dollar would kill the Japanese financial system.</p>
<p>&quot;That's not in our interest to see that happen, clearly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Leven also noted that a strong dollar can be tolerated as long as the U.S. economy stays strong and the unemployment rate remains low.</p>
<p>The jobless rate stood at 5.2 percent in September.</p>
<p>&quot;The minute the unemployment rate starts to creep up, then I think the (strong) dollar will become very quickly an issue,&quot; Leven added.  </p>
<p>Leven said he does not expect a dramatic shift in dollar policy after the election.</p>
<p>&quot;But over the next six to nine months, I think, you will see gradually a shift in the Administration's attitude towards the dollar and desire to get the dollar down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While some major U.S. corporations are griping about the dollar rally, others seem to be taking it in stride.</p>
<p>&quot;One of our biggest competitors are the Japanese in the U.S. market, but I don't know that we're terribly concerned about them right now,&quot; said a foreign exchange manager at a Fortune 500 firm.  </p>
<p>The foreign exchange manager noted that the Japanese had dominated the power tools professional market in the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;We launched a counter attack ... and have taken that market back from them substantially,&quot; the foreign exchange manager said. &quot;I think we're well positioned to deal with them.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar has climbed dramatically since it tumbled to a Post World War II low of 79.75 yen on April 19, 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;If you think about it, dollar/yen had collapsed ... and now it's back up, but if you think of the bigger, longer-term picture, this is still a pretty darn good level,&quot; the foreign exchange manager said.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
