<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132640" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Novametrix Medical amends merger agreement.</title>
<headline>Novametrix Medical amends merger agreement.</headline>
<dateline>WALLINGFORD, Conn. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Novametrix Medical Systems Inc said it and Andros Inc have revised the terms of their merger agreement in response to unanticipated order delays at Andros.</p>
<p>Under the revised agreement, Andros' share of Novametrix after the merger has been reduced, the company said.</p>
<p>The order delays have led to the deferral of projected revenues of Andros from the 1997 fiscal year to the 1998 fiscal year, it said.  </p>
<p>However, Novametrix Chairman, President and Chief Executive William Lacourciere said in a statement Tuesday that he remains &quot;confident that the merger will result in substantial earnings accretion for the Novemetrix stockholders.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Although we anticipate a resumption of the normal order pattern at Andros, the revised terms of the merger will protect Novametrix while permitting the Andros stockholders to increase their ownership as revenues achieve their projected levels for fiscal 1998,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Under the amended merger agreement, which has been approved unanimously by the boards of both companies, Novametrix will issue at the closing to stockholders of Andros shares of Novametrix common stock constituting 38 percent of the combined company at closing.</p>
<p>After the end of Novametrix's fiscal year ending May 3, 1998, additional shares of Novametrix common stock constituting up to five percent of the company may be issued based upon Andros' revenues and the combined company's earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization for the 1998 fiscal year.</p>
<p>The company did not say what the original terms were, and could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WALLINGFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
