<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132636" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Con Edison net continues to reflect cuts.</title>
<headline>Con Edison net continues to reflect cuts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consolidated Edison Co of New York results continue to reflect the three year electric rate agreement effective April 1, 1995, which provides for a lower level of incentive opportunities and lower allowed returns, the company said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Profits declined from the year ago level again in the third quarter, although a drop in preferred dividend payments kept earnings per share unchanged from last year. The lower preferred dividends were now enough to offset the drop in nine month and 12 month earnings, leaving per share results lower for both periods.  </p>
<p>The utility said electricity sales slipped to 13.1 million megawatt hours in the latest quarter from 13.5 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>It said natural gas sales to Con Edison customers rose to 14.2 trillion Btu from 13.3 trillion in 1995's third quarter, but transportation of customer owned natural gas declined, leaving total sales at 20.98 trillion Btu down from 23.36 trillion a year earlier.</p>
<p>Steam sales also declined, to 6.4 trillion pounds from 6.9 trillion in 1995's third quarter.</p>
<p>For the first nine months of the year, Con Edison said, electric sales increased 0.9 percent from 1995. Firm natural gas sales volume icnreased 12.1 percent and steam sales volume increased 6.3 percent due primarily to the colder than normal winter early this year.</p>
<p>Under existing ratemaking procedures, the company pointed out, most of the variations in electric sales from the level projected in rate decisions and most of the weather-related variation in natural gas sales are excluded in determining earnings.  -- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
