<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132635" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends near highs in thin dealings.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends near highs in thin dealings.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar traded narrowly throughout the session and settled near the day's highs, buoyed by local and speculative buying, dealers said.</p>
<p>March settled up 0.02 to 10.59, having ranged from 10.61 to 10.53. The back months ended 0.05 to 0.03 firmer.</p>
<p>Trade remained thin at an estimated 10,599 lots.</p>
<p>Market sources view today's close near the highs as mildly positive.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't take out yesterday's lows (10.52 basis March),&quot; a trader said. &quot;But we're having difficulty getting excited about this because the range is horrible.&quot;</p>
<p>Additionally, players are faced with a dearth of news on which to trade, and the technical outlook remains to the downside.</p>
<p>Support remained at 10.50 in March and resistance at 10.70 and then at 10.85.</p>
<p>Today, Brazil released an additional 1.04 million tonnes of sugar for export. The authorization comes amid ample world supplies and could weigh on prices in the near term amid a lack of physical offtake, analysts said.</p>
<p>Only 80 percent of the 5.2 million tonnes of sugar that had been authorized for export, had been released thus far.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities, 212-859-1647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
