<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132671" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW-Monsanto warns against '96 EPS view rise.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Monsanto warns against '96 EPS view rise.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monsanto Co, which exceeded analysts' expectations for its third quarter, warned analysts not to increase earnings estimates for the full year, according to Nicholas Filippello, chief economist.</p>
<p>&quot;I warned them (analysts) not to increase expectations for the full year,&quot; Filippello said, adding the First Call mean of analysts' estimates is $1.48 a share, compared with $1.25 a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We're urging people not to increase the number,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Monsanto reported third quarter earnings of $0.28 a share, up from $0.23 a year ago and above the First Call mean of $0.24.</p>
<p>Filippello said certain factors, including the timing of bulk aspartame sweetener shipments and an adjustment in the full-year tax rate, contributed to third quarter earnings exceeding First Call expectations.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, Filippello said Monsanto continues to weigh options for its chemical business, as reported earlier this month.  One possibility is to spin the chemicals operation off as a separate publicly traded company.  </p>
<p>Or chemicals could be spun off and then merged with another company, Filippello added. The &quot;spin-off/merger option,&quot; he said, would be preferrable from a tax standpoint from an outright sale of the chemical operations.</p>
<p>But he said it was too early to speculate which options was likely to take place.  &quot;I think it's too early to speculate,&quot; Filippello said.</p>
<p>If Monsanto shed its chemical operations, it would be left with a life sciences business consisting of agricultural products, pharmaceuticals and food ingredients.  </p>
<p>Filippello said Monsanto is considering ways to make food ingredients &quot;an important part of this life sciences company.&quot; But it remains to be seen how much growth in food ingredients would be accomplished internally or if the company would undertake licensing, partnerships and possible acquisitions, he added.</p>
<p>The life sciences business would include the G.D. Searle pharmaceutical company, which analysts in the past had expected Monsanto to sell.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no interest at this point in selling Searle,&quot; Filippello said. &quot;Searle clearly is an appreciating asset at this point...Our expectation at this time is that value is going to continue increase over time.&quot;</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
