<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13263" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt group urges ban on female circumcision.</title>
<headline>Egypt group urges ban on female circumcision.</headline>
<byline>Mona Eltahawy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Egyptian human rights group on Sunday mourned the death of a 14-year-old girl after a circumcision operation and urged the government to ban the ancient but dangerous procedure.</p>
<p>Amina Abdelhamid Mohammed died in a private hospital on Saturday after a doctor performed the operation, which involves the removal of some or all of the external genitalia.</p>
<p>The government daily newspaper al-Ahram said she died from haemorrhage and that the surgeon had disappeared.</p>
<p>According to research in 1995 by a national task force made up of women and human rights activists, doctors and religious scholars, 80 percent of Egyptian girls are subjected to the procedure every year.</p>
<p>Some activists prefer to call the practice female genital mutilation (FGM) for the severe form it often takes. Side effects include haemorrhage, shock and sexual dysfunction.</p>
<p>&quot;We will hold a day of remembrance every year for girls who have died from genital mutilation to remind people that enough is enough,&quot; Maha Attiya Eweiss of the Egyptian Human Rights Organisation (EOHR) told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;One of our goals is to have the government pass a law banning and criminalising genital mutilation and punishing anyone who carries out the procedure, be it a doctor, nurse, barber or traditional midwife,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Eweiss is coordinator of the group's Campaign Against Female Genital Mutilation, launched in 1995 to educate the public about the dangers of female circumcision and eradicate the procedure.</p>
<p>Amina's death was particularly shocking because it dispelled the notion that it is safer for parents to take their daughters to doctors for circumcision.</p>
<p>In Egypt, a traditional midwife or barber usually performs the procedure using unsterilised equipment.</p>
<p>Health Minister Ismail Sallam last month banned female circumcision operations at public hospitals. Eweiss said his ban also prohibits all doctors from carrying out the procedure.</p>
<p>Eweiss said mothers she had interviewed during research told her they circumcised their daughters to ensure their chastity before marriage and for cleaniless.</p>
<p>She said a group of doctors from southern Egypt wanted to challenge the minister's decree in court on the grounds that it was less dangerous for doctors to carry out the procedure.</p>
<p>&quot;A doctor killed Amina yesterday. It is horrible. He is supposed to be responsible and he acted with carelessness,&quot; Eweiss said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a black market in genital mutilation now. People use back doors. Some doctors use it to make money and do what they want without respect to the medical oath,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Female circumcision is practised in many Middle Eastern and African countries. Some Egyptians say the procedure is based on Islamic teaching, but others say it has more traditional roots because Moslem and Christian girls are circumcised.</p>
<p>Sheikh Mohammed Sayyed Tantawi, the head of the eminent Islamic institute al-Azhar, has said the practice is un-Islamic and has supported Sallam's decision.</p>
<p>EOHR tried to sue his predecessor for advocating the practice but he died before the end of the case.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
