<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13268" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Iraq sent out feelers to Israel - former minister.</title>
<headline>Iraq sent out feelers to Israel - former minister.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq tried to establish contact with Israel two years ago but then-prime minister Yitzhak Rabin vetoed any relations with Baghdad, a former Israeli cabinet minister said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Two years ago, a European oil man came to Israel...and told me the Iraqi ambassador in Geneva, (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein's brother, was interested in meeting me to discuss Israeli-Iraqi relations,&quot; former energy minister Moshe Shahal said.</p>
<p>Shahal, who was born in Iraq, told Israel Radio: &quot;This, of course, was a matter for the prime minister. I spoke to Yitzhak Rabin at the time and two days later we agreed to reject the offer.</p>
<p>&quot;The refusal stemmed from a very simple reason -- to avoid any damage to our relations with the United States, which would not have viewed this meeting favourably,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In August 1994, Rabin denied reports that Saddam had made peace overtures to him.</p>
<p>&quot;No message has reached me from Saddam Hussein. I didn't ask for mediation with him, and I'm not interested in it,&quot; Rabin said at the time, reacting to an Israel Television report that Iraq had expressed readiness to discuss peace.</p>
<p>Iraq, which fired dozens of Scud missiles at Israel during the 1991 Gulf War, had called the television report unfounded.</p>
<p>Shahal said two years ago that the government should explore the possibility of making peace with Baghdad as a counter-move against a future nuclear threat from Iran.</p>
<p>On Sunday, he said: &quot;I think the prime minister made the right decision in this matter.&quot;</p>
<p>Rabin was assassinated last November by a religious Jew opposed to his peace moves with the Arabs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
