<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132693" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MCI, NYNEX shares stable on Q3 results.</title>
<headline>MCI, NYNEX shares stable on Q3 results.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in MCI Communications Corp and NYNEX Corp largely resisted the weak broad market on Tuesday after analysts declared themselves satisfied with third quarter results from both companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Both beat our earnings estimate by a penny. We have seen solid growth from the telecom sector this earnings period,&quot; said analyst Simon Flannery of brokers J. P. Morgan.</p>
<p>NYNEX lost 1/8 to 43-1/2 and MCI added 1/16 at 24-15/16  by 1245 EDT/1645 GMT. MCI beat the consensus forecast by a penny, and NYNEX equalled forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We're impressed by the NYNEX quarter, and particularly the access line growth and the operating margin improvement,&quot; said Bill Vogel of Dillon Read.</p>
<p>NYNEX increased its access lines to customers by 3.9 percent year on year in its local service territory, and increased its operating margin by 1.2 percentage points to 22.7 percent while increasing its investment.</p>
<p>Flannery noted that MCI increased its operating profits by 25 percent, but dilution from a host of new ventures meant there was only a 10 percent improvement at the bottom line.</p>
<p>&quot;Dilution continues to be a problem, while the performance of the ventures themselves are a mixed bag,&quot; he said. -- Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
