<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13269" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt offers 30 pct of milling company to public.</title>
<headline>Egypt offers 30 pct of milling company to public.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt's official Holding Company for Rice and Flour Mills said on Sunday it was offering investors at least 30 percent or 2.25 million shares of its subsidary Central and West Delta Flour Mills.</p>
<p>Individual investors can buy 750,000 shares -- priced at 40 pounds ($12) each -- which represent 10 percent of the firm's total 7.5 million shares. The holding company said it would increase the amount of shares on offer to individuals to meet demand.</p>
<p>Mutual funds and investment institutions are allocated another 10 percent of the shares while another 10 percent is set aside for the milling firm's employees.</p>
<p>The share offer opens for two days on August 28, the firm said. Banque Misr is handling the sale.</p>
<p>Central and West Delta Flour Mills is one of the country's main producers of bread, pastas and packing materials. Among its assets are 18 mills and 24 bakeries in five provinces in the Delta area.</p>
<p>The holding company said that all shareholders would get a minimum 4.1 pounds dividend for the financial year ending June 30, 1996 on a forecast after-tax profits of 42.22 million. Profits for the previous financial year were 38.08 million.</p>
<p>Central and West Delta Flour Mills forecast after-tax profits to increase this fiscal year to 48.31 million pounds and in 1997/98 to 54.22 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
