<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13267" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Turkish drug firms seek Iraqi deals.</title>
<headline>Turkish drug firms seek Iraqi deals.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish pharmaceutical firms displayed their products in Baghdad on Sunday in their first such exhibition since sanctions were clamped on Iraq in 1990.</p>
<p>The fair is the latest bid by Turkey to win the largest portion of funds that will emanate from Iraq's partial oil sales deal with the U.N., expected to go into effect in September.</p>
<p>&quot;About 26 companies are taking part. All ready to strike deals to supply Iraq with medicines and medical supplies,&quot; said Sameh Hamdan, a Jordanian middleman supplying both Iraq and Jordan with Turkish drugs.</p>
<p>Of the $2 billion worth of oil Iraq will be allowed to export in six months, $210 million will be earmarked for medicines and medical supplies. Since Iraq signed the oil deal with U.N. in June, Turkish officials and businessmen have been flocking to Baghdad in the hope of getting the lion's share of the $1.3 billion that will be available to Iraq after deducting 1991 Gulf War reparations and other U.N. costs.</p>
<p>The official press reported that representatives of Canadian and Greek companies were also in Baghdad seeking deals.</p>
<p>Latif Oguz Kester of Fako, a Turkish medicines manufacturer, said he used to export $30 million worth of drugs and medical supplies to Iraq before U.N. trade sanctions were imposed on Iraq for invading Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;We sacked 250 workers after sanctions. We are here to bring them back and even hire more,&quot; Kester said.</p>
<p>Ismail Oncel of Bioforma said Iraq's health needs were enormous and his company joined the exhibition as part of an &quot;Iraq trade rush&quot; hitting Turkey .</p>
<p>Soon after Iraq's June oil deal a Turkish trade delegation under Foreign Trade Undersecretary Nejat Eren visited Baghdad and signed protocols for the export of food supplies to Iraq.</p>
<p>Turkey's Justice Minister Sevket Kazan and Education Minister Mehmet Saglam visited Iraq this month and agreed with Iraq officials to set up a gas pipeline and boost trade. Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein received the two Turkish ministers.</p>
<p>A delegation of 27 more Turkish businessmen came to Iraq in mid-August, seeking food contracts for the $870 million Iraq has allocated for the purchase of foodstuffs under the oil deal.</p>
<p>Iraq's Health Minister Umeed Madhat Mubarak opened the Turkish pharmaceutical exhibition in Baghdad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
