<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132623" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muni bond insurance volume up 20 pct - Reuter poll.</title>
<headline>Muni bond insurance volume up 20 pct - Reuter poll.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Municipal bond insurers backed $19.5 billion of new debt in the third quarter, a 20 percent increase over the $16.2 billion insured in the same period last year, according to a Reuter poll of the industry.</p>
<p>The poll also found that the usually stable rankings of the industry's top players shifted for the first time in three years, as AMBAC Indemnity Corp and Financial Security Assurance moved up in the market share competition.</p>
<p>MBIA Insurance Corp, a unit of MBIA Inc, is the industry's perennial market share leader, usually by a wide margin.  </p>
<p>But in this year's third quarter AMBAC, a unit of AMBAC Inc, took the number one slot on the strength of several large deals.</p>
<p>AMBAC insured $6.9 billion compared to MBIA's $6 billion.</p>
<p>Company officials, however, downplay market share, preferring to focus instead on earnings and other performance measures. And market analysts usually discount the importance of single-quarter volume statistics, noting that they are more volatile than full-year statistics.</p>
<p>In fact, MBIA is well ahead of AMBAC for the year to date, with $23.6 billion compared to AMBAC's $18.4 billion.  </p>
<p>But the market share figures reflect how aggressively individual companies are pursuing new deals on a quarterly basis.</p>
<p>For instance, GE Capital Services's Financial Guaranty Insurance Co has for several quarters been following a conservative strategy, shying away from what it considers riskier sectors.</p>
<p>That strategy may partly explain FGIC's slip in the rankings for the quarter, allowing FSA, a unit of Financial Security Assurance Holdings Ltd, to take the number three position for the first time in its history.  </p>
<p>FSA insured $3.2 billion compared to FGIC's nearly $3 billion. GE Capital is a unit of General Electric Co.</p>
<p>Rounding out the industry were Connie Lee Insurance Co with $294 million for the quarter and Asset Guaranty Insurance Co, a unit of Enhance Financial Services Group Inc, with $83 million.</p>
<p>Insured penetration, or the percentage of the total market that was insured in the quarter, was 51.7 percent versus 43.9 percent for the same period last year, according to the poll.</p>
<p>Year to date, the industry insured $62.9 billion of the $129 billion sold, or nearly 49 percent. That compared to a 41 percent penetration rate for the first nine months of 1995.</p>
<p>MBIA shares were down 3/4 in afternoon trading at 89-3/4, and AMBAC was down 1/2 at 61-5/8. FSA rose 5/8 to 28-1/4.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
