<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132617" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fannie Mae says $2.80/shr '97 EPS plausible.</title>
<headline>Fannie Mae says $2.80/shr '97 EPS plausible.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street's consensus estimates that Federal National Mortgage Association will earn $2.47 per share this year and $2.80 in 1997 are &quot;within the range of plausibility,&quot; Fannie Mae Executive Vice President and Chief Financial Officer Timothy Howard said</p>
<p>Howard spoke to a reporter about the earnings projections after Fannie Mae executives spoke to the New York Society of Security Analysts.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on one estimate of $3.25 per share earnings for 1998, saying it was too far into the future.  </p>
<p>On October 10 Fannie Mae reported third-quarter earnings of $0.63 per share, which brought earnings for the first nine months of the year to $1.83 per share. That compared to $0.54 in the third quarter of 1995 and $1.58 for the first nine months of 1995.</p>
<p>Fannie Mae Chairman and Chief Executive James Johnson told the meeting with analysts that U.S. mortgage originations are projected to fall to $650-$700 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>Fannie Mae economists expect originations this year to be about $775 billion. A drop to the midpoint of the range stated by Johnson would be equivalent to a decline of 13 percent.  </p>
<p>In response to a question about future repurchases of common stock, Johnson told the group that if Fannie Mae management believed the opportunities were right for a buyback, it would not hesitate to go the board and seek authorization.</p>
<p>In connection with a capital restructuring, Fannie Mae has issued $1 billion of preferred stock this year and repurchased 48 million common shares.</p>
<p>Johnson said when he spoke to the same group in 1994 he committed Fannie Mae to achieving double-digit annual earnings growth, $1 trillion in targeted lending to U.S. families in need of help, industry leadership and building its franchise.  </p>
<p>Johnson said Fannie Mae had met all four of the commitments and was making a new one -- that earnings will show a healthy rate of growth relative to Fannie Mae's peers, and with a high rate of predictability.</p>
<p>He said &quot;peers&quot; were selected by asking the biggest institutional holders of Fannie Mae to identify their other big holdings. These included such companies as General Electric Co and Merck &amp; Co Inc, he said.</p>
<p>According to a chart comparing Fannie Mae to 10 peers, Fannie Mae had higher-than-average five-year historic and five-year predicted growth rates, with less volatility.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
