<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13274" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: New U.S. envoy due in Saudi Arabia.</title>
<headline>New U.S. envoy due in Saudi Arabia.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington's new ambassador to Saudi Arabia is due in Riyadh shortly to fill a vacuum in what has become one of the most sensitive U.S. diplomatic posts.</p>
<p>There has been no U.S. ambassador in the kingdom since April when Raymond Mabus returned home. Before the arrival of Mabus, who was close to President Bill Clinton but lacked foreign policy experience, the Riyadh post had been empty between August 1992 and July 1994.</p>
<p>His successor is another political appointee -- Wyche Fowler, formerly a Georgia Democrat in the Senate, who was appointed two weeks ago when Clinton invoked special powers because the Senate dallied in confirming his nomination.</p>
<p>&quot;He's due in the next few days,&quot; a U.S. embassy spokesman said by telephone from the Saudi capital.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia places much emphasis in its dealings with its main ally on close personal contact, especially the relationship between the representative in Riyadh and the White House.</p>
<p>Time was when a posting to the world's richest oil power meant little more hardship than living in splendid isolation in a closed compound in the capital's Safarat diplomatic quarter.</p>
<p>Now the American embassy and 5,000 U.S. armed forces personnel are potential targets of what the White House calls an international terrorist campaign against the United States.</p>
<p>Two bomb attacks have killed 24 Americans and two Indians and wounded nearly 500 in Saudi Arabia since last November.</p>
<p>More Americans have been killed in Saudi Arabia during the past year than in Bosnia, where U.S. troops were placed in a combat situation, noted Claiborne Pell, ranking Democrat on the Senate Foreign Relations Committee.</p>
<p>The United States must be prepared for more and bigger attacks in the Gulf, Defence Secretary William Perry said after a recent visit to the region. &quot;Future attacks could be with more powerful bombs, or standoff weapons, or even chemical weapons,&quot; he told the American Bar Association.</p>
<p>Four Saudis opposed to the U.S. presence were beheaded after confessing on television to the first attack last November.</p>
<p>But two months after a fuel truck bomb at a Saudi apartment block killed 19 U.S. airmen on June 25, no arrests have been announced despite the lure of $5 million in rewards.</p>
<p>Poor intelligence and high personnel turnover -- American security staff in the kingdom were rotated every 90 days -- contributed to unpreparedness for the second bomb, according to a U.S. congressional report.</p>
<p>It said much of the U.S. intelligence on Saudi Arabia came from Saudis who may not have passed on full information on the Saudi dissident threat.</p>
<p>Federal Bureau of Investigation agents sent to Saudi Arabia were denied an opportunity to interrogate the four confessed bombers. FBI Director Louis Freeh twice visited the kingdom after the second attack to seek more cooperation.</p>
<p>About 800 members of U.S. government employees' families in Saudi Arabia are being repatriated as a precaution and military personnel are on maximum threat alert.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
