<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132730" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Weyerhaeuser mortgage unit seeking business.</title>
<headline>Weyerhaeuser mortgage unit seeking business.</headline>
<dateline>WOODLAND HILLS, Calif. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weyerhaeuser Mortgage Co said Tuesday it has no intention of leaving the mortgage business and continues to pursue new subservicing and origination outsourcing partners.</p>
<p>The Weyerhaeuser Co subsidiary said it is actively recruiting and hiring top producers around the country, adding that numerous producers have been hired since its parent company announced it is investigating options for the mortgage subsidiary, including a possible sale.  </p>
<p>Weyerhaeuser Mortgage chief executive Donald E. Lange said the perception the firm is getting out of business grew out of that announcement.</p>
<p>He said rumors about the unit's demise bring to mind Mark Twain's famous quote about the reports of his (Twain's) death being an exaggeration. &quot;Let me assure you -- we are still planting daisies, not pushing them up,&quot; said Lange.</p>
<p>&quot;We're moving ahead aggressively,&quot; said Lange, who added that the company has launched four new consumer loan programs and new initiatives for Controlled Business Arrangements with real estate companies and builders since the announcement.  </p>
<p>Weyerhaeuser Mortgage is in the process of finalizing the previously announced restructuring of its wholesale operation, which will include opening a new operations center in Memphis, Tenn.</p>
<p>According to Lange, Weyerhaeuser, the forest products company, is trying to find a buyer for WMC that is more strongly focused on financial services, will keep the lender intact, and expand it aggressively.</p>
<p>&quot;Although our name could possibly change at some point, WMC will remain customer-focused and a major force in the mortgage industry,&quot; said Lange.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WOODLAND HILLS, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
