<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132799" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed may conduct US bill pass in late Oct - experts.</title>
<headline>Fed may conduct US bill pass in late Oct - experts.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve may add permanent reserves to the U.S. banking system late in the month or early in November in a bid to meet higher demand for cash ahead of the year-end holidays, Wall Street pundits said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for a bill pass. I think the most likely dates are either October 30th or November 6th,&quot; said Dana Saporta, economist at Stone and McCarthy Research Associates.</p>
<p>Historically, the Federal Reserve faces a seasonal add need late in the year. Analysts said, however, they see the Fed entering the market through a single bill pass operation and not several tranches of coupon passes.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think that with bills they (Fed officials) still do it the old-fashioned way,&quot; said Kevin Flanagan, first-vice president and an economist at Dean Witter Reynolds Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;It's likely to be just one go-around type of a thing unlike the coupons which take them a couple of days to accomplish,&quot; Flanagan added.</p>
<p>The Fed has bought bills every year in late October or early November for at least the past seven years, analysts said. &quot;That's the history. That's why I'm calling for bills rather than coupons,&quot; Saporta said.</p>
<p>-- Jose Paulo Vicente 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
