<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13278" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Aug 25.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Sunday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- IMF tells Middle East News Agency in Washington that Egypt has succeeded in creating appropriate atmosphere to attract investors.</p>
<p>- Finance minister tells conference in Alexandria that 120 international investment funds trade in Egyptian stock market and announces new tourism projects worth 13 billion pounds.</p>
<p>- Writer Ahmed Bahaa el-Deen dies after long illness.</p>
<p>- 51 percent of 11 housing companies to be sold to private sector.</p>
<p>- Archaeologists find pharaonic pots that may reveal secrets of mummification.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- Agriculture Minister Youssef Wali tells youth conference that land set aside for graduates has produced harvest worth a billion pounds.</p>
<p>- Thieves getaway with 560,000 pounds from exchange bureau.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIA</p>
<p>- Finance minister says land will be given free or rented for symbolic fee to companies in western desert to encourage investment.</p>
<p>- Senior presidential adviser Osama el-Baz says Egypt plays important role in creating stability and balance in the Middle East.</p>
<p>- Public enterprise minister says shares in 10 construction companies will be floated on stock market within the next year.</p>
<p>AL-WAFD</p>
<p>- IMF criticises inflation in Egypt's foreign reserves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
