<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13277" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq hits out at U.S., Iran over Kurdish fighting.</title>
<headline>Iraq hits out at U.S., Iran over Kurdish fighting.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq on Sunday lashed out at the United States for its protection of rebel Kurds in the north of the country and lambasted its eastern neighbour Iran for aiding a main faction in inter-Kurdish fighting there.</p>
<p>&quot;Time has come for the voices of our noble people in the autonomous area (Iraqi Kurdistan) to be raised against this criminal American ploy which has no aim other than inflicting harm on Iraq and its people,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said in a statement to the official Iraqi News Agency (INA).</p>
<p>He accused Iran of taking sides in the latest flare-up of fighting between rival Kurdish factions and described Tehran's action as &quot;hostile, flagrant...and harbouring serious expansionist tendencies&quot;.</p>
<p>The ruling Baath party newspaper al-Thawra said U.S. policy toward Iraq encouraged &quot;Iranian rats to leave their holes&quot;. It warned Iran not to take the current situation in the area as a pretext to meddle in Iraq's affairs.</p>
<p>Last month Iran sent a small force into northern Iraq in pursuit of the rebels of Kurdistan Democratic Party of Iran (KDPI). The thrust also drew condemnation from Iraq.</p>
<p>The latest fighting in northern Iraq pit guerrillas of the Kurdish warlord Jalal Talabani of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) against rebels of Massoud Barzani, head of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP).</p>
<p>Washington brokered a ceasefire between them on Friday and persuaded them to attend peace talks next month. Britain on Saturday offered to host the talks.</p>
<p>A similar ceasefire agreed under Washington's auspices last year failed to solve the differences between Talabani and Barzani on how to run their breakaway enclave which they have divided into two separate spheres of influence.</p>
<p>A U.S.-led airforce in southern Turkey guards Iraqi rebel Kurds against any possible military attacks by Baghdad since the Gulf War in 1991.</p>
<p>Aziz said the force was &quot;illegitimate&quot; and its presence in Turkey was &quot;a matter of ridicule&quot; since it has so far failed to provide stability to the Kurdish region.</p>
<p>Both Barzani and Iraq accuse Talabani of liaising with Tehran in the latest fighting. Iraq's official press has been critical of Talabani and last week published overtures to lure Barzani to Baghdad's camp.</p>
<p>Sunday's official newspapers published the full text of a statement Barzani's KDP issued last week, accusing Tehran of sending troops to back Talabani's guerrillas. Talabani's PUK also accused Baghdad of shelling areas under its control.</p>
<p>Aziz said Iran's armed forces and Revolutionary Guards took part in the clashes, using rocket launchers and heavy artillery.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who provided the chance for this Iranian interference, particularly the opportunist agent Jalal Talabani, prove by this conduct their treason and treachery of both Iraqi and Kurdish citizens,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
