<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13275" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO says Netanyahu's stalling killing peace accord.</title>
<headline>PLO says Netanyahu's stalling killing peace accord.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian officials say Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's stalling on PLO-Israel peace deals is killing the accords and doubt a new round of negotiations would bear fruit.</p>
<p>&quot;The Oslo (peace) agreement is decaying. Even backers of the accord are grumbling and frustrated and soon it will be buried,&quot; a senior aide to Palestinian President Yasser Arafat said.</p>
<p>Palestinians are worried that what they won from the previous Israeli government -- limited self-rule in parts of the West Bank and Gaza Strip -- will be all they will get.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's delay in redeploying Israeli troops in the West Bank town of Hebron is only the tip of the iceberg, they say.</p>
<p>According to agreements signed with the government Netanyahu ousted in May elections, further redeployments from the rest of the West Bank must begin on September 7 and end mid-July 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Hebron is already negotiated and agreed. Israel has only to implement the accord,&quot; chief PLO peace negotiator Saeb Erekat said. &quot;Staged further redeployments from the West Bank are more important.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu, apparently shaken by Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak's hint last week he might cancel a Middle East economic summit in November, promised on Thursday that peace talks with the PLO would start &quot;in the very near future&quot;.</p>
<p>The prime minister also gave the green light on Sunday to Israeli President Ezer Weizman to meet Arafat. Weizman will host Arafat at his private home in central Israel within two weeks, Israel Radio said.</p>
<p>PLO officials on Saturday said Israel told them talks, which have been suspended since before Netanyahu's May election, would resume before September 2.</p>
<p>But the officials were sceptical the talks would advance the process. They believed that Netanyahu was anxious for window dressing to shield his unravelling of accords on the ground.</p>
<p>&quot;One is wondering if this government has a plan to say good bye to peace. Its policy of expanding settlements and changing the nature of Jerusalem is planting bombs with each step,&quot; Erekat told Reuters.</p>
<p>Final peace talks are to deal with Jerusalem, refugees, Jewish settlements on occupied Arab land, and borders. Netanyahu has said until interim issues like Hebron are cleared up he does not want to move to final status issues.</p>
<p>Palestinians said Netanyahu's election removed the fig leaf concealing weakenesses in the 1993 PLO-Israel framework peace deal negotiated at talks in Oslo and signed in Washington.</p>
<p>Some officials say they still are not sure if Netanyahu's stalling is because he is a pragmatist who is running into far-right opposition in his government or if it is a ploy by a right-wing idealogue bent on tearing apart the peace deals.</p>
<p>Arafat aide Tayeb Abdul-Rahim said whether it was a tactic or not: &quot;Netanyahu's inability to take decisions is a policy of a weak man, not a statesman.&quot;</p>
<p>Another senior PLO official said: &quot;Netanyahu clearly lacks leadership. He acts and gives us verbal promises only when he comes under Arab and international pressure, but nothing is implemented on the ground.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
