<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132773" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSX gets $4.8 bln for Conrail deal.</title>
<headline>CSX gets $4.8 bln for Conrail deal.</headline>
<dateline>RICHMOND, Va. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSX Corp said on Tuesday that it set up a five-year, $4.8-billion financing arrangement for its proposed acquisition of Conrail Inc.</p>
<p>Lead banks are NationsBank Corp, BankAmerica Corp, Bank of Nova Scotia and Chase Manhattan Corp. Chase Securities is administrative agent.</p>
<p>&quot;Completing this arrangement clearly underscores our commitment to the merger,&quot; CSX Chairman John Snow said.</p>
<p>The leading transportation companies announced they would combine on Oct. 15, with Conrail being absorbed in a cash and stock deal worth $8.4 billion, or $92.50 per Conrail share.  </p>
<p>Under the financing deal, each lead bank has agreed to commit $1.2 billion of the $4.8 billion financing with syndication to a consortium of leading financial institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very encouraged by the early response we are getting from key constituents, including shippers and public officials,&quot; Snow said. &quot;We are anxious to work with other carriers in the region, and so far have reached out in that regard to Norfolk Southern (Corp ) as the other leading carrier in the area.&quot;</p>
<p>Norfolk Southern is viewed as a major rival of the merged CSX, which plans to move to Philadelphia from Richmond, Va.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are intent on reaching agreements with Norfolk Southern and other carriers and having them completed prior to filing our application with the Surface Transportation Board,&quot; Snow said.</p>
<p>The merger will create a leading freight transportation and logistics company with revenues exceeding $14 billion, CSX said.  It will offer single-line rail service opportunities to shippers and receivers in 22 states from Chicago, Boston and New York to Miami and New Orleans, the company said.</p>
<p>Shares of CSX were down 5/8 at 46, and Conrail was down 1/2 at 84-1/2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHMOND, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
