<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132788" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Digital CEO sees breakeven or better Q2.</title>
<headline>Digital CEO sees breakeven or better Q2.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Digital Equipment Corp Chief Executive Officer Robert Palmer said he expects the company to break even or return to profitability in the fiscal second quarter, begun September 29.</p>
<p>Palmer told a conference call of analysts and reporters that the realignment of Digital's worldwide sales force hurt first quarter earnings but should lead to stronger sales in the second and successive quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect that as a result we will return to profitablity in the December (second) quarter as the sales pick up and we get this thing behind us,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Mullarkey said he is confident that product gross margins, which rose to 31.1 percent in the first quarter from 30.9 percent a year earlier, will continue to rise.</p>
<p>&quot;I continue to have confidence in our ability to achieve the 35 percent product gross margin goals set recently in our intermediate model,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As a result of the sales force realignment, Digital missed its product revenue targets by about 10 percent, he said.</p>
<p>Palmer said that although the realignment had unexpected negative consequences, it will result in improved performance in the long-term.  </p>
<p>&quot;These actions allow us to cover more accounts, enable us to improve customer loyalty, reduce channel conflict, lower our costs, and they will achieve greater sales productivity and revenue growth in the future,&quot; Palmer said.</p>
<p>Palmer said sales of its Alpha systems, up a modest four percent in the first quarter, will resume stronger growth. &quot;I'm pretty confident that as we get stable with the sales force, we'll see the Alpha revenues continue to grow again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Palmer said he expects Digital's work force to fall to about 53,000 at the end of the fiscal year.  </p>
<p>Digital employed about 57,000 at the end of the first quarter.</p>
<p>Asked if it might be time for him to step aside, Palmer said he had the continued support of the board of directors and the company had a capable management team.</p>
<p>Over the past two years, since Palmer restructured the company into business units, Digital's profitability excluding restructuring charges has improved by more than $1 billion, and the balance sheet has strengthened, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a difficult turnaround. We've been working through a lot of previous problems, but we remain committed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Michael Ellis, Boston Bureau 617 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
