<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132819" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-BLACKBURN CRASH OUT OF CUP TO STOCKPORT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BLACKBURN CRASH OUT OF CUP TO STOCKPORT.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blackburn's miserable season continued on Tuesday when they were dumped out the English Football League Cup by second division Stockport.</p>
<p>Ray Harford's side lost 1-0 at home to a side 34 places below them in the league thanks to a first-half own goal from captain Tim Sherwood, who just 18 months ago lifted Blackburn's first English league trophy since 1914.</p>
<p>Tuesday's defeat compounds the Lancashire side's dismal start to the league season. After 10 matches they are the only club in the 92-team English league without a win, and sections of the home crowd chanted for Harford to quit at the final whistle.</p>
<p>Blackburn were not the only premier league side to struggle in the League Cup, the least prestigious of England's three soccer competitions.</p>
<p>Ruud Gullit's Chelsea relinquished a 1-0 lead to go down 2-1 at first division Bolton, while Wimbledon and Coventry could only manage draws against second division opponents.</p>
<p>High-flying Wimbledon, who have won their last seven league matches, were held 1-1 at home by Luton, and Ron Atkinson's Coventry, only one place above Blackburn in the premier league, drew 2-2 at tiny Gillingham.</p>
<p>Leicester were the only top-flight side to advance to the fourth round. They won 2-0 at York, conquerers of Everton in the previous round and Manchester United in last season's competiton.</p>
<p>There were no suprises in Scotland's only Cup tie.</p>
<p>Glasgow Rangers, humbled in the European Champions' League for a second successive season, continue to sweep all before them closer to home, routing Dunfermline 6-1 in a Scottish League Cup semifinal.</p>
<p>Danes Brian Laudrup and Erik Bo Andersen scored twice each for the Scottish champions and Derek McInnes and Jorg Albertz added one apiece.</p>
<p>Heart of Midlothian meet Dundee in the second semifinal on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
