<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132891" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - OCT 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - OCT 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- Polish Airlines LOT will increase all ticket prices by about four percent as of November 1 this year, LOT representatives said.</p>
<p>- The combined revenues of Poland's municipalities totalled 12 billion zlotys in 1995 while their outlays accounted for 11.9 billion zlotys. Local fees and taxes accounted for more than 65 percent of all municipal revenues.</p>
<p>- The Luxembourg-based RTL media network wants to start commercial radio broadcasting in Poland. The CLT group, which owns RTL, holds stakes in 30 television and radio stations in nine European countries.</p>
<p>- Investor interest remains high in Poland's three special economic zones of Mielec, central Poland, Katowice, southern Poland, and Suwalki, northern Poland, the state industrial development agency (ARP) said.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Poland's first rating agency (PAR) will be founded on November 8 this year by a group of banks. PAR's start-up capital presently amounts to 2.2 million zlotys.</p>
<p>- The unbalanced public budget, the crisis of the pension system and the existence of such monopolists such as TPSA telecoms firm, will make it very difficult to achieve single-digit inflation in the next two years, the central bank (NBP) president Hanna Gronkiewicz Walc said.</p>
<p>- Over 76 percent of Poles have already collected the National Investment Fund (NFI) privatisation certificates with 120,000 units collected every day.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Bank Handlowy Capital Operations Centre (BH COK) has recommended buying shares of Warta insurer because of its good earnings outlook and the insurance sector development perspectives in Poland.</p>
<p>- Poland's NFI funds have sold a 60 percent stake in the Chorzow-based Konstal rolling stock maker to France's Gec- Alsthom concern for an undisclosed sum.</p>
<p>- South Korea's Kyungbang concern plans to invest $20 million in Poland, mostly in the textile industry sector, Kyungbang deputy president Joon Kim said.</p>
<p>- Poland's state owned firms are still managing $50 billion which account for half of the gross domestic product (GDP). At the present rate, their privatisation will take another 20 years, World's Bank representaives said.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- A lack fo thorought knowledge of the needs of Polish consumers costs producers and advertisers millions every year in ill-conceived advertisign campaigns, Frederic Winkler, the head of J.Walter Thompson-Parintex advertising agency.</p>
<p>PARKIET - Jelfa pharmaceutical firm will benefit from the recent six-percent rise in prices of state-subsidised drugs but it is too early to estimate how much the company will gain, Jelfa's board member Czeslaw Murawski said.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch investment bank has recommended buying Agros, Elektrim, Mostostal Export and Polifarb Cieszyn shares in its weekly report dated October 9.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
