<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132833" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SOCCER-DUNDEE IN TUG-OF-WAR BETWEEN GERMANY AND SOUTH AFRICA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DUNDEE IN TUG-OF-WAR BETWEEN GERMANY AND SOUTH AFRICA.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Karlsruhe striker Sean Dundee was at the centre of a tug-of-war on Tuesday between his adopted country Germany and his native South Africa.</p>
<p>Dundee, top scorer in the Bundesliga with nine goals this season, said at the weekend he dreamed of playing at international level for Germany and not South Africa -- remarks that have begun a storm of controversy at home.</p>
<p>The South African government said on Tuesday it would not try to stop him if he wanted to play for Germany but some angry MPs said he should not be allowed to do so.</p>
<p>His decision has been the subject of some intense public debate in both the South African media and on telephone phone-ins.</p>
<p>Many black South Africans feel national team coach Clive Barker, who is white, is bending over backwards to try to entice Dundee, a fellow white, into his squad, overlooking black players who want to play only for South Africa.</p>
<p>Dundee said at the weekend he did not want to play for his native country but was hoping to be selected for Germany's national squad.</p>
<p>In an interview with German magazine Kicker he said: &quot;I've signed a seven-year deal with Karlsruhe, my future is in Germany and my dream is to pull on a German jersey.&quot;</p>
<p>German coach Berti Vogts is widely reported to have been instrumental in trying to get him naturalised in time to be considered for Germany's World Cup qualifier against Northern Ireland on November 9.</p>
<p>South Africa play Zaire in a World Cup qualifier on the same day and Barker has been trying to persuade him to return home for that match -- and all future internationals.</p>
<p>Dundee's weekend statement angered South African members of parliament who on Tuesday urged the government to make diplomatic representations to Germany to block Dundee's move.</p>
<p>But Sports Minister Steve Tshwete said the issue had to be addressed first by the South African Football Association.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like them to take the initiative and then they will get the full backing of the government,&quot; he told MPs.</p>
<p>Dundee, who was also courted by Republic of Ireland manager Mick McCarthy earlier this year when it was learned Dundee's grandparents were Irish, has established himself as a potent striker since moving to Karlsruhe at the start of last season.</p>
<p>He scored 16 goals in his first season -- the second highest total in the Bundesliga.</p>
<p>Uncapped, he was in South Africa's squad for a friendly international against Germany last December but withdrew because of injury.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
