<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132840" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: SOCCER-RUSSIA MAY OPT FOR AUTUMN-SPRING SEASON.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-RUSSIA MAY OPT FOR AUTUMN-SPRING SEASON.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's top soccer official wants to defy the elements and change the country's domestic soccer calendar, bringing it into line with most European countries.</p>
<p>Vyacheslav Koloskov, president of the Russian Football Union, said he supported an autumn-spring season for the 18 premier league teams to improve the country's disappointing record in European competitions.</p>
<p>The current season runs from early April to early November, sparing supporters and players the ordeal of freezing winter temperatures.</p>
<p>During the dark winter months many pitches are carpeted with ice or are ankle-deep in mud. Only a few stadiums have underground heating systems.</p>
<p>Koloskov said at least half of the premier division coaches and players supported the transition to autumn-spring but it was not clear when the plan could be implemented.</p>
<p>&quot;I put forward this idea in September and will try to bring it into effect,&quot; he said, adding that he hoped it could be introduced next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russian and west European calenders don't coincide at all. When our teams are playing their west European counterparts are resting and vice versa.&quot;</p>
<p>Koloskov said some coaches opposed his idea but most were from teams languishing in the lower reaches of the table with little prospect of playing in European tournaments.</p>
<p>He said the he issue would be settled at a meeting of the Russian Football Union on January 22.</p>
<p>Russia has no covered soccer stadiums, although late last year Moscow Mayor Yuri Luzhkov launched a plan to build a roof over the 100,000-seat Luzhniki stadium, home to Moscow Torpedo.</p>
<p>Work has started and is due to be completed late next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Then we could play football in the domestic championship and European cups throughout the year,&quot; Luzhkov said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
