<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132898" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: ZYWIEC SEES NO IMPACT OF DRINKS PHASE-OUT.</title>
<headline>ZYWIEC SEES NO IMPACT OF DRINKS PHASE-OUT.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish brewer Zaklady Piwowarskie w Zywcu Zywiec SA (Zywiec) said its decision to halt soft-drinks production in December would not hurt its sales and earnings in 1997, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said the revenues from soft drinks production, made on PepsiCo licence since 1982 accounted for only 3.1 percent of the company's overall sales in 1995 and 2.1 percent of its sales in the first three quarters of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Ending the production of soft drinks will not negatively influence the firm's sales and profits in 1997,&quot; Zywiec said, but did not give any figures of the planned earnings.</p>
<p>Zywiec said it had not yet decided what would be the future of its soft-drinks facility, which employs 72 people.</p>
<p>The company said that also the announced plan to shut down its brewery in Bielsko-Biala, would not weigh significantly on its results.</p>
<p>Zywiec said the Bielsko-Biala brewery, which employed 45 people, was supplying malt extract for its two other breweries and produced 38,400 hectolitres of the extract -- 3.1 percent of Zywiec overall production.</p>
<p>On Monday Zywiec said it would lay off 145 out of its 990 workers following the decisions to shut down its Bielsko-Biala brewery and stop soft-drinks production.</p>
<p>It said it had decided to shut down the Bielsko-Biala facility because of its poor technical standard and to move production to its modernised facilities at its Zywiec headquarters.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
