<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132849" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SELES OPTIMISTIC ABOUT AVOIDING SURGERY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SELES OPTIMISTIC ABOUT AVOIDING SURGERY.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tennis star Monica Seles is optimistic that a new therapy programme will enable her to avoid shoulder surgery and another lengthy layoff from the WTA Tour.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel it is getting better so that is very encouraging,&quot; Seles said Tuesday after undergoing nearly four weeks of a new exercise regimen for the shoulder she injured while winning the Australian Open in January.</p>
<p>Seles has been bothered all year by a small tear in the left shoulder socket, an injury that sidelined the co-world number one several times during the year and causes pain when the left-hander serves.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels much better, not anything drastic, but if we can stay on this plan, not serve that many balls or overuse my arm, we are on a good course,&quot; Seles said.</p>
<p>Seles began the new therapy programme immediately after leading the United States to the Fed Cup title last month. In a teleconference call she described the four-week regimen as one to two hours of stretching, light weightlifting and ice and heat treatments.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing is to stabilise the shoulder, we can not repair the tear,&quot; she said. &quot;If I keep doing it, the pain stays away, but if I stop it for a few days the pain comes back.&quot;</p>
<p>The 22-year-old Seles, who missed nearly two and a half years of competitive tennis in her prime while recovering from being stabbed in the back during a 1993 match in Hamburg, is anxious to avoid shoulder surgery that could sideline her for another 12 weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I would have to start a second comeback and I don't want to do that,&quot; said Seles, who only returned from the stabbing in August of 1995 and has played sporadically since due to a number of injuries.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not mean that we have ruled out surgery, but as long as we manage it like this we should be ok,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Seles plans to try out the non-surgical solution to her shoulder woes at next week's WTA event in Chicago.</p>
<p>Her schedule also includes the Oakland tournament in early November before finishing her year at the WTA championships in New York from November 18-24.</p>
<p>Seles won the prestigious season finale in 1990, 1991 and 1992 but has not been back since, missing the event twice because of the stabbing and last year due to injury.</p>
<p>&quot;Next year the key is to play a regular schedule and not miss as many months as I did this year,&quot; Seles said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
