<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132844" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: SOCCER-MARADONA WAS AT FLAT BEFORE DRUGS BUST, MANAGER SAYS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MARADONA WAS AT FLAT BEFORE DRUGS BUST, MANAGER SAYS.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diego Maradona's manager Guillermo Coppola, held on drug charges, has told a judge the Argentine soccer star was at his home with three women shortly before police found cocaine there, a prosecutor said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Coppola was arrested two weeks ago, along with Maradona's brother-in-law Gabriel Esposito, former soccer international Alberto Tarantini and others, after police found a pound (500 grams) of cocaine in a flower pot at Coppola's apartment.</p>
<p>State prosecutor Jorge Mola told local radio that in a six hour declaration to Judge Hernan Bernasconi on Monday, Coppola &quot;brought new evidence about a party at his home a day before he left it, with Diego Maradona and other people he named.&quot;</p>
<p>And Bernasconi told radio stations that Coppola said he left the party, held the weekend before the raid, leaving Diego alone with three &quot;well known but not famous women.&quot; The judge said he may have to question Maradona now.</p>
<p>The proceedings in Dolores provincial courthouse south of Buenos Aires have given ordinary Argentines a glimpse into the sleazy nightlife of a jet set where politicians, models and sports stars partied with drug dealers and prostitutes.</p>
<p>Many Argentines blame 49-year-old Coppola for Maradona's self-confessed cocaine habit, which put the 36-year-old Boca Juniors player in a Swiss clinic for 10 days last month. Days after checking out, he smashed up a Spanish hotel in a rage.</p>
<p>Bronzed, silver-haired Coppola, Maradona's manager and friend for most of the past decade, has had brushes with the law before, including drug-peddling charges in Italy while managing Maradona's career in Naples.</p>
<p>His arrest has embarrassed senior members of Argentina's government. Coppola was a visitor to President Carlos Menem's home with Maradona and was a friend of Menem's late son Carlitos and Menem's private secretary Ramon Hernandez.</p>
<p>But Bernasconi tried to cool down speculation about who would be arrested next: &quot;The investigations may lead us along new paths, but I think expectations are exaggerated.&quot;</p>
<p>Coppola says he is a cocaine user but not a dealer and that the drugs were planted. His lawyer Mariano Cuneo Liberona wants Judge Bernasconi taken off the case because Coppola's Buenos Aires home is outside his provincial jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Bernasconi argued the case is within his jurisdiction since it was launched eight months ago as a drugs crackdown in beach resorts along Buenos Aires province's Atlantic coast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
