<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132895" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: U.S. URGES SLOVAKIA TO PURSUE SENSITIVE CASES.</title>
<headline>U.S. URGES SLOVAKIA TO PURSUE SENSITIVE CASES.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Tuesday warned Bratislava that abandoning sensitive criminal probes linked by the opposition to a political feud between the president and premier could damage Slovak ambitions of joining &quot;western structures&quot;.</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador to Bratislava Ralph Johnson told the independent Slovak Foreign Policy Association that dropping the probe into the kidnapping of the Slovak president's son and the subsequent death of a former policeman involved in the case would damage attempts to join organisations like NATO and the EU.  </p>
<p>&quot;We make no judgments about the outcome of these investigations, but abandoning them would in our view be very damaging to Slovakia's candidacy (to join western structures),&quot; Johnson said in an address in Presov according to a text released by the embassy in Bratislava.</p>
<p>Michal Kovac Junior, adult son of President Michal Kovac, was kidnapped in August 1995, when he was bundled into the boot of his car and dumped outside a police station in Austria.</p>
<p>Following the sacking of two state detectives who said their investigations led them to suspect the involvement of the state secrete service (SIS) in Kovac Junior's abduction, a third investigator in May adjourned the case due to lack of evidence.</p>
<p>Former policeman Robert Remias was killed in a car blast this spring after acting as the only contact between a former SIS member who said the abduction was organised by Ivan Lexa, the SIS head and close ally of Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar who is locked in a bitter political feud with the president.</p>
<p>The police also adjourned the case of Remias death due to lack of evidence, after it said the blast had been caused by an unspecified explosive set up inside the car.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
