<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132874" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ITALIAN COACH SACCHI UNDER INCREASING PRESSURE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ITALIAN COACH SACCHI UNDER INCREASING PRESSURE.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy coach Arrigo Sacchi, widely seen as a lame duck after a poor Euro 96 and recent dismal form by his team, could be ousted before Italy play England in their next World Cup qualifier in London on February 12.</p>
<p>Italian newspapers reported on Tuesday that the Italian soccer federation, currently governed by a special commissioner after a failed attempt to elect a successor to Antonio Matarrese, had discussed Sacchi with top officials.</p>
<p>They included Luciano Nizzola, the League president now considered the inevitable successor to Matarrese, who was Sacchi's main mentor before himself being ousted after Euro 96.</p>
<p>The federation holds its next ballot to elect a new president in December.</p>
<p>The Rome daily La Repubblica quoted an unnamed top federation official as saying that &quot;Sacchi's presence in England is now a hypothesis, no longer a certainty&quot;.</p>
<p>It said under-21 coach Cesare Maldini, the father of Italian skipper Paolo Maldini, was expected to take over until June 1997, when a permanent replacement would be announced -- with Lazio and former Italian goalkeeper Dino Zoff a front runner along with former Parma coach Nevio Scala.</p>
<p>The daily Corriere dello Sport quoted Nizzola saying that &quot;the problem exists, we must look at it carefully...The fact is that we want to bring all Italy behind the team.&quot;</p>
<p>Sacchi, who led Italy to the 1994 World Cup final against Brazil, was given a new contract just before the Euro 96 championship in England last June. And that contract, which does not expire until after the 1998 World Cup finals, is the main reason he has not been sacked from his job.</p>
<p>Worth a huge $1.07 million a year after tax, the Italian federation know it would be economic madness to dismiss Sacchi, pay him off -- and pay his successor.</p>
<p>Recent opinion polls have shown a majority of Italians want him to go, even though Italy currently have a maximum six points from their two World Cup qualifiers so far.</p>
<p>Indeed, Italy have one of the best records in Europe over the last two years despite their failure in Euro 96. Since reaching the World Cup final in 1994, they have played 20 matches, won 13, drawn four and lost three -- a record bettered only by Germany, Spain and France.</p>
<p>But it is the nature of the way the national team have been playing, and Sacchi's philosophy about his team's tactics and personnel, which have antagonised almost the entire, passionate world of Italian soccer.</p>
<p>If Sacchi does leave, speculation is that he will return to club coaching and media reports have linked him with several clubs recently, including Inter and his former employers Milan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
