<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13282" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli president to meet Arafat.</title>
<headline>Israeli president to meet Arafat.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli President Ezer Weizman said on Sunday he would meet Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat at his private residence in central Israel but no date had been set.</p>
<p>&quot;After an exchange of opinions, we agreed that the meeting would be held -- no date was set -- in my house, which is the most appropriate place,&quot; Weizman told reporters after holding talks with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.  </p>
<p>Weizman confirmed he had received a letter from Arafat &quot;in which he spelled out his troubles and problems and said 'I hope we will meet soon'&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;After the letter was translated to Hebrew, I invited the prime minister to see me last Tuesday. I showed him the letter. He read it carefully. Afterwards I told him, 'Look I want to agree to his request and meet him and I propose I do so in (my private residence in) Caesarea,&quot; Weizman said.</p>
<p>Israel's biggest daily Yedioth Ahronoth reported that Netanyahu had opposed the idea and that Weizman had threatened to meet Arafat over the objections of the prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no ultimatum. I am not a child who tells the prime minister, either you meet him or I will,&quot; said Weizman, who has met Arafat once, at the 1994 inauguration of South African President Nelson Mandela.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
