<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13288" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli president invites Arafat to home - paper.</title>
<headline>Israeli president invites Arafat to home - paper.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli President Ezer Weizman has invited Yasser Arafat to meet him at his private home, Israel's biggest newspaper said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Yedioth Ahronoth daily reported that Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who has said he has no desire to hold talks with the Palestinian president, opposes the meeting due to be held this coming week.  </p>
<p>The newspaper said Weizman scheduled the meeting at his private residence in the central Israeli village of Caesarea after Arafat sent him an emotional appeal &quot;to save the peace process&quot;.</p>
<p>Netanyahu met Weizman last Tuesday and voiced his opposition, Yedioth said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am prepared to postpone the meeting under one condition -- that you give me a commitment right now to meet Arafat yourself within 10 days,&quot; the paper quoted Weizman as telling Netanyahu. It said Netanyahu had yet to give Weizman an answer.</p>
<p>The office of Israeli president is largely ceremonial. But Weizman, a former defence minister and an architect of Israel's peace treaty with Egypt, has spoken out frequently on the peace process with the Palestinians -- at times urging the former Labour government to slow it down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
