<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132801" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MCI long distance revenues up 11.4 pct.</title>
<headline>MCI long distance revenues up 11.4 pct.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>MCI Communications Corp said on Tuesday its third quarter long distance revenues rose 11.4 percent to $4.3 billion from a year ago, exceeding its traffic growth of 11.0 percent over the same period.</p>
<p>&quot;The gap (revenue growth minus traffic growth) grew a positive 0.4 percent from a year ago,&quot; chief financial officer Doug Maine told an analysts' conference call.</p>
<p>This improvement, which means each minute spent on the network earns the company more money, came partly from a fall in access charges by regional Bells and lower settlement rates paid on outbound international calls.  </p>
<p>Less low-revenue carriage of traffic for other telecommunications firms, compared with a year ago, improved the ratio, but there was some offset from increased provisions for uncollectible revenues, Maine said.</p>
<p>MCI said wireless revenues fell by $13 million to $83 million from a year ago, because of a decline in paging customers while the company reorganized its marketing approach to cut customer turnover, or churn.</p>
<p>&quot;Look for declines in paging customer accounts to continue during the fourth quarter, with a pickup in net customers during 1997,&quot; Maine said.  </p>
<p>MCI paging customers fell to 342,000 from 474,000 in the second quarter. No year-ago figure was given.</p>
<p>However, cellular telephone customers rose to 407,000, 28 percent up from a year ago.  MCI resells both paging and cellular services carried on the networks of others.</p>
<p>Maine said business services continued to grow very strongly, with double digit revenue gains continuing.</p>
<p>Data services grew revenues 24 percent from a year ago, dedicated access rose 30 percent and frame relay and hyperstream high speed data services doubled.</p>
<p>Pre-paid phone card revenues trebled from a year ago.  </p>
<p>Internet access revenues rose 80 percent from the second quarter. The company had not begun the service a year ago.</p>
<p>Maine said that service guarantees and customizing data services had allowed MCI to get an even stronger grip on the business market.</p>
<p>&quot;This has enabled MCI to command a premium in the (business) marketplace over all other carriers while at the same time increasing market share,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He told analysts to look for MCI's proportion of total revenues derived from business markets to continue to increase from the current two-thirds.  </p>
<p>In the consumer long distance market, which is beset by fierce competition from resellers and intense promotional activity by AT&amp;T Corp, Maine said MCI had changed its sales and marketing focus.</p>
<p>&quot;We're focused on long term profitability, not the maximum number of customer additions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It has begun to focus on high value-added customers and decreasing the value of promotional schemes by 70 percent from a year ago.  Though customer churn is up year on year, it has already fallen from the second quarter, he said. -- Nick Louth, New York Newsroom 212 859 1712</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
