<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132847" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: HORSE RACING-BAN LIFTED ON AUSTRALIA'S WATERHOUSE.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-BAN LIFTED ON AUSTRALIA'S WATERHOUSE.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Australian racehorse trainer Gai Waterhouse on Tuesday won an appeal against a three-month ban and said she was keen to get on with training her horses for next month's Melbourne Cup.</p>
<p>Waterhouse and jockey Kevin Forrester were suspended from racing for three months by stewards of the Sydney Turf Club (STC), who held an inquiry into the way Forrester rode the Waterhouse-trained galloper Gossips during a race last month.</p>
<p>Forrester was charged by the STC with failing to give Gossips &quot;every possible chance&quot; of winning the race, won by the Waterhouse-trained Juggler. Waterhouse was charged with being a party to Forrester breaching the rules.</p>
<p>While an appeal committee apointed by the Australian Jockey Club, the sport's national governing body, overturned Waterhouse's ban, the same committee dismissed Forrester's appeal but cut his suspension from three months to two.</p>
<p>The successful appeal means Waterhouse is now free to continue training horses during the lucrative spring racing carnival which started this month in Melbourne, where Juggler will run in Saturday's A$1.5 million (US$1.2 million) Cox Plate.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel relieved and very happy,&quot; Waterhouse told reporters on Tuesday. &quot;It has been very traumatic, a cloud hanging over me, but it hasn't impacted on the carnival preparations of my horses.&quot;</p>
<p>Another of Waterhouse's horses, Nothin' Leica Dane, is among the early favourites to win the A$2.5 million (US$2.0 million) Melbourne Cup on November 5.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
