<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132883" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN TAX LEGISLATION ON TRACK - MANUEL.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN TAX LEGISLATION ON TRACK - MANUEL.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tax collection was improving and legislation outlining the South African Revenue Services' (SARS) autonomy would be tabled in the first quarter of 1997, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Briefing the parliamentary public accounts committee, Manuel said that negotiations were still underway but that he was optimistic that the legislation would make SARS autonomous enough to become a performance driven entity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a few feathers in our collective cap on the negotiations already but I would not like to say more at this stage,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>He said that while efficiencies still had to be improved, progress was being made with the help of tax officials from other countries and intensive training programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is improving and it is improving rapidly.&quot;</p>
<p>Over the past 12 months, SARS had been formed, unifying inland revenue and customs and excise departments.</p>
<p>Particular attention had been paid to retraining the 11,000 staff and outsourcing information technology systems to allow the computerisation of PAYE (pay as you earn) tax deductions.</p>
<p>Progress to date included the fact that the number of assessments issued had risen to 581,000 by September this year compared to 264,000 last year.</p>
<p>The number of VAT (value added tax) cases audited had risen to 11,000 by September this year, bringing in an extra 210 million rand compared to 7,386 in September last year.</p>
<p>As a result, revenue collection for 1996/97 was &quot;perfectly on track&quot; to achieve the targeted reduction in the budget deficit to 5.1 percent, Manuel said. He added that 900 million rand in arrear taxes had already been collected.</p>
<p>He said SARS would be funded by receiving a certain percentage of revenue collected and this would be used to help provide incentive schemes to staff in the new fiscal year.</p>
<p>As soon as it had finalised its business plan, SARS would receive the extra 150 million rand allocated to revenue collection by bthe budget in the current financial year.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary office +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
