<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132817" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE SET FOR 100TH CAP IN ITALY.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE SET FOR 100TH CAP IN ITALY.</headline>
<dateline>PADUA, Italy 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Whatever the final score against Italy on Wednesday, the first test match of Australia's European rugby union tour will be David Campese's day.</p>
<p>Call him what you will -- the world's top test try scorer, legendary entertainer, or just plain Campo -- the Australian winger whose retirement has turned into something of an annual event will make his 100th test appearance in Padua.</p>
<p>Even if the Wallabies win by the tidy margin everyone expects at the Stadio del Plebiscito, Campese is assured of a hero's welcome in the northern town whom he guided to two titles in his three years as a resident.</p>
<p>He celebrated his 34th birthday on Monday with old friends, shrugging off any suggestion that partying might not be the best training for a man who has not played for seven weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Why not? Can't I celebrate with old friends? I'm Australian. No problem,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Apart from being Campese's 100th cap, Wednesday's match will mark the start of his 18th tour with the Wallabies and could bring him a 66th international try.</p>
<p>Only France's Philippe Sella has won more caps -- 111 in total -- and nobody is yet ruling out the blunt-talking Campese making a bid for the overall number one spot, although he claims he is not fussed by figures.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not interested in records. I'm just thinking about the tournament, about the match against Italy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wallaby coach Greg Smith has made four changes to the side beaten 25-19 by South Africa in Australia's last test in early August, with Tim Horan winning a recall at wing.</p>
<p>Horan, who has played most of his 43 tests in the centres, replaces Ben Tune after missing Australia's last two tests due to a broken nose.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a good running player with good vision and I think he fits all of those criteria,&quot; said Smith.</p>
<p>In other changes, injured prop Dan Crowley has been replaced by Richard Harry, David Knox returns to the test fold after a two-year absence in place of flyhalf Scott Bowen, while Daniel Manu replaces number eight Tim Gavin.</p>
<p>The Wallabies suffered their first setback on Saturday when they lost backrower Garrick Morgan for the rest of their European tour. Morgan broke his ankle in Australia's 55-19 victory over Italy A in Catania and is to be replaced by Warwick Waugh.</p>
<p>Italy, beaten 31-22 by Wales in their last test on October 5, are without injured captain Massimo Cuttitta, who pulled a muscle in a recent European club match. Massimo Giovanelli, who plays in France for PUC, takes over as captain.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Italy (from) - Massimo Ravazzolo, Paolo Vaccari, Walter Cristofoletto, Ivan Francescato, Alessandro Troncon, Leandro Manteri, Diego Scaglia, Mauro Dal Sie, Andrea Sgorlon, Carlo Orlandi, Franco Properzi, Orazio Arancio, Massimo Bonomi, Diego Dominguez, Stefano Bordon, Massimo Giovanelli (captain), Javier Pertile, Pier Flavio Donato, Andrea Castellani, Alessandro Moscardi, Andrea Barattin, Gian Luca Guidi, Francesco Mazzariol.</p>
<p>Australia - Matt Burke, Tim Horan, Daniel Herbert, Pat Howard, David Campese, David Knox, George Gregan, Daniel Manu, Michael Brial, David Wilson, John Welborn, John Eales (captain), Andrew Heath, Michael Foley, Richard Harry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PADUA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
