<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132826" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-QPR AND WASPS TO BE FLOATED ON LONDON STOCK MARKET.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-QPR AND WASPS TO BE FLOATED ON LONDON STOCK MARKET.</headline>
<byline>Andy Drinkwater</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The company that owns Queens Park Rangers football club and Wasps rugby club announced an ambitious plan on Tuesday to float itself on the London Stock Exchange in a bid to raise 12 million sterling ($15 million).</p>
<p>The stock issue is the first of its kind linking soccer and rugby outfits and is the brainchild of Chris Wright, the multi-millionaire chairman and chief executive of the music company Chrysalis who acquired the clubs for about 10 million sterling ($12.5 million) in August.</p>
<p>Wright, floating the company on London's Alternative Investment Market, is a long-standing QPR supporter and said at the launch at its Loftus Road ground in London that the flotation offered a &quot;unique sporting investment.&quot;</p>
<p>QPR, who are looking for a quick return to the English premier league following relegation last season, and Wasps, bidding to compete in rugby's new European club cup competition, both now come under the umbrella of the newly-formed Loftus Road plc, the company about to be floated.</p>
<p>But Wright emphasised that success on the pitch was vital for the future financial health of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;The two key things are that QPR are promoted to the premier league either this year or next and that Wasps finish high enough to qualify for Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New money was needed he said to lengthen players' contracts in the light of the Bosman ruling and to enable QPR manager Stewart Houston and his assistant Bruce Rioch to buy players.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clearly important that they do whatever deals they have to to get back into the premier league,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Shares will start trading at 72 pence (90 cents) valuing the company at between 25 million sterling ($31 million) and 30 million sterling ($37.5 million).</p>
<p>After debts of around four million pounds ($5 million) are paid off the company hopes to have around 10 million pounds ($12.5 million) available for ground improvements, new players and expansion of commercial activities.</p>
<p>The company hopes to take advantage of television money coming into both sports to improve corporate hospitality facilities at Loftus Road, merchandising, subscriptions, sponsorship and advertising.</p>
<p>But with negotiations over television money still continuing Wright, said it was impossible to predict how much revenue would result from any future television deal but he thought it could be between 500,000 sterling ($626,000) and one million sterling ($1.25 million).</p>
<p>Trading in the majority of shares starts on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
