<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132810" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-FRENCH COCKERELS RUFFLE BATH FEATHERS.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-FRENCH COCKERELS RUFFLE BATH FEATHERS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>English rugby club Bath have had their feathers ruffled by reports that supporters of French side Dax plan to release cockerels on to the field before the start of their European Cup match on Saturday.</p>
<p>The English champions have contacted the animal welfare group, RSPCA, for advice and are mulling over whether to employ a professional bird catcher.</p>
<p>Club press officer Ken Johnstone said on Tuesday an RSPCA chief inspector &quot;thought it would cause a lot problems for our stewards as they tried to catch them&quot;.</p>
<p>RSPCA's regional manager Jonathan Silk said: &quot;People think it is a laughing matter, seeing us and police running around trying to catch them, but we don't think it's funny.</p>
<p>&quot;If they have got through customs, then goodness knows what the cockerels have been through.&quot;</p>
<p>It has long been a French tradition to bring cockerels to international matches.</p>
<p>Dax spokesman Jean-Yves Degos said he had heard nothing of the report.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be some sort of intimidation device,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We know who the people planning to go to the match are. They will all go through a local travel agency and there's no way they can carry cockerels.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
