<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132830" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLAND'S WORLD CUP HERO CHARLTON PROUD TO BE &quot;IRISH&quot;.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLAND'S WORLD CUP HERO CHARLTON PROUD TO BE &quot;IRISH&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Peter Tozer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jack Charlton, his name written into English soccer folklore as a member of the 1966 World Cup winning team, admits he refers to only two teams as &quot;We&quot;.</p>
<p>The first is his beloved Newcastle United. He was, after all, born in the coal mining village of Ashington, only 18 miles (29kms) from their ground in the north east of England.</p>
<p>The other is the Republic of Ireland, whom he managed for 93 matches in almost 10 years until last Christmas, having guided them to previously uncharted territory: the European Championship finals of 1988 and the last eight of the World Cup in 1990.</p>
<p>He does not call England, for whom he played 35 times &quot;we&quot; nor does he say that about Leeds United despite making a record 762 cup and league appearances for them between 1953 and 1973.</p>
<p>You cannot believe that he would truly discount England, for whom he played so proudly and effectively under Sir Alf Ramsey.</p>
<p>However, he still likes mischievously to make a point about being passed over for the manager's job of his own country in 1977.</p>
<p>&quot;I was well qualified. I was told to apply and did, but never received an acknowledgement.</p>
<p>&quot;They couldn't say I wasn't an Establishment man. After all, I was an F.A. staff coach, which remember, is an appointment, not a grade,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>At 61, he has written &quot;Jack Charlton The Autobiography.&quot; His happiest moments are predictable enough: walking out of the coal mines and getting into the Leeds United team as a 17-year-old, following his illustrious brother Bobby into the England side at 29 and that World Cup victory.</p>
<p>After mixed success in charge of Middlesbrough, Sheffield Wednesday and, briefly, Newcastle, he accepted the role of managing Ireland and developed such a high profile that Pope John Paul II referred to him as The Boss.</p>
<p>Charlton took particular delight in making life difficult for England in four competitive matches -- a win and three draws -- and recalls the 1-1 draw at Wembley in 1991 as a tactical triumph.</p>
<p>&quot;We put four men on their back four and pressurised them so much they couldn't get the ball beyond 18 yards. It was my idea.</p>
<p>&quot;Later I went to a European conference and they started talking about pressure football as if it was new. I started it and never copied anyone.&quot;</p>
<p>It rankles that he has been condemned by some as an advocate of kick and rush football.</p>
<p>&quot;You do what you need to do with the people available. It's a game of opinion. Numbers don't matter. One-four-three-two or five-three-two is all a load of nonsense. It's about having people in the right place.&quot;</p>
<p>He has tackled his autobiography so conscientiously that he spent two months checking and re-checking it at his farmhouse in Yorkshire, supported by his wife Pat -- &quot;my secretary and a person I can always bounce ideas off but I don't think she's read a word of it&quot;.</p>
<p>He says: &quot;I wanted to make sure I hadn't offended too many people.&quot;</p>
<p>Which brings us to the cool relationship with brother Bobby, publicised at the time of the death of their mother Cissy this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The significant thing was his marriage in the early 1960s,&quot; writes Jack. &quot;Robert's wife, Norma, never really got on with our mother.</p>
<p>&quot;Without being boastful, I think it is fair to say that we're the most famous brothers in English football, perhaps two of the best-known brothers in the entire country...but where do we stand after all these years...what is the relationship between the brothers who played alongside each other on the greatest day for English football ? In a couple of words -- not goos. And that saddens me greatly.&quot;</p>
<p>Jack's path crossed that of the now-troubled Paul Gascoigne, &quot;a fat, 16-year-old apprentice&quot; who was under his wing at Newcastle.</p>
<p>He recalls: &quot;A likeable, pleasant lad, but what has happened recently -- sent off in disgrace for Glasgow Rangers against Ajax last week plus accusations of wife-beating in the British press -- is totally unacceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;England shouldn't drop him; somebody needs to speak to him. He's a great player and don't forget he has had to spend what should have been the most productive time of his career recovering from serious injuries.&quot;</p>
<p>Charlton has a full diary, taking in coaching and speaking in the United States, Singapore and Australia, until next May, when he will take off a summer off &quot;for the first time in 10 years.&quot;</p>
<p>Then he hopes to have celebrated Newcastle's winning the English league title. And not only does he call them &quot;we&quot; explaining &quot;when I'm watching them on TV, they're the only team I stand up for when they score.&quot;</p>
<p>England World Cup hero, Freemnan of Dublin and an Honoray Irish citizen too -- but there's no doubt he would like &quot;Jack Charlton, Geordie&quot; carved on his gravestone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
