<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13289" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Corporate America taking new view on compensation.</title>
<headline>Corporate America taking new view on compensation.</headline>
<byline>Anne Murray</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corporate America is planning major changes in employee compensation in the next few years, according to a recent study.</p>
<p>What it comes down to is this: If you're highly skilled, you'll benefit nicely. But if you're not and cannot contribute to your employer's goals, you'll be paid less.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted in late 1995 and the early part of this year by management consulting firm Towers Perrin, showed that the focus will be on an employee's overall value to the company's bottom line -- rather than how well an employee performs a specific task.</p>
<p>Presently, for example, if an accountant's job involves doing five specific tasks, he or she can expect a certain salary, said Sandra O'Neal, a Towers Perrin principal.</p>
<p>In the future, the accountant will be evaluated solely on &quot;knowledge, skill and abilities,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>In addition to using accounting skills, the accountant will also have to be creative, work well in a team, be sensitive to customer needs and set productivity goals.</p>
<p>&quot;The good news is, if you're highly skilled and have many abilities, you'll be paid more,&quot; said O'Neal.</p>
<p>&quot;The bad news is, if you're not skilled and can't contribute to a team, to customer service and the organisation's goals, you'll be paid less.&quot;</p>
<p>Of the 750 mid-to-large size corporations surveyed, 81 percent had undergone a major restructuring in the last three years, and more than two-thirds reported that productivity and profits were up as result.</p>
<p>Next on the agenda for these firms is developing a new compensation structure, and 78 percent report that they are considering a new, skills-based plan for both management and non-management employees.</p>
<p>This coming shift, O'Neal said, &quot;is not just isolated or a fad. It's an inexorable change.&quot;</p>
<p>After World War II, corporations adopted a &quot;military model&quot; creating hierarchical organisations where &quot;the concept of defined tasks worked great,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But as the economy became global, customers were more demanding and problems became more complex.</p>
<p>&quot;Multi-layers kept management at a distance from its customers,&quot; O'Neal said.</p>
<p>Now organisations must change to stay competitive.</p>
<p>O'Neal says firms will place a greater emphasis on teams and team performance in giving raises. If your team does well, you'll do well. If it doesn't do well, don't expect a raise.</p>
<p>Is this fair to an employee who can go the distance but is on a team that can't keep up?</p>
<p>&quot;That's an important question we used to ask a lot,&quot; said O'Neal. &quot;It's not a question we ask any more. The more important question is -- 'Do we have results?'&quot;</p>
<p>To get those results, 27 percent of the companies surveyed plan to eliminate base pay increases in favour of cash bonuses and incentives, such as employee and team award programmes and education.</p>
<p>Companies that can change their culture and view employees as business partners will do well, O'Neal said.</p>
<p>For example, the survey rated some participants in the survey as &quot;high-performing&quot; companies, based on their return on equity above 16 percent.</p>
<p>Those companies also said they already offer employees variable pay and business education, give their managers more control over pay decisions and celebrate employee and team success.</p>
<p>&quot;They respect employees more, they trust employees more and they value their employees more,&quot; O'Neal said.</p>
<p>&quot;The key to success at high-performance companies is engaging employees in a business partnership. It will improve a company's bottom line.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
