<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132876" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: CRICKET-REFEREE LETS OFF AZHARUDDIN AFTER CROWD VIOLENCE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-REFEREE LETS OFF AZHARUDDIN AFTER CROWD VIOLENCE.</headline>
<dateline>BANGALORE, India 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Cricket Council (ICC) referee John Reid said on Tuesday no action would be taken against India's former captain Mohammad Azharuddin, whose reaction to his dismissal in Monday's Titan Cup match provoked crowd violence.</p>
<p>Angry spectators threw stones onto the field at Bangalore after Azharuddin was visibly upset on being adjudged lbw to Australian paceman Jason Gillespie during a one-day game in the triangular tournament which India won by two wickets.</p>
<p>&quot;I've talked strongly to Azharuddin and Indian manager Madan Lal but there would be no further action,&quot; Reid told reporters after the day-night match.</p>
<p>&quot;Azharuddin's behaviour led to the incidents,&quot; he said. &quot;I've taken the entire sequence into view before deciding against any fines,&quot; Reid said.</p>
<p>The ICC code of conduct permits the match referee to impose fines and even slap suspensions on players for dissent against umpiring decisions.</p>
<p>Reid's lenient view of events was apparently influenced by Azharuddin's personal role in ensuring the resumption of play after a 20-minute interruption due to the violence.</p>
<p>The crowd threw objects on the outfield and shouted slogans against umpire S.K.Bansal as Azharuddin kept gesticulating as he walked back to the pavilion.</p>
<p>Former New Zealand captain Reid also ruled out action against Australian all-rounder Steve Waugh, who argued with the umpire after an appeal for leg before off his bowling was turned down.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been informed that it was only normal discussion,&quot; Reid said.</p>
<p>South Africa complete the Titan Cup line-up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGALORE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
