<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132800" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAL Q3 revenue gain reflects domestic unit rise.</title>
<headline>UAL Q3 revenue gain reflects domestic unit rise.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>UAL Corp, parent of United Airlines, said Tuesday that the 8.7 percent rise in operating revenues for the third quarter was due principally to an 11 percent improvement in its domestic business on a unit revenue basis.</p>
<p>Earlier, UAL reported $4.49 billion in operating revenues, up from $4.13 billion a year ago. Fully distributed earnings for the quarter, before extraordinary charges, rose to $3.58 a share from $2.53 a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We just had the best third quarter in the history of the company,&quot; John Edwardson, president, told a teleconference.  </p>
<p>Edwardson said United's unit costs, excluding special charges, rose about 3.4 percent in the third quarter. Excluding jet fuel prices increases, which was the biggest component, unit costs rose about 0.8 percent, he added.</p>
<p>He said he believes that increase in unit costs, excluding fuel prices, &quot;is favorable compared with the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Edwardson told reporters that UAL's Shuttle by United, a short-haul airline that operates on the West Coast, had a 20 percent increase in sales in the third quarter compared with a year ago. The Shuttle's yield rose 14 percent, which Edwardson said was due mostly to improved prices.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the good news is pricing,&quot; Edwardson said, adding the average Shuttle ticket price in the third quarter was $65 compared with $58 a year ago.</p>
<p>The Shuttle was profitable in the third quarter, he said.</p>
<p>Internationally, UAL's sales were flat in the third quarter, principally because of an unfavorable exchange rate between the U.S. dollar and the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>Edwardson said this unfavorable exchange rate cost UAL $80 million in sales compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;While the Pacific was a little difficult, we had great results in both the European and the Latin American marketplaces,&quot; Edwardson said.</p>
<p>UAL continues to pursue alliances with other airlines in international markets, Edwardson said. These alliances typically include joint marketing and code-share agreements.</p>
<p>He said UAL is in active discussions, individually and jointly with existing alliance partners, with about three or four airlines.</p>
<p>Edwardson said UAL is looking for partners in South America as well as at least one additional partner in the Pacific. &quot;Other than that, I don't want to be too specific,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
