<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132879" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA SIGCAU ORDERS AFFIRMATIVE ACTION AT DENEL.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA SIGCAU ORDERS AFFIRMATIVE ACTION AT DENEL.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Public Enterprises Minister Stella Sigcau said on Tuesday that arms manufacturer Denel (Pty) Ltd should hasten its affirmative action programme to reflect South Africa's black dominated society.</p>
<p>Sigcau, addressing a parliamentary portfolio committee on defence, told MPs that two years after white rule was scrapped the parastatal still reflected a white bias.</p>
<p>&quot;We must begin to see the shaping of an entity which must carry with it the demographics of the people of this country,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>Sigcau said she understood the low skills base in the country perpetuated by apartheid had hampered Denel's efforts at affirmative action, but instructed the company to immediately pump funds into wide-ranging education programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;We in Public Enterprises are aware that it is a specialised field. You cannot take anyone off the street and say 'go run that position'.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is high time that training starts vigorously so that our people fit in -- it is important because we are dealing with the new South Africa,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A Denel delegation, mapping out its development strategy, told MPs it had begun a fast-track recruitment programme to find suitable candidates, both in the marketplace and at tertiary institutions, and had increased its social spending to 13.6 million rand for the 1995/96 financial year.</p>
<p>Whites still outnumbered blacks at the company, Denel acknowledged. Of its 14,000 employees the number of white men on staff had however decreased over the past four years to 56 percent from 61 percent, while the percentage of black males rose to 20.8 from 18.6 percent.</p>
<p>Denel, which specialises in high-technology weaponry, civil aviation and information technology, was established as a private company in 1992 with the state as sole shareholder.</p>
<p>It reported net attributable profit after tax of 379 million rand in 1995/96 after gross revenue of 3.4 billion rand.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 252-238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
