<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132871" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-GINOLA SAYS HE STILL HAS SOMETHING TO OFFER FRANCE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GINOLA SAYS HE STILL HAS SOMETHING TO OFFER FRANCE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Ginola, who played a significant role in Newcastle's 5-0 premier league rout of Manchester United on Sunday, believes he still has something to offer France at international level.</p>
<p>But he does not rate his chances of a recall too highly.</p>
<p>&quot;For me to be recalled to the French team one day, I'm going to have to do some extraordinary things,&quot; he said in an interview published in the sports daily L'Equipe on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;They're trying to build a new team but, at 29, one can offer a lot: one has international experience...I'm more mature, more steady in my head, I analyse situations better.&quot;</p>
<p>Ginola, hurt in the past by criticism in his home country, played one of his last internationals in harrowing circumstances three years ago.</p>
<p>With France's qualification for the 1994 World Cup finals in the bag in the dying seconds of a 1-1 draw with Bulgaria in Paris in November 1993, Ginola lost posession and allowed the Bulgarians to snatch a winner and a U.S. berth at their expense.</p>
<p>Ginola, a 68th minute substitute for Jean-Pierre Papin, was blamed for giving the ball away from a free kick. He was widely criticised in his home country and has been capped only once since.</p>
<p>Ginola admitted to some difficulty in adapting to the requirements of Newcastle manager Kevin Keegan this season.</p>
<p>Keegan wanted his winger to take on defensive responsibilities given the side play with two strikers in Alan Shearer and Les Ferdinand.</p>
<p>&quot;On Friday I had a discussion with Keegan to remind him that in these last years I've given my best playing all out in attack,&quot; the former Paris Saint-Germain player said.</p>
<p>&quot;(The result was) he asked me to play my favourite role.&quot;</p>
<p>A close season offer from Barcelona that fell through and Ginola's difficulty in holding down a first team place at Newcastle earlier in the season led to suggestions he was no longer happy in the northeast of England.</p>
<p>But Ginola refutes such suggestions, saying his relations with Keegan were as good as last season.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Newcastle are ripe to become the team of the future in England,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
