<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132848" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: SOCCER-GALATASARAY ASK FIFA TO ACT OVER FILIPESCU DEAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GALATASARAY ASK FIFA TO ACT OVER FILIPESCU DEAL.</headline>
<byline>Suna Erdem</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Galatasaray have asked FIFA to authorise Romania midfielder Iulian Filipescu's transfer from Steaua Bucharest despite the Romanian champions accusing the Turks of illegally poaching the player.</p>
<p>Filipescu signed for Galatasaray last week and was presented to local reporters and fans when he arrived in Turkey.</p>
<p>But Steaua claim the $3.0 million deal is invalid as their officials were excluded from the transfer negotiations. Steaua have returned the first instalment of the fee -- $800,000 -- and say they want Filipescu back.</p>
<p>But in a letter Galatasaray wrote to FIFA general secretary Sepp Blatter on Monday and made available to Reuters on Tuesday, Galatasaray claim the deal is valid and have asked FIFA to issue the player's international clearance certificate releasing him to play for them.</p>
<p>&quot;Having paid the officially registered fee of $800,000 to Steaua Bucharest, we kindly ask ... for the release certificate of the player in order for him to play with our team immediately,&quot; said the letter, dated October 21.</p>
<p>The letter adds: &quot;Unfortunately, our efforts to find a fair solution were in vain. Our club, having the consent of Iulian Filipescu, used the `release clause' and transferred $800,000 to Steaua Bucharest on October 17, 1996, for his release. We assume the above mentioned details all conform with FIFA rules and regulations,&quot; it states.</p>
<p>Galatasaray say they met with Steaua executives twice during the negotiations, and even offered extra money and to play a friendly as part of the deal. They have also paid most of the transfer fee for a second player, forward Adrian Ilie.</p>
<p>If Filipescu does join Galatasray he would become the club's third Romanian as international skipper Gheorge Hagi also plays for them.</p>
<p>Filipescu's agent Ioan Becali said his client, who has a contract from Steuau until 1999, was free to move providing Galatasaray paid the initial sum in his first year with his new club, plus $1.0 million in the second year and $1.2 million in the third.</p>
<p>Steaua say Filipescu is still contracted to them and have written to Galatasaray demanding his return, saying he faces a ban unless he does so.</p>
<p>Galatasaray chairman, Faruk Suren, is expected to travel to Bucharest this week to try and resolve the problem.</p>
<p>Galtasaray scored an unexpected 4-2 victory over holders Paris St Germain in the European Cup Winners' Cup last week and are keen to have Filipescu to bolster their league campaign.</p>
<p>Filipescu meanwhile made what could be his last appearance for Steaua in their 1-0 European Cup Champions' League victory over Widzew Lodz of Poland last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
