<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132888" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: US, EU WARNS SLOVAKIA ON DEMOCRATIC REFORMS.</title>
<headline>US, EU WARNS SLOVAKIA ON DEMOCRATIC REFORMS.</headline>
<byline>Peter Laca</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and European Union ambassadors to Bratislava on Tuesday both warned Slovakia that foot dragging on democratic reforms could delay the country's membership in western organisations.</p>
<p>In separate, stinging criticisms of Slovak post-communist behaviour, U.S. Ambassador Ralph Johnson and EU Ambassador Georgious Zavvos, struck a common theme saying there was much work to do for Slovakia to earn a place in western structures.</p>
<p>Johnson said in a speech to the Slovak Foreign Policy Association that ending the investigation into the kidnapping of the president's son and the death of a former policeman involved in the case would damage attempts to join organisations like NATO and the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;We make no judgments about the outcome of these investigations, but abandoning them would in our view be very damaging to Slovakia's candidacy (to join western structures),&quot; Johnson said in an address in the eastern city of Presov according to a text released by the embassy in Bratislava.</p>
<p>Michal Kovac Junior, adult son of President Michal Kovac, was kidnapped in August 1995, when he was bundled into the boot of his car and dumped outside a police station in Austria.</p>
<p>Following the sacking of two detectives who said their investigations led them to suspect the involvement of the state secrete service (SIS) in Kovac Junior's abduction, a third investigator in May adjourned the case due to lack of evidence.</p>
<p>Former policeman Robert Remias was killed in a car blast this spring after acting as the only contact between a former SIS member who said the abduction was organised by Ivan Lexa, the SIS head and close ally of Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar who is locked in a bitter political feud with the president.</p>
<p>The police also adjourned the case of Remias death due to lack of evidence, after it said the blast had been caused by an unspecified explosive set up inside the car.</p>
<p>In his address, Johnson repeated U.S. concerns a number of Slovak laws and proposals &quot;which do not conform to generally accepted notions of a deomcratic society&quot;.</p>
<p>He listed as troublesome restrictive media laws, a law governing univesities, and a language law widely seen as discriminatory to the country's large Hungarian minority.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the EU's Zavvos told a town meeting in Stupava, near Bratislava that Slovakia still had &quot;much work to be done and in this task there can be no delay.&quot;</p>
<p>Referring to EU plans to recruit members from central and eastern Europe, he said: &quot;The clock is ticking towards the final opinions, negotiations and decisions, which will begin as soon as late 1997. Slovakia must seize the messages and act.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is only through its own efforts in the field of democracy, as in the economy, that Slovakia can hope to join the EU,&quot; he said according to the text released by the EU's Bratislava office.</p>
<p>Slovakia applied formally for EU membership in June 1995. But the EU and United States have expressed concerns about the development of democracy since the populist Meciar was returned to power in 1994.</p>
<p>Slovakia insists that it should be in the earliest expansions of the EU and NATO.</p>
<p>Meciar's coalition, which includes junior partners from the far right and left, is embroiled in a series of disputes with Kovac, the opposition, leaders of the Hungarian minority, the independent media and the medical and acting professions.</p>
<p>Slovakia was once among the favourites for early EU and NATO entry alongside Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary.</p>
<p>But this has been thrown into doubt since Meciar launched a campaign to force President Kovac to resign, apparently in revenge for a parliamentary no-confidence vote which temporarily removed the prime minister from power in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
