<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132831" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TENNIS-FRAZIER, RAYMOND ADVANCE IN QUEBEC CITY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-FRAZIER, RAYMOND ADVANCE IN QUEBEC CITY.</headline>
<dateline>QUEBEC CITY 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seeded Americans Amy Frazier and Lisa Raymond posted straight sets wins on Monday to advance to the second round of the Bell Challenge tennis tournament.</p>
<p>The third-seeded Frazier downed Spanish Fed Cup player Virginia Ruano-Pascual 6-3 6-2, while fifth seed Raymond ousted Andrea Glass of Germany 6-3 6-4.</p>
<p>Sixth-seeded Argentine Florencia Labat had a tougher time before taking her place in the second round. Labat dropped the first set before taking control for a 4-6 6-1 6-4 win over American qualifier Angela Lettiere.</p>
<p>Canadian qualifier Jana Nejedly gave the home crowd something to cheer about when she pulled off the lone opening-day upset by bouncing eighth-seeded American Lindsay Lee 6-2 6-3.</p>
<p>The 26th-ranked Frazier said she felt right at home on the fast indoor Uniturf surface at the Club Avantage against the Spaniard who was raised on clay courts.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I played really well because she's a good player,&quot; said Frazier after eliminating the 86th-ranked Ruano-Pascual. &quot;I grew up on indoor courts in Michigan so I really like the surface.&quot;</p>
<p>Raymond, a quarter-finalist here last year, next faces her close friend Debbie Graham, who eased past Canadian Maureen Drake 6-3 6-2.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time you step on the court you put your friendship aside,&quot; said the 44th-ranked Raymond said. &quot;You're friends before and you're friends after.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUEBEC CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
