<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132858" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-MADDUX, MCGRIFF LEAD BRAVES TO 2-0 WORLD SERIES LEAD.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-MADDUX, MCGRIFF LEAD BRAVES TO 2-0 WORLD SERIES LEAD.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greg Maddux yielded just six hits in eight scoreless innings and Fred McGriff drove in three runs as the Atlanta Braves blanked the New York Yankees 4-0 on Monday to take home a two games to none lead in the World Series.</p>
<p>The Braves head back to Atlanta for Games 3, 4, and if necessary 5 in the best-of-seven series, having outscored New York 16-1 in their two wins in Yankee Stadium.</p>
<p>Maddux, the winner of four consecutive Cy Young awards as the National League's best pitcher, threw just 82 pitches, 62 of them strikes, walked none and struck out two in facing only four batters above the minimum in eight innings.</p>
<p>Twenty of his 24 outs came in the infield, including two double plays. One was caught stealing and only one flied out in the outfield.</p>
<p>&quot;He's something, he really is,&quot; said New York manager Joe Torre. &quot;He has his way with you.&quot;</p>
<p>Maddux was busy in the field, too. Through four innings, the winner of seven consecutive Gold Gloves had a hand in seven of the first 12 outs, five hit to him and two thrown to him covering first.</p>
<p>Maddux wiggled out of several jams, his most serious in the sixth inning when he yielded no-out singles to Derek Jeter and Tim Raines.</p>
<p>But he then got Wade Boggs to ground into a double play and struck out Bernie Williams, the American League Championship Series Most Valuable Player who remains hitless in the World Series, to leave Jeter languishing at third.</p>
<p>Mark Wohlers finished up, yielding one Cecil Fielder single after striking out Williams and Tino Martinez, then whiffing Paul O'Neill to end the game.</p>
<p>McGriff singled in Mark Lemke in the first and Marquis Grissom in the third and hit a sacrifice fly in the fifth to again score Lemke as the Braves went up 3-0. Atlanta's fourth run came on a Grissom single that brought home Terry Pendleton.</p>
<p>McGriff set a major league record with 15 runs batted in during one post-season. He had three RBI in the division series, seven in the National League Championship Series and five so far in the World Series. The previous record of 14 was set by the Yankees' Reggie Jackson in 1978.</p>
<p>Braves pitching has allowed one run and 12 hits in its last 27 innings in World Series play dating back to the first inning of Game 6 last season. The Braves have a remarkable 1.43 earned run average (17 earned runs/107 innings pitched) in their 12 games this post-season.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't see pitching like this every day,&quot; said Torre. &quot;Unfortunately we have seen it every day.&quot;</p>
<p>Jimmy Key took the loss, yielding all four runs on 10 hits in six innings. Three Yankee relievers held the Braves hitless for the last three innings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
