<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132837" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: SOCCER-POZNAN CLOSES LECH STADIUM OVER HOOLIGANISM.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-POZNAN CLOSES LECH STADIUM OVER HOOLIGANISM.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governor of the western Polish city of Poznan has closed Lech soccer stadium until the end of the season in reaction to disturbances by fans there at the weekend, PAP news agency reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It said the closure would apply until June next year.</p>
<p>Lech Poznan fans went on a rampage in the stadium on Saturday, tearing up seats and hurling them at police, after their team lost 0-2 to Legia Warsaw in a first division game.</p>
<p>Police responded with water-cannon and 47 police and 10 other people were injured in the ensuing battle.</p>
<p>City governor Wlodzimierz Lecki warned the club last year, after disturbances following another match with Legia, that he would shut the stadium if there was any repetition of the hooliganism.</p>
<p>Lech director Andrzej Menke told PAP he would not comment until he had a copy of the governor's decision. The side now lies fifth in Poland's first division and is not involved in any European competition this season.</p>
<p>Michal Listkiewicz, secretary general of the Polish Soccer Association, had said Lech Poznan could be fined up to 50,000 zlotys (about $18,500) and have its stadium closed for two matches, but Lecki's decision went much further.</p>
<p>The governor of the southwestern province of Wroclaw was earlier reported by PAP to be considering closing down first division club Slask Wroclaw's stadium following clashes on Saturday between local fans and those of visiting Widzew Lodz.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
