<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132823" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-BARRICHELLO SIGNS THREE-YEAR DEAL WITH STEWART. [corrected 20:43 gmt]</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-BARRICHELLO SIGNS THREE-YEAR DEAL WITH STEWART. [corrected 20:43 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Stewart Grand Prix team said on Tuesday they had signed Brazilian Rubens Barrichello to a three-year contract but added they did not expect him to bring them overnight success.</p>
<p>The 24-year-old Brazilian will team up with Denmark's Jan Magnussen at the Scottish Ford-powered team after four years with Jordan.</p>
<p>&quot;We are delighted to have Rubens with us from the start,&quot; said team head and former world champion Jackie Stewart.</p>
<p>&quot;We said from the outset that we want a driver with Formula One experience alongside a young, up-and-coming talent.</p>
<p>&quot;Rubens brings the experience to complement the raw talent of Jan, but he is still young himself and can continue to develop as he helps us to build the team.</p>
<p>&quot;We invested six million pounds sterling ($9.60 million) this year in technology alone,&quot; Stewart said, adding that total investment would be between 20 million and 25 million pounds ($32 to $40 million). (Corrects dollar conversion)</p>
<p>&quot;Our car will be the first ever in Formula One to be produced exclusively by computer design.&quot;</p>
<p>Stewart said the team's first car would be ready by mid-December and tested early next year but conceded Grand Prix success could be a long time coming.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't expect to be successful too soon. I am a Scottish man. I am conservative. We want to be competitive in a five-year period,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Barrichello added: &quot;The kind of opportunity I have been presented with by Stewart-Ford doesn't come along every day, the chance to build a new Formula One team from the ground up.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Magnussen, 23, agreed to a four-year contract with the team who will make their debut in the 1997 season opener in Australia next March.</p>
<p>Barrichello's replacement at Jordan has yet to be announced.</p>
<p>In Portugal, German Heinz-Harald Frentzen, who takes over from world champion Damon Hill at Williams next season, had his first test drive for his new team.</p>
<p>The 29-year-old, who is still contracted to Swiss team Sauber, completed 54 laps at Portugal's Estoril circuit.</p>
<p>&quot;The important task today was to try different seat positions and a two-pedal set-up which I am not used to,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have very good impressions of the car and the team but I do not wish to give too many details away because I am still officially working with Sauber.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
