<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132853" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-YANKEE STADIUM FANS CAN'T INTIMIDATE BRAVES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKEE STADIUM FANS CAN'T INTIMIDATE BRAVES.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yankee Stadium fans have a reputation for intimidating opponents, but they were reduced to a few foolish episodes of running onto the field by the Atlanta Braves' mastery in Game 2 of the World Series on Monday.</p>
<p>With their Yankees stifled by Greg Maddux's six-hit pitching performance, the normally noisy New York fans were virtually silenced during the late innings of the 4-0 Atlanta victory.</p>
<p>Five fans bolted onto the field on separate occasions, in effect saying they saw no chance of their team winning and so they didn't mind missing the rest of the game.</p>
<p>The fans, who were not shown on television, were chased down by security guards, tackled and hauled off to police. At least one was placed in handcuffs.</p>
<p>Fans who run onto the field normally receive little more than a minor fine if they pass a search for illegal substances and a check for outstanding arrest warrants.</p>
<p>One of the more exhibitionist fans touched Atlanta left-fielder Andruw Jones, the 19-year-old from Curacao who was the hero of Game 1 with two home runs in his first two World Series at bats.</p>
<p>&quot;I was scared,&quot; said Jones. &quot;I didn't know he was there. He gave me a little tap on the butt. They warned me about the New York fans. I didn't like it at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Maddux had mixed feelings about Yankee Stadium and the fans. &quot;This is an intimidating place to pitch at times. It can get to you,&quot; he admitted. &quot;I kind of blocked it out.&quot;</p>
<p>It was jokingly suggested to Maddux that more fans had reached second base than Yankees. &quot;It was kind of scary,&quot; he said seriously. &quot;The people come on the field and you don't know what can happen.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said that warming up in the bullpen before the game had in a way made him immune to any onfield pressure. After the abuse he received from the fans around the bullpen, he said, nothing the Yankees might do on the field could shake him.</p>
<p>Overall, however, he enjoyed Yankee Stadium: &quot;I loved it. It's a great place to pitch. The hitter's got a chance if they hit it down the line and the pitcher's got a chance if they don't.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
