<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132867" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-LAMA LOOKS SET FOR TIMELY RETURN TO PSG SIDE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-LAMA LOOKS SET FOR TIMELY RETURN TO PSG SIDE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>France goalkeeper Bernard Lama, who has yet to concede a goal this season, looks set to return for his faltering club side Paris Saint-Germain on Friday after more than a month out with a knee injury.</p>
<p>Lama, who underwent surgery after damaging a cartilage saving a penalty against Cannes on September 15, trained normally with the French first division leaders on Tuesday ahead of their trip to Rennes on Friday.</p>
<p>PSG are looking to bounce back from a 4-2 defeat away to Galatasaray of Turkey in the first leg of their second round European Cup Winners' Cup tie last week and a 1-1 draw at home to defending champions Auxerre on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Parisians are six points clear of second placed Auxerre in the French first division and should beat Galatasaray at home next Wednesday in the return leg, but since Lama's injury they have conceded eight goals in league and Cup games.</p>
<p>Lama is unbeaten in nearly seven league matches, injuring his cartilage in the 84th minute against Cannes.</p>
<p>Defender Bruno N'Gotty is also fit again after a calf muscle injury. &quot;I feel fine. I have no worry when I kick and I'm ready for the trip to Rennes,&quot; said the French international.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
