<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132854" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL-OSGOOD RECORDS SHUTOUT AS DETROIT BLANKS KINGS.</title>
<headline>NHL-OSGOOD RECORDS SHUTOUT AS DETROIT BLANKS KINGS.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brendan Shanahan scored twice and Chris Osgood stopped all 19 shots the Kings sent his way as the Detroit Red Wings blanked Los Angeles 3-0 in the lone National Hockey League contest on Monday.</p>
<p>Osgood stopped five shots in the first, six in the second and nine in the third to record his 10th career shutout and second of the young NHL season, tying him with Colorado's Patrick Roy for the 1996-97 league lead.</p>
<p>&quot;Osgood deserved the shutout,&quot; said Red Wings coach Scotty Bowman. &quot;The first two periods, he did not have to do much, but he had to work for it in the third when we had some breakdowns.&quot;</p>
<p>It took just 17 seconds for Shanahan, who was acquired from the Hartford Whalers in a four-player trade October 9, to give Osgood the only goal he would need.</p>
<p>Shanahan took a pass from rookie Anders Eriksson at the top of the left circle, skated across and blasted a shot from the slot that beat Kings goaltender Stephane Fiset for his second goal of the season and first as a Red Wing.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt it would come,&quot; said the two-time 50-goal scorer of his first in a Detroit uniform. &quot;I think (the fans) were more relieved than I was. They were probably thinking, 'He's left all his goals in Hartford.'&quot;</p>
<p>Red Wings captain Steve Yzerman doubled the Detroit lead at 5:35 of the second.</p>
<p>Yzerman took a pass from Nicklas Lidstrom low in the left circle and drew Fiset towards him before putting a backhander into the Los Angeles net from a tight angle.</p>
<p>Shanahan capped the scoring just under five minutes later when he took a pass from Yzerman at the top of left circle and ripped a slap shot that banked in off the left post.</p>
<p>Greg Johnson assisted on all three goals for Detroit, which put together consecutive wins for the first time this season.</p>
<p>Fiset came up with 37 saves as the constantly attacking Red Wings produced more than double the Kings' shots on goal at 40-19.</p>
<p>But Detroit, which gave up veteran point man Paul Coffey in the Shanahan trade, continued to struggle on the powerplay. The Red Wings were 0-for-7 with the man advantage Monday and are a woeful 0-for-33 on the powerplay this season.</p>
<p>&quot;When the powerplay comes around, things are going to be even better,&quot; said Shanahan. &quot;I don't think guys have hit the point where it is frustrating yet, because it seems like we're close.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
