<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132850" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-RAIDERS BEAT CHARGERS FOR THIRD SUCCESSIVE VICTORY.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-RAIDERS BEAT CHARGERS FOR THIRD SUCCESSIVE VICTORY.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO, California 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Oakland defence limited the San Diego Chargers to a mere 29 yards rushing as the Raiders recorded their third consecutive victory, a 23-14 triumph on Monday night.</p>
<p>Cole Ford kicked his second of three field goals and Jeff Hostetler connected with Derrick Fenner on a 17-yard touchdown pass in a 10-0 third quarter that gave the Raiders a solid 20-7 lead heading into the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Oakland, which began the season with a rocky 1-4 start, raised its record to 4-4 to move one-half game behind San Diego (4-3) for third place in the AFC West.</p>
<p>San Diego's starting quarterback Stan Humphries was knocked out in the first quarter with a separated left shoulder after being tackled by Oakland's Chester McGlockton.</p>
<p>Backup Sean Salisbury was 22-of-35 for 252 yards for the Chargers, connecting with Tony Martin for touchdown passes in the first and fourth quarters.</p>
<p>But that was all the offence the Chargers could muster as a fired up Oakland defence kept San Diego off the scoreboard in the second and third quarters. It was a far cry from the Chargers' wild 40-34 win in the first meeting between the AFC West rivals last month.</p>
<p>Napolean Kaufman, who ran for 56 yards on 13 carries, scored on a 12-yard run to give Oakland a 7-0 advantage just over three minutes into the game. The Chargers responded with Martin's first touchdown, an 11-yard catch that tied the score with three seconds left in the opening quarter.</p>
<p>Ford's 36-yard field goal 3:33 into the second gave the Raiders a 10-7 halftime lead.</p>
<p>In the third quarter, Hostetler directed an 8-play, 65-yard scoring drive. He was 20-of-33 for 191 yards with one touchdown and one interception.</p>
<p>Oakland linebacker Pat Swilling later recovered a fumble by Salisbury and returned it 49 yards to set up Ford's 32-yarder that made it 20-7.</p>
<p>Salisbury's 12-yard touchdown pass to Tony Martin -- his league-leading ninth touchdown reception -- pulled the Chargers within 20-14 just under two minutes into the fourth.</p>
<p>Martin also had catches of 25 and 31 yards on the 13-play, 79-yard scoring drive.</p>
<p>Ford third field goal, a 34-yarder with 2:11 left completed the scoring.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
