<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132815" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY LEAGUE-BRITAIN CRASH TO THIRD STRAIGHT LOSS.</title>
<headline>RUGBY LEAGUE-BRITAIN CRASH TO THIRD STRAIGHT LOSS.</headline>
<dateline>WHANGAREI, New Zealand 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain crashed to a third successive loss on their rugby league tour of New Zealand when the New Zealand Maoris overwhelmed the visitors 40-28 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Britain, whose best result so far is a 22-22 draw with a Lion Red XIII in their opening match, conceded seven tries and ran in five of their own.</p>
<p>&quot;We did one or two pretty good things and one or two players showed they can play football,&quot; British coach Phil Larder said after the match.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have committed suicide again. They scored three tries from errors we made just receiving kicks. We made too many errors on our line and they punished us.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maori side led 20-18 at halftime after at one stage galloping to a 20-6 advantage.</p>
<p>New Zealand won the opening test in the three-test series 17-12 last week. The second test is in Palmerston North on Friday.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>New Zealand Maoris - David Murray, Whetu Taewa, Ricky Henry, Marlon Gardiner, Tukere Barlow, Jamie Stevens, Paul Howell, Tawera Nikau, David Pearce, Mathew Sturm, Paul Rauhihi, Sonny Whakarau, Gavin Hill. Substitutes: John Farrar, Jason Walker, Neville Ramsay, George Milner.</p>
<p>Britain - Steve Prescott, Jonathan Roper, Barrie-Jon Mather, Tulsen Tollett, Keith Senior, Karle Hammond, Tony Smith, Bernard Dwyer, Adrian Morley, Mick Cassidy, Brian McDermott, James Lowes, Steve Molloy. Substitutes: Nathan McAvoy, Rowland Phillips, David Bradbury, Neil Harmon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WHANGAREI, New Zealand"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
