<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13284" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu, Weizman consult on Arafat invitation.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu, Weizman consult on Arafat invitation.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli President Ezer Weizman, weighing a possible meeting with Yasser Arafat, consulted on Sunday with Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Weizman and Netanyahu met at the president's official Jerusalem residence and planned to speak to the media at the end of their talks, the prime minister's spokesman said.  </p>
<p>Earlier, the director of the president's office denied a report in Israel's Yedioth Ahronoth newspaper that Weizman had already invited Arafat to his private home for talks in the coming week on the future of the Israel-PLO peace process.</p>
<p>But the official, Aryeh Shumer, said it was only fitting that Weizman and Arafat should talk after the Palestinian leader sent the Israeli president a letter which Yedioth Ahronoth reported contained an emotional appeal to save the peace proces.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Netanyahu, who is cool to meeting Arafat himself, opposed talks between Weizman and the Palestinian president.</p>
<p>After Moslem suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in February and March, Weizman called for peace efforts with the PLO to be suspended. Shumer said his current position was that the peace process must continue.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
