<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132971" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Funds flourish in Channel Islands, Dublin - survey.</title>
<headline>Funds flourish in Channel Islands, Dublin - survey.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Assets in Guernsey-based funds rose 25 percent in the 12 months to end-August 1996, while Jersey funds were up 34 percent and Dublin fund assets rocketed 65 percent, according to three new directories on Europe's offshore fund industry published by Fitzrovia International Ltd.</p>
<p>The U.K.-based fund consultancy issued the three new guides this week, following on a previous one focusing on Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Fitzrovia said pure Jersey-domiciled investment funds rose 44 percent to $34.6 billion. Funds domiciled elsewhere may be serviced in Jersey but are not included in this figure.</p>
<p>The guide also offers a first glimpse of the 100 private schemes operating under Jersey's Control of Borrowing Order (COBO) law. They are estimated to have some 111 subfunds containing $8.7 billion in total net assets.</p>
<p>COBO schemes do not require permits from Jersey's regulator and are therefore &quot;well below the horizon in terms of public scrutiny, although they represent a significant part of Jersey's fund activities&quot; Fitzrovia said.</p>
<p>Managing director Paul Moulton said the analysis was the first to provide an accurate comparison with Guernsey funds, where private COBO schemes are automatically included in publicly released figures.</p>
<p>&quot;Jersey's fund sector has seven percent fewer fund numbers but is 90 percent larger than Guernsey's in terms of assets within those funds,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>Guernsey is making a name servicing non-domiciled funds, with assets in this sector rising 72 percent in the 12 months to end-August to $5.5 billion.</p>
<p>Moulton said that despite the move to Dublin of Lazards, one of the island's largest promotors and service providers, Guernsey &quot;has managed to show a healthy increase both in number of funds and assets under management&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Guernsey's local fund industry appears to have capitalised on several valuable market niches, including closed end, emerging market and venture capital funds, all of which require greater specialisation and expertise than more regular &quot;vanilla-type' funds,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The findings of the Dublin guide showed UCITS funds, which can be marketed freely through the European Union, accounted for 58 percent of all assets and 48 percent of all fund numbers.</p>
<p>Unit trusts and investment companies each accounted for 25 percent of the market.</p>
<p>Nearly half (48 percent) of all assets in Dublin funds originate from UK-based sponsors, with another 19 percent and 14 percent from the U.S. and Germany respectively.</p>
<p>Deutsche Morgan Grenfell was deemed the most successful promoter over the 12 months to September 2, 1996, increasing its market share of total assets from nine percent to 15 percent, even as the market grew by 65 percent. Five of the 10 largest Dublin-domiciled funds are from the DMG stable.</p>
<p>Fitzrovia said the Bank of Ireland has pipped Chase as the largest custodian out of 19 by market share, with assets under custody up by 67 percent to $7.2 billion.</p>
<p>KPMG is the largest auditor in terms of fund assets, having displaced Coopers &amp; Lybrand, while legal advisers William Fry and Matheson Ormsby Prentice advise 83 and 40 funds respectively.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Allen, London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
