<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132981" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil slips as heating fuel shortage fears ease.</title>
<headline>Oil slips as heating fuel shortage fears ease.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices slipped on Tuesday as fears of winter heating oil shortages eased but traders were cautious about predicting the end of a rally which has added about $6 to the cost of a barrel since early August.</p>
<p>London December futures for international benchmark Brent crude lost 37 cents to trade at $24.27 a barrel by 1525 GMT. Last week, Brent hit a post-Gulf War high of $25.06.</p>
<p>Oil traders said industry attempts to relieve a prompt shortage of heating fuel in the northeast United States, including opening extra pipeline capacity and maximising production, were drawing the rally's sting.</p>
<p>But weekly inventory data, due to be released later on Tuesday, would hold the key to short-term market direction, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Attempts are being made to tackle the stock issue and we will have to wait and see how this reflects in inventories,&quot; said brokers GNI in a daily report.</p>
<p>Total U.S. stocks of middle distillates, which consist largely of heating oil and diesel, were 17.7 million barrels below year-ago levels at October 11.</p>
<p>After a meeting last week, two U.S. refiners said they would maximise distillate output and late on Monday, Colonial Pipeline said it was opening its gasoline line from the Gulf coast to the northeast to distillate shipments for at least 40 days.</p>
<p>A Colonial spokesman said he had received a surge in distillate shipping orders since Friday's meeting between the government and oil companies about the parlous stock situation.</p>
<p>&quot;The Colonial pipe story implies potential for a build in inventories and should take the steam out of heat(ing oil prices in the U.S.),&quot; said brokers Prudential-Bache Ltd.</p>
<p>Traders said a spell of relatively warm weather in Europe was also reducing fears of a shortage of heating oil this winter but they were unwilling to rule out further price gains.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a general reluctance to sell the markets right now... U.S. refiners have been stepping up distillate production of late, although the market may yet have to cling to hopes of a relatively mild winter in order to avoid price spikes,&quot; GNI said.</p>
<p>European middle distillate inventories are running some 10.6 percent below year-earlier levels even though refineries on both sides of the Atlantic are running flat out to build stocks.</p>
<p>The recent torrid rally in world crude prices claimed a casualty on Tuesday as Turkey's private Atas oil refinery said it would cease production from Wednesday due to increasing losses exacerbated by the squeeze on margins.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last few months the international price of crude oil has risen significantly and the Turkish lira has continued to depreciate steadily against the dollar,&quot; said a statement released by Atas owners Mobil, Shell, British Petroleum and Turkish Marmara Petrol.</p>
<p>Mobil's general manager in Turkey Ertugrul Tuncer told reporters that a 40 percent increase in refined product prices could end the refinery's losses.</p>
<p>State-owned Tupras, which controls 86 percent of domestic production, raised prices by seven percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					   Oct 21	 Oct 21</p>
<p>					 (1525 GMT)    (close)</p>
<p> Dated Brent			   $24.97	 $25.07</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Dec)  $24.27	 $24.65</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Nov) $25.52	 $25.92</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
