<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132977" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British explorer to join Antarctic solo race.</title>
<headline>British explorer to join Antarctic solo race.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British explorer Sir Ranulph Fiennes set off from Britain on Tuesday to join a race to become the first man to cross the Antarctic on foot alone and without any material backup.</p>
<p>Fiennes, 53, who aims to raise three million pounds ($4.5 milion) in aid of cancer research, will compete against four others, including Poland's Marek Kaminski.</p>
<p>In 1995, Kaminski became the first person ever to walk to both the North and South poles in a single year.</p>
<p>Two Norwegians and a Swiss will also join in the race across 1,800 miles (3,000 kilometre) of frozen wilderness, which starts on November 1 from Berkner Island, a part of Antarctica which lies off the southern coast of Chile.</p>
<p>Fiennes, a former member of the Special Air Service elite commando unit, will have to drag 500 lb (227 kg) of supplies and equipment on a sledge in temperatures as low as -20C (-4F).</p>
<p>&quot;I can only liken it to towing a legless bathtub filled with three large men over 1,800 miles of sand dunes,&quot; Fiennes said.</p>
<p>The journey is expected to take nearly three months.</p>
<p>Fiennes and a companion made a similar trek across Antartica in 1993, during which he lost a third of his bodyweight and nearly lost some toes due to frostbite.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AARCT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
