<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132948" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dirty tanker chartering picks up after slow start.</title>
<headline>Dirty tanker chartering picks up after slow start.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dirty tanker chartering activity picked up on Tuesday after Monday's slow start.</p>
<p>Brokers said business in most regions was fairly active with hefty VLCC trade from the Middle East Gulf to Asia.</p>
<p>However, rates for voyages to Singapore and Japan were little changed with South Korean desitnations enjoying the bulk of the business. VLCCs to South Korea were booked at rates between W47 and up to W55 later in the day. Freight to Singapore was assessed around W47.5 and to Japan around W62.5 although the latter was largely notional with no voyages to Japan booked recently.</p>
<p>A ULCC was booked to UKC at W49 and VLCCs held W52.  </p>
<p>Aframax tonnage was fairly busy in the Asia/Pacific region with Indonesia to Australia taking W127.5 and Wandu to Japan W130. Brazilian refiner Petrobras also booked a VLCC from Ras Ias to Brazil paying W52.5.</p>
<p>Rates for Aframax tonnage in the Mediterranean also held firm with good demand seen for cross Med voyages but levels for Suezmax vessels appeared under pressure with a million barrels booked by a French major from Sidi Kreir to Lavera at W80 compared with W92.5 late last week.</p>
<p>Inter UK/Cont activity was still fairly slow after last week's active demand and rates were a touch softer at W137.5.  </p>
<p>ULCC and VLCC vessels remained out of favour with few players seen looking to arbitrage crude transatlantic, but Aframax tonnage continued to find some trade.</p>
<p>Rates for Inter-UK/Cont voyages were slightly weaker with W137.5 paid for 80,000 tonnes from Mongstad to UKC and a Suezmax vessel taking W107.5 for a voyage from Sture to the Med.</p>
<p>Transatlantic activity from West Africa was also slow with most October requirements covered. Some trade was seen to UKC and the Med with a ULCC taking W70 for a voyage with UKC-Med options.</p>
<p>-- Colin Wooster, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7456</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
