<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132998" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY LEAGUE - NZ Maoris want World Cup spot after win.</title>
<headline>RUGBY LEAGUE - NZ Maoris want World Cup spot after win.</headline>
<dateline>WHANGAREI 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Maori officials will use last night's historic 40-28 win over the British Lions in Whangarei to push for inclusion in the 1998 rugby league World Cup, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>With the win, the Maori team completed an unbeaten international season having beaten Tonga, Western Samoa and Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>It was also their first victory over the Lions in 86 years and 11 meetings.  </p>
<p>It was not a poor Lions side they beat either. Instead, they outplayed a side that showed improvement in their ball handling from recent tour matches, and a great deal of commitment.</p>
<p>The seven-tries-to-five win was a fair reflection of the discipline, flair and attacking style employed by the Maori team under the leadership of captain Tawera Nikau, who was in majestic form last night.</p>
<p>Both Nikau and coach Cameron Bell, who already had a win over Great Britain under his belt from his time in charge of Auckland last decade, did not hesitate to push for the New Zealand Maori team's inclusion in the next World Cup, which will be held in Australasia.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a bone of contention. I think we're good enough, I think we'd add a bit more colour to the competition,&quot; Bell said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been around for 80 years and my thinking is that we deserve a go in the World Cup.</p>
<p>&quot;This year we've beaten Tonga, Samoa, Papua New Guinea and now Great Britain, so surely that gives us some sort of lever through the front door for the World Cup.&quot;</p>
<p>Nikau was just as forthright.</p>
<p>&quot;I think definitely we should be there at the World Cup; we've shown that now,&quot; Nikau said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Surely we have a valid case to be included in the World Cup.&quot;</p>
<p>He was delighted to be the first New Zealand Maori captain to lead his team to victory over the British.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a great honour for me to lead the Maori team and to be in charge of our people in winning against the British is just a tremendous and fantastic thing.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maori led the entertaining and fiesty encounter 20-18 at halftime and it wasn't until the final minute that they were assured of the win when Auckland Warriors fullback David Murray scored after chasing a long kick into the in-goal and diving on it ahead of the defence.</p>
<p>Murray score two of his team's seven tries while for the Lions, Junior Great Britain player Nathan McAvoy and stand off Karle Hammond made a strong push for test selection with convincing performances.</p>
<p>Bell was personally delighted with his success.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been a bit fortunate, I'm probably being a bit greedy with a second win over Great Britain, I never thought I'd get a second one,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His counterpart, Phil Larder was again a disappointed man.  </p>
<p>&quot;They scored three tries from errors on just receiving the kick,&quot; Larder said.</p>
<p>&quot;We did one or two good things, we had one or two players who showed they could play football, but we just committed suicide in the end.</p>
<p>&quot;We made far too many errors in their line and they punished us.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought they would be good and they were.&quot;</p>
<p>The mid-week touring squad now rejoins the British test squad in Palmerston North tomorrow for Friday night's second test.  </p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TONGA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WSOMOA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WHANGAREI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
