<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132927" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: One million children abused in Britain - report.</title>
<headline>One million children abused in Britain - report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least one million children in Britain each year are victims of child abuse, a commission said in a report published on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The National Commission of Inquiry into the Prevention of Child Abuse which spent two years researching its report said abuse was preventable but a culture change was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;Preventing child abuse is in everyone's interest and must be everyone's responsibility,&quot; Christopher Cloke, secretary to the commission, told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We can no longer afford to overlook the tragic toll which child abuse takes upon our society; a universal commitment to taking action is required.&quot;</p>
<p>The commission, which compiled evidence from more than 10,000 people plus 1,000 survivors of abuse, estimated more than one billion pounds ($1.6 billion) is spent each year on treating victims of child abuse.</p>
<p>It described abuse as &quot;anything which individuals, institutions, or processes do or fail to do, which directly or indirectly harms children, or damages their prospects...&quot; and said people must act if they suspect a child is being harmed.</p>
<p>&quot;We will never be able to prevent abuse wholly. But much of it can be prevented. This depends on the effort of imagination and will on behalf of the whole of the country,&quot; said Lord Williams who headed the commission.</p>
<p>Research by the group, which was set up by children's charities, found that many had suffered sexual abuse but very few had told anyone about it during their childhood.</p>
<p>The commission, which recommended 85 ways to help prevent child abuse, urged the government to appoint a minister for children and said money should be used for preventative services.</p>
<p>The report said the law should be changed to give children the same protection against assault as adults. Teachers should be educated to help spot the signs of abuse and people should be given lesson in parenting skills.</p>
<p>The commission also called for a campaign to raise public awareness of the problem of child abuse. ($1=.6253 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
