<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132918" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-New products boost SmithKline profits.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-New products boost SmithKline profits.</headline>
<byline>Hans de Jongh</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo-American drugs giant SmithKline Beecham Plc on Tuesday reported a 20 percent increase in third-quarter profit, boosted by new products and a strong performance in Northern America.</p>
<p>Pretax profits climbed to 374 million pounds ($468.3 million) from 312 million, coming in at the higher end of analyst forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a great success in our new product sales,&quot; SmithKline chief executive Jan Leschly said, pointing to the &quot;outstanding performance&quot; of anti-depressant drug Seroxat/Paxil.</p>
<p>The product saw worldwide sales rise by 54 percent to 189 million pounds over the period.</p>
<p>Antibiotic Augmentin, another one of the company's best-selling drugs, posted a sales increase of nine percent to 290 million pounds and raised its market share in both Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>Overall, group sales grew 15 percent to 2.0 billion pounds, led by an 80 percent volume rise in prescription drugs and a 33 percent rise in Northern America.</p>
<p>&quot;This quarter was really extraordinary in terms of sales growth,&quot; Leschly said.</p>
<p>Operating margins in the third quarter had been held, despite a 25 percent rise in spending on research and development, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;SmithKline's shape is okay. The most encouraging thing is that the decent pharmaceutical sales growth is reflected in profits,&quot; said Paul Diggle at broker SocGen.</p>
<p>The company plans to cut debt levels in coming years, but Leschly said the drive would not prevent the drugs firm from making an aquisition if the right opportunity came along.</p>
<p>&quot;We can reduce capital expenditure; we can improve our free cash flow and thereby will be able to reduce our debt levels,&quot; he said. &quot;On the other hand we are not too concerned (about the debt level).&quot;</p>
<p>SmithKline's gearing, or debt-to-equity ratio, of 79 percent compares with a group target of 50 percent.</p>
<p>Leschly said SmithKline was always interested in any deals that would boost its new product range, but he stressed the firm was in no rush to buy.</p>
<p>&quot;We always look for new opportunities for new products,&quot; he said. &quot;We are, however, in the fortunate situation that we don't need to do anything.&quot;</p>
<p>Unlike drugs rival Glaxo Wellcome, Leschly said he saw the current wave of mergers and acquisitions in the industry continuing unabated.</p>
<p>&quot;As always there will be companies looking for opportunities to get cost savings through mergers because the market is very competitive,&quot; saids Leschly, pointing at reforms in Europe and Northern America aimed at reducing government health care spending.</p>
<p>SmithKline shares were 2-1/2p higher at 796p by 1515 GMT having earlier peaked at 805. ($1=.7986 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
