<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132988" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gazprom opens way for more foreign money in Russia.</title>
<headline>Gazprom opens way for more foreign money in Russia.</headline>
<byline>David Chance</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Success for energy giant RAO Gazprom in international markets paves the way for more foreign money to enter Russia, but investors say that companies will be judged on merit and there will not be an indiscriminate rush.</p>
<p>&quot;It is natural for people to look at the rest of the market, but what we found with Gazprom is that most investors were making fundamental investment decisions based on the company,&quot; said John-Paul Smith, Russia analyst at joint global coordinator for the issue Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>On Monday, Gazprom's $373.3 million issue saw applications for five times that amount, which means up to $1.0 billion of foreign money was disappointed and could be looking at other investments in Russia.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, there appeared to be a desperate scramble for Gazprom's dollar-denominated American Depositary Shares (ADS) which traded as high as $19.50 before settling back to $18.25 by mid-afternoon, but still well up on their issue price of $15.75.</p>
<p>As well as a stable management, clear accounts and a coherent strategy, Gazprom boasts closer connections to the Russian government than any other domestic company.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin used to manage the gas giant, and his political party &quot;Our Home is Russia&quot; was dubbed &quot;Our Home is Gazprom&quot; during Russia's parliamentary election.</p>
<p>But foreign investors believe that there are many other companies, which even if they cannot boast Gazprom's political clout or overseas earnings, can stand up in terms of revenue.</p>
<p>Russian electricity utility UES is in the process of putting together an international share offering of up to $350 million.</p>
<p>&quot;UES is a company of same order as Gazprom with $20 billion of consolidated sales in 1995 and it is a pure Russia play,&quot; said Kingsmill Bond, Russia fund manager at MC Securities.</p>
<p>Also in the pipeline is an international share offer from one of Russia's leading banks, Inkombank.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are looking to increase their weightings in Russia. Gazprom should not be looked at as a one-off,&quot; said Patrick Shanahan, managing director of Societe Generale European Emerging Markets, which has completed a number of successful issues this year.</p>
<p>Investors are also willing overlook Russia's turbulent polical scene, analysts say.</p>
<p>During the bookbuilding for the issue there was talk of military coups and the sacking of security supremo Alexander Lebed as well as numerous rumours that President Boris Yeltsin had died.</p>
<p>&quot;We found that while investors are aware of the politics they are now willing to look beyond changes in personalities,&quot; said Morgan Stanley's John-Paul Smith.</p>
<p>He says that the key for Russian companies to succeed in western capital markets is a set of consolidated accounts and consistent management with a clear strategy.</p>
<p>Others note that even though investors paid over three times what they could have bought Gazprom for in the local market - in return for safety, settlement and liquidity - they were still getting a good deal on any international comparison as even at $15.75 per ADS, Gazprom is valued at one percent of its western peers in terms of its reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;Gazprom is not being sold at the same price as Shell or Exxon. Given the cheapness, I am prepared to take the Russian political risk,&quot; said Kingsmill Bond of MC.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
