<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132926" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - October 29.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - October 29.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on October 29 in history.</p>
<p>1507 - Fernando Alvarez de Toledo, Duke of Alba, born. A Spanish soldier and statesman who was a tyrannical governor general of the Netherlands, he led a successful invasion of Portugal.</p>
<p>1618 - Sir Walter Raleigh, English adventurer who was a favourite of Queen Elizabeth I, was executed in London for treason.</p>
<p>1740 - James Boswell, Scottish diarist and biographer noted for his two-volume chronicle of the life of Samuel Johnson, born.</p>
<p>1787 - The first performance of Mozart's &quot;Don Giovanni&quot; took place in Prague.</p>
<p>1811 - (Jean Joseph Charles) Louis Blanc, pioneering French utopian socialist, born.</p>
<p>1814 - The first steam-powered warship, the USS Fulton, was launched at New York. It was designed by Robert Fulton.</p>
<p>1879 - Franz von Papen, German statesman and diplomat who was named chancellor in 1932 and was instrumental in helping Adolf Hitler to power in 1933, born.</p>
<p>1888 - The Constantinople Convention on Free Navigation of the Suez Canal was signed.</p>
<p>1889 - The British South Africa Company, headed by Cecil Rhodes, was granted royal charter by the British government giving it extensive powers and rights in the area which became Rhodesia.</p>
<p>1897 - Joseph Goebbels, minister of propaganda for the German Third Reich under Adolf Hitler, born.</p>
<p>1923 - Turkey became a republic under its first president, nationalist leader Kemal Ataturk.</p>
<p>1929 - Prices virtually collapsed at the New York Stock Exchange on Wall Street. The day became known as &quot;Black Tuesday&quot; and lead to the Great Depression of the 1930's.</p>
<p>1950 - King Gustav V of Sweden died and was succeeded by his son Gustav VI.</p>
<p>1956 - Israeli troops crossed the border with Egypt and swept into the Sinai peninsula toward the Suez Canal.</p>
<p>1964 - The United Republic of Tanganyika, Zanzibar and Pemba changed its name to Tanzania.</p>
<p>1972 - The Black September guerrilla group hijacked a Lufthansa Boeing 727 as it flew over Turkey and demanded the release of three colleagues still held for the massacre of Israeli athletes at the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>1973 - Klaus Altmann, wanted in France for war crimes under the name of Klaus Barbie, was released after nearly eight months in a Bolivian jail.</p>
<p>1977 - The Roman Catholic Primate of Poland, Cardinal Stefan Wyszynski, and Communist party leader Edward Gierek met officially for the first time.</p>
<p>1980 - A declaration by Communist party Vice-Chairman Deng Xiaoping that Chairman Mao made serious political mistakes during his rule was made public.</p>
<p>1982 - The trial of Lindy Chamberlain, whose baby daughter disappeared in the Australian outback in 1980, ended when she was convicted of murder. She had claimed a wild dog took the child. After several appeals she was finally pardoned in 1987.</p>
<p>1990 - Norway's centre-right government collapsed after a dispute over how far to link the economy to the European Community.</p>
<p>1995 - 289 people were killed when a crowded underground train caught fire between stations in Baku, Azerbaijan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
