<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132955" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Santander says buy Mexico Bradys, sell UMS 2026.</title>
<headline>Santander says buy Mexico Bradys, sell UMS 2026.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. brokerage Santander Investment on Tuesday recommended buying Mexico's Brady bonds and selling its 2026 global bond (UMS '26), due chiefly to an obscure warrant triggered by rising oil prices.</p>
<p>In a research note released in London, Santander analyst Julian Eisner said Mexico's Par  MX625L19=RR and Discount bonds MXFLL19=RR looked cheap against the UMS '26 -- a landmark $1.7 billion 30-year global bond which the United Mexican States launched in May.</p>
<p>&quot;Since last month, when it became increasingly likely that a Value Recovery Right payment would be made in December, the spreads between Bradys and the UMS '26 have widened by 50 to 60 basis points,&quot; Eisner said.</p>
<p>Overlooked until earlier this year when oil prices began to rise, Value Recovery Rights (VRRs) are obscure provisions within the Brady bond structure that oblige Mexico to pay out cash to Brady holders if its oil earnings rise above a certain level.</p>
<p>In addition, a rise in current and future oil prices had increased the value of the VRRs by $0.50 to $0.80, Eisner said, making the Bradys look increasingly good value.</p>
<p>A $0.50 increase translates into 20 basis points on the Par bonds, and 23 on the Discs, while $0.80 translated into 32 b.p. on the Pars and 37 on the Discs, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Adding this to the 50-60 basis points that the Bradys have widened versus the UMS '26, the effective widening is actually 80-100 basis points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For these reasons, Santander expected a correction in the spread differential between Bradys and the UMS '26, due to a rally in Bradys rather than a weakening in the Eurobond.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential return on the long Brady/short UMS '26 trade is very attractive,&quot; said Eisner, adding the transaction was particularly attractive to investors who already held the UMS '26. --Caroline Brothers, London Newsroom +44 171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
