<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13298" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Citadel prepares &quot;Hell Week&quot; for new class.</title>
<headline>Citadel prepares &quot;Hell Week&quot; for new class.</headline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, S.C. 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Citadel's class of 2000 -- including the first four women ever admitted -- spent Sunday gearing up for a pre-dawn wake up call that will launch &quot;Hell Week&quot;, a brutal indoctrination into the rigours of the previously all-male military college.</p>
<p>Joseph Trez, the commandant in charge of training, said on Sunday the four women and their 564 male classmates were getting ready with a programme of church, academic orientation, and exercise.</p>
<p>&quot;They're acting just as you'd expect fourth-classmen to act,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The state-funded Citadel changed its all-male policy this summer after the U.S. Supreme Court said a similar rule at Virginia Military Institution was unconstitutional. Last year, Shannon Faulkner was admitted to The Citadel under a federal court order, but dropped out after a week, citing stress.</p>
<p>Four of the seven women accepted this year by The Citadel enrolled Saturday: Petra Lovetinska of Washington, D.C., Jeanie Mentavlos of Charlotte, N.C., Nancy Mace of Goose Creek, S.C., and Kim Messer of Clover, S.C.</p>
<p>Bryant Butler, a senior who is the regimental commander, said on Sunday he had heard nothing but positive comments about the arrival of women on campus, and expects that to continue when the upperclassmen arrive next week.</p>
<p>&quot;You will always have that little 5 percent that will have a problem with it,&quot; he said. &quot;I look at it as another step in my development at The Citadel.&quot;</p>
<p>Monday morning, the students begin Cadre Week, known as &quot;Hell Week.&quot; The cadre, the upperclassmen responsible for training, tear them down psychologically, stripping away their individuality so they can resurrect a tight, well-honed unit.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of those here now will be totally different a year from now,&quot; said Shaun King, a senior.</p>
<p>Among the rules, Freshmen must walk in the gutters and square all corners. No fewer than 120 steps per minute is tolerated.</p>
<p>&quot;Smiling and laughing is not encouraged,&quot; said Charles Perreault, a senior.</p>
<p>The freshman &quot;knobs&quot; -- called such because their shaved head resembles a knob -- can talk only in their rooms or in class, and must always look straight ahead.</p>
<p>The spartan code means no televisions and no phones.</p>
<p>On Monday, the day begins with 5:20 a.m. reveille, 6:10 a.m. breakfast and a 7 a.m. address from Trez and Butler. The schedule says lights out at 10:30 p.m. But anyone familiar with The Citadel knows that is a ruse. Hell Week means no sleep. At some point each night, the knobs will be roused from bed to paint floors, walk the quadrangle or some other duty.</p>
<p>The attrition rate varies from year to year, Trez said. Last year, 101 left, most of them during the first two weeks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
