<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132908" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: KLM TO LAUNCH THREE NEW DESTINATIONS.</title>
<headline>KLM TO LAUNCH THREE NEW DESTINATIONS.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>KLM Royal Dutch Airlines said on Tuesday it would launch three new destinations on October 27.</p>
<p>San Juan in Puerto Rico; Baku, the capital of Azerbeijan and Bologna in Italy are the trio to be launched as KLM embarks on its winter schedule, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>Though the moves are largely driven by the tourist market, there will be considerable cargo capacity available, he said.</p>
<p>San Juan will be operated twice-weekly with an MD-11, via St.Martin. The aircraft has a capacity of around ten to 15 tons, depending on its passenger lift.</p>
<p>Cargo expected on the route includes pharmaceuticals, chemicals, footwear and electronics, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>A Boeing 767 will be deployed on the Baku route and this destination will be operated three times a week. Baku has been added because of the oil, gas and mineral industry in the area.</p>
<p>Spare parts and mining equipment for explorations in the area are likely to be the major cargo consignments.</p>
<p>Bologna, will be KLM's fifth destination in Italy and it will be operated twice-daily with a Fokker 70.</p>
<p>KLM will also increase its Atlanta flights from four to five per week from January. Taipei flights will rise to six a week.</p>
<p>Accra, in Ghana, also gets an additional frequency from December 3, bringing the service up to four times a week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
