<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13293" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole vows all-out war on drugs as &quot;moral terrorism&quot;.</title>
<headline>Dole vows all-out war on drugs as &quot;moral terrorism&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>PALOS PARK, Il. 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Campaigning within shouting distance of Chicago on the eve of the Democratic convention, Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole on Sunday vowed an all-out war on illegal drugs which he decried as the &quot;moral equivalent&quot; of terrorism.</p>
<p>Harshly attacking the White House for what he called a &quot;Don't Worry, Be Happy&quot; stance on drugs, Dole promised to deploy all resources necessary to fight drugs -- including the army, the navy, the Coast Guard, the Central Intelligence Agency and the National Guard.</p>
<p>Citing the study released last week that showed that drug abuse has doubled since President Bill Clinton took office, Dole blasted what he characterised as a &quot;Don't Worry, Be Happy&quot; attitude of the Democratic administration.</p>
<p>&quot;This president has been known not for his eloquence but his silence,&quot; he said. &quot;This administration replaced the unambiguous message of &quot;Just say no&quot; with this message: 'Just say nothing.'&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We will treat drugs for what they are -- the moral equivalent of terrorism,&quot; Dole said. &quot;The terrorism of drugs destroys our young peole and hijacks America's future.&quot;</p>
<p>Breaking with a tradition in which candidates do not venture close to their opponents' nominating conventions, Dole made the speech at a picnic and rally in a park in affluent suburbs southwest of Chicago, where the Democratic convention begins on Monday. Dole campaigns in Oregon later on Sunday, and starts a working vacation in Santa Barbara, California, on Monday.</p>
<p>In a speech that dwelt far more on stopping drug traffic than on prevention and education, Dole noted the traditional reluctance to use the military to confront domestic problems but said drugs come from abroad and are thus not only a home-grown problem.</p>
<p>He said that if elected he would call on his defence secretary and military leaders to draw up battle plans for the war on drugs, including contingency plans for interdiction along the southern U.S. border.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, one would hope that such interdiction by U.S. military forces would never need to take place.  But just as U.S. combat readiness is a deterrent to those who would challenge us in a war, so will the knowledge that all the capabilities -- I said all the capabilities -- of our federal government will be used to reduce the flow of drugs across our border if necessary,&quot;he said.</p>
<p>In an oblique reference to recent reports that some White House staffers had used drugs in the past, he said his own stance would be &quot;zero tolerance&quot; from the White House on down to every workplace and school in America.</p>
<p>&quot;In the Dole administration we're going to return to what works -- a clear and forceful policy of zero tolerance. That's zero tolerance. Zero tolerance for drug sumugglers, zero tolerance for drug pushers. Zero tolerance for drugs in the workplace and zero tolerance for illegal drugs period. Zero. Zero. Zero.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALOS PARK, Il."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
