<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132924" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Divorce can be predicted - even before knot tied.</title>
<headline>Divorce can be predicted - even before knot tied.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>An American psychologist has claimed that nine out of 10 divorces can be predicted even before the couples are married.</p>
<p>Howard Markham, a clinical psychologist at the University of Denver, told a conference of marriage guidance counsellors on Tuesday that failure to communicate, or letting small problems escalate into big ones were sure signs that the relationship was doomed to fail.</p>
<p>&quot;Conflict in relationships is inevitable. But we think if people learned to manage it, the divorce rate could be reduced by 80 to 90 percent,&quot; Markham said.</p>
<p>Some people, particularly those whose parents had divorced, were more prone to fall into the same pattern, but couples who had communication problems before tying the knot were nearly always destined to undo it.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe we can predict divorce with 90 percent accuracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Couples who are destined to divorce are more likely to hurl insults at one another and the men are more likely to withdraw. We find over time that one insult or character assassination erases five, 10 or even 20 acts of kindness in a relationship.&quot;</p>
<p>During his 20 years of research Markham found that money is the most common cause of problems in a relationship, followed by children, careers, clothes and in-laws.</p>
<p>Markham said couples having problems should take time out to listen to each other and try to solve their problems without further damaging their relationship.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
