<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13297" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chicago Seven &quot;return to scene of the crime&quot;.</title>
<headline>Chicago Seven &quot;return to scene of the crime&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The aging, worn-out warriors whose anti-Vietnam War protests convulsed the Democratic convention in 1968 returned in triumph &quot;to the scene of the crime&quot; on Sunday and were welcomed by the mayor whose father set the police on them.</p>
<p>It was a case of letting bygones be bygones on the eve of the first time in 28 years that the Democrats have dared to hold their national convention in the Midwest's largest city, so brutal was their reception the last time.</p>
<p>Mayor Richard Daley welcomed Tom Hayden, Bobby Seale, David Dellinger and other surviving members of the group known as the Chicago Seven to a three-hour reconciliation rally and songfest where the hit tunes of the protest movement were played by Bonnie Raitt, Jackson Browne and two-thirds of Crosby, Stills and Nash.</p>
<p>Moments after the fully clothed cast of &quot;Hair&quot; sang &quot;This is the dawning of the age of Aquarius,&quot; the mayor stepped to a barely lit podium not to offer an apology, but a welcome -- something his tough, no-nonsense father would never have done.</p>
<p>&quot;You are welcome today. We can't bring back Martin Luther King Jr. or Bobby Kennedy. We can't change the past, but we can learn from it ...  The challenges of today are too great to keep fighting the past,&quot; he said, referring to two heroes of the 1960s assassinated in that year, 1968.</p>
<p>The rally was sponsored by the Nation Magazine and the mayor skipped out as quickly and as quietly as he could -- long before giant images of police beating demonstrators were shown, long before haughty pictures of his father and Judge Julius Hoffman were shown.</p>
<p>The judge presided over a 5 1/2 month trial that bordered on farce when it did not actually cross that border. He ordered Seale, the rapid-speaking founder of the Black Panthers, bound and gagged because he wanted to defend himself and sentenced the other defendants and their lawyers to long prison terms for &quot;contempt of court&quot; because they broke into his comments from the bench and ridiculed him.</p>
<p>The sentences were later overturned and an official commission accused the Chicago police of staging &quot;a riot&quot; against the protesters.</p>
<p>Hayden, now a California state senator and establishment politician, joked, as did the other defendants who came back, that he was &quot;returning to the scene of the crime.&quot;</p>
<p>The defendants climbed the stage with their families as a crowd of almost 1,500 cheered what was called, &quot;family values from the Chicago conspiracy.&quot;</p>
<p>But Andrew Hoffman, 35, the son of Abbie Hoffman, the clown prince of Vietnam protests, refused to go on stage because, &quot;my father would not have done it. It would be an establishment act. I am continuing in my father's business.&quot;</p>
<p>Instead he stood outside the door, selling &quot;Chicago police&quot; t-shirts that said, &quot;We kicked your father's ass in 1968. Wait 'til you see what we do to you.&quot;</p>
<p>Abbie Hoffman and Jerry Rubin were the only two members of the group to have died. A third member, Lee Weiner, did not attend the rally because of long-standing disagreements with Hayden.</p>
<p>But Paul Krassner, a co-founder of the Youth International Movement, was at the rally explaining to reporters that there were two words he created that have entered the English language. One was &quot;Yippie&quot; for the movement that combined practical jokes with political seriousness, and &quot;soft-core pornography.&quot;</p>
<p>Krassner had testified at the trial after taking a large dose of LSD. He said he took the drug because he hoped it would make him vomit in the dock. But it didn't. &quot;Instead I gave very surreal testimony, like when I tried to remember the word Chicago,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
