<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132933" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cable &amp; Wireless on track after turbulent past.</title>
<headline>Cable &amp; Wireless on track after turbulent past.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless Plc, which merged its British operations with those of NYNEX Corp and Bell Canada International on Tuesday, is reaping the fruits of new management after a bloody boardroom row last year.</p>
<p>Current chief executive Richard Brown took over just five months ago, filling the gap left by former chief executive James Ross who was sacked by the board along with then chairman Lord Young late last year.</p>
<p>The two had acrimoniously rowed over fundamental differences in views over strategy for the company and they left the company under pressure either to focus on international partnerships or demerge parts of its diverse portfolio.</p>
<p>Brown has so far pursued the former path, signing up to a deal last month in which C&amp;W replaced British Telecommunications in a major German alliance with diversified utility RWE.</p>
<p>That alliance is seen as the main competitor to Deutsche Telekom dominance as the German market is liberalised.</p>
<p>Brown trumpeted the pace at which Tuesday's deal was completed -- in just five weeks -- saying that the companies had &quot;a common vision of what could be done and we have done it with speed and nimbleness.&quot; Brown joined the company in May from H&amp;R Block Inc, the parent company of on-line network CompuServe, where he was president and chief executive.</p>
<p>He is now in charge of a company whose operating profits have run at about 1.0 billion pounds ($1.25 billion) on sales of around five billion pounds for the past two years.</p>
<p>Brown did not rule out further international alliances for C&amp;W after Tuesday's deal.</p>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless had previously tried to link up with BT but talks broke down in March. After that, it was tipped for a tie-up with Italian state telecommunications company STET SpA.</p>
<p>In terms of share market size, C&amp;W is smaller than BT, but it was a major name in global telecommunications decades before BT took to the world stage.</p>
<p>In one of its early guises, it laid the first undersea telegraph cables across the Atlantic in the 1860s, and over a century later it laid the first private-financed transatlantic fibre optic cable, which came into service in 1989.</p>
<p>Like many British companies with a long international history, C&amp;W has built up a large but fragmented portfolio of interests, in telecoms systems, equipment and services.</p>
<p>Its jewels include a 57.5 percent stake in the fast-growing and highly-profitable Hong Kong Telecom, shares in several booming Japanese mobile telephone networks and the largest fleet of commercial cable-laying ships in the world.</p>
<p>Others are C&amp;W's extensive spread of joint ventures, in the Americas and elsewhere, and particularly the German and European alliances created last year with German utility VEBA.</p>
<p>At home, its best known assets include its 80 percent stake in Mercury Communications, set up in 1982 to compete with BT -- the former Post Office monopoly phone company.</p>
<p>C&amp;W was brought out of national ownership in the early 1980s in Conservative prime minister Margaret Thatcher's privatisation spree but the government still has a deciding &quot;golden share&quot; in Cable which gives it ultimate veto on deals.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
