<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132903" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: BOURSE CRITICIZES SWARZEDZ ACCOUNTANCY.</title>
<headline>BOURSE CRITICIZES SWARZEDZ ACCOUNTANCY.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warsaw bourse president Wieslaw Rozlucki criticized on Tuesday accounting methods in the furniture maker Swarzedz SA saying they were not up to modern standards.</p>
<p>Rozlucki commented on Swarzedz last month's results which showed a net loss of 28.5 million zlotys in September alone after the firm made large provisions for receivables as required by its auditor.</p>
<p>The total net loss of Swarzedz had thus jumped last month to 34.1 million zlotys for January-September period.</p>
<p>&quot;Let me express my concern over Swarzedz's results, which suggest poor accountancy...as far as I know it's a result of using old accountancy standards,&quot; Wieslaw Rozlucki said.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope companies will think over the ways they carry out their accountancy to avoid such situations,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Swarzedz earlier said it had been advised by its auditor Deloitte &amp; Touche to raise receivable provisions to 17 million zlotys from the previous 0.4 million, and that total provisions of 22.9 million zlotys included warranty and other claims.</p>
<p>The audit was requested by the firm's main creditors, Polish Development Bank (PBR), Bank Gdanski and Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy (PBG), which in late July agreed that Swarzedz should stop debt payments for three months.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
