<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132997" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>David Campese will become the first Australian, and only the second player in the history of rugby union, to have played 100 Test matches when he plays for the Wallabies against Italy tomorrow. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian cricket captain Mark Taylor has warned that if there is a repeat of crowd violence, which marred the one-day clash against India in Bangalore on Monday, he would not hesitate to abandon the match to protect his players. Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite a torn hamstring and selectors' efforts to get him home, Australian wicket keeper Jeff Healy will stay on tour in India. Twenty-four-year-old wicket keeper Adam Gilchrist has been chosen as a stand-in for Healy during last four matches of the trianular one-day series against India and South Africa</p>
<p>Page 24.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>On appeal to the Australian Jockey Club, racing's governing body, and after two days of legal argument in which seven stewards took the witness stand, trainer Gai Waterhouse emerged from the AJC Randwick victorious after having her training license suspended for the &quot;Gossips&quot; affair overturned. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a bid to provide a more equitable distribution of talent, Super League will introduce a player pool at the end of each season in which each club will be required to nominate a maximum of up to 23 players they wish to retain with surplus players being nominated in a pool whereby other clubs will bid for their services. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Football operations manager of the Australian Football League, Ian Collins, has warned the Sydney Cricket Ground Trust to improve the dressing room facilities for visiting AFL teams at the ground or lose future AFL finals. Facilities at the ground have ben described by Collins as simply &quot;inadequate&quot;.</p>
<p>Page 45.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>In a muddled sequence of events after Australian wicket-keeper Shane Healy strained his hamstring, in India, the Australian Cricket Board announced Healy would be returning home immediately with Western Australian gloveman Adam Hilchrist being sent to Inda as a replacement. However, in a mysterious turnaround, the ACB reversed its decision to send Healy home, allowing him to remain a team-member before the extent of his injuries are known. Page C16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Leading Sydney trainer Gai Waterhouse will concentrate on Saturday's Cox plate at Moonie Valley after yesterday winning a marathon appeal over her controversial three-month suspension by Australian Jockey Club stewards. Page C16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Football League clubs must list six players for a &quot;rookie&quot; list to be approved by the AFL Commission from next season in a bid to encourage the development of young players. The players on the list will be exempt from the clubs salary cap, and ould be able to play senior football. Page C15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>The Moonie Valley Racing Club will split the 1997 W.S. Cox Plate in two with the Moonie Valley Gold Cup, the feature event, coming under a proposal of being held on either the Saturday or Sunday, depending on the clubs decision. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian cricket captain Mark Taylor has accused former Indian Captain Mohammed Axharuddin of sparking Monday's crowd unrest, which bordered on a riot, during the game at Chinnaswamy Stadium which Australia lost by two wickets. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Carlton Australian Football League Veterans Barry Mitchell Gleeson will be among the discards who will nominate for Friday's AFL draft. Both players will be forced to take sizeable pay cuts if they are drafted. The final draft nominations will e lodged with the AFL by 2 pm today. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Rugby League's Justin Dooley from Wests and Sydney City's Peter Jorgensen have asked to dissolve their contracts with Super League. Both players were paid by Super League this year to play in the Australian Rugby League finals. After both having a successful season with the ARL-aligned clubs Dooley and Jorgensen wish to sever their Super League ties. Page 78.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The ACT Government, desperately looking for a slice of the action, has lodged a bid to host a soccer match at the 2000 Olympics. With Melbourne and Brisbane expected to host matches, Canberra and Adelaide will fight it out for the right to host some games. The ACT believes Bruce Stadium offers the most suitable facilities. Page 73.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A major row has erupted between the National Basketball League and Network Ten over the coverage of the Australian grand final series. The clash between Melbourne Tigers and Melbourne Magic has been rescheduled from Saturday to Friday night. Following Ten's progamming commitments, the match can't be broadcast live on Friday, except in Melbourne - where the match will be played. Page 72.</p>
<p>    -- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
