<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132958" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE cocoa ends off lows but still under pressure.</title>
<headline>LIFFE cocoa ends off lows but still under pressure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE cocoa futures apparently lacked the stamina to break out of well-trodden ranges on Tuesday and prices ended off the day's lows.</p>
<p>Sterling's advances in currency markets continued to occupy centre stage, luring origin sellers every time it ticked higher against other European currencies.</p>
<p>Traders said Ivory Coast, Nigeria and Cameroon were offloading cocoa on a daily basis.</p>
<p>Afternoon deals included small amounts of trade and arbitrage buying, dragging the benchmark March contract to an unchanged close at 986 stg a tonne after a morning dip to 977 stg. It narrowly escaped a test of the critical 975 support.</p>
<p>December was off four stg at the close at 956 stg and turnover totalled an unimpressive 3,648 lots on the day.</p>
<p>The Ivorian cocoa season is expected to open Wednesday or Thursday although ex-farm and freight prices have yet to be agreed.</p>
<p>Traders said it was difficult to gauge the size of the crop based on clues from initial arrivals, but weekly figures could slowly renew pressure on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not expecting a sharp fall but I think we're going to drift off until Christmas. Then we'll see a good tail of the crop,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Abidjan traders put the weekly arrivals ahead of the season at around 5,000-6,000 tonnes, with the total since the beginning of October said to be around 20,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Estimated arrivals by this time in the 1995/96 season ranged from 22,000 to 47,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>On the fundamental news front, ministers from producing countries meeting in Gabon gave their thumbs up to international plans drawn in September to cut world output by 90,000 tonnes in the next three years.</p>
<p>The plan, agreed by the International Cocoa Organization (ICCO), envisages cutting output by 15,000 tonnes in 1996/97, by 30,000 in 1997/98 and by 45,0000 in 1998/99.</p>
<p>--Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
