<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132991" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain calls on Zaire to release aid pilot.</title>
<headline>Britain calls on Zaire to release aid pilot.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain demanded on Tuesday that Zaire release immediately a British pilot who has been held in detention since July when his aircraft was found to be carrying military berets as well as refugee relief supplies.</p>
<p>The demand was made during a meeting at the Foreign Office between Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo, who is on an official visit to Britain, and Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind and overseas aid minister Lady Lynda Chalker, a Foreign Office spokesman said.</p>
<p>Captain Glen Neville-Smith has been held at a hotel since the berets were discovered in the aircraft which he had flown in with aid supplies for Rwandan and Burundi refugees in a camp at Goma in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>His three crew, one of whom is Spanish, are also being held.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely disappointed that the Zairean authorities have still not released Captain Smith...they (the British ministers) made it clear that we expect Captain Smith to be released immediately,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>There has recently been growing conflict in eastern Zaire where ethnic Tutsis from the Masisi region have been battling the Zairean army.</p>
<p>Zaire is host to more than a million members of the Hutu tribe from Rwanda and Burundi who have fled across the border following civil strife in their homelands because they fear reprisals by armies dominated by their Tutsi rivals.</p>
<p>The United Nations has sent an envoy, Ibrahim Fall, to Zaire and diplomats say the violence has serious implications for Zaire, a vast nation of 45 million people which has looked increasingly on the brink of political and economic collapse.</p>
<p>Tensions in Zaire apparently spilled over into the streets of London on Monday when protesters threw tomatoes at Kengo's motorcade. Two people were arrested.</p>
<p>No one was available at Zaire's diplomatic mission in London to comment on whether Kengo's visit was connected with the violence at home.</p>
<p>The owners of the plane flown by Neville-Smith, Liberia World Airlines, have said the berets, which were intended for the Ugandan Army, were mistakenly put on his plane.</p>
<p>But Zaire has demanded that it should pay $50,000 for the plane's release and that the charity Oxfam and the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees should each pay $20,000, Foreign Office sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
