<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132983" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper, aluminium end with modest gains.</title>
<headline>LME copper, aluminium end with modest gains.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper and aluminium prices rose on Tuesday on the London Metal Exchange (LME), helped by falling stocks, short-covering and technical buying.</p>
<p>Other base metals followed the market leaders higher, but volumes overall were routine.</p>
<p>&quot;There was one big buying order on copper which got it through $1,957 (a tonne), which in turn triggered a bit of speculative buying,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall there was not much done, although there was some physical consumer interest from the U.S. for the second quarter of 1997,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Copper stocks fell 13,075 tonnes to the lowest level since August 1995. Reaction to the sharp decline was muted, because traders expected some metal on the way to Shanghai and some copper already there to arrive back in LME warehouses again soon.</p>
<p>Bank liquidation was also cited as a factor thwarting copper's upside potential.</p>
<p>But the main talking point among floor traders on Tuesday was the arrest of Sumitomo Corp's former top copper dealer Yasuo Hamanaka for his involvement in the $2.6 billion unauthorised copper trading scandal.  </p>
<p>Sumitomo also said it had found no evidence to suggest Hamanaka manipulated copper prices, and that it had no plans to take formal legal action against foreign brokers.</p>
<p>Traders assumed many sceptics would continue to suspect that the market has been held artificially high, while foreign brokers' possible involvement in the scandal was still being investigated by UK and U.S. regulatory authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;These announcements have had no impact on the price because there is nothing really new in them,&quot; said Brandeis' Robin Bhar.</p>
<p>Three month copper futures ended the afternoon kerb close at $1,960 a tonne, up $9 from Monday's afternoon close.  </p>
<p>Aluminium rose on speculative buying, helped on its way by a fall in stocks of 2,875 tonnes. Prices ended up $15 at $1,367.</p>
<p>Lead followed the market leaders higher in a correction to recent heavy losses. The market ended $7 firmer at $732 after stocks rose 300 tonnes.</p>
<p>Nickel gained $90 to $7,160 despite a modest rise in stocks of 120 tonnes. Tin managed to rise just $10 to $5,990 after stocks rose 230 tonnes. Zinc barely budged, gaining $0.50 to $1,025 on a stock draw of 1,750 tonnes.</p>
<p>Alloy was last at $1,245 from $1,225/30. Stocks fell 320 tonnes. --Mike Collett-White, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
