<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132900" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: LITHUNANIAN POLL RESULT INSPIRES POLISH OPPOSITION.</title>
<headline>LITHUNANIAN POLL RESULT INSPIRES POLISH OPPOSITION.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish opposition politicians on Tuesday hailed the defeat of ex-communists in Lithuania's parliamentary polls as a sign of a possible swing back towards the right in the region, including their own country.</p>
<p>But the failure of the Polish minority to win parliamentary seats also aroused concern among rightists in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Poland's ex-communist President Aleksander Kwasniewski mentioned the issue as one that needed to be addressed.</p>
<p>&quot;The President hopes for good relations with the newly elected (Lithuanian) parliament in the framework of political and economic cooperation...and the question of protecting the rights of ethnic minorities,&quot; his spokesman Antoni Styrczula told reporters in Warsaw.</p>
<p>The Homeland Union party of Vytautas Landsbergis, who led Lithuania's 1990-91 independence drive, unseated the former communists of the Lithuanian Democratic Labour Party (LDLP) in a sweet revenge for its shock defeat at the polls in 1992.</p>
<p>The leftist return to power in Lithuania was followed in 1993 by the triumph of the now-ruling Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) of ex-communists in Poland, who ousted a government rooted in the pre-1989 Solidarity movement.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that just as Lithuania first showed a certain swing to the left, now this pendulum goes to the right, and that example will be followed by other countries including ours,&quot; Janusz Onyszkiewicz, a leader of Poland's centrist Union for Freedom, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Polish ex-communists disputed this view. SLD deputy Tadeusz Iwinski said the left in Lithuania had made mistakes and the pattern was not set to be repeated in countries like Hungary and Poland, which faces parliamentary polls next year.</p>
<p>However, he told Rzeczpospolita daily: &quot;The social democrats of Eastern Europe should analyse what happened in Lithuania, to avoid the mistakes made by the LDLP.&quot;</p>
<p>Attendance at Lithuania's polls was low in areas inhabited by ethnic Poles, whose parties failed to cross the new five percent threshold needed to get into parliament although they account for seven percent of the population.</p>
<p>Rightist Polish parties attacked Lithuania for failing to lower this threshold in the case of minorities.</p>
<p>Marian Pilka, head of Poland's small Christian National Union (ZChN) alleged to Gazeta Wyborcza daily that ethnic Poles already suffered discrimination in Lithuania.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of Polish representation in parliament will lead to an escalation of this repression,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Landsbergis rejected such allegations and told Poland's private Radio Zet that ethnic Lithuanians in Poland were worse off than Poles in his own country.</p>
<p>&quot;The position of Lithuanian schools (in Poland) could be improved and... the situation of the Lithuanian minority in Poland is worse than that of the Polish minority in Lithuania,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
