<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132999" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY LEAGUE - NZ Maori ready to fight fire with fire.</title>
<headline>RUGBY LEAGUE - NZ Maori ready to fight fire with fire.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tawera Nikau's New Zealand Maori team are expecting a battle royal against the touring Great Britain rugby league team in Whangarei tonight, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Nikau believes the Lions, who have not had a win in three tour games so far, will turn on a spirited performance at Lowe Walker Stadium.</p>
<p>However he promised his team would fight fire with fire in what could be a torrid encounter.  </p>
<p>&quot;They'll be hurting after the test loss and they've got players who are playing for test jerseys next Friday,&quot; Nikau, who is captaining the team, said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we've prepared well; our training runs have been fantastic and we've come together as a side pretty well.&quot;</p>
<p>Nikau said that after wins over Tonga, Western Samoa and Papua New Guinea this season, the New Zealand Maori team wanted to finish the season on a high against the British.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't here for the first two games but when we came together for the game against PNG, our goals were to make it two wins from two games at home,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We needed the run against PNG to start getting our combinations together and I think we've improved on that.&quot;</p>
<p>Nikau said he was familiar with most of the players in the Lions' side for the match.</p>
<p>&quot;I've played with and against a lot of those guys so I know what to expect from them. They've got a big pack and it means we're going to have to do our work up front first,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If our forwards can do the job then we've got the backs, like Whetu Taewa, Doc Murray and Ricky Henry, who can finish off the moves.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're ready for them, and we're going to lay it all on the line in our final outing for the season.&quot;</p>
<p>The good news for the Maori team is that young prop Paul Rauhihi, who made such a strong impression against PNG despite his heel injury, is fit and ready for action.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Maori coach Cameron Bell believes Nikau, whom he expects will get through plenty of work tonight, will eventually return to the Kiwis.</p>
<p>Bell said Nikau has made his choice (not to play for the Kiwis) and he didn't want to get involved in an issue which was between the player and the New Zealand Rugby League.  </p>
<p>&quot;But he is good enough to walk into any team in the world,&quot; Bell said.</p>
<p>&quot;He's not finished and I'm sure when the time is right we'll see him pushing for higher honours, the Kiwis and the World Cup squad possibly next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Tonight's game kicks off at 7.30 p.m.</p>
<p>Great Britain: Steve Prescott, Jonathan Roper, Barrie-Jon Mather, Tulsen Tollett, Keith Senior, Karle Hammond, Tony Smith, Bernard Dwyer, Adrian Morley, Mick Cassidy, Brian McDermott, James Lowes (captain), Steve Molloy. Reserves: Nathan McAvoy, Rowland Phillips, David Bradbury, Neil Harmon.  </p>
<p>New Zealand Maori: David Murray, Whetu Taewa, Ricky Henry, Marlon Gardiner, Tukere Barlow, Jamie Stevens, Paul Howell, Tawera Nikau (captain), David Pearce, Mathew Sturm, Paul Rauhihi, Sonny Whakarau, Gavin Hill. Reserves: John Farrar, Jason Walker, Neille Ramsay, George Milner.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
