<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132911" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British women lag behind men in average wage.</title>
<headline>British women lag behind men in average wage.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women in Britain are paid 20 percent less than men doing the same jobs despite legislation banning wage discrimination, a government report said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There can never be real equality of opportunity between the sexes when such pervasive pay distinctions exist,&quot; said Equal Opportunities Commission (EOC) chairwoman Kamlesh Bahl.</p>
<p>&quot;The pay gap is the biggest barrier to equality between women and men and is widespread and deep-seated.&quot;</p>
<p>The EOC has published a new equal pay code that explains current law and the causes relating to pay equality. The code is expected to become admissable as evidence in tribunal proceedings early in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The code will provide valuable guidance and encourage employers, whether small or large, to adopt good working practices,&quot; said Education and Employment Secretary Gillian Shephard. She will present lay a draft code of practice on equal pay to parliament next month.</p>
<p>&quot;The government fully supports the Equal Opportunities Commission's commitment to promoting equal pay between men and women,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Women in their early 20s earn 91 per cent of men's hourly pay. By the time they reach 50, this falls to 72 percent, the EOC said.</p>
<p>The picture is worse for female part-time workers who earn less than 50 per cent of the pay of men in full-time employment.</p>
<p>&quot;The major problem is the entrenched attitude that the work done by women is of lesser value than that done by men,&quot; Bahl said.</p>
<p>&quot;They can be doing a job that takes just as much skill and ability but social, economic and cultural attitudes have conspired to undervalue the tasks done by women.&quot;</p>
<p>A second survey published on Tuesday found age discrimination widespread in Britain.</p>
<p>The Employers Forum on Age found that 80 percent of 2,000 workers surveyed favoured a law against age discrimination, but fewer than 30 percent thought such a law would do any good.</p>
<p>Ruth Jarratt, Development Director of the group, said: &quot;One of the most striking points that emerges from this survey is the strong belief that people should be recruited on merit alone, and yet it is obvious that the workplace abounds in misconceptions about both young and older people's abilities.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
