<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132993" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe the next battleground for TV/phone changes.</title>
<headline>Europe the next battleground for TV/phone changes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Mainland Europe's telephone and television industries, largely immune so far from aggressive takeovers and mergers on U.S. lines, will soon experience the kind of turmoil seen in Britain, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cable and Wireless's Mercury, Videotron, Bell Cablemedia and NYNEX CableComms Group on Tuesday said they would set up an integrated telecommunications, information and entertainment service in another step towards liberalising the multimedia business in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Cable companies in Europe have generally been state or quasi-state utilities funded by taxation and by and large with capital costs not met by normal market forces,&quot; said Adam Smith, head of publications at Zenith Media.</p>
<p>But not for much longer.</p>
<p>The trigger date is January 1, 1998, when the European Union has decreed that all telecommunications monopolies must end.</p>
<p>Mainland Europeans can then expect a rush of tempting offers from companies offering cheap telephone calls, more television channels and Internet connections.</p>
<p>Often companies offering these services will be unrecognisable as traditional telephone or TV companies as differences are blurred by mergers and alliances. &quot;Deregulation in Europe should bring in market forces and TV customers will finally be able to get what they want, not what's ordained by the state utility,&quot; Zenith's Smith said.</p>
<p>&quot;Deutsche Telekom's monopoly (of the German cable system) allows it to play God and decide who gets a place on the cable delivery system,&quot; Smith said.</p>
<p>Britain's liberalised telecommunications markets have seen intense competition among cable companies which initially sought to win customers with cheap telephones.</p>
<p>Former monopoly supplier British Telecommunications has been weakened by new, mainly U.S.-controlled, cable entrants.</p>
<p>The new cable operators have already spent six billion pounds ($7.5 billion) building a national network and plan to double this before they are finished.</p>
<p>Because of this, Britain's multimedia delivery capability has more in common with the United States than continental Europe.</p>
<p>However, some industry experts wonder whether this huge spending on cable might soon be obsolete, hit by developments in high-technology digital televison delivered by satellite.</p>
<p>Satellite television's BSkyB, 40 percent owned by Rupert Murdoch's News Corp, has said it will start a digital television service next year.</p>
<p>According to Kathy Hammond of the London Business School, only minor technical problems need to be overcome before satellite-delivered services can match a cable-based system at a fraction of the infrastructure cost.</p>
<p>Companies seeking to offer Europeans entertainment in the home can take heart from a recent EU poll.</p>
<p>The poll showed more Europeans are opting for couch-bound entertainment. In 1981 the average EU citizen went to the cinema three times a year but in 1994 this had slid to 1.8 times.</p>
<p>Receipts from sales and rentals of video cassettes brought in $5.6 billion in 1994, while cinema revenue from gross box office receipts was only $3.6 billion. ($1=.7986 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
