<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13292" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton denounces Dole tax cut on train tour.</title>
<headline>Clinton denounces Dole tax cut on train tour.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>ASHLAND, Ky. 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Riding the rails to Chicago, President Bill Clinton urged Americans on Sunday to reject Republican Bob Dole's proposed across-the-board tax cut, saying it sounds good but would &quot;blow a hole&quot; in the national budget deficit and trigger economic disaster.</p>
<p>On the first day of a four-day whistle-stop train tour through middle America that will take him to the Democratic National Convention in Chicago, Clinton urged Americans to &quot;stay on the right track&quot; and give him a second four-year term.</p>
<p>His &quot;21st Century Express&quot; chugged through rolling, coal-rich Appalachian hills from its starting point at Huntington, W.Va., and came to a stop on the banks of the Ohio River in Ashland, where hundreds of people waving &quot;Clinton-Gore&quot; signs greeted him under a blazing sun.</p>
<p>There, he took dead aim at Dole's campaign pledge to give Americans a 15 percent, across-the-board tax cut that the Republican nominee says will help middle-class voters. &quot;We can't afford it,&quot; said Clinton.</p>
<p>Clinton said his own more modest tax-cut proposals are affordable and targeted toward education and first-time homebuyers and that Dole's would return America to the days of 1980s tax cuts under Republican President Ronald Reagan that led to skyrocketing annual budget deficits and a legacy of national debt.</p>
<p>&quot;You look at that train there,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;If you were on that train going to your destination, which is the 21st century, the last thing in the wide world you want to do is to make a U-turn because you heard a pretty song somewhere along the way. That's a pretty song, that big ole tax cut.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the tax cut would &quot;blow a hole in the deficit&quot; and trigger higher interest rates that would hit Americans with higher mortgage payments, credit card payments and bigger cuts in Medicare and Medicaid health insurance for the poor and elderly.</p>
<p>With Clinton was Kentucky's Democratic Gov. Paul Patton, who said his tobacco-rich state largely supported the president except for his imposition last week of strict rules on tobacco aimed at keeping young people from smoking.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. President, many of us disagree with you on tobacco, but we love you,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kentucky native Billy Ray Cyrus, a country music singer, sang the national anthem, performed his hit song &quot;Achy Breaky Heart&quot; with pro-Clinton verses substituted, and delivered his own political speech: &quot;The steel mills, the coal mines, the train tracks -- this is America.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was to enter parts of five states on his ride to Chicago. After Ashland his next stop was Chillicothe, Ohio.</p>
<p>Whistle-stop campaigning goes back over a century in America but in recent decades politicians have tried to emulate the legendary 1948 tour that Harry Truman rode to an improbable come-from-behind election.</p>
<p>Clinton hopes the train tour will generate some excitement and momentum going into Chicago and help negate a rise in the polls by Dole on the strength of the Republican convention in San Diego.</p>
<p>The president plans to make news with some policy initiatives almost every day -- anti-crime on Monday, education on Tuesday and the environment on Wednesday, to add to a string of major bill-signings last week that kept him in the public eye.</p>
<p>On his departure from Huntington, the crowd spilled off the grounds of the train station and gave an enthusiastic welcome to Clinton, his wife Hillary and daughter Chelsea as they began their journey under a cloudless blue sky.</p>
<p>The president and his immediate entourage were travelling in two vintage &quot;office cars&quot; at the tail end of the 13-car, three-engine train. Clinton's car is the Georgia 300, also named the General Polk. The luxury car frequently carried President Franklin Roosevelt to his summer vacation home in Warm Springs, Ga.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASHLAND, Ky."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
