<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132959" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MARKETS-COMMODITIES.</title>
<headline>MARKETS-COMMODITIES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain prices broke a key downside barrier on Tuesday, while coffee prices raced higher on tight supplies in the United States.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the commodity markets, industrial metals prices yawned at news that Japanese prosecutors arrested Sumitomo's former star copper trader Yasuo Hamanaka for forgery in the first arrest in the world's costliest financial scandal.</p>
<p>In Chicago, the price of wheat slipped under the key $4.00 per bushel level, continuing its steady slide since touching record highs of over $7.00 in April.</p>
<p>Prices of the nearby futures contract carved out their lowest levels since June 1995 and breached an important psychological barrier.</p>
<p>The immediate cause of concern on the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) was a hike in an estimate for Australia's 1996-97 wheat crop that was two million tonnes over the previous forcast.</p>
<p>But this was only one more indication that fears were overdone early this year of continuing shortages after global grain stocks fell to 20-year lows.</p>
<p>Crops around the world have bounced back and fresh rainfall in the US bread basket presages a bounteous harvest in 1997/98.</p>
<p>At 1100 Chicago time, wheat for December delivery on the CBOT was down 4-1/2 cents at $3.96 per bushel.</p>
<p>Corn and soybean prices were also weaker.</p>
<p>Coffee prices, however, jumped after inventories in New York fell by more than 80 percent, leaving only 5,583 60-kg bags.</p>
<p>&quot;If no more coffee is tendered for grading over the next few weeks, then it could be impossible to get enough coffee through the system to satiate the smallest of delivery demands,&quot; broker GNI said.</p>
<p>The head of the National Growers Federation in major producer Colombia warned that any sudden tightness in world supply could unleash a wave of speculative price rises.</p>
<p>Robusta coffee prices in London hit a high of $1,433 per tonne, a rise of $46, before gains were trimmed.</p>
<p>Copper prices shrugged off news that Japanese prosecutors arrested former copper trader Hamanaka, accused by Japanese conglomerate Sumitomo of losing $2.6 billion through unauthorised deals.</p>
<p>Sumitomo Corp issued a criminal complaint against its former star trader, but said it had found no evidence he had manipulated markets.</p>
<p>Copper prices -- which tumbled from a high of $2,715 per tonne in June after Sumitomo uncovered the scandal -- held to recent ranges.</p>
<p>It finished the afternoon on the London Metal Exchange, the world's centre for industrial metals trade, up $9 at $1,960, failing to challenge a key barrier of $1,970.</p>
<p>Copper stocks in LME warehouses fell on Tuesday by a substantial 13,075 tonnes, bringing the total decline since the end of August to well over 100,000 tonnes. Availability of scrap copper is also tight, but prices remain stalled.</p>
<p>Some analysts say banks which have taken over Sumitomo's positions are taking advantage of price spikes to liquidate them.</p>
<p>In other markets, gold prices marched higher, fixing at the strongest level in five weeks at $383.35 per ounce and the other precious metals followed.</p>
<p>Dealers attributed gold's gains to market players covering short positions after prices tenaciously held above the key $380 level during downside tests over the past two weeks.</p>
<p>Cocoa trimmed its losses and sugar was marginally weaker.</p>
<p>Following are some key commodity prices at 1615 GMT</p>
<p>						  Tuesday	  Monday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			   383.65	  381.75</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Dec)	    24.35	   24.56</p>
<p>(London Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)	1,960.00	1,951.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM				1,367.00	1,352.00</p>
<p>(Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Jan)	     1,427.00	1,387.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Mar)	 986.00	  986.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Dec)	  316.40	  317.40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
