<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132931" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's religious leaders call for moral society.</title>
<headline>Britain's religious leaders call for moral society.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Religious leaders in Britain have joined together and supported a campaign for a more caring and moral society launched by the widow of a headmaster knifed to death outside his school.</p>
<p>France Lawrence outlined her &quot;manifesto for the nation&quot; -- a call for a nationwide movement to banish violence, encourage children to learn civic values and promote the family -- in a full-page article in The Times newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>The leaders of Britain's Anglicans, Roman Catholics and Jews said the time was right to do something to make Britain a less violent society.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are deeply concerned about violence in our society. Broadly I think people want something to happen. I believe we can seize a particular tide and do something about it,&quot; Archbishop of Canterbury George Carey, leader of the world's 70 million Anglicans, told BBC television.</p>
<p>He referred to the killing of 16 schoolchildren by a lone gunman in Dunblane, Scotland in March and the murder of Philip Lawrence, 48, who was stabbed in December as he tried to stop a gang attack on a pupil at his London school.</p>
<p>Carey called for more stable family lives supported by parenting classes and more emphasis on the teaching of right and wrong in schools.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major and opposition politicians, aware that it will be an issue in the general election due by next May, have already endorsed Lawrence's plea.</p>
<p>But Tuesday was the first time Britain's main religious leaders spoke out.</p>
<p>Dr Jonathan Sacks, Britain's chief rabbi, called for the establishment of a royal commission on the question of teaching citizenship.</p>
<p>Cardinal Basil Hume, head of the Roman Catholic Church in Britain which issued its own document on Monday on the need for a fair society, emphasised the need to act now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
