<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132910" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Expatriates face severe test in India - report.</title>
<headline>Expatriates face severe test in India - report.</headline>
<byline>David Chance</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Expatriates working in India find doing business and living in the country very stressful, a survey by consultants Price Waterhouse showed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The report, which covered 53 multinational companies and separate interviews with 70 expatriates, painted a grim picture of life in India where foreigners are confronted with a disturbing mass of humanity, noise and traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;The report reveals that most (expatriates) have drivers and household help, but even with a cultural awareness course, most expatriates find the poverty and standards of living a real shock,&quot; Price Waterhouse said.</p>
<p>In order to escape the hurly-burly of life in India, the majority of expats seek refuge in one of the most enduring of British colonial institutions, the club.</p>
<p>&quot;Frequented by both locals as well as foreigners, the Gymkhana, Polo, Golf and Cricket clubs are are a good way to establish contacts both in and outside of the expatriate community.&quot;</p>
<p>As well as the stresses of everyday life in a country of more than 900 million people, business is fraught with difficulty.</p>
<p>&quot;Even after one year in India I can't just get on with my job. I am still involved in a huge amount of administration,&quot; one expatriate manager told Price Waterhouse.</p>
<p>India's infrastructure also presents challenges, ports and airports are jammed with cargo, roads are pushed to the limit and major cities such as Bangalore, the capital of Karnataka State in southern India, suffer lengthy power cuts.</p>
<p>In Bombay, the country's financial capital that was recently renamed Mumbai by the Mahrashtra State government, the greatest difficulty is finding accommodation at an affordable price. A one-bedroom flat costs $1,400 a month.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand currently outstrips supply and the result is rental prices on a par with, if not higher than, anywhere else in the world,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>In the capital, New Delhi, a population of nine million combined with factories and choking traffic creates a thick smog over the city.</p>
<p>&quot;The roads are crowded throughout the day, particularly during the two peak periods at the beginning and the end of the day, when a melee of buses, trucks, cars, rickshaws and animals competes for every available space on the congested roads,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Price Waterhouse said foreign companies and employees were keen to tap the potential of an economy growing at more than six percent a year.</p>
<p>&quot;The report shows that despite the difficulties, those living through the current economic changes brought about by the recent liberalisation policies are finding it extremely exciting with many opportunities to make a dynamic contribution to their company's success,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
