<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="132941" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea crude premiums slump on oversupply.</title>
<headline>North Sea crude premiums slump on oversupply.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crude premiums slumped on Tuesday as an overhang of prompt cargoes met with thinning demand from refiners, traders said.</p>
<p>December Brent recovered its early losses to trade up seven cents on the day at $24.71 per barrel, but physical premiums fell by over 10 cents in many cases.</p>
<p>An Oseberg cargo loading at the end of October traded at Dated Brent +25 cents, 13 cents below Monday's sale of a Nov 4-6 loader.</p>
<p>A Forties cargo loading on Nov 4-6 was sold at Dated +22 cents, 32 cents below Friday's traded level.</p>
<p>And Dated Brent loading Nov 6-8 fell to parity to Nov paper.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's coming off hard today and I don't know if we've seen the bottom yet,&quot; a major North Sea equity holder said.</p>
<p>One trader, who already held about five Brent cargoes, was bidding for the Nov 6-8 Brent at Nov +15 cents, but this was seen as a specific requirement and going somewhat against the recent weaker trend. The trader said he was buying for system requirements, but also kept an eye on the U.S. arbitrage.</p>
<p>Tuesday's sole Brent date was kept by Esso, dealers said.</p>
<p>The slide in premiums was not restricted to the prompt period only, as a Nov 7-9 Forties cargo traded at Dated +25 cents.  </p>
<p>Urals in the Mediterranean held around dated -60/-55 cents with 2-3 large cargoes for sale. Planned pipeline maintenance of 3-4 days at Novorossiisk was thought by some to have started on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nigeria's Qua Iboe was under some pressure with a cargo loading today heard still unsold but overall West African light crudes were balanced in a market where most refiners were already covered for the first half of November.</p>
<p>Syrian negotiations continued with the best offer at dated Brent -5 cents fob Syria while lifters held off 15 cents lower. &quot;The negotiations are very tough,' one lifter said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
