<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133000" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Rugby union-Springboks put worst foot forward.</title>
<headline>Rugby union-Springboks put worst foot forward.</headline>
<byline>Anton Ferreira</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Once united against a hostile world, Springbok rugby has imploded this season.</p>
<p>The elation of last year's World Cup triumph evaporated swiftly in the full season of professional rugby union with humiliating defeats to Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>Then as the South Africans prepared for a tour of reconstruction to Argentina, France and Wales, new coach Andre Markgraaff sparked further anguish by dropping captain Francois Pienaar.</p>
<p>Pienaar's axing was the latest in a series of calamities for the Springboks.</p>
<p>They have been criticised for failing to develop the game in the black townships and lost World Cup coach Kitch Christie and manager Morne du Plessis.</p>
<p>Strains within the team and between players and Markgraaff, who took over from the ailing Christie earlier this year, have emerged amid the recriminations accompanying the dismal Springbok display against the All Blacks in August.</p>
<p>Markgraaff dropped winger James Small for three tests, either because he went to a nightclub on the eve of a game or because he swore at team mates on the field and confronted them in the changing rooms.</p>
<p>If Markgraaff's reasons for dropping Small were never entirely clear, his reasons for dropping Pienaar are nothing short of opaque.</p>
<p>By Pienaar's own count Markgraaff gave four different reasons, the most compelling being a claim that Pienaar was out of form.</p>
<p>Pienaar's provincial side, Transvaal, failed miserably in the Super 12 competition and Pienaar himself was forced out of the August series against the All Blacks by a neck injury.</p>
<p>Number eight Gary Teichmann took over the captaincy with aplomb and Pienaar's replacement as flanker, Andre Venter, played with verve. With that combination South Africa salvaged some pride by winning the final test against New Zealand but still lost the series 2-1.</p>
<p>Former Springbok hooker Uli Schmidt backed the decision to drop Pienaar, saying the former captain should take a long rest for the sake of his own health.</p>
<p>Schmidt, a doctor, said Pienaar had suffered so many bouts of concussion that he was in danger of becoming punch drunk.</p>
<p>But Schmidt's advice may not be totally impartial. Schmidt who was among those who called for Pienaar's head last year when the World Cup captain was involved in tough negotiations over pay-for-play contracts.</p>
<p>Pienaar apparently used lucrative offers from Kerry Packer's World Rugby Corporation (WRC) to obtain a better deal for South African players from South African Rugby Union chief Louis Luyt. It emerged that Pienaar had been offered $300,000 by WRC to act as their agent.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think Pienaar will captain South Africa again,&quot; Schmidt said then in words that were echoed by a leading local rugby writer who said: &quot;Pienaar's reputation lies in tatters.&quot;</p>
<p>This opinion has not been shared by the South African public and Pienaar was carried shoulder-high from the field in triumph after Transvaal defeated arch-rivals Northern Transvaal 31-21 on Saturday to reach the Currie Cup final.</p>
<p>Luyt, who contributed to South Africa's morale problems by firing SARFU chief executive Ed Griffiths in February, was at pains to deny that the tense pay negotiations last year had anything to do with the departure of Pienaar.</p>
<p>Much of the public outcry that has greeted the dumping of Pienaar -- which has included death threats to Markgraaff -- has focused not on his ability as a flanker but on his value as a symbol of racial and national unity in sport.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela wore Pienaar's number six jersey at the World Cup award ceremony and it seemed that the combination of Pienaar, Griffiths, Christie and du Plessis would build on this to make rugby a truly national sport in South Africa.</p>
<p>But as each has left the scene, the unity movement has run out of steam.</p>
<p>In August black Finance Minister Trevor Manuel openly declared his support for New Zealand &quot;because I am not a white South African&quot;.</p>
<p>Fly-half Naas Botha, Pienaar's predecessor as captain, has called for unity and appealed to fans to put aside their anger at Markgraaff.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing for the whole of South Africa is to get behind Markgraaff and support the team because it's still the national side,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't want to support the team, then there's something wrong with South African supporters.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
