<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133045" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: 3,000 Hutu refugees flee fighting to Zaire town.</title>
<headline>3,000 Hutu refugees flee fighting to Zaire town.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 3,000 Hutu refugees streamed into the eastern Zairean town of Bukavu from camps near the battlegrounds of Uvira, a spokesman for the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The 3,000 refugees arrived last night...these are refugees coming from the most northern Uvira camps who fled on Sunday and Monday,&quot; Paul Stromberg told Reuters in the Rwandan capital Kigali. He said there were no reports of casualties.</p>
<p>Estimates of the size of the exodus from 12 refugee camps near Uvira by the border with Burundi ranged up to a quarter of a million. Some sources said they had taken to nearby mountains, others that they were heading north to Bukavu.</p>
<p>In Geneva, UNHCR spokesman Ron Redmond expressed fears for the tens of thousands of Hutu refugees, who had fled to Zaire from unrest in Rwanda and Burundi.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to all sides to step back from the brink of what now threatens to become a very real humanitarian disaster in a region that has already suffered enough,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Zaire army had been battling the Banyamulenge Tutsis largely on the high plateau above Uvira. But clashes have spread to the plains, threatening settlements and closing most of the 100 km (60-mile) road between Uvira and Bukavu.</p>
<p>Military authorities in Bukavu ordered all journalists without visas to leave. Air charter companies in the Kenyan capital Nairobi said they had been told not to take reporters to Zaire and described the airport at Bukavu as chaos.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been told that any plane carrying reporters, whether they have valid visas or not, will not be allowed into the eastern Zairean towns of Bukavu, Goma or Uvira,&quot; an official with one charter firm told Reuters.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent William Wallis and a cameraman working for Reuters Television, Mark Hoogsteyns, were jailed overnight in Bukavu after being arrested by Zairean soldiers. They were given no explanation and were released early on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A senior official of the Tutsi-dominated Rwandan government said nearly 76,000 of the refugees displaced by the new fighting were Rwandan Hutus and should &quot;stop wandering and return home&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Why don't they come here? We have spent two years trying to make them come home. Now they are on the move, we desperately hope they will come to Cyangugu,&quot; said Jean Karusisi, director of repatriation at the Rwandan rehabilitation ministry.</p>
<p>Tensions between Banyamulenge Tutsis, who arrived from Rwanda about 200 years ago, and native Zaireans were exacerbated by the 1994 massacres of Tutsis and Hutu moderates in Rwanda by militant Hutus. After Tutsis took power in a subsequent civil war, many Hutus became refugees in Zaire.</p>
<p>A World Food Programme plane was expected in Uvira to evacuate 54 U.N. and aid agency staff trapped by the fighting between the Zairean army and ethnic Tutsi rebels. Michelle Quintaglie, WFP spokeswoman in Nairobi, said contact was &quot;very difficult&quot; but &quot;it is important we get them out today.&quot;</p>
<p>Humanitarian sources said Hutu refugee camps near Goma, north of Bukavu, were still quiet although Stromberg said security sources reported skirmishes north of the camps.</p>
<p>&quot;The road north from Goma to the refugee camps is completely shut except for transportation of water and this only with the permission of the Zairean authorities and the Zairean camp security contingents,&quot; Stromberg said.</p>
<p>In Kigali, rumours circulated that up to 1,700 Rwandan soldiers were in the south Kivu area of Zaire. On Monday, a Rwandan government spokesman denied its army had entered Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
