<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13308" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Democratic support for Clinton masks differences.</title>
<headline>Democratic support for Clinton masks differences.</headline>
<byline>Rich Miller</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Democrats are coming together this week to formally back President Bill Clinton for a second term, but the united front masks deep differences over the future course of the party and the country.</p>
<p>On one side are self-styled New Democrats, including lately Clinton himself, who favor smaller government, open trade and market-oriented solutions to America's ills.</p>
<p>On the other are more traditional liberals, who back an increased role for the government and question the efficacy of free trade and unfettered markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The liberals in the party have by and large resigned themselves and are committed to electing Clinton,&quot; said Jeff Faux, president of the Economic Policy Institute, a liberal think tank. &quot;But the debate is far from over.&quot;</p>
<p>The coming ideological battle is of more than academic interest because it could shape the parameters of the second term of a president who even some supporters acknowledge seemed to govern as a liberal in his first two years in office and a New Democrat thereafter.</p>
<p>&quot;It hasn't always been a stright line,&quot; said Al From, president of the moderate Democratic Leadership Council (DLC).</p>
<p>Recent opinion polls have put Clinton ahead of Republican challenger Bob Dole in the race for the presidency, although the gap has narrowed in the past two weeks.</p>
<p>An inkling of what might be in store after the Nov. 5 election came last week when many of the party's members attacked Clinton for signing the welfare reform bill.</p>
<p>The bill, which Clinton himself has said is flawed, fulfills the president's 1992 election-year pledge to &quot;end welfare as we know it&quot; by limiting eligibility for government help and ending direct federal aid for poor children.</p>
<p>Patricia Ireland, president of the National Oragnization for Women, denounced Clinton and accused him of caving into religious and political extremists.</p>
<p>&quot;While some of us may hold our noses and vote for President Clinton, many of us will refuse to lift a finger or contribute a penny toward his re-election,&quot; she said. &quot;We know he is at best our option this year, not our answer.&quot;</p>
<p>The coming power struggle in the party rests on differing interpretations of the political revival of Clinton and the Democrats since the 1994 congressional election debacle, when they lost control of the House of Representatives for the first time in 40 years.</p>
<p>New-style Democrats -- and Clinton's political guru Dick Morris -- have ascribed his revival to his decision to tack to the right, staking out a position between liberals in his own party and hard-line Republican conservatives in Congress.</p>
<p>But liberals argue that it has been Clinton's staunch defense of traditional big government programs such as Medicare against Republican attacks that have led to his comeback in the polls.</p>
<p>The divided loyalties within the Democratic Party have not been lost on Dole, who has tried to capitalize on them in his uphill campaign to oust the president from the White House.</p>
<p>&quot;Just imagine what he'll do if he were somehow to win a second term -- his liberalism unrestrained by the need to face the American people in another election,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>The DLC's From argued that the steps that Clinton has taken away from old-style liberalism -- backing the North American Free Trade Agreement, a balanced budget and welfare reform -- are irrevocable and that it will not matter much if Democrats or Republicans win control of Congress in November.</p>
<p>Democrats were in charge of Congress during Clinton's first two years in office, when he tried unsuccessfully to push through health care reform that Republicans branded a bureaucratic nightmare and a return of big government.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether Democrats regain control of Congress or the Republicans do ... probably isn't going to make a big difference because the balance of power is going to be very small,&quot; From said.</p>
<p>He wants Clinton to use a second term to complete welfare reform by helping states cope with their increased roles under the new legislation.</p>
<p>Also on From's wish list for a second term: modernization of the education system, measures to help the cities and reform of entitlement programs such as Medicare health benefits for the elderly.</p>
<p>Not surprisingly, Democratic liberals see things differently and predict a struggle for power after Nov. 5.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be a ferocious fight,&quot; said Robert Borosage, co-director of Campaign for America's Future, a group formed this year by labor unions and others concerned about the party's drift to the right.</p>
<p>Borosage has a different agenda than From: an end to the tight money policies of the Federal Reserve, laws and tax incentives to make corporations more accountable to their workers and stepped-up public investment.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a long-term struggle that we're involved in to help determine the direction of the Democratic Party and the country as a whole,&quot; said Steve Rosenthal, political director of the 13.1 million-member AFL-CIO labor group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
