<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133094" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa 96/97 revenue collection on track - Manuel.</title>
<headline>S.Africa 96/97 revenue collection on track - Manuel.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Revenue collection for 1996/97 was &quot;perfectly on track&quot; to achieve the targeted reduction in the budget deficit to 5.1 percent, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said.</p>
<p>He said on Tuesday 900 million rand in arrear taxes had already been collected.</p>
<p>Tax collection was improving and legislation outlining the South African Revenue Services' (SARS) autonomy would be tabled in the first quarter of 1997, he said.</p>
<p>Briefing the parliamentary public accounts committee, Manuel said negotiations were still underway but he was optimistic the legislation would provide the SARS with enough autonomy to become a performance driven entity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a few feathers in our collective cap on the negotiations already but I would not like to say more at this stage,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>Over the past 12 months, SARS had been formed, unifying inland revenue and customs and excise departments.</p>
<p>He said SARS would be funded by receiving a certain percentage of revenue collected and this would be used to help provide incentive schemes to staff in the new fiscal year.</p>
<p>As soon as it had finalised its business plan, SARS would receive the extra 150 million rand allocated to revenue collection by the budget in the current financial year.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary office +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
