<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133087" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa Manuel reaffirms four pct deficit target.</title>
<headline>S.Africa Manuel reaffirms four pct deficit target.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel reaffirmed on Tuesday that his March budget would be based on a deficit equivalent to four percent of gross domestic product, down from 5.1 percent in fiscal 1996/97.</p>
<p>But he told a news conference the reduction would be achieved by improved revenue collection as well as spending restraint on the part of government.</p>
<p>&quot;Arriving at a four percent deficit next year is not a book-keeping exercise that looks at only taking money away.</p>
<p>&quot;It is about an enrichment, it is about giving a new thrust and impetus to policy work that has already been undertaken. It certainly is about improving your revenue collection capability as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Manuel said he believed investors and rating agencies were aware that South Africa's post-apartheid government had started work with backlogs inherited from the previous government.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pursuing this path of deficit reduction. It's a hard path that we are pursuing because of the nature of the backlogs we have to deal with.&quot;</p>
<p>Director General of Finance Maria Ramos said the programme intended to cut the deficit to four percent next year and three percent by the end of the century had to be structural.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't move from 5.1 percent to four percent by shifting expenditures or by doing some cosmetic changes.</p>
<p>&quot;We are really talking about a change in the structural deficit and that's what you need to aim for, but you don't expect reductions in the structural deficit in the short term - you change it over years,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Boyle, Parliamentary newsroom +27 21 403 2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
