<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133063" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Coffee prices rise in Tanzania, steady in Kenya.</title>
<headline>Coffee prices rise in Tanzania, steady in Kenya.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee prices for mild arabicas rose in Tanzania and were fully steady in Kenya, traders said.</p>
<p>Quality remained high in Tanzania and Kenya's fly crop was very good for the time of year.</p>
<p>Traders in Nairobi said premium grade AAs fetched around $154 per 50 kg on Tuesday while ABs fetched around $160, which was around $29 and $34 above New York March.</p>
<p>&quot;Coffee will continue to be very expensive. The Coffee Board (of Kenya) has just announced that it does not have much coffee, which will increase market pressure,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>An official from a leading brokerage house added, &quot;The coffee was expensive. I still think the quality is good for this time of the year. This has not been a bad fly crop at all.&quot;</p>
<p>The Coffee Board of Kenya said it sold all 22,493 60 kg bags it had on offer, against the 21,792 sold last week.</p>
<p>Traders said there was coffee at least for two more auctions.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment it is still open but we are likely to receive the main crop in December, the earliest in many years. So quality should start looking up,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Another trader said the market was fully steady and had risen compared to New York despite expectations of a fall.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems there is more demand and quantities are becoming less so prices are up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kenya Coffee Auctions Ltd said grade AAs averaged $148 per 50-kg bag bag from $149.50 last week, grade ABs averaged $141 from $141.5 last week, while grade Cs gained $8.5 to stand at $141 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market appears to have become steady after recent advances,&quot; an auction official said.</p>
<p>In the northern Tanzanian coffee town of Moshi, traders said Tanzanian AA and AB grades sold at high prices at the auction last Thursday, while lower grades followed world market prices.</p>
<p>A total of 33,223 60-kg bags of mild washed arabicas and 11,256 bags of robusta were sold at the auction.</p>
<p>Tanzania holds coffee export auctions twice a month.</p>
<p>&quot;Thursday was one of the most incredible days at the auction. The highest prices for mild arabicas grade AA sold at $165 per 50 kg bag,&quot; a trader said. Lower grades sold at prices averaging between $117 and $159.20 per 50 kg.</p>
<p>Tanzania Coffee Board statistics showed northern arabica prices at $125 per 50 kg for premium AAs and $124 per 50 kg for ABs at the previous auction on October 3. It showed prices for lower grades at $75-107.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are going to remain fairly constant. Differentials are not falling as expected. That won't happen -- most likely differentials will go up but we can't really predict the New York prices,&quot; a senior trader in Moshi told Reuters.</p>
<p>Coffee is measured in 60 kg bags but sold in 50 kg units.</p>
<p>The trader attributed the top prices for Tanzania's premier grades to a general shortage among buyers in the world market for mild arabicas in addition to improvements in quality.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom +254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
