<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133017" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Barrick posts lower Q3 on charge, costs.</title>
<headline>Barrick posts lower Q3 on charge, costs.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>North America's largest gold producer, Toronto-based Barrick Gold Corp, reported lower third-quarter earnings on Tuesday due to an after-tax charge and higher operating costs.</p>
<p>&quot;I think their quarter clearly underscores that Barrick has made the transition from a growth company to one that's trying to maintain its existing base,&quot; said mining analyst Barry Allan of Gordon Capital.  </p>
<p>Barrick's net income for the quarter fell to US$21 million, or US$0.06 a share, from US$67.7 million, or US$0.19 cents a share, in the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>Earnings were slightly below analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>Barrick pointed to higher cash costs, which rose to US$203 an ounce from US$194 an ounce a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company also took a US$38 million hit to bail out of its Cerro Corona exploration project in Peru.</p>
<p>And Barrick hiked its exploration budget more than 50 percent, to US$46.4 million for the first nine months of the year, compared to US$30.9 million previously.  </p>
<p>Investors seemed to shrug that off. Barrick's shares rose C$0.50 to C$36.15 in heavy trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange. In New York, the stock rose 3/8 to US$26 7/8.</p>
<p>The market seemed positive to Barrick's plans to develop its Pascua mine in Chile and its new Pierina property in Peru, analysts said.</p>
<p>Barrick bought the Pierina deposit last summer through its US$800 million takeover of Arequipa Resources Ltd, based on a minimum of 4.5 million ounces of gold. According to the company, recent drilling on the property suggests the number was conservative.  </p>
<p>Barrick said production at Pierina should begin in late 1999 at a rate of 500,000 ounces of gold a year. Costs should be below US$100 an ounce thanks to a substantial silver credit and high grade gold.</p>
<p>Capital costs should be about US$200 million, the company said. It has eight drills on the property working to define the deposit.</p>
<p>&quot;They are proceeding very aggressively on Pierina,&quot; analyst Allan said. However, he cautioned that it was risky to make such claims while drilling was still underway and a feasibility study is still a long way off.</p>
<p>At Pascua in Chile, recent exploration suggests the deposit may extend across the nearby border into Argentina, Barrick said. Production is expected to begin in 1999, totaling 400,000 ounces a year at an operating cost of US$240 per ounce. Capital costs are expected of about US$475 million.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
