<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133074" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Shell says Nigeria has to invest for &quot;Vision 2010&quot;.</title>
<headline>Shell says Nigeria has to invest for &quot;Vision 2010&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria needs to promote investment in oil and gas to achieve its plan for sustainable economic growth by 2010, Brian Anderson, the chief executive of Royal Dutch Shell Group in Nigeria, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Military ruler General Sani Abacha last month launched &quot;Vision 2010&quot;, modelled on plans in other countries, notably Malaysia, to bring economic prosperity in the next century.</p>
<p>&quot;In the world of Vision 2010, the Nigerian oil and gas industry has tremendous potential for growth,&quot; Anderson told an oil seminar in Lagos. &quot;The potential can only be realised with major investments in the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>Vision 2010 envisages significant boost in Nigeria's gross domestic product through agriculture and industrialisation as well as literacy levels, healthcare and employment.</p>
<p>Anderson said if the rate of economic growth was between six to eight percent annually from 2.2 percent currently, it would improve the prospect of expanding the domestic energy and gas market.</p>
<p>But the government had to develop strategies for the oil sector, the economic engine of Nigeria, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A coherent treatment of oil, gas and power within a comprehensive national energy policy is required,&quot; Anderson said. &quot;Gas-based projects including power generation should be promoted, prices of power and all energy-related products should be liberalised.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the sale of government equity in oil joint ventures with multinational firms and privatisation, which is being considered by government, was the &quot;fundamental solution&quot; to the logjam in Nigeria's economy.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Anthony Ani said on Monday that the government was seriously considering divesting its 57 percent equity stake in the joint ventures.</p>
<p>Anderson said it was important Nigeria sought a higher OPEC output quota to match its investment in increased capacity.</p>
<p>Nigerian output, he said &quot;could grow to four million barrels per day (bpd) or more by 2010&quot;.</p>
<p>Nigeria currently pumps about two million bpd of crude oil, which accounts for more than 90 percent of its foreign earnings.</p>
<p>Shell's Nigerian joint venture, now producing 930,000 bpd, was aiming to reach at least two million bpd by 2010, Anderson said on Monday.</p>
<p>Nigeria's economy, the biggest in Sub-Saharan Africa, slumped into recession when the army annulled an election in 1993 to restore democracy, resulting in strikes and riots.</p>
<p>More pragamatic economic policies in place since 1995 have stabilised the economy but with few signs of growth as yet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
