<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133059" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's poor need more than growth - Mbeki.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's poor need more than growth - Mbeki.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa needs to combine the efforts of the state and the private sector to alleviate the plight of its poor, Deputy President Thabo Mbeki told parliament on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In a speech marking the end of a week-long focus on poverty, Mbeki, President Nelson Mandela's chief economic strategist and his heir-apparent, said the post-apartheid government faced formidable expectations from the poor.</p>
<p>&quot;Poverty-reducing measures, by enhancing the purchasing power of the poor, play a considerable role in expanding the market, which is instrumental in accelerating growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Since neither the market nor the state alone can tackle this massive backlog of poverty and inequality, we have to work out an optimal mix of state and market.</p>
<p>&quot;The view that all state interventions are unnecessary, inefficient and wasteful is erroneous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mbeki told Reuters afterwards that Finance Minister Trevor Manuel's June 14 macro-economic strategy for growth, employment and redistribution (GEAR) was not the sum of government policy.</p>
<p>The programme, which has been applauded by investors and the International Monetary Fund, foresees economic growth up from almost three percent now to six percent by the end of the century.</p>
<p>In includes a reduction in the budget deficit from 5.8 percent last year to four percent next year, massive job creation and incentives for industry.</p>
<p>Mbeki said GEAR, which has been strongly criticised by labour unions and left-wing members of the ruling African National Congress, remained the kingpin of economic policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not like we're going to be discovering new policy which we then append to GEAR to make GEAR more humane.</p>
<p>&quot;But there are many other elements not dealt with in GEAR that are being dealt with elsewhere - sectoral programmes, poverty relief programmes and the like,&quot; Mbeki said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes the allegation is made that if you take the GEAR route, for instance...what is going to happen as a result of the reduction of the budget deficit is that you are going to be cutting social spending and therefore impoverishing the poor.</p>
<p>&quot;The point is you need to take GEAR together with whatever else is there to get the full picture,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
