<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133041" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Apartheid police say politicians must take blame.</title>
<headline>Apartheid police say politicians must take blame.</headline>
<byline>Ingeborg Lichtenberg</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An apartheid police chief told South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot; on Tuesday his men had killed black activists rather than arrest them and believed they had government approval to do so.</p>
<p>The testimony from retired police brigadier Jack Cronje heaped further blame on the country's political leaders for apartheid atrocities after evidence on Monday directly implicated ex-president P.W. Botha in dirty tricks.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela said on Tuesday the evidence by former police commissioner Johan van der Merwe that Botha had personally ordered the bombing of a building used by black activists in 1988 did not surprise him.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think there is anything new that we did not know,&quot; Mandela told reporters. &quot;But the information is now coming out in public.&quot;</p>
<p>Cronje, who commanded a secret police unit that spawned a death squad and is accused of 27 murders, told the commission's amnesty committee that eliminating enemies had been generally accepted behaviour among apartheid security forces.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I understood and I am still convinced of it... (the) action against the liberation movements was sanctioned by the government of the day,&quot; said Cronje, one of five policemen asking for pardons in return for telling all about 40 state- sponsored murders in the last decade of white domination.</p>
<p>Cronje said the fight against black liberation movements in the 1980s was part of the war against communism and was overseen by a state security council that included senior police, soldiers and politicians.</p>
<p>&quot;A war psychosis was created by the South African government, with the use of the media, television, newspapers, churches and cultural organisations, that there was a total onslaught on the country,&quot; Cronje told the commission hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore the elimination of terrorists and activists under any circumstances was seen as justified and part of the fight.&quot;</p>
<p>Cronje said the only way to counter activists was to kill them. Jail was a short-term solution and the law too cumbersome.</p>
<p>Daily reports about police actions, including the murder of activists, were sent to police headquarters and then the state security council, Cronje said.</p>
<p>&quot;If anyone therefore alleges that the state security council had no knowledge of security force activities and of specific cases...it is not true,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nobel peace laureate Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission has so far mainly heard testimony from victims of apartheid but the hearings this week have initiated what could be flood of disclosures by perpetrators of abuses.</p>
<p>Cronje and the four other policemen seeking amnesty said in an earlier submission that they doubted claims of innocence by F.W. de Klerk, the country's last white president.</p>
<p>&quot;The horrific admissions indicate a complete abdication of classical policing principles and will forever be a stain on the history of South Africa's policing,&quot; said current commissioner of police George Fivaz .</p>
<p>Botha has not responded to the bombing allegations but the commission said it expected him to do so and would subpoena him if he did not.</p>
<p>Tutu has proposed that the cut-off date for crimes qualifying under amnesty provisions be extended three months to May 10, 1996, the date of Mandela's inauguration, but the president on Tuesday ruled this out.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any possibility of extending the cut-off date,&quot; Mandela said. He said such a move would hinder the fight against crime and corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
