<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133032" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TD Bank sees Canadian growth accelerating.</title>
<headline>TD Bank sees Canadian growth accelerating.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Toronto-Dominion Bank on Tuesday said it expects Canada's economic growth to accelerate in the coming year, powered by low interest rates and the strong performance of export industries.</p>
<p>Canada's fifth-largest bank forecast growth will accelerate to about 3.0 percent in 1997 from 1.6 percent in 1996. The bank made the forecasts in its quarterly economic report.</p>
<p>The bank said growth will be boosted by a drop in interest rates, which have fallen to 30-year lows, and the continued strong performance of export-oriented industries.  </p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are beginning to spend more on goods and services, including cars and light trucks, as well as new and resale homes,&quot; said Ruth Getter, chief economist with TD Bank, in the report.</p>
<p>The report noted there had been a dramatic shift of sentiment in international financial markets in favor of Canada, prompted by a low inflation rate, falling government deficits and a surplus in Canada's international current account. The bank said those favorable trends would support a gradual rise in the Canadian dollar to about US$0.75 to US$O.76 over the medium term.  </p>
<p>In its interest rate outlook, TD Bank said it did not expect the Bank of Canada to ease monetary conditions further this year, but that if the Canadian dollar appreciated, the central bank would likely cut rates again to keep monetary conditions unchanged. The Bank of Canada has made nine interest rate cuts of 25 basis points each this year.</p>
<p>In its regional outlook, the bank said Alberta would have the highest growth of any Canadian province this year, boosted by healthy conditions in the oilpatch and a rise in crop production. Saskatchewan, Manitoba, and Ontario were also expected to post above average economic growth.  </p>
<p>TD Bank said British Columbia and Quebec would record below average growth this year because of weak conditions in the pulp and paper industry, TD Bank said.</p>
<p>The quarterly report forecast that Ontario would lead the provinces in economic growth in 1997, propelled by the manufacturing sector.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
