<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133033" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada auto union reaches deal with GM.</title>
<headline>Canada auto union reaches deal with GM.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian Auto Workers union on Tuesday reached an tentative agreement with General Motors Corp that would end an 19-day strike by 26,000 auto workers at GM's Canadian plants, the company and the union announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a new 1996 collective agreement,&quot; the Canadian Auto Workers president Buzz Hargrove told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Asked whether the deal was a win-win compromise, GM's chief negotiator Dean Munger responded: &quot;Yes, sure is.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Let's get it ratified, it's a good agreement. It suits our business needs and fits your members needs,&quot; Munger told the union's negotiating team.</p>
<p>The pact, which must now be ratified by union membership Wednesday, was reached after three days of intensive bargaining that ran past several deadlines previously agreed by both sides.</p>
<p>The agreement includes a pledge by GM to recognize limits on contracting out work, known as outsourcing, and the sale of facilities. The union, in turn, made a major concession by accepting that GM's business plan may require deviance from a pattern agreement reached in September with Chrysler Corp and intended to serve as the model for the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We look forward to moving to the future now,&quot; said Hargrove. &quot;I would have hoped we could have done it without a strike.&quot;</p>
<p>The strike paralysed GM's plants in Canada and idled nearly 20,000 GM workers in the United States and Mexico.</p>
<p>Membership meetings to ratify the agreement have already been set up for Wednesday morning and Hargrove has said workers could be back at GM plants across the country by tomorrow afternoon Eastern time.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau  (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
