<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133096" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Shell expects Nigeria to sell joint venture stakes.</title>
<headline>Shell expects Nigeria to sell joint venture stakes.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria looks set to embark on the multi-billion-dollar sale of its majority share in the country's six oil-producing joint ventures, Brian Anderson, managing director of Shell in Nigeria, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The sale, worth at least $11 billion, would put Nigeria's debt-ridden oil sector back on track and provide a huge injection of cash for the country's fragile economy, Anderson said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's inevitable. There's a need for a fundamental change in the financing structure (of the oil industry) which has been recognised by the government,&quot; Anderson told a small group of reporters.</p>
<p>Nigerian Finance Minister Anthony Ani first proposed the phased five-year sale at Nigeria's economic summit in Abuja at the end of September and presented an outline to the International Monetary Fund in Washington three weeks ago.</p>
<p>Nigeria, through Nigerian National Petroleum Corp, owns an average 57 percent share in six joint ventures with Royal Dutch/Shell, Mobil Corp, Chevron Corp, Elf Aquitaine, Agip SpA and Texaco Inc.</p>
<p>Shell Development Production Co of Nigeria, accounting for nearly half of the country's two million barrels per day (bpd) of crude output, is easily the biggest producer, earning profits of some $220 million a year.</p>
<p>The sale is likely to provoke huge interest among international oil companies keen to lay their hands on proven reserves ripe for development at low cost. Anderson said Shell, which held a majority share in its operations before nationalisation in the 1970s, would consider buying extra equity, depending on the terms.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there are plenty of people in the oil business who would like to invest in Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;In spite of the problems there aren't that many countries where there's oil equity for sale  and relatively low cost production. So I think there will be a big uptake and big potential to grow output, as soon as the process starts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested but it will depend on just how much its going to cost. We'd have a look at everything and see how it fits the portfolio.&quot;</p>
<p>Previous plans by Nigerian military governments for the possible privatisation of state assets have failed to materialise.</p>
<p>But Anderson said internal discussions in General Sani Abacha's government and been underway for some time. He said he expected the oil asset sale to be raised in January's budget and get underway in about 18 months' time.</p>
<p>Government arrears and wrangling over budgets and the terms of a new operating agreement have left foreign oil companies struggling to maintain production and unable to exploit new reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that without investment the production capacity of the country is going to decline. There hasn't been much investment over the last few years,&quot; said Anderson.</p>
<p>&quot;This will take the government out of the upstream business. &quot;It is an opportunity for them to use the cash, if used wisely, to diversify the economy and improve the general infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>Nigeria would move to a tax and royalty system on its oil sales. That would strip state NNPC of its responsibility for some 850,000 bpd of crude exports and prevent revenue losses to the middlemen that manage contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Abacha may genuinely trying to end corruption,&quot; Anderson said.</p>
<p>On the basis of a minor sale of NNPC equity in 1991, the oil joint ventures could raise $11 billion, he added.</p>
<p>But when bids are requested Nigeria could easily see much larger proceeds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
