<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133062" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African golds finish up on bullion, seen firmer.</title>
<headline>S.African golds finish up on bullion, seen firmer.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African gold shares ended a quiet day well up on a healthy bullion price and dealers expected further riches on the metal board.</p>
<p>&quot;Golds were quite bullish on bullion. They were definitely the interesting part of the day. If the gold price holds these sort of levels for the next few days we could see a nice little run in gold shares,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Industrials struggled to rise and settled just above opening levels at the close of trade, having traded in a narrow band all day, dealers said.</p>
<p>The local market seemed to buck the international weaker trend and a lower Wall Street was unlikely to have much impact on South African shares on Wednesday, they added.</p>
<p>By 1436 GMT the Dow Jones Industrial index was 18.63 points off at 6,072.24.</p>
<p>The weakening rand and September's CPI, due on Wednesday, were also unlikely to cause much upheaval.</p>
<p>The overall index was up 16.3 points to 7,027.8, industrials gained 7.3 points to 8,270.2 and golds were up 32.3 points to 1,708.9 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
