<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133012" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Northern Telecom profits beat estimates.</title>
<headline>Northern Telecom profits beat estimates.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Edmonds</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telecommunications equipment maker Northern Telecom Ltd. posted a 34 percent increase in third-quarter earnings on Tuesday, beating analysts' estimates by a penny and winning their applause.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought (they were) pretty terrific,&quot; analyst Charles DiSanza of Gerard Klauer Mattison said of the results.</p>
<p>Mississauga, Ontario-based Nortel earned $113 million, or 43 cents a share, in the third quarter, versus $81 million, or 32 cents a share, in the prior year period.</p>
<p>Analysts' consensus estimate was 42 cents a share.</p>
<p>Nortel shares climbed 85 Canadian cents to C$81.85 on the Toronto Stock Exchange and added 75 cents to $61 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Revenues in the quarter rose 23 percent to $3.05 billion from $2.49 billion in the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Third-quarter order input climbed to $3.09 billion from $2.69 billion, due mainly to increases in the U.S., Caribbean, Latin American and European markets.</p>
<p>Nortel saw more than 50 percent growth in wireless revenues and posted a 30 percent increase in U.S. sales across all its product lines.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Jean Monty said in a telephone interview there was more &quot;good growth&quot; in order input ahead, likely in the range of 15 to 20 percent. Nortel's order input so far this year is ahead of its expectations.</p>
<p>Analysts said gross margins in the quarter of about 38.6 percent were a little shy of expectations. But sales were better than most expected. Gross margins are the difference between sales and the cost of sales.</p>
<p>Analyst DiSanza said Nortel's research and development spending would likely fall to about 12 percent of sales over time as last year's high level of investment -- around 16 percent of sales in the third quarter -- begins translating into increased revenues.</p>
<p>Research and development spending in the third quarter was $439 million or 14.4 percent of sales.</p>
<p>DiSanza said Nortel was capable of 25 percent earnings growth over the long term.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
