<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133088" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa has no plans to expand foreign borrowings.</title>
<headline>S.Africa has no plans to expand foreign borrowings.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa has no plans to expand significantly its foreign debt portfolio, finance department director-general Maria Ramos said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment only 4.2 percent of our portfolio is in anything but rands and we will be managing it next year to keep it at around those ratios,&quot; she told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be marginally up, it may be marginally down, we don't have any plans to expand our foreign debt portfolio in any massive way.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ramos said the government had no need to raise more funds offshore.</p>
<p>&quot;We actually don't need to because we can finance the entire deficit domestically. We have done these issues for reasons of other strategies, benchmarking, extending the maturity of the profile of the existing debt,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said that government had now completed its plans to raise 2.5 billion rand of its borrowing requirement offshore.</p>
<p>In September, South Africa issued a seven-year 500 million mark issue at a 140 basis points above equivalent German government issues.</p>
<p>On October 11, the country issued a $300 million 10-year Yankee bond at 195 basis points above the 10-year U.S. Treasury bond.</p>
<p>-- Lynda Loxton, Cape Town newsroom, +27 21 252-238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
