<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133082" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African rand sinks to two-month low on dollar.</title>
<headline>S.African rand sinks to two-month low on dollar.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand sank to a two-month low against the dollar and plumbed record depths against the British pound on Tuesday in a fall the finance minister blamed on strong overseas currencies.</p>
<p>The rand touched a low of 4.5765 against the dollar, its worst level since August 19 when it hit an all-time low of 4.59. Against sterling it fell below 7.30 for the first time.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said he was sanguine about the currency's latest slide, blaming the fall on strong overseas currencies rather than rand weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;You are dealing in an interesting situation a few weeks before the elections in the U.S. and the dollar is strengthening,&quot; Manuel told reporters in Cape Town.</p>
<p>&quot;Against the crosses, sterling has strengthened even more than the dollar,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The rand has been hit hard this year by speculators wary of South Africa's economic performance.</p>
<p>But Manuel said that the rand's latest slide had brought little pressure to bear on the country's gold and foreign exchange reserves, which stood at just over 10 billion rand ($2.2 billion) at the end of September.</p>
<p>&quot;The Reserve Bank as of this morning says that there has been no pressure on the reserves. We have not seen significant outflows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that the currency's depreciation over the last few days had been fairly marginal.</p>
<p>&quot;On a trade-weighted basis the depreciation since February is still at 19 percent,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>The rand has fallen from 3.65 against the dollar since February 15 this year.</p>
<p>Dealers said there appeared to be no new factors in the market and said the currency fell early on a wave of dollar demand by local and London-based operators.</p>
<p>The central Reserve Bank was said to be active in trying to stem the tide but foreign exchange traders said it had limited ammunition to fight the market given the low level of official reserves, equivalent to just four weeks import cover.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
