<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133089" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica rand fall due to dlr, stg strength -Manuel.</title>
<headline>SAfrica rand fall due to dlr, stg strength -Manuel.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A robust dollar and even stronger British currency were the reasons for the rand's renewed fall in recent days, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The rand sank to a fresh two-month low of 4.5765 bid against the dollar earlier on Tuesday and a worst ever level of over 7.30 against sterling.</p>
<p>&quot;You are dealing in an interesting situation a few weeks before the elections in the U.S. and the dollar is strengthening,&quot; Manuel told reporters at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Against the crosses, sterling has strengthened even more than the dollar,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Manuel said that the rand's latest slide had brought little pressure to bear on the country's gold and foreign exchange reserves, which currently stand at just over 10 billion rand, equivalent to four weeks import cover.</p>
<p>&quot;The Reserve Bank as of this morning says that there has been no pressure on the reserves. We have not seen significant outflows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that the currency's depreciation over the last few days had been fairly marginal.</p>
<p>&quot;On a trade weighted basis the depreciation since February is still at 19 percent,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>The rand has fallen from 3.65 against the dollar since February 15 this year.</p>
<p>Shortly after 1030 GMT on Tuesday it was trading at 4.5730/5780, its worst level since August 19 when it touched an all-time low of 4.59 against the U.S. currency.</p>
<p>Against sterling it was trading at 7.2898/3001.</p>
<p>-- Parliament newsroom, +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
