<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133083" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Gencor still studying Mozambique titanium deposit.</title>
<headline>Gencor still studying Mozambique titanium deposit.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gencor Ltd will decide whether to go ahead with a $500 million mineral sands project in Mozambique after completion of a detailed feasibility study late in 1998, the company said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Project leader John Dudaf told Reuters Gencor had recently started the second phase of its probe into mining the Moebase mineral sands deposit 550 km northwest of Beira.</p>
<p>Initial drilling results indicated reserves of some 20 million tonnes of titanium dioxide at the deposit.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in a feasibility study stage and there is no way one would make a decision until the feasibility study is completed, and that would only be to the end of 1998,&quot; Dudaf said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We last reported our latest drilling results about a month ago, and we have got about 20 million tonnes of titanium dioxide, just about 80 percent of that is proven,&quot; Dudaf said.</p>
<p>With reserves of some 20 million tonnes of titanium dioxide, the Moebase deposit would be in the same league as South Africa's Richards Bay Minerals (RBM) -- one of the largest mineral sands mining operations in the world.</p>
<p>South Africa has the second largest reserves of titanium dioxide after Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Richards Bay has a reserve of 26 million tonnes, so it (Moebase) is very much in the world class for a deposit,&quot; Dudaf said.</p>
<p>Gencor, with its partners the Mozambican government and Caribbean-based Edlow Resources, planned to strip-mine the sand at Moebase to supply feedstock for a $230 million titanium smelter.</p>
<p>Titanium dioxide is used as a whitening agent, for instance in paints, and also as a welding rod cover and for ceramic components in the electronics industry.</p>
<p>Titanium alloy is used in aircraft, ships, spacecraft and missiles.</p>
<p>Local newspapers quoted Mozambican Prime Minister Pascal Mocumbi saying last week that the country would become a large exporter of titanium early in the next century.</p>
<p>South African papers speculated that his comments meant the project would go ahead but Dudaf was more cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously the (Mozambican) government wants the project but...there are a lot of things we have to thrash out first before we make the decision,&quot; Dudaf said.</p>
<p>He said the feasiblity study was in two phases. One part of the study continued into 1997 while the detailed study would only be completed at the end of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing with our drilling programme up there and we have commenced the detailed feasibility study,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
