<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133092" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Federal government to divest from oil sector soon, Finance Minister Anthony Ani tells seminar in Lagos.</p>
<p>- Investors offload shares on the stock exchange as cash crunch in Nigeria's economy bites harder.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Nine airforce officers jailed for a total of 588 years for misappropriating public funds.</p>
<p>- International oil firms Exxon and Total jostle to take up 57 percent stake Nigerian government plans to sell off in joint ventures, newspaper's investigations show.</p>
<p>- Shell oil company offers 200 youths employment.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Ani tells seminar government is willing to undertake further economic reforms to attract foreign investments.</p>
<p>- Military ruler General Sani Abacha asks ministers to prune number of people that accompany them on foreign trips.</p>
<p>- Road tanker drivers threaten strike over continued detention of former national secretary of oil union NUPENG.</p>
<p>- United Bank for Africa recovers 1.1 billion naira bad debts, its chairman Nuhu Bamali tells sharehlders.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
