<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133099" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Southern Africa aims to boost trade, investment.</title>
<headline>Southern Africa aims to boost trade, investment.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investment conference that starts on Wednesday hopes to capitalise on regional developments like the end of apartheid in South Africa and the start of peace in Mozambique and Angola to attract foreign investment and boost trade.</p>
<p>The two-day Southern Africa Trade and Investment Summit has attracted a host of senior ranking politicians, including the presidents of Zimbabwe, Zambia, Botswana and Angola and the heir apparent in South Africa, deputy president Thabo Mbeki.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time in years people are talking about the continent of Africa as having some kind of prospects. We are starting from a very low base level, but there is some light at the end of the tunnel,&quot; said Carole Mason, chief economist at Investec bank in Johannesburg.</p>
<p>After decades of being shunned by the international business community, economists said there was real hope that Africa could attract investment thanks to political changes that make its markets more friendly.</p>
<p>An issue that is going to be top of the agenda at the meeting in Harare is the role South Africa plays in the region.</p>
<p>The country -- shunned by its neighbours under apartheid -- is seen as an economic powerhouse whose success or failure is the key to the whole region's future.</p>
<p>The South African government's progress on privatisation, criticised for being too slow, is seen as vital for attracting foreign investment and also encouraging structural reform in other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;If South Africa takes the lead in privatisation it makes the process ideologically easier for other countries,&quot; said Floris Bergh, investment manager at life assurer Old Mutual in Namibia.</p>
<p>The scrapping of South African exchange controls sometime in the future is also a hot topic. This would free up cash to move out of South Africa and neighbouring countries hope some of it would flow their way.</p>
<p>It would also make it easier for foreign firms to use South Africa as a base for regional expansion. &quot;An overseas investor of a big size would first enter the South African market and use that as a base to penetrate the rest of the region,&quot; Bergh said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
