<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133056" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian share trading dull on delayed results.</title>
<headline>Nigerian share trading dull on delayed results.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading was dull on Tuesday on the Nigerian stock exchange because expected company results needed to drive the market were not forthcoming, dealers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 6616.18 from 6611.27 on Monday as most stocks ended the day unchanged.</p>
<p>Although demand for oil shares remained strong brokers were cautious in marking up prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Caution is the watchword because we are yet to receive the half-year results of some of these companies,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>African Petroleum and Nestle Foods led led gainers with 20 kobo to 34.90 naira and 36.00 naira, respectively.</p>
<p>Total was 10 kobo up at 48.50 naira and Texaco five kobo more at 27.45 naira while Union Dicon Salt rose 15 kobo to 36.65 and Nigerian Tobacco Company added four kobo to 3.05 naira.</p>
<p>West African Portland Cement notched 15 kobo, so did construction firm G. Cappa, to close, respectively at 35.75 naira and 9.05 naira.</p>
<p>The main loser was conglomerate UAC which fell by 10 kobo to 9.80 naira while troubled brewers were steady, Nigerian Breweries at 11.30 naira and Guinness at 7.30 naira.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected the bearish trend to persist as the traditional Christmas seasonal rush to cash shares to pay for other expenses seemed to have begun early.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
