<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133024" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: EU feed barley export subsidy pressures prices-CWB.</title>
<headline>EU feed barley export subsidy pressures prices-CWB.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The return of European Union export subsidies three weeks ago has pressured world feed barley prices, a Canadian Wheat Board market analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been exporting quite a bit to Saudi Arabia, so any time they do make an export sale at a subsidy level in order to be competitive, of course, we have to compete,&quot; CWB market analyst Larry Sawatzky told Reuters.</p>
<p>European barley was valued at US$138 a tonne fob last week. The CWB's world price forecast in September estimated world feed barley prices at C$150-170 (US$112-126) a tonne, fob St. Lawrence.  </p>
<p>The CWB will issue its October world feed barley price estimate Thursday at 1400 CDT amid Canadian trade speculation the price will drop significantly.</p>
<p>Sawatzky declined to comment on Thursday's price outlook.</p>
<p>Still, the EU's subsidy in the past three weeks converts to about C$53 (US$39) a tonne, a significant price factor, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In general, it does tend to depress the barley price complex,&quot; Sawatzky said.</p>
<p>The EU exported a weekly average of 100,000 tonnes of feed barley in each of the last three weeks, he said.  </p>
<p>EU barley output was expected to be 16 percent higher than last year, he said.</p>
<p>Higher output means the EU has enough barley to meet its own demand and still have some left over in contrast to last year's tight supply situation when export taxes were imposed.</p>
<p>In anticipation of higher European production the CWB reduced its monthly price forecast in September by C$7 a tonne to the C$150-170 range from August's world price estimate of C$157-177 because of higher European barley output prospects.</p>
<p>Winnipeg Commodity Exchange barley traders and industry analysts speculated the CWB would reduce its October price forecast again when it is issued at 1400 CDT Thursday.</p>
<p>Some of them said they expect the outlook to fall below the federal government's guaranteed price to farmers which could keep supplies away from the domestic market.</p>
<p>About 30 percent of Canada's barley is exported, and the remainder is fed to livestock or used in brewing.</p>
<p>The Canadian government guaranteed the CWB's initial, or partial downpayment, for No1 Canada Western Feed Barley at C$137 a tonne.</p>
<p>-- Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
