<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133081" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: De Klerk, P.W. Botha weather storm of accusations.</title>
<headline>De Klerk, P.W. Botha weather storm of accusations.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior apartheid-era policemen have implicated former South African presidents P.W. Botha and F.W de Klerk in bombings and raids to preserve white power, but neither looks likely to end up in court.</p>
<p>The agents of apartheid, squeezed by prosecutors and the &quot;truth commission&quot;, are at last beginning to talk.</p>
<p>But political analysts said while the secrets they are revealing may illuminate, they will make little difference.</p>
<p>Botha is a discredited elderly man whose bad reputation could hardly be worsened by the accusation on Monday, by apartheid's last police chief Johan van der Merwe, that he ordered black activists' offices to be blown up.</p>
<p>&quot;He sanctioned subversion and financed armies elsewhere in southern Africa that led to half a million deaths. If he also blew up a building used by his opponents, this won't cause shockwaves,&quot; said political scientist Tom Lodge.</p>
<p>The truth commission, set up to uncover the past in an effort to heal it, warned Botha on Tuesday it expected him to answer the allegations and would subpoena him if he did not.</p>
<p>De Klerk, who ousted Botha in 1989, paved the way to democracy in 1994 and still leads the white-dominated National Party, has more to lose from damaging claims.</p>
<p>Senior apartheid policemen who applied to the Truth and Reconciliation Commission on Monday for amnesty, for crimes they say were politically motivated, said they doubted de Klerk was as innocent as he protests.</p>
<p>An apartheid police assassin also claimed de Klerk knew all about dirty deeds and had ordered a 1993 raid into a black homeland in which five children were killed.</p>
<p>De Klerk, who has apologised for apartheid, dismissed the allegations and says he never knowingly authorised assassination, murder, torture, rape or assault.</p>
<p>Whatever disclosures are still to come, commentators believe a trial of the two surviving apartheid presidents for alleged human rights abuses is not practicable.</p>
<p>The evidence is likely to be flimsy, as seen in this month's acquittal of ex-defence minister Magnus Malan, accused of approving a hit squad that massacred children.</p>
<p>&quot;Proving the chain of command is extremely hard,&quot; said Kenneth Christie of the University of Natal in Durban.</p>
<p>What everyone agrees on is that the atmosphere in the dying days of apartheid in the late 1980s was one of war.</p>
<p>Both sides, to varying degrees, committed atrocities. If trials are pursued, African National Congress (ANC) leaders could be affected as much as old white adversaries.</p>
<p>&quot;What you would really need is a war crimes tribunal,&quot; Christie said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you did that you would need to bring in the ANC too. There are too many vested interests.&quot;</p>
<p>Instead, South Africa has its truth commission.</p>
<p>De Klerk has appeared before Archbishop Desmond Tutu's commission on behalf of his party and will be called back for cross-examination at a later date.</p>
<p>Botha, who says he did only the best for his country, has refused to cooperate with the inquiry but may now be dragged before it.</p>
<p>While President Nelson Mandela is trying to reconcile his nation, for many blacks who suffered under white rule a bit of revenge would also be sweet.</p>
<p>Some find it hard to understand that being to blame for apartheid is not cause enough to mete out punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;The real immorality was not what was done to defend apartheid,&quot; commented Lodge. &quot;It was apartheid itself.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
