<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133072" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Zambia puts fertiliser producer up for sale.</title>
<headline>Zambia puts fertiliser producer up for sale.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zambian government has put fertiliser producer Nitrogen Chemicals of Zambia up for sale under a continuing privatisation programme, the Zambia Privatisation Agency said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Offers are invited for the acquisition of at least a 70 percent shareholding Nitrogen Chemicals of Zambia,&quot; the agency said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company, located 45 kilometres south of the capital, manufactures explosive grade ammonium nitrate, chemical fertilisers and industrial chemicals.</p>
<p>It commands a 50 percent market share for fertilisers in the country, constituting 80 percent of its sales volume. It also supplies dense ammoniuim nitrate and sulphuric acid to Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines (ZCCM) and exports diammonium phosphate to Zimbabwe, solubar to South Africa and fertilisers to Zaire.</p>
<p>It has an annual turnover of about $8 million, but is operating below its full potential.</p>
<p>&quot;The company is currently operating below capacity due to liquidity problems and is unable to meet demand for its products,&quot; the privatisation spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the tender for the acquisition of government's shares in the company were open until December 13, 1996.</p>
<p>-- Jowie Mwiinga, Lusaka newsroom, +26 01 222-689</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
