<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133021" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Imperial has weak Q3, strong year-to-date.</title>
<headline>Imperial has weak Q3, strong year-to-date.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imperial Oil Ltd, Canada's biggest energy company, on Tuesday continued the trend in Canada's integrated oil sector to weaker third-quarter earnings amid high refining costs and a harsh retail gasoline environment.</p>
<p>However, Imperial, 69.6 percent owned by U.S. energy giant Exxon Corp, reported that its nine-month results were the company's highest.</p>
<p>In the third quarter, Toronto-based Imperial earned C$99 million or C$0.58 per share, down from C$138 million or C$0.72 per share the year before.  </p>
<p>Revenues in the period totalled C$2.6 billion, up from C$2.4 billion in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Nine-month earnings were C$588 million or C$3.24 per share, up from C$421 million or C$2.18 per share in 1995.</p>
<p>The company reported January to September revenues of C$7.6 billion, an increase from C$7.4 billion last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite weaker third-quarter earnings and an especially competitive petroleum products market, our year-to-date results are the best ever,&quot; Imperial chairman and chief executive Bob Peterson said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Imperial's 1996 profits include a gain of C$250 million from a C$840-million tax refund the company pocketed earlier this year.</p>
<p>One of the company's main competitors, Shell Canada Ltd, also reported lower third quarter earnings on Tuesday, citing tough business conditions in the downstream market.</p>
<p>Third-quarter earnings in Imperial's petroleum products division were C$26 million, a big drop from the C$56 million earned last year.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a factor across the board where you had crude oil costs increasing during the quarter and because of the competitive market in all products and not really able to recover some of that increased costs in the marketplace, so margins are certainly smaller,&quot; said Imperial spokesman Richard O'Farrell.</p>
<p>Quebec was the battleground for gasoline price wars during the quarter, which saw margins squeezed hard.</p>
<p>O'Farrell declined to comment on the company's downstream outlook beyond the third quarter.  </p>
<p>The company's upstream oil and gas division reported earnings of C$600 million during the quarter, up from C$529 million in 1995.</p>
<p>O'Farrell said higher prices for its commodities were partly offset by a drop in conventional oil and Cold Lake, Alberta bitumen volumes.</p>
<p>Crude oil and gas liquids production during the quarter averaged 251,000 barrels per day, down from 293,000 in the same period last year. Imperial sold 295 million cubic feet per day of natural gas, down from 380 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Imperial's huge Cold Lake heavy oil project has seen its volumes decline since last winter when frigid weather pushed back maintenance and drilling schedules.</p>
<p>&quot;It is later than anticipated but there are some indications in the latter part of the quarter and the early part of this quarter that show this is coming on stream,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Calgary Bureau 403 531-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
