<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133086" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South Africa extends tax amnesty.</title>
<headline>South Africa extends tax amnesty.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel on Tuesday announced new measures to persuade errant South African taxpayers to own up and start paying their dues.</p>
<p>The measures, which will go into effect between November 1 and February 28, will include a repeat of last year's general tax amnesty as well as new measures to provide relief to existing taxpayers.</p>
<p>But Deputy Finance Minister Gill Marcus warned that there would be no further amnesties and this was the last chance to come clean &quot;before the full weight of the envigorated new revenue services comes into play.&quot;</p>
<p>The amnesty would be reintroduced for people who were not registered on April 26, 1994 and they would be exempted from liability for taxes due before February 28, 1994. They would not have to pay interest, penalties and additional taxes.</p>
<p>Taxpayers who had under-declared their taxes due would also be able to apply for relief from interest, penalties and extra tax due as a result of full disclosure.</p>
<p>Registered taxpayers who had fallen into arrears on income tax, employers tax or VAT would also be able to apply for relief as would people who had not paid sales tax due.</p>
<p>The legislation covering the new concessions is being considered by the parliamentary finance committee and Manuel said he hoped it would be passed by parliament this session &quot;so that in can kick in on November 1&quot;.</p>
<p>He said it had become clear during the last amnesty that it had not addressed &quot;the situation of registered taxpayers whose arrears, interest, penalties and additional tax...had reached such proportions that they were (and still are) unable to redeem the outstanding amounts.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
