<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133073" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South Africa offers final tax amnesty.</title>
<headline>South Africa offers final tax amnesty.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa on Tuesday offered errant taxpayers a fresh amnesty, which it said would be their last chance to own up and start paying their dues.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel announced a repeat of last year's general tax amnesty and new measures providing relief to existing taxpayers, which will go into effect between November 1 and February 28.</p>
<p>But Deputy Finance Minister Gill Marcus warned there would be no further amnesties and said this was the last chance to come clean &quot;before the full weight of the envigorated new revenue services comes into play.&quot;</p>
<p>The amnesty was to be reintroduced for people not registered on April 26, 1994, and offer exemption from tax liabilities due before February 28, 1994. They will also be exempted from the payment of interest, penalties and additional taxes.</p>
<p>Taxpayers who had under-declared their taxes would be able to apply for similar relief.</p>
<p>Registered taxpayers who have fallen into arrears on income tax, employers tax or VAT will likewise be able to apply for relief.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that in dealing with the matter in this way, we will bring people back into the system,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>Manuel estimated that about 420,000 taxpayers who were previously in the system had stopped paying tax and by February owed 6.7 billion rand ($1.47 billion).</p>
<p>($=4.57 rand)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
