<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133090" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya shilling slightly firmer against the dollar.</title>
<headline>Kenya shilling slightly firmer against the dollar.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Kenyan shilling firmed against the dollar on Tuesday in a moderately active market, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Central Bank of Kenya posted a mean shilling rate of 55.78 against the dollar from 55.83 on Friday. On the pound, it was posted at 88.83 from 88.56 on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Exporter sales into the market sent the shilling on a rally against the dollar as sentiment continued to help favour it's bullish tone,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Exporters put more pressure on the dollar, resisting intervention attempts by the central bank to prop up the dollar,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>A commercial banker said the market remained stable at 55.75/85, unchanged from Friday with further depreciation of the dollar being halted by players covering their short positions.</p>
<p>Over the next week a test of the 55.50 level is expected with players striving to stay short dollar.</p>
<p>The overnight money market was short with many banks on the borrowing side. Rates were quoted at 20-24 percent from 20-23 percent on Friday.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
