<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133039" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Governor of Burundi's troubled north region killed.</title>
<headline>Governor of Burundi's troubled north region killed.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governor of Burundi's troubled northwestern Cibitoke province was killed in an ambush by suspected Hutu rebels on Tuesday, a military spokesman said.</p>
<p>He told Reuters that Lieutenant-Colonel Marcel Senarenze was ambushed along with several other people, including his aides and bodyguards.</p>
<p>&quot;The governor of Cibitoke was killed today in an ambush along with several other people. I can confirm that he is dead,&quot; the military spokesman said.</p>
<p>But in the Kenyan capital Nairobi, Innocent Nimpagaritse, a spokesman for the main Burundian Hutu rebel group, said Senarenze was not killed in an ambush but in fighting in eastern Zaire where he said Burundi's army had reinforced Banyamulenge Tutsi rebels in their conflict with the Zairean army.</p>
<p>Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army is engaged in a vicious guerrilla war with Hutu rebels fighting for a greater political stake in the tiny military-controlled central African state.</p>
<p>But Nimpagaritse said Senarenze had been in command of Burundian troops helping out the Banyamulenge inside Zaire.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge, like Burundi's army, are ethnic Tutsis who came to Zaire from Rwanda at the end of the 18th century.</p>
<p>They are currently locked in heavy fighting with Zaire's ragged army in the eastern Zairean town of Uvira. Zaire accuses its neighbours of supporting the Banyamulenge in a conflict analysts say could draw in Rwanda and Burundi's army.</p>
<p>A quarter of a million ethnic Hutu refugees have fled their camps in eastern Zaire because of the fighting which U.N. officials warned could trigger a humanitarian disaster.</p>
<p>But Burundi's chief of staff insisted Senarenze was killed by Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;It was Hutu rebels who killed the governor along with others,&quot; said Major Gabriel Sabushimike.</p>
<p>After more than a year of fighting Hutu rebels have left Burundi's northwestern Cibitoke province a virtual no-go area for the Tutsi-dominated army. All aid work in the province is suspended.</p>
<p>More than 150,000 people have died in Burundi's ethnic war over the last three years. Aid workers estimate the death toll is running at 1,000 a month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
