<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133038" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: U.N. says disaster looms in east Zaire.</title>
<headline>U.N. says disaster looms in east Zaire.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>BUKAVU, Zaire 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations on Tuesday evacuated 48 aid workers trapped in eastern Zaire by fighting between the army and ethnic Tutsis and said the region was on the brink of yet another humanitarian disaster.</p>
<p>As tens of thousands of exhausted Hutu refugees and displaced Zaireans trudged north towards the provincial capital of Bukavu, one report from near Goma in the north of the volatile refugee zone suggested fighting was spreading there.</p>
<p>&quot;I am deeply worried by the widening scale of violence in eastern Zaire in recent weeks,&quot; Sadako Ogata, U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, said in a statement in Geneva.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless all parties to this conflict step back, we are, I am afraid, heading toward a humanitarian catastrophe.&quot;</p>
<p>Zaire accuses Rwanda's Tutsi-led army of using the Banyamulenge, ethnic Tutsis who came from Rwanda in the late 18th century, to destabilise its eastern provinces. The Banyamulenge accuse Zaire of forcing them to leave.</p>
<p>The fighting has fuelled fears that the Tutsi and Hutu rivalry which triggered the 1994 genocide in Rwanda and the equally bitter civil war in Burundi could engulf the whole Central African Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>Humanitarian sources said as many as 10,000 weary refugees were on Bukavu's doorstep and that up to 1,000 had already entered the city. One source said relief food stocks in the region were running low.</p>
<p>&quot;Fighting has been reported around three of the biggest refugee camps in all of eastern Zaire, in the Goma region,&quot; U.N. spokesman Ron Redmond said in Geneva. &quot;We can't confirm the reports, but we are taking them very seriously as they come from the military...If it is true, it is very alarming.&quot;</p>
<p>Humanitarian sources spoke of an attack around Kamanyola refugee camp in the south. Unconfirmed reports spoke of Rwandan troops being involved.</p>
<p>Witnesses reported armed soldiers walking with refugees. &quot;The fact that Zairean soldiers themselves are withdrawing is adding to the panic amongst refugees,&quot; one relief source said.</p>
<p>The exodus, involving up to a quarter of a million Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi, followed a flare-up on Friday in fighting between Zairean soldiers and Banyamulenge Tutsi rebels in the town of Uvira, 100 km (65 miles) south of Bukavu.</p>
<p>There was no reliable death toll from the fighting. Relief workers said local staff in the Uvira area had asked for 78 body shrouds and had spoken of 60 wounded, mostly civilians.</p>
<p>Earlier reports had 28 civilians killed near Uvira on Friday and a Zairean soldier killed near Goma in the north on Sunday.</p>
<p>Bukavu, until now unaffected by the chaos around Uvira, was tense with signs that civilians were stocking up on food.</p>
<p>Belgium advised its nationals to leave the region.</p>
<p>The evacuated U.N. workers were flown initially from an airport outside Uvira to Bukavu. Most were flown on to Uganda and Kenya, aid workers said.</p>
<p>The U.N. said aid workers would not return to the Uvira area until security had improved.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw tens of thousands of refugees on the road,&quot; Reuters photographer Corinne Dufka said after a trip south of Bukavu.</p>
<p>Michelle Quintaglie, spokeswoman for the U.N. World Food Programme in Kenya, said there were indications refugees from other camps were also taking to the road near Bukavu.</p>
<p>Bukavu has 22 camps for Rwandan and Burundian Hutus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
