<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133001" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY  UNION - Lomu citing angers Counties coach.</title>
<headline>RUGBY  UNION - Lomu citing angers Counties coach.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Counties-Manukau coach Mac McCallion is angry Jonah Lomu has been cited for a dangerous tackle just days before the NPC first division rugby final against Auckland, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Lomu is to appear before a New Zealand Rugby Football Union (NZRFU) judicial hearing on Wednesday night after being cited by citing commissioner David Howman.</p>
<p>Howman cited the big All Black wing for an alleged spear tackle on Canterbury fullback Kieran Flynn in the semifinal at Pukekohe on Sunday. The incident was not detected by match officials.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a bloody joke,&quot; McCallion said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no consistency in Howman's rulings.</p>
<p>&quot;I've looked at it on the video and there are a lot of worse things in there. It depends on how you interpret it and read the law book.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm disappointed he's been cited for that. It wasn't malicious and it wasn't intended as a spear tackle.</p>
<p>&quot;Some things happen in a contact sport. I wonder what they're trying to turn the game into?&quot;</p>
<p>McCallion was also upset that the hearing meant Lomu would miss Counties' training session on Wednesday night.  </p>
<p>Under the NZRFU's penalties for player misconduct, Lomu faces a suspension of up to six weeks which would rule him out of this Sunday's final against Auckland, and the Barbarians' tour to England next month.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
