<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133064" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Offshore dollar sales helped the rand off its worst levels of the day towards the close on Tuesday after it slid to a two-month low in early morning activity.</p>
<p>The rand ended at 4.5705/5755 against the dollar from 4.5650/5750 at 1400 GMT on Monday. In early trade it fell as low as 4.5765 bid on the dollar, its lowest level since August 19 when it touched an all-time low of 4.59 in after-hours trade.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a bit of selling of dollars out of London this afternoon which gave the rand a bit of a boost,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders said the rand had difficulty in breaking dollar support at the 4.57 level.</p>
<p>&quot;It tried to get through 4.57 (on the downside) a few times, but there was some support there,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The rand was driven weaker in early dealings by offshore dollar demand, coupled with local importer demand and short-covering, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rand tested the 4.57 psychological level in early trading. There were a lot of offshore stop losses between 4.57 and 4.5750 and the rand ran up in panicky trade,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>However, the Reserve Bank was present in the market, supplying dollars above the 4.5750 level, thereby capping the rand's fall.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the Reserve Bank) were there adding liquidity. It was more of a smoothing of the fall, it was not aggressive,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The bank's involvement helped the rand retrace to a 4.5720-50 band around noon after which offshore dollar sales helped it back to near 4.57 in quiet trading around the close.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rand was expected to trade in a 4.5650-5850 range on Wednesday, with 4.60 on the cards if it broke above this range.</p>
<p>&quot;I see it ratcheting higher slowly for the next couple of sessions reaching 4.60 if the it breaks out of the range,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand sank to yet another record low against the British pound touching 7.3067 bid in after-hours trade from 7.2561/2663 late on Monday. On the mark, the rand was last at 0.3353/3357 from 0.3361/0.3366 before.</p>
<p>On the bond market the yield on the key R150 was unchanged at its overnight levels of 15.375 percent, retracing from earlier weakness as the rand improved.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a bit of short-covering on bonds as the rand improved,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Trading had been thin amid nervousness on the rand and ahead of September consumer inflation figures due out at 0900 GMT on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to a Reuters poll of 12 economists, the September consumer price index will rise 8.1 percent year-on-year or 0.7 percent month-on-month after rising 7.5 percent and 0.7 percent in August.</p>
<p>Traders said bonds were likely to start off Wednesday range-bound in a 15.35-15.45 percent band ahead of the data. Yields were likely to remain in the bottom end of the range, unless the rand weakened further.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely to spike above 15.42 percent unless the rand breaks the 4.58 level,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures show foreigners sold a net 47.77 million rand worth of South African bonds on Monday after buying a net 197.40 million rand on Friday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 2.51 billion rand from 3.69 billion rand on Friday.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs edged higher on Tuesday to be quoted at between 16.15 percent bid and 16 percent from at between 16.10 percent bid and 15.95 percent on Monday. The 90-day BA rate lifted to between 15.55 and 15.40 percent from between 15.55 and 15.35 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank indicated the daily shortage at 8.0 billion rand on Monday from 7.744 billion rand on Saturday.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
