<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133084" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse opens week on stable note.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse opens week on stable note.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange opened on a stable note for the week on Tuesday, with the index dipping slightly to stand at 3038.75 from 3039.89 on Friday, brokers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted 5.655 million shillings traded on 183,312 shares from 5.366 million shillings traded on 164,393 shares on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Usually the first day of trading for the week is very very dull, but the market opened at almost the same level of turnover as last week's closing,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>Monday was a bank holiday in Kenya.</p>
<p>Bourse officials said that the turnover was still low and that most share prices remained stable.</p>
<p>Rea Vipingo Plantations traded 22,200 shares at 10.40, Kenya Airways traded 33,125 shares at 9.50 from 9.55 on Friday, Uchumi Supermarket gained 0.50 cents to close at 47 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of interest in Diamond Trust Bank shares at the 36 shillings level,&quot; said a senior broker. &quot;A lot of investors appear to have confidence in the management of the bank,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;In the Industrials and allied, Firestone East Africa appears to attract a lot of interest in investors, the motor vehicle industry seeming quite stable,&quot; said the broker.</p>
<p>Foreign investors bought 14,600 shares of Firestone East Africa, and 200 shares of Cooper Motor Corporation (CMC) Holdings at 64.50 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, all the shares are a good buy at the moment as many of them are at their lowest price,&quot; added another broker.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
