<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133004" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - NZCC draft opposes rugby transfer rules.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - NZCC draft opposes rugby transfer rules.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand Commerce Commission said in a draft ruling on Tuesday that it would not authorise proposed rugby union transfer rules on the information currently available to it.</p>
<p>The Commission said its decision was based on examining the relationship between rugby unions in the trading of rights to players' services.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission's preliminary view is that the cap on the number of players a union can acquire, the transfer fees it must pay and the restriction of transfers to November only, all substantially lessen competition,&quot; it said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;The cap on player numbers prevents competing unions acquiring player services and the cap on transfer fees is a form of price fixing. The Commission preliminary conclusions are that both detriments and benefits from the arrangements are small, and it is not satisfied that benefits outweigh detriments.&quot;</p>
<p>The New Zealand Rugby Football Union has until November 6 to make submissions on the draft ruling, and a conference is planned for November 18-20 to give the NZRFU and interested parties the chance to make submissions.</p>
<p>The Commission said it would release a final decision by about December 17. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
