<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13303" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hollywood's political outlay $23.5 million - paper.</title>
<headline>Hollywood's political outlay $23.5 million - paper.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The entertainment industry has contributed at least $23.5 million to the major political parties, political action committees and national candidates since 1991, the Los Angeles Times reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>Citing an analysis of federal election records, the paper found that Hollywood overwhelmingly supported Democrats, contributing nearly 10 times as much money to the Democratic National Committee than to its Republican counterpart and seven times more to President Bill Clinton's re-election bid than to that of Republican Bob Dole.</p>
<p>Among the biggest givers were all three members of DreamWorks SKG -- Steven Spielberg, Jeffrey Katzenberg and David Geffen -- who gave a total of nearly $1.5 million to Democratic causes, along with such famous personalities as Barbra Streisand, Dustin Hoffman and rock musician Don Henley.</p>
<p>Streisand contributed more than $142,000, Henley $107,685 and Hoffman $96,500.</p>
<p>Other big givers included Paul Newman with $72,500, jazz musician Lionel Hampton, $84,034, and Sylvester Stallone, $50,200. Stallone contributed $29,000 to Republicans and $21,000 to Democrats, the paper said.</p>
<p>Film producer Steven Tisch gave $283,500.</p>
<p>Appearing high on the list of industry givers were some relatively unfamiliar names. Gail Zappa, widow of rock musician Frank Zappa, gave $218,000 in political contributions, largely to Democrats.</p>
<p>The biggest beneficiaries of Hollywood's generosity were California's two Democratic senators, Dianne Feinstein and Barbara Boxer, followed by former Representative Mel Levine, a Democrat whose district included Los Angeles' Westside.</p>
<p>Feinstein received $589,609, Boxer $442,777 and Levine $401,625.</p>
<p>Clinton's primary campaign ranked fifth in donations from the entertainment industry with $381,390, while Bob Dole came in 27th with $55,250.</p>
<p>Ranked sixth was Sen. Edward Kennedy. The Massachusetts Democrat received $247,371.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
