<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133055" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: JCI gold mines lift profit, output rises.</title>
<headline>JCI gold mines lift profit, output rises.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>JCI Ltd's three gold mines reported increased profit after tax on Tuesday, lifting earnings almost 17 percent to 128.24 million rand in the three months to end-September from 109.71 million in the June quarter.</p>
<p>Gold output increased to 11,049 kg from 10,608 kg, although tonnes milled fell to 2,713,000 tonnes from 2,733,000. The average yield was 4.07 grams per tonnes against 3.88.</p>
<p>&quot;The above was a consequence of an increase in both gold production of 4.2 percent to 11,409 kg and a 6.8 percent improvement in the gold price combined with a containment of total working costs to a 9.6 percent increase,&quot; JCI said.</p>
<p>Average unit costs rose to 46,961 rand per kg from 44,624, while average revenue was 54,982 rand per kg from 51,479.</p>
<p>The star performer in the JCI stable was H.J. Joel Mining Co Ltd. The mine almost doubled profit after tax to 41.01 million rand in the September quarter from 21.00 million in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We are achieving far better results than we had forecast,&quot; JCI gold and uranium operations chief executive John Brownrigg told a results presentation.</p>
<p>Brownrigg said the 1,600 kg of gold produced at Joel in the September quarter, up from the 1,241 kg in the June quarter was an all-time record.</p>
<p>He said the mine's working costs continued to fall. Unit working cost for the quarter under review was 36,805 rand/kg.</p>
<p>&quot;Within the next two quarters, H.J. Joel will be lowest cost producer (in South Africa),&quot; Brownrigg said.</p>
<p>JCI said it benefitted from full calendar operations at the mine.</p>
<p>&quot;Full calendar operations are in place generating significant benefits for both company and employees and current levels of production are expected to be maintained, if not improved on, during the coming quarter,&quot; JCI said in a results statement.</p>
<p>Western Areas Gold Mining Co Ltd reported a 11.6 percent increase in profit after tax. The mine lifted earnings in the September quarter to 49.79 million rand from 44.61 million in the preceding quarter.</p>
<p>Although the average yield decreased, gold production increased to 4,436 kg from the 4,263 kg in the June quarter.</p>
<p>JCI attributed the increase in output to a 7.1 percent increase in tonnes milled to 706,000 in the September quarter from 659,000 tonnes in June.</p>
<p>Randfontein Estates Gold Mining Co Ltd reported a 15.1 percent drop in profits in the September quarter to 37.44 million rand from 44.10 in the three months to end-June.</p>
<p>JCI said this was due to lower tonnes milled and a drop in yield.</p>
<p>&quot;However, during the second half of the quarter there was an improvement in recovery grade which we believe is sustainable,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
