<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133093" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST-S.Africa 97 growth down to 2.5 pct - Sanlam.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-S.Africa 97 growth down to 2.5 pct - Sanlam.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sanlam investment company sees South Africa's economic growth slowing to 2.5 percent next year in what chief economist Johan Louw termed a moderate growth recession.</p>
<p>&quot;The South African economy is showing signs of decelerating,&quot; Louw said in his October economic survey.</p>
<p>He cited as contributing factors sustained high interest rates, weakening business confidence, a marked decrease in the inflow of foreign capital and expectations of a significant tightening of fiscal discipline in next year's March budget.</p>
<p>&quot;All in all, we estimate that the real economic growth rate will be of the order of 2.5 percent in 1997 in comparison to an estimated 2.9 percent in 1996,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Louw said he did not expect a reduction in the bank rate before the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>He said an improvement in the current account of the balance of payments and a slowing demand for credit should lead to easier money market conditions, but low foreign reserves would prevent an early relaxation of fiscal policy.</p>
<p>Louw said inflation was likely to rise, but not to double digit levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The prices of consumer services will continue to exert upward pressure on the overall consumer price index,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The depreciation of the rand against foreign currencies, wage increases significantly higher than inflation, a new wave of food price hikes and fuel price increases would keep pressure on the inflation rate.</p>
<p>&quot;We now expect an average inflation rate of 7.2 percent for 1996 and one of between 8.5 percent and nine percent in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Louw said sentiment towards the rand appeared to be improving and he predicted a stabilisation and possible firming against foreign currencies.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the rand is currently undervalued and that the prospects for an improvement on the current account of the balance of payments will contribute to a more stable and possibly firmer rand during the rest of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We foresee that the rand/dollar exchange rate will fluctuate between 4.45 and 4.55 in the next few months,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 23 2258</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
