<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133020" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Noranda blames poor metals prices for Q3.</title>
<headline>Noranda blames poor metals prices for Q3.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natural resources giant Noranda Inc reported lower third quarter earnings on Tuesday, blaming the downfall on lower metals volumes and lower prices for metals and newsprint.</p>
<p>Third quarter profits clocked in at C$51 million or C$0.20 per share, down from C$128 million or C$0.55 a share for the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>The decrease stems from lower copper, aluminum, nickel and newsprint prices as well as decreased volume from the mining and metals operations, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Higher gas, oil and lumber prices help offset the decline.  </p>
<p>Noranda said the profits included one-time gains of C$22 million from Noranda's stake in Falconbridge Ltd less the costs associated with this summer's merger between Hemlo and Battle Mountain Gold Co.</p>
<p>Noranda owns 28 percent of Battle Mountain Gold.</p>
<p>Noranda's mining and metals group earned C$22 million in the third quarter compared to C$99 million last year.</p>
<p>Lower volumes from the company's Brunswick aluminum operation and from Falconbridge's base metals mine at Kidd Creek in Northern Ontario contributed to lower earnings, Noranda said.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking toward 1997 we are optimistic that commodity prices, particularly some of the metals, will improve,&quot; chairman David Kerr said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We have several projects in hand designed to increase profitability.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416-941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
