<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13315" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac pledges to enforce tough immigration laws.</title>
<headline>Chirac pledges to enforce tough immigration laws.</headline>
<byline>Helene Fontanaud</byline>
<dateline>BREGANCON, France 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac pledged on Sunday to stick to France's strict immigration laws despite a furore over a police roundup of Africans in a Paris church.</p>
<p>A group of 10 hunger strikers among the Africans seized in Friday's swoop on the Saint-Bernard church decided to call off a 52-day fast after they were released from detention with about 40 other people on Sunday, a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Only a handful of the 210 Africans originally arrested in the church, where they were protesting against expulsion orders, are still in formal custody after a string of releases by police and court rulings in the Africans' favour.</p>
<p>Most, however, still face expulsion orders being contested in courts by their lawyers. France deported four of the Africans, most of whom are from Mali, Senegal and Zaire, by plane on Saturday.</p>
<p>Chirac, ending his silence since the raid that brought condemnation from left-wing opposition parties and human rights groups, said he wanted to send a &quot;strong signal&quot; to discourage potential immigrants from poor countries.</p>
<p>But the conservative president also said France should review details of the implementation of controversial 1993 immigration laws, which outlawed some immigrants previously living legally in France, and promote aid to poor nations.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no question of the government changing policy but the government will have the heart to see how the practice of the laws must be adapted,&quot; he said after a weekend meeting with Prime Minister Alain Juppe in a Riviera fortress.</p>
<p>He said French people, regardless of their politics, felt &quot;a growing irritation over immigration&quot;.</p>
<p>The hunger strikers were freed after police made an about-turn and decided not to seek to extend their custody. But police said only one of them would qualify for a residence permit and the rest would be expelled.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to start feeding them again. They've stopped their hunger strike, that makes 52 days today,&quot; the Africans' spokeswoman Madjiguene Cisse said. &quot;They are rejoining the group and will see how to pursue the struggle.&quot;</p>
<p>Tired and drained by the fast, the hunger strikers smiled and were able to walk unaided as they left a detention centre in Vincennes on the eastern edge of Paris. The hunger strikers say they had been drinking only sugared tea and taking vitamins.</p>
<p>Actress Emmanuelle Beart, star of the U.S. blockbuster &quot;Mission Impossible&quot; who has long supported the Africans, turned up at a celebration of the Africans' release in Vincennes. &quot;They've given me a lesson of courage, of dignity,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>About 200 protesters scuffled with police in Paris on the fringes of celebrations of the 52nd anniversary of the liberation of Paris from the Nazis on Sunday but there were no reports of injuries. LCI television said 61 were detained.</p>
<p>Earlier on Sunday, another 40 Africans were freed after their lawyers embarrassed the centre-right government with a string of court victories over detention orders. A judge ruled that unauthorised officials had signed custody documents.</p>
<p>The court that earlier freed the 40 other detainees agreed to extend the detention of 13 other Africans. A separate court sentenced three Africans to jail for up to three months, with another four people getting suspended prison terms.</p>
<p>The government has said that about 30 or 40 percent of all the Africans originally arrested can expect residence permits and the rest would be expelled. The Interior Ministry has said that more than 40 will get residence permits this week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BREGANCON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
