<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133196" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary forint firms vs dlr on forint buyer market.</title>
<headline>Hungary forint firms vs dlr on forint buyer market.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's forint regained some ground against the dollar Tuesday afternoon, tracking the dollar/mark's international movements, on a market dominated by forint buyers, dealers said.</p>
<p>The forint ended at 155.88/93 to one dollar, compared with 155.95/156.00 at midday and 155.71/86 at the opening.</p>
<p>Market bids tracked the National Bank of Hungary's (NBH) resistance level but often rose above the NBH bid and substantial amounts of foreign currencies may have been sold to the central bank, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Almost everybody was a (foreign currency) seller,&quot; said Szabolcs Brezina of Kereskedelmi Bank. &quot;Overnight rates went up a lot and I think many players sold to cover forint needs.</p>
<p>O/n rates rose to 25.75 percent on Tuesday from Monday's 24.00.</p>
<p>Dealers said a deal of some 50 million dollars can usually move the forint a few pips away from the central bank bid.</p>
<p>Mark futures closed firmer for the November and December maturities on the Budapest Commodity Exchange, while the dollar eased for December and February. The Ecu closed mixed, while yen futures mainly dropped. --Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
