<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133109" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Former president P.W. Botha and two of his ministers had ordered police dirty tricks in the 1980s which left several anti-apartheid activists dead or maimed and reduced Khotso House to rubble, former police commissioner Johan van der Merwe said yesterday.</p>
<p>- The National Empowerment Consortium's (NEC) deadline to raise funds for Johnnic has been extended a further 48 hours to cater for those members who have yet to secure financing.</p>
<p>- Black economic empowerment has been identified by government as one of the main goals of the Industrial Development Corporation.</p>
<p>- Investment and private banking group Investec lifted attributable earnings 54 percent to 150.9 million rand for the six months to September, helped by sound organic growth in its local operations and an improved contribution from offshore.</p>
<p>- The taxpayer will fund all legal abortions performed in state institutions in terms of the new legislation before Parliament if amendments are accepted by the parliamentary health committee.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Individual spatial development projects like the Maputo Corridor, aimed at making the South African economy more adaptable to global trade trends and more sensitive to events in regional trade blocs, are on the cards, Alec Erwin, the trade and industry minister, said at the Durban Metro Business Conference yesterday.</p>
<p>- The government plans to amend its growth, employment and redistribution strategy (Gear) by adding the RDP's social goals to it.</p>
<p>- Tobacco stocks ended unscathed on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange yesterday despite the smouldering tension between Nkosazana Zuma, the health minister, and Johann Rupert, the chairman of Rembrandt.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Retired police commissioner Johan van der Merwe and former law and order minister Adriaan Vlok are to apply for amnesty from the Truth and Reconciliation Commission following dramatic new disclosures about their involvement in apartheid-era crimes.</p>
<p>- Moses Sithole, accused of being South Africa's worst serial killer, pleaded not guilty in the Pretoria Supreme Court yesterday to all charges of murder, rape and robbery against him.</p>
<p>- Legal abortions could be performed for as little as 136 rand, according to the Department of Health.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
