<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133146" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Russia cautious, Poland enthusiastic over NATO move.</title>
<headline>Russia cautious, Poland enthusiastic over NATO move.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia reacted cautiously and Poland enthusiatically to U.S. President Bill Clinton's declaration on Tuesday that the United States wanted NATO to recruit new members from former Soviet bloc countries by 1999.</p>
<p>The Russian foreign ministry said it needed to see details of Clinton's speech before commenting, but sacked security chief Alexander Lebed dismissed it as pre-U.S. election posturing.</p>
<p>In a campaign speech widely leaked in advance, Clinton said he wanted NATO to take on its first new members from the former Soviet Union by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;(Clinton's comments) are just a pre-election statement, a kind of pre-election posturing,&quot; Lebed told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no grounds for conflict,&quot; said Lebed, a popular and blunt-speaking former paratroop general and likely future contender for the Russian presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's attitude to NATO's expansion has not changed,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Gennady Tarasov told a routine news briefing before Clinton delivered his speech.</p>
<p>Moscow has long opposed the move, fearing that any NATO expansion would bring Western military might right up to its borders and deprive it of an east European buffer zone.</p>
<p>In contrast, Poland enthusiastically welcomed the speech.</p>
<p>&quot;I greeted with satisfaction U.S. President Bill Clinton's words regarding the timetable of NATO enlargemnent...and the pledge to take a final decision in this matter in the first half of 1997,&quot; President Aleksander Kwasniewski said.</p>
<p>&quot;This conforms with Polish expectations, which I have repeatedly expressed to our Western partners,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Romania also praised Clinton's remarks, saying it was eager for assurances on the alliance's planned eastward drive.</p>
<p>&quot;We hail all political steps and all steps taken regarding NATO's expansion,&quot; President Ion Iliescu's spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be among the first countries admitted to the alliance, in which we see a pillar of security and a guarantee for further development,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are seen heading the queue for NATO membership, but the Supreme Allied Commander in Europe, General George Joulwan, said on Tuesday cooperation programmes with non-members must continue no matter what deadline was set for NATO expansion.</p>
<p>Western political analysts have already said they see the issue of NATO expansion as a key plank of foreign policy in any second term in office for a Clinton administration.</p>
<p>&quot;It (enlargement) was pretty much a done deal, but there can be no question of back-sliding now,&quot; Philip Gordon, an expert on enlargement at London's International Institute for Strategic Studies, said.</p>
<p>Analysts also said Clinton's move threw the gauntlet down to European allies, some of whom were apparently less enthusiastic about eastward expansion.</p>
<p>There was no immediate word from Hungary, this week celebrating the 40th anniversary of the 1956 uprising against Soviet rule, or from the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>Czech officials said earlier on Tuesday that the U.S. Secretary of State, Warren Christopher, had privately expressed concern that Prague's defence spending may be too low.</p>
<p>NATO officials have said post-communist states cannot expect a free ride financed by the West and that their armed forces must be able to work to NATO standards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
