<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133164" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: CA rates Hungary Horizon-Multiplan &quot;sell&quot;.</title>
<headline>CA rates Hungary Horizon-Multiplan &quot;sell&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Creditanstalt Securities rated Hungarian pharmaceuticals company Horizon-Multiplan as &quot;sell&quot; and said the share was overvalued.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that fundamentally the share price cannot be justified. We believe Horizon-Multiplan shares are the most expensive stocks on the Budapest Stock Exchange, so we recommend their sale,&quot; said Daniel Straub, Creditanstalt Securities' Budapest-based analyst.</p>
<p>The average price/earnings ratio on the Hungarian market is just above nine based on 1996 forecasts and around seven based on 1997 estimated results, he said.</p>
<p>According to Creditanstalt Securities' estimates Horizon-Multiplan's P/E is 257 in 1996 and 64 in 1997, he said.</p>
<p>Horizon's share price has steadily risen from 154 forints at its listing on July 25, 1996 to 250 forints now, he said. The subscription price was 154 forints.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Horizon-Multiplan closed at 250 forints, up one.</p>
<p>The share's 154 forint subscription price was based on after-tax profit forecasts of 43 million, 371 million and 658 million forints for 1996, 1997 and 1998, respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;It's questionable whether, after the IAS loss of 27 million forints in 1994, the 3.5 million forints profit in 1995 and the 1996 first half results, these profit forecasts are realistic,&quot; Straub said.</p>
<p>To achieve its forecast of a tripling of sales revenues in 1996, Horizon-Multiplan needs to sell 480,000 units of Humet-R -- a health supplement containing trace elements -- compared to 200,000 in 1995 and only 60,000 in the first seven months.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course it can't be excluded that after the planned launch of foreign sales (in H2 1996), the rise in exports will somewhat compensate for a weaker performance on the domestic market. Still, the target of 480,000 units seems brave,&quot; Straub said.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
