<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133132" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: OSCE postpones Bosnian polls, Western official.</title>
<headline>OSCE postpones Bosnian polls, Western official.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The international organisation in charge of Bosnia's polls has decided to postpone local elections scheduled for late November due to a lack of cooperation by the parties, a Western official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Municipal elections will be postponed later today because of political difficulties in all areas of the country,&quot; the official told reporters in Sarajevo on condition of anonymity.</p>
<p>Earlier diplomats said the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) was expected to announce within hours a decision to postpone controversial local elections in Bosnia until next spring.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the decision to postpone the polls to be announced later this evening in Sarajevo,&quot; a Western diplomat based in Belgrade told Reuters.</p>
<p>The elections are viewed as the last chance for Bosnia to be reunited after a war that divided the country into ethnic ghettoes. Voting for local officials could pave the way for refugees to return to communities they had been expelled from during 43 months of war.</p>
<p>But critics say polls held in a country with no freedom of movement, uncooperative nationalist leaders and unresolved disputes about voting by displaced people cannot be a success.</p>
<p>Technically the decision rested with Robert Frowick, head of the OSCE mission in Bosnia which supervised Bosnia's first post-war general elections on September 14. It had to postpone local polls because of irregularities in voter registration.</p>
<p>The Western official said a lack of cooperation by Bosnian parties was behind the latest OSCE decision.</p>
<p>&quot;The OSCE is confident it can meet the logistical challenges but if it has the full support and cooperation of the parties,&quot; the official said in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) they are not confident of that support during the four weeks between now and the election day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An independent elections watchdog body welcomed the postponement decision.</p>
<p>&quot;We wholeheartedly welcome the (OSCE decision) to postpone municipal elections,&quot; Hrair Balian, head of Sarajevo office of International Crisic Group told Reuters.</p>
<p>ICG has been actively involved in monitoring Bosnian elections and is largely responsible for revealing irregularities in voter registration this summer which led to the initial postponement of local polls.</p>
<p>Balian said the polls would have been plagued by a lack of freedom of movement, the presence of war criminals and lack of a &quot;credible start on reunification and repatriation of refugees.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that the interval until next spring will be used to improve not only technical but also political conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>The Serbs have already said they will abstain, citing security problems in their villages resettled by Moslems.</p>
<p>But in reality they fear the results of their ethnic cleansing campaigns to create ethnically pure territory could be reversed when Moslem refugees vote in their hometowns where they were once a majority, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Postponement would be a concession to the Serbs who would probably repay it by joining Bosnia's governing bodies after a three-week boycott, diplomats said.</p>
<p>OSCE's choice was stark -- to press ahead with imperfect elections or postpone them and risk unsupervised voting in the future if it does not win an extension of its mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;The best solution would be if everybody agreed to an extension of the mandate and then OSCE could postpone elections with a mind at peace,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the OSCE's mandate extension will be most likely agreed at a meeting of the Steering Board of countries involved in Bosnia's peace implementation in Paris on November 15 or at the Peace Implementation Council meeting in London on December 4 and 5.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
