<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133131" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: EU warns Slovakia against delaying democracy.</title>
<headline>EU warns Slovakia against delaying democracy.</headline>
<byline>Peter Laca</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union's ambassador to Slovakia warned the government on Tuesday against dragging its feet on democratic reform as decisions on bids by former communist countries to join the EU were approaching fast.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Pavol Hamzik has repeatedly said Slovakia should be in the first wave of former East Bloc countries to join the EU and NATO defence alliance.</p>
<p>But EU ambassador Georious Zavvos made clear that Slovakia, which has been beset by political instability, still had much work to do to earn a place in the first wave.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only through its own efforts in the field of democracy, as in the economy, that Slovakia can hope to join the EU,&quot; he told a meeting in the town of Stupava, near Bratislava.</p>
<p>&quot;There is much work to be done and in this task there can be no delay,&quot; Zavvos said in comments released by the European Commission's Bratislava office.</p>
<p>His remarks echoed comments from the U.S. State Department early this month expressing concern that Slovakia's commitment to democracy was weakening.</p>
<p>Referring to EU plans to recruit members from central and eastern Europe, Zavvos said: &quot;The clock is ticking towards the final opinions, negotiations and decisions, which will begin as soon as late 1997. Slovakia must seize the messages and act.&quot;</p>
<p>Slovakia applied formally for EU membership in June 1995. But the EU and United States have formally expressed reservations about the development of democracy since populist Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar returned to power in 1994.</p>
<p>Meciar's coalition, which includes junior partners from the far right and left, is embroiled in a series of disputes with President Michal Kovac, the opposition, leaders of Slovakia's Hungarian minority, the independent media and the medical and acting professions.</p>
<p>Western diplomats privately express exasperation that the Meciar government has responded neither to quiet informal diplomacy nor high-profile diplomatic notes.</p>
<p>Slovakia was once among the favourites for early EU and NATO entry alongside Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary.</p>
<p>But this has been thrown into doubt since Meciar launched a campaign to force President Kovac to resign, apparently in revenge for a parliamentary no-confidence vote which temporarily removed the prime minister from power in 1994.</p>
<p>Kovac's son was later kidnapped and dumped in neighbouring Austria amid allegations of SIS secret service involvement.</p>
<p>Last week Meciar dimissed Western concerns and said there were other, more serious reasons behind them.</p>
<p>Slovakia was under pressure to accept a different economic programme and open itself fully to foreign markets, he said.</p>
<p>The EU was pressing Slovakia to allow foreign capital to enter Slovak banks and allow it free rein in the country. &quot;If we refuse to do this, then their attitude is that there is no democracy (in Slovakia),&quot; Meciar said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
