<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133139" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Serb leader signs away nationalist war aims.</title>
<headline>Serb leader signs away nationalist war aims.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Serb member of Bosnia's new collective presidency has signed an oath of loyalty to the state he and fellow hardline nationalists vowed never to recognise.</p>
<p>Momcilo Krajisnik reluctantly bowed to international pressure on Tuesday evening and put his signature to the &quot;solemn declaration&quot;, pledging to support Bosnian statehood and the U.S.-brokered peace agreement.</p>
<p>After signing the oath, Krajisnik shook hands with his former foes, the Moslem chairman of the presidency, Alija Izetbegovic, and Croat member Kresimir Zubak.</p>
<p>It was a moment without fanfare or ceremony, but for many Sarajevans it symbolised the end of the Bosnian conflict that raged from 1992 to 1995.</p>
<p>Krajisnik was a powerful figure in the Serb leadership which sought to carve out a separate state in Bosnia and divide the capital Sarajevo into two cities, one Serb and one Moslem.</p>
<p>The Serbs, backed by the Yugoslav army, held the upper hand militarily throughout much of the war, tightening their stranglehold on Sarajevo and other towns when it suited them.</p>
<p>But Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, widely blamed for helping to incite the conflict, later forced his Serb proteges to swallow a peace accord after the tide turned against the flagging Serb war machine.</p>
<p>The Serb hardliners were made to accept a treaty that preserves Bosnia as a loose union comprised of a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>Krajisnik had to sign the declaration in Sarajevo's battered national museum, which was repeatedly fired on by Serb gunners laying siege to the city during the war.</p>
<p>Wearing an elegant blue suit, Krajisnik smiled after putting his name to a statement that effectively renounced Serb war aims.</p>
<p>&quot;If this small sacrifice is a contribution to the peace then I will be happy,&quot; Krajisnik said afterward.</p>
<p>He said he was optimistic the common institutions governing post-war Bosnia would succeed.</p>
<p>The joint bodies would function &quot;if we respect each other, if we develop a system of trust, and if we manage to establish equality,&quot; Krajisnik said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the signing merely confirmed what had already become clear, that the Bosnian Serbs have no choice but to abide by the terms of the Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>Diplomats have warned the Serbs they will miss out on badly needed reconstruction aid if they persist in obstructing common institutions.</p>
<p>They said Serb officials have already begun quietly cooperating with plans to set up a single central bank in Bosnia for Serb and Moslem-Croat territories.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bosnian Serb republic cannot survive alone. If it tries, it would slide into the middle ages,&quot; said one Western diplomat.</p>
<p>Krajisnik had refused to sign the oath three weeks ago and boycotted an inauguration ceremony, forcing Western diplomats to wait for hours as his chair stood empty on the stage.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic and Zubak signed the same &quot;solemn declaration&quot; at the earlier ceremony.</p>
<p>Serb deputies to the newly-elected Bosnian parliament were also expected to sign the oath soon, Western mediators said.</p>
<p>Diplomats, including U.S. President Bill Clinton's envoy, John Kornblum, applauded the signing on Tuesday and said it was a boost for the peace process.</p>
<p>The signing took place after a session of the three-man presidency which met for the second time since post-war general elections were held on September 14.</p>
<p>The presidency has been plagued by a dispute over where the body should meet. The presidency members agreed a compromise on Tuesday in which the body would convene alternately in the city centre and the Serb-held suburb of Lukavica.</p>
<p>Kornblum and European envoys also managed to defuse, or at least delay, an impasse over local elections.</p>
<p>International organisers announced the municipal polls set for November would be postponed until next year to allow time to work out innumerable political and logistical difficulties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
