<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133114" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Serb presidency member signs oath to Bosnian state.</title>
<headline>Serb presidency member signs oath to Bosnian state.</headline>
<byline>Samir Koric</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Serb member of Bosnia's collective presidency signed an oath of loyalty to Bosnian statehood on Tuesday in Sarajevo, effectively renouncing Serb war aims to carve out a separate state.</p>
<p>Momcilo Krajisnik, a hardline Serb nationalist, signed the declaration pledging to uphold Bosnia's constitution and the Dayton peace agreement shortly after 8 p.m. (1800 GMT) as foreign dignitaries and reporters looked on.</p>
<p>Krajisnik had refused to sign the oath three weeks ago, boycotting an inauguration ceremony in Sarajevo national theatre.</p>
<p>But the man who peace mediators once dubbed &quot;Mr No&quot; bowed to international pressure on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He had to sign the declaration in Sarajevo's battered national museum, which was repeatedly fired on by Serb gunners laying siege to the city during the war.</p>
<p>Wearing an elegant blue suit, Krajisnik smiled after signing the oath in a small room in the national museum, which straddles a former front line that cut through the city.</p>
<p>Krajisnik then shook hands with the Moslem chair of the presidency, Alija Izetbegovic, and the Croat member, Kresimir Zubak.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a big effort for me to come to Sarajevo after what happened to the Serbs from Sarajevo but I do not regret coming,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;...If this small sacrifice is a contribution to the peace then I will be happy.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats, including U.S. President Bill Clinton's envoy, John Kornblum, applauded the signing and called it a step forward for the peace process.</p>
<p>Krajisnik helped lead a Serb nationalist rebellion against the Bosnian government when it broke from Serbian-dominated Yugoslavia in 1992.</p>
<p>But Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, widely blamed for igniting the conflict, later forced his Serb proteges to accept a peace treaty that preserves Bosnia as a loose union comprised of a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>The signing took place at a session of the three-man presidency which met in Sarajevo on Tuesday for the second time since post-war general elections were held on September 14.</p>
<p>Krajisnik ruined a ceremony three weeks ago at the national theatre, pulling out at the last moment after forcing Western diplomast to wait for hours as his chair stood empty on the stage.</p>
<p>Izetbegovic and Zubak signed the same &quot;solemn declaration&quot; at the earlier ceremony.</p>
<p>After about four hours of talks, the presidency members said they would meet again on Friday on the outskirts of Sarajevo in Serb-held territory and again next week in the city centre.</p>
<p>All three men signed an agreement pledging support to common institutions which are supposed to govern Bosnia under terms of the U.S.-brokered Dayton peace accord reached last November.</p>
<p>The agreement calls for the presidency to meet alternately in Moslem-Croat federation territory or Serb territory in a compromise devised to settle a two-month old dispute.</p>
<p>The collective presidency had been plagued by an argument over where the body should meet.</p>
<p>Krajisnik has resisted holding presidency sessions in Sarajevo, which separatist Serb forces besieged during the Bosnian conflict.</p>
<p>The three men agreed to a &quot;provisional arrangement&quot; in which the presidency would meet at the national museum in the city centre or at the electrical engineering faculty in the Serb-held suburb of Lukavica.</p>
<p>At least every third session would be held in Serb territory, according to the accord.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
