<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133192" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Sanok rubber firm sees no need for partner.</title>
<headline>Polish Sanok rubber firm sees no need for partner.</headline>
<byline>Steven Silber</byline>
<dateline>SANOK, Poland 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main shareholders of Polish rubber producer Stomil Sanok SA, whose initial public offering starts next month, are in no hurry to sell their shares to a strategic investor, Sanok board chairman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jacek Siwicki said the Polish-American Enterprise Fund and two Polish Private Equity Funds, which together hold about 78.7 percent of Sanok, would wait for the firm's various departments to form joint-ventures and thereby increase profits. @</p>
<p>&quot;There's no need to leave quickly because there is still a chance to up share value by cooperating with foreign and domestic partners,&quot; Siwicki told a meeting of journalist and investment analysts at the firm's base in southeastern Poland.</p>
<p>Sanok, Poland's largest producer of technical non-tyre rubber goods, is selling 500,000 shares at 25 zlotys each in a public offering from November 4 to November 15. It currently has 4.7 million shares, all approved for public trade. @</p>
<p>Sanok, whose full name is  Sanockie Zaklady Przemyslu Gumowego Stomil Sanok SA, plans to invest all the proceeds from the issue in buying production machinery and expanding waste control facilities.</p>
<p>President Marek Leski told the meeting that the company planned to invest a total of 29.9 million zlotys this year and 26.1 million next year after having invested 15.7 million zlotys over the past two years. @</p>
<p>He said the firm would try to defend its domestic market share of 65.6 percent for automotive rubber products, 80.4 percent for household appliance rubber products and 78.6 percent for agricultural machinery rubber products.</p>
<p>&quot;A rise of one or two percent annually would be a lot,&quot; Leski told Reuters after the meeting, adding that overall the firm, which also produces for the construction and pharmaceutical industries, had a 49.1 percent market share in non-tyre rubber products market.</p>
<p>Leski said sales could pick up from increasing demand in the auto industry, with Polish subsidiaries of General Motors and Daewoo, among the firm's clients.</p>
<p>Sanok expects to earn net 15 million zlotys this year and 16.9 million zlotys next year on sales of 147 million and 185.4 million zlotys respectively.</p>
<p>Last year Sanok earned net 8.2 million zlotys on 114.2 million zlotys sales.</p>
<p>Leski said the slower 1997 earnings growth would largely result from an end of a tax holiday. @</p>
<p>He said the firm sought to lift exports from 13.4 percent to about 25 percent of sales within the next few years.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANOK, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
