<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133137" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Oct 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - Parliament starts its October session today. The preliminary agenda includes a non-confidence vote against Education Minister Eva Slavkovska and the revision of the six laws returned by President Michal Kovac.</p>
<p>- The preliminary agenda of today's regular government session includes unspecified changes to the law on the state retaining interests in the privatisation of strategic firms, and the development trends of the economy in light of the development of the world economic situation.</p>
<p>- Jan Rencko, a leading economist at the Prognostic Bureau said there was no room left for a further rapid drop in inflation. Rencko said 1997 inflation should stand between six to seven percent, with energy and food prices being the strongest factor hindering its progress.</p>
<p>- Gemerska Horka, a wholly-owned subsidiary of Swedish hygienic paper producer Moelnlycke AB, posted turnover of 925 million crowns in the first nine months of the year, more than in the whole 1995, and said it planned 1996 full year turnover of more than one billion crowns.</p>
<p>- The fate of three Slovak workers kidnapped in Ingushenia, near Chechnya, is still uncertain and the Slovak embassy in Moscow has no information about them.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - The National Property Fund, the state privatisation agency, has offered shares in 155 medium-sized companies to those holding privatisation bonds. The total value of the minority stakes is 7.9 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Economics Minister Karol Cesnek said Slovakia needed to finish construction of the first two blocks of the Mochovce nuclear power plant, due to a potential shortage of electrical energy this winter and because of the advanced stage of completion of the plant.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Peter Mihok, head of the Chamber of Commerce and Industry, said Slovakia still lacked a long-term economic strategy, defining its position in the European and world economic context.</p>
<p>- State-run Slovak Railways will open on Wednesday the first Slovak cargo terminal for combined transport in the eastern regular terminal at Cierna Nad Tisou.</p>
<p>- Major celullose and paper producer SCP Ruzomberok plans to invest some six billion crowns over the next 10 years in modernisation. SCP said it planned turnover of over six billion crowns this year, five percent more than in 1995.</p>
<p>- The chemical company NCHZ said it would invest around 800 million crowns in ecological projects over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
