<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133180" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia plans to host Tajik summit in Moscow.</title>
<headline>Russia plans to host Tajik summit in Moscow.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia said on Tuesday it had invited Tajikistan President Imomali Rakhmonov and his Islamic opponent Said Abdullo Nuri to Moscow as part of efforts to restore peace in the war-ravaged former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>&quot;An inter-Tajik summit will take place in Moscow and the date will be agreed once Mr Nuri has accepted the invitation,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Gennady Tarasov told a regular news briefing.</p>
<p>On Monday Interfax news agency quoted Tajik government spokesman Zafar Saidov as saying the meeting, aimed at getting peace talks going again, could take place as early as this week.</p>
<p>&quot;The government side hopes that this meeting (in Moscow) will speed up a resolution of the Tajik problem by peaceful political means,&quot; Interfax quoted Saidov as saying.</p>
<p>But a leading member of the Tajik opposition suggested that the proposed meeting might not go ahead at all.</p>
<p>&quot;This meeting will probably not take place due to the intransigent attitude of President Rakhmonov,&quot; Ali Akbar Turajonzoda, deputy head of the Tajik united opposition, told Reuters by telephone from Tehran on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The experts (from both sides) who gathered in Tehran on October 15 to 17 (to draw up a peace document for signing in Moscow) failed to work out the slightest compromise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the opposition was seeking the creation of a &quot;council of national reconciliation&quot; that would help govern the country during a transitional period lasting up to 18 months.</p>
<p>&quot;During this transition period Rakhmonov, the government and parliament would stay in place, they would lose nothing and would continue to hold power,&quot; Turajonzoda said.</p>
<p>The opposition's eventual aim was free elections held probably under the auspices of the United Nations, he added.</p>
<p>Since winning its independence nearly six years ago Tajikistan has been battered by a civil war that has pitted pro-Moscow forces against Islamic revivalists and liberals whose leaders are now in exile in Afghanistan, Iran and Russia.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands died in the fighting and nearly a million were displaced in the &quot;hot&quot; civil war of 1992-93.</p>
<p>Russian frontier guards are helping the pro-Moscow government in Dushanbe to resist Islamic Tajik rebels based in neighbouring Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Moscow and Dushanbe, alarmed by the rise to power in Kabul of the hardline Islamic Taleban militia, agreed to tighten security along the Tajik-Afghan border.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TADZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
