<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133135" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: OSCE to postpone Bosnia polls, diplomats.</title>
<headline>OSCE to postpone Bosnia polls, diplomats.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe is expected to announce within hours a decision to postpone controversial local elections in Bosnia until next spring, diplomats said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision to postpone or not is being made as we speak. It would take a miracle to save the elections as scheduled and miracles we are very short of in Bosnia,&quot; a Western diplomat based in Belgrade told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the decision to postpone the polls to be announced later this evening in Sarajevo,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Technically the decision rests with Robert Frowick, head of the OSCE mission in Bosnia which supervised Bosnia's first post-war general elections on September 14. It had to postpone local polls because of irregularities in voter registration.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher said on Monday the U.S. administration has not yet decided whether to recommend delaying municipal elections in Bosnia, which Bosnian Serb leaders have threatened to boycott.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that some of the parties, particularly the Bosnian Serbs...(have) brought forward obstacles to the going forward of the elections, but we have not reached a recommendation on that subject,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the New York Times on Monday quoted U.S. officials as saying the Clinton administration had concluded that the elections should be put off.</p>
<p>The elections are viewed as the last chance for Bosnia to be reunited after a war that divided the country into ethnic ghettoes. Voting for local officials could pave the way for refugees to return to communities they had been expelled from during 43 months of war.</p>
<p>But critics say polls held in a country with no freedom of movement, uncooperative nationalist leaders and unresolved disputes about voting by displaced people cannot be a success.</p>
<p>The Serbs have already said they will not take part, citing security problems in villages in Serb territory resettled by Moslem refugees.</p>
<p>But in reality they fear the results of their ethnic cleansing campaigns to create ethnically pure territory could be reversed when Moslem refugees vote in their hometowns where they were once a majority, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Postponement would be a concession to the Serbs who would probably repay it by joining Bosnia's governing bodies after a three-week boycott, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serb member of Bosnia's three-man presidency, Momcilo Krajsinik, was expected in Sarajevo around mid-day.</p>
<p>Reasons for his visit remain unclear but it fueled speculation that the presidency will hold its first session on Tuesday with all three members attending.</p>
<p>The veunue of the meeting, the national museum building, was on Tuesday morning under NATO's heavy security blanket.</p>
<p>OSCE's choice is stark -- to press ahead with imperfect elections or postpone them and risk unsupervised voting in the future if it does not win an extension of its mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;The OSCE has to decide between fiasco, disaster-prone local elections in November or try to get written assurances for the extension of the mandate and postpone them for next year,&quot; a Western official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The best solution would be if everybody agreed to an extension of the mandate and then OSCE could postpone elections with a mind at peace,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the OSCE's mandate extension will be most likely agreed at a meeting of the Steering Board of countries involved in Bosnia's peace implementation in Paris on November 15 or at the Peace Implementation Council meeting in London on December 4 and 5.</p>
<p>Any postponement of the polls would also force NATO-led peace implementation force IFOR, which provided security for the September 14 elections, to stay on after its mandate expires on December 20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
