<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13317" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: UN veteran Erskine Childers dies of heart attack.</title>
<headline>UN veteran Erskine Childers dies of heart attack.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Veteran diplomat Erskine Childers, whose father was the fourth president of the Irish Republic, died on Sunday of a heart attack, associates said.</p>
<p>Childers, Secretary-General of the World Federation of United Nations Associations (WFUNA), died during the federation's 50th anniversary congress in Luxembourg.</p>
<p>&quot;He was sitting in Congress after giving a speech when he suddenly had breathing difficulties and keeled over,&quot; Federation chairman Malcolm Harper said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;His sudden death is a bitter tragedy for WFUNA,&quot; a statement issued in Brussels said.</p>
<p>Childers, 68, became Secretary General of WFUNA only five months ago after a career that began in academia and ended in 1989 after 22 years working at all levels in the United Nations.</p>
<p>Between leaving the U.N. and taking up his post at the WFUNA, Childers toured extensively lecturing and writing on U.N. matters.</p>
<p>A special session of the Congress was held to pay tribute to him, the Federation statement said.</p>
<p>Childers came from a distinguised Irish family.</p>
<p>His father, also Erskine Childers, who died on November 17, 1974 was only the second protestant to be president of the Irish Republic.</p>
<p>Before him, his father -- also called Erskine Childers -- wrote the best-seller mystery book &quot;The Riddle of the Sands&quot; and was a distinguished naval flying officer in World War One before being executed by the British in 1922 for supporting the nationalist cause.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
