<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133107" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- A 24-year-old man was on Sunday stabbed to death in cold blood in a Blantyre squatter township while his helpless mother watched and neighbours stood by. The stabbing resulted from a quarrel between two families. Neighbours, in a backlash, later gutted the killer's house and destroyed property.</p>
<p>- 12 members of the opposition Alliance for Democracy (AFORD), with its stronghold in Malawi's northern region, have warned that they will turn the area into another Rwanda unless police prevent business tycoon and millionaire Chenda Mkandawire from speakng at presidential rallies. Mkandawire is member of parliament but sides with six other MPs from his party who are serving as cabinet ministers in the Bakili Muluzi government after the party pulled out from a coalition with the ruling United Democratic Front (UDF) party.</p>
<p>- Malawi is among countries with the highest rates of road accidents, suffering 200 deaths for every 10,000 cars registered in Sub-Saharan Africa. Road Safety Council Executive Secretary Robert Cheleuka said Malawi has officially 50,000 vehicles on the road but the fatality rate is higher because the unofficial number of vehicles is higher.</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- The main opposition Malawi Congress Party (MCP) has threatened to seek court intervention if the Electoral Commission does not investigate registration irregularities in the run up to the November 19 by-elections in Blantyre.</p>
<p>- Opposition Malawi Democratic Party (MDP) says it is pulling out of an alliance of nine smaller opposition parties formed over the week-end because some of the members are directors of statutory bodies appointed by President Bakili Muluzi. &quot;Some of them are even chairmen of some parastatal bodies... how can one have his allegiance to Muluzi and at the same time want to form an effective opposition party,&quot; said MDP president Kamulepo Kalua.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
