<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133120" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia wary on Clinton NATO speech, Lebed relaxed.</title>
<headline>Russia wary on Clinton NATO speech, Lebed relaxed.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia reacted cautiously on Tuesday to Bill Clinton's proposal to admit new members into NATO by 1999 but sacked security chief Alexander Lebed dismissed the U.S. president's comments as &quot;pre-election posturing&quot;.</p>
<p>In an election campaign speech widely leaked in advance, Clinton said he wanted NATO to take on its first new members from the former Soviet bloc by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;(Clinton's comments) are just a pre-election statement, a kind of pre-election posturing,&quot; Lebed told Reuters ahead of Clinton's speech in reaction to the leaked content.</p>
<p>Lebed, a politically ambitious and popular ex-soldier sacked last week by President Boris Yeltsin for insubordination, said he did not think Clinton's comments would fuel tensions between Moscow and Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no grounds for conflict,&quot; said Lebed, who is a likely future contender for the Russian presidency.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the Russian foreign ministry said it needed to see the details of Clinton's speech before commenting, but it signalled that its opposition to NATO's expansion had not softened.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's attitude to NATO's expansion has not changed,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Gennady Tarasov told a regular news briefing a few hours before Clinton delivered his speech.</p>
<p>Moscow has often said the expansion of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation to include its former communist era allies risked creating new lines of division.</p>
<p>Clinton, speaking in Detroit at a campaign rally for the November 5 poll, did not name specific countries. But alliance members see Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic as heading the queue.</p>
<p>He said NATO's doors would remain open to others after the first new members were accepted, adding: &quot;NATO will remain open to all of Europe's emerging democracies who are ready to shoulder the responsibilities of membership.&quot;</p>
<p>In remarks clearly aimed at Moscow, he added: &quot;No country outside NATO will have a veto.&quot;</p>
<p>However Clinton, who has a warm personal relationship with Yeltsin, also sounded a conciliatory note, insisting that NATO's enlargement was not directed against anyone and would enhance the security of members and non-members alike.</p>
<p>He called for a formal cooperation agreement between Russia and NATO and said: &quot;We should set up a mechanism for regular NATO-Russia meetings at all levels.&quot;</p>
<p>NATO ministers are to meet in December to pave the way for an alliance summit in 1997 that would name the first candidates for membership and lead to the opening of negotiations.</p>
<p>Lebed, a stern critic of NATO's expansion plans, was hailed by NATO officials during his visit to Brussels as a man they could do business with.</p>
<p>It is not clear how the plain-speaking former paratroop commander plans to rebuild his political career following his sacking.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
