<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133119" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chernomyrdin meets Yeltsin, vows policy continuity.</title>
<headline>Chernomyrdin meets Yeltsin, vows policy continuity.</headline>
<byline>Janet Guttsman</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, fresh from meeting ailing President Boris Yeltsin in a sanitorium, vowed on Tuesday that there would be no departure from current policies &quot;under any circumstances&quot;.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, who discussed a range of issues with Yeltsin at the Barvikha sanatorium near Moscow, told a new tax commission that the president and the government remained committed to creating conditions for economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible to move away from the main political line which we are following, impossible, impermissible and unacceptable under any circumstances,&quot; said the premier in remarks broadcast by NTV commercial television.</p>
<p>Yeltsin is resting in hospital to prepare for heart surgery. A leading U.S. cardiologist who is advising Russian doctors said in an interview published in an Italian newspaper on Tuesday the 65-year-old president was on track for his planned operation in late November and his condition was improving.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are no complications -- and I repeat, there are none right now -- the operation will take place at the end of November, during the last two weeks of the month,&quot; Michael DeBakey told Corriere della Sera.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency quoted Yeltsin's press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky as saying the president was determined to go ahead with the operation to relieve his clogged arteries and was following doctors' orders.</p>
<p>The Kremlin press service said the main topic of the meeting with Chernomyrdin, Yeltsin's constitutional stand-in, was a new power structure announced by the president last week.</p>
<p>The so-called &quot;permanent four&quot; group of officials -- Chernomyrdin, presidential chief of staff Anatoly Chubais and the heads of the two chambers of parliament -- is expected to coordinate key policies during the next three months or so when Yeltsin's condition will restrict his activity.</p>
<p>Yeltsin called for compromise and cooperation after sacking security chief Alexander Lebed last Thursday and bringing in a moderate as secretary of the influential security council.</p>
<p>Lebed's sudden dismissal ignited fears that a bloody war in breakaway Chechnya might resume, but Chernomyrdin ruled this out. Lebed was the architect of a fragile peace deal that halted 21 months of fighting there.</p>
<p>There have been no reports of clashes in the Caucasus region and separatist leaders have indicated they are ready to work with Lebed's successor, Ivan Rybkin.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's press service said the talks with Chernomyrdin also covered the draft 1997 budget which the lower house of parliament rejected last week on a first reading, saying revenue forecasts were hopelessly optimistic.</p>
<p>The two men examined problems in financing the army, where salaries have not been paid for months, and far northern regions which depend on budget funds to get through the harsh winter.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin told the special tax commission that urgent measures had to be taken to improve budget revenues, a reference to the woeful tax collection performance that has deprived the state of funds to pay salaries and fund investment.</p>
<p>One official, quoted by Itar-Tass news agency, said company bosses could be held personally responsible if tax bills were not paid.</p>
<p>The forthcoming wrangling over the budget, one of the few areas where parliament holds real power over the government and president, may have been a factor in Yeltsin's decision to establish the &quot;permanent four&quot; group.</p>
<p>The group includes Gennady Seleznyov, the communist speaker of the opposition-dominated State Duma lower house.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
