<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133124" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Observers say Albania poll mainly free and fair.</title>
<headline>Observers say Albania poll mainly free and fair.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>International observers, including a Council of Europe delegation, monitoring Albania's local elections said on Tuesday voting was mainly free and fair but regretted some irregularities in the poll.</p>
<p>&quot;The delegation of the Council of Europe believes that the elections were free and fair,&quot; Swiss socialist Victor Ruffy told a news conference in Tirana.</p>
<p>&quot;They reflected the will of the electorate and were also the product of thorough administrative and technical preparations that very largely complied with the requirements laid down by the (Council's) parliamentary assembly,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But the Council of Europe monitors expressed some reservations, advising that in future polling stations should be set up in public not private buildings and that results should be published at each polling station.</p>
<p>Sunday's polls were considered a lithmus test for Albania's fledgling democracy after controversial general elections in May and June, boycotted by most opposition parties who alleged the ballot was rigged in favour of the ruling Democratic Party.</p>
<p>The Democrats won 122 seats in the 140-member parliament while the Socialists still refuse to take up the 10 they won.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, which strongly criticised the conduct of the general election, decided not to send a delegation ato the local elections after the government refused to aldmit all its observers.</p>
<p>On Monday, the Democrats said their preliminary results for the local polls showed they had won control of more than 61 percent of city halls, including Tirana, and 58 percent of commune seats.</p>
<p>The Socialists had won just six percent of city halls and commune seats, the Democrats said -- a dramatic slump from the 50 percent they took in the last local elections in 1992.</p>
<p>Official results are due in the next few days.</p>
<p>Ruffy said the Council of Europe and a 163-strong Italian delegation concluded the vote had been good in 67 percent of the cases, satisfactory in 28 percent and bad in five percent.</p>
<p>They had visited 263 voting stations with 178,371 registered voters. There were 4,665 polling stations throughout the Balkan state.</p>
<p>The main opposition Socialist Party, reformed heirs to the former communists, complained of irregularities which they said took place away from the eyes of foreign observers.</p>
<p>&quot;The essence about these elections is that they were not free and fair,&quot; party secretary-general Rexhep Mejdani said.</p>
<p>The U.S. International Republican Institute (IRI) said the polls were an improvement compared to the general election.</p>
<p>&quot;While IRI delegates did notice a number of irregularities and some incidents of intimidation, none appears to have threatened the legitimacy of the elections,&quot; IRI delegation chief William Taft said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
