<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133130" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian presidency to meet Tuesday -- agency.</title>
<headline>Bosnian presidency to meet Tuesday -- agency.</headline>
<dateline>PALE, Bosnia 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The three-man Bosnian presidency will meet on Tuesday at 1330 GMT in Sarajevo, the Bosnian Serb news agency SRNA reported without quoting a source.</p>
<p>This will be the first meeting of all members of Bosnia's collective governing body after its Serb member, Momcilo Krajisnik, failed to attend an inaugural session and swear an oath of allegiance to the Bosnian Constitution three weeks ago.  </p>
<p>The veunue of the meeting, the national museum building, was under NATO's heavy security blanket on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>The SRNA report follows a decision by the international organisation in charge of Bosnia's polls to postpone local elections scheduled for late November due to a lack of cooperation by the parties. The Serbs have already said they will abstain, citing security problems in their villages resettled by Moslems.</p>
<p>Postponement is a concession to the Serbs who would probably repay it by joining Bosnia's governing bodies after a three-week boycott, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Krajisnik will later meet representatives of the so-called Contact Group of western countries and Russia on former Yugoslavia, SRNA said.  </p>
<p>It is the first meeting of all members of Bosnia's collective governing body since its Serb member, Momcilo Krajisnik, failed to attend an inaugural session and swear an oath of allegiance to the Bosnian Constitution three weeks ago.</p>
<p>Before leaving for Sarajevo, Krajisnik told the Bosnian Serb news agency SRNA he would sign the solemn oath as a &quot;sign that problems in the work of the joint bodies have been overcome.&quot;</p>
<p>The venue of the meeting, the national museum building in the centre of the city, was under a heavy NATO security blanket on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>Krajisnik apparently ended the boycott just hours after the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, in charge of Bosnia's polls, postponed local elections scheduled for late November due to a lack of cooperation by the parties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALE, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
