<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133167" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania prints ex-communist spy files on artists.</title>
<headline>Romania prints ex-communist spy files on artists.</headline>
<byline>Karin Popescu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Post-Communist Romania has begun lifting the lid on the activities of dictator Nicolae Ceausescu's dreaded Securitate police by issuing a volume of documents on how its agents observed and hounded intellectuals.</p>
<p>The &quot;White Book of the Securitate -- Literary and Artistic stories 1969-89&quot; was released on Monday, the first of four compilations of secret police misdeeds.</p>
<p>Its revelations amounted to the first tentative cracks in a 40-year ban on Securitate archives imposed after Ceausescu's violent overthrow and execution in 1989 -- unlike those of East Germany's STASI, thrown open to public scrutiny.</p>
<p>The 536-page book, on cheap newsprint, consists of police records submitted by a vast network of informers setting down how writers, artists and musicians criticised Ceausescu.</p>
<p>&quot;Notes&quot; or &quot;reports&quot; set down details of meetings with diplomats or foreign journalists or of interrogations of artists summoned to Securitate headquarters.</p>
<p>But the identites of informers are not disclosed.</p>
<p>&quot;The Securitate does not allow you to bring together a group of people,&quot; an agent referred to as &quot;comrade general&quot; told Dumitru Tepeneag, a well-known novellist, in one note.</p>
<p>&quot;You have no right to speak to others...Anything you discuss in a group outside the organised framework is called illegal activity under our laws.&quot;</p>
<p>One 14-page note shows the penchant for detail by agents observing poet Mircea Dinescu, one of a few intellectuals subject to house arrest after writing a letter of protest against Ceausescu in 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;From 17.07 hours Dinescu and (other guests) were in the room,&quot; the note says of a gathering of cultural figures at the poet's home. &quot;Masa (Dinescu's wife) enters and consults guests if they want tea or coffee...Tea, coffee and snacks are served ...At 22.00 hours the guests leave and the room falls silent.&quot;</p>
<p>The volume shows that intellectuals strongly resisted Ceausescu's authoritarian and megalomaniac rule, though they lacked a leader of stature, like Russia's Alexander Solzhenitsyn or Vaclav Havel in Czechoslovakia.</p>
<p>Released two weeks before general elections, the report was published by top political analyst Ion Cristoiu two weeks after securing permission from the successor to the Securitate -- the Romanian Intelligence Service. Anyone can order a copy by mail for 35,000 lei ($10), one-third the minimum monthly wage.</p>
<p>&quot;This is great satire telling us how some people were followed by an army of other people,&quot; Cristoiu told Reuters. &quot;We decided to publish it now because the floodgates of information could be closed again in Romania at any time.&quot;</p>
<p>The volume is one of a series initially intended for internal use. Others to be published relate the agency's history from the late 1940s until 1977, when Securitate chief Ion Mihai Pacepa defected to the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
