<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133154" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Four Polish banks to offer up to 35 pct of shares.</title>
<headline>Four Polish banks to offer up to 35 pct of shares.</headline>
<dateline>LODZ, Poland 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of four Polish state-owned banks, controlling 20 percent of the country's market, is likely to offer up to 35 percent of its shares to the public late in 1997, its leading bank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to place between 25 and 35 percent of shares on the bourse,&quot; Andrzej Dorosz, president of  Pekao SA, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our ambition is to go public as soon as possible and...realistically speaking this could take place at the end of 1997,&quot; he told a news conference in the city of Lodz. @</p>
<p>Apart from Pekao, the group also includes  Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy SA, based in Lodz,  Bank Depozytowo-Kredytowy SA, based in Lublin, and  Pomorski Bank Kredytowy SA, based in the Baltic port of Szczecin.</p>
<p>Under the deal signed last month, Pekao will receive 100 percent stakes in the three banks by the end of the year, creating Poland's strongest banking group in terms of balance sheet total and own funds.</p>
<p>The creation of the group was sponsored by the government, as part a programme to strengthen Poland's banking system ahead of its full opening to Western competition in 1999. @</p>
<p>Pekao's management board member Igor Halupiec, also present, said the group would not seek a strategic investor.</p>
<p>&quot;Our offer will be aimed at a wide range of foreign and domestic investors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dorosz said the group forecast its gross profit at about one billion zlotys this year after scoring 479 million zlotys in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>The four banks had a balance sheet total of 37 billion zlotys in June 1996 and own funds of nearly two billion zlotys. @</p>
<p>By comparison, state-owned PKO BP, the largest savings bank, had a balance sheet total of 33.4 billion, while the whole banking system has a total of 180 billion zlotys.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LODZ, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
