<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13310" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton in driver's seat on eve of convention.</title>
<headline>Clinton in driver's seat on eve of convention.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>On the eve of the Democratic convention that will nominate him for a second term in the White House, President Bill Clinton remains in the driver's seat in the contest against Republican nominee Bob Dole.</p>
<p>The campaign so far has gone almost exactly as envisaged by White House political strategists, who wanted to enter the convention holding a solid lead against Dole and end it with a healthy bounce for Clinton.</p>
<p>White House political director Doug Sosnik laid out the scenario in an interview with Reuters in the spring. Clinton, he said, would use the months of May, June and July to build up as large a lead as possible over Dole. He would also attempt to define the main issues around which the campaign would be fought.</p>
<p>Sosnik predicted that Dole would make a comeback in August as he chose a running mate and went through the Republican convention. But Clinton would stretch the lead again with the Democratic convention.</p>
<p>Polls suggest Clinton is now leading by between five and 12 percentage points. More importantly, he appears to have control of most, though not all, of the dominant issues in the campaign. And the economy continues to be healthy, especially in the key Midwestern states and California.</p>
<p>&quot;With the economy doing as well as it is, most political models suggest this race may be close but Clinton will win,&quot; said John Geer, a political scientist at Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee.</p>
<p>If Clinton receives even a five point boost in his ratings from his convention this week -- and he could well get more -- he will enter the fall campaign with a 10-17 point advantage. That would be a lot of ground for Dole to make up in the light of past history which shows that the candidate leading the race in early September generally wins.</p>
<p>Al Tuchfarber, a pollster and political scientist at the University of Cincinnati, said Dole needed to be within 8 to 12 points of Clinton in early September to have a chance. Even so, he would have to run the campaign of his life against a president who is generally seen as a superior communicator and debater.</p>
<p>A Reuters-Zogby poll last week revealed that Clinton had essentially held on to his base support through the Republican convention, when Dole's message dominated the air waves. Conversely, Dole has still not managed to fully win back the support of an important element of his natural constituency.</p>
<p>For example, only 65 percent of those who said they had voted for former Republican president George Bush in 1992 intend to back Dole this time. Only nine percent of those who voted for Texas billionaire Ross Perot four years ago currently support Dole.</p>
<p>Three quarters of Clinton's 1992 voters and 21 percent of Perot voters intend to vote for the president. Clinton has the support of 77 percent of Democrats, 10 percent of Republicans and 36 percent of independents. Dole has the backing of 72 percent of Republicans, eight percent of Democrats and only 28 percent of independents.</p>
<p>One major problem for Dole, which refuses to go away, is his age of 73. Almost a quarter of voters who describe themselves as either very conservative or conservative said they strongly agreed with the proposition that Dole was too old to be president. A further 21 percent said they somewhat agreed.</p>
<p>There are few things more tiring than the last eight weeks of a U.S. presidential campaign, which can make even young men look old. Dole is in superb physical shape for his age, but the big test still lies ahead.</p>
<p>The Reuters poll surveyed respondents on their views about 10 issues, asking them to rank them as: most important, very important, somewhat important or not important. The most surprising fact to emerge was that taxes, which Dole has made the centrepiece of his campaign, came out in eighth place in terms of importance.</p>
<p>That is bad news for Dole who is counting on the tax issue to dominate the election. But voters rated education most important, followed by jobs and the economy.</p>
<p>Even the environment, widely seen as a Clinton strength and a Dole weakness, ranked more important than taxes in voters minds, according to this poll.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
