<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133116" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: OSCE says Bosnian local polls postponed.</title>
<headline>OSCE says Bosnian local polls postponed.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the international mission organising Bosnia's post-war elections announced on Tuesday that local polls set for November would be postponed because of &quot;continuing political problems&quot;.</p>
<p>Robert Frowick, chief of the Bosnia mission for the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), confirmed earlier reports from diplomats when he told reporters that the municipal elections should be held sometime next year.</p>
<p>The OSCE's Provisional Election Commission unanimously decided on Tuesday to delay &quot;the exceptionally complex&quot; polls, Frowick said.</p>
<p>&quot;As chairman of the commission I would urge that these critically important elections take place as soon as possible in 1997,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The decision was made a day after U.S. envoy John Kornblum met Moslem, Croat and Serb leaders in Sarajevo to try to resolve an impasse over the politically sensitive local elections.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serb authorities, citing security concerns in villages where Moslems have resettled, had threatened to boycott the poll if the OSCE went ahead with it in November.</p>
<p>Frowick urged that the municipal elections be internationally supervised but he said Bosnia's factions had yet to agree to an extension of the OSCE's mandate.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently involved in diplomatic contacts with the parties to obtain agreement for an extension of the mandate through the end of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western and Bosnian analysts say holding unsupervised elections would play into the hands of the ruling nationalist parties and ruin any chance of reunifying the country or permitting refugees to return to their homes.</p>
<p>Rival ethnic factions view the local elections as a struggle for control of territory which their armies fought over during 3-1/2 years of war.</p>
<p>It was the second time international mediators had decided to postpone the municipal polls, which were originally supposed to coincide with general elections held on September 14.</p>
<p>Human rights monitors and a number of European diplomats had also warned that rushing ahead with the local elections would be a mistake.</p>
<p>Despite the logistical difficulties presented by post-war local elections, Frowick said politics was the main obstacle to moving ahead on schedule.</p>
<p>&quot;Our problems have been mainly political, not logistical,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Frowick said that Moslem, Croat and Serb parties ruling Bosnia had all expressed objections to holding the vote in November. The OSCE was considering scheduling the elections between next April and June, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
