<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133113" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Volvo opens bus plant in Poland.</title>
<headline>Volvo opens bus plant in Poland.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Volvo opened a bus factory in Poland on Tuesday to produce about 250 vehicles annually, PAP news agency reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Entering the Polish market we start with the production of buses. But in the future we plan to produce Volvo's other models,&quot; PAP quoted Heimo Ylenius, director general of the Volvo Bus Poland, as saying at the opening ceremony.</p>
<p>The factory, based in the south-western city of Wroclaw, employs 200 people and will assemble 28 buses in 1996. Its annual output target is 250 vehicles.</p>
<p>The plant will produce bus bodies but will import most techonologically advanced components from Sweden, PAP quoted factory's sales official Tymoteusz Skroban as saying.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700  </p>
<p>The New Financial Stabilisation Fund, an investment fund set up under a government scheme to clear up the bad loan mess at failed mortgage firms seems to have bought about 15 billion yen worth of the new 10-year JGBs, the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;They seem to be investing much of their funds in short-term instruments, however. I heard that the fund invited offers to buy Treasury Bills yesterday morning,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A brokerage trader said traders will be watching a regular news conference by Yasuo Matsushita, the Bank of Japan governor, due at 3 p.m. (0600 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Masayuki Kitano, Tokyo Treasury Desk, 81-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
