<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13316" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac says France to stick to austerity track.</title>
<headline>Chirac says France to stick to austerity track.</headline>
<byline>Helene Fontanaud</byline>
<dateline>BREGANCON, France 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac said on Sunday France should keep on its path of economic austerity despite union threats of labour unrest and widespread gloom.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we've got over the hardest part and that we're now getting to situations that are easier to manage, on condition the needed reforms and adaptations are pursued,&quot; he told reporters at a Riviera fortress where he is on holiday.</p>
<p>He said he did not know whether there would be turbulence after the summer break as threatened by unions, who say conditions are ripe to revive unrest to match a crippling 24-day wave of strikes in late 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the government's responsibility to command the situation but certainly not to change target,&quot; Chirac said after a weekend of talks with Prime Minister Alain Juppe on issues ranging from immigration to record unemployment and the budget.</p>
<p>A poll for the daily Le Parisien showed 54 percent of French people were pessimistic about the outlook and 78 percent foresaw troubles for the centre-right government when the French return to work after the mass summer exodus.</p>
<p>The CSA survey of 1,005 people for Monday's edition showed that strikes, poverty, and job losses topped voters' worries.</p>
<p>Juppe said the government would keep its promises to slash the budget deficit in order to qualify for a single European currency from 1999 at the same time as reducing the tax burden.</p>
<p>&quot;We will stick to our European commitments, not out of pleasure but because it's in the interests of France and the French people,&quot; he said. &quot;It makes good sense.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Also, there will be lower income taxes from 1997, and over five years. This will especially concern families because it's important to give them the means for greater stability.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the budget and plans for funding the creaking social security system in 1997 were &quot;practically ready&quot; and would be presented to parliament around September 10.</p>
<p>Neither Chirac nor Juppe gave details of the size of planned tax cuts.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said he expected economic growth in 1997 of 2.25 to 2.5 percent, revising down his earlier assumption that the economy would expand by 2.5 to 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>Chirac and Juppe got some encouragement from an opinion poll on Sunday, showing that voters were slightly less dissatisfied with their performance.</p>
<p>The IFOP survey, for the Journal du Dimanche weekly, showed 38 percent were satisfied with Chirac's performance against 50 percent dissatisfied. In July, the split was 35-53. Juppe's less favourable rating improved to 31-57 percent from 30-59.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BREGANCON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
