<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133138" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Nomura International's confirmed interest in Investicni a Postovni Banka (IPB) has catapulted IPB's share price to a half-year high of 316 crowns.</p>
<p>- The government did not discuss the direct sale of Aero Vodochody a.s. to the Chemapol Group during its meeting on the financial restructuralisation of the company, according to Minister of Industry and Trade Vladimir Dlouhy. He also mentioned the government's intention to sell the company to Czech, not foreign, investors.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - While CEZ still predicts the Temelin nuclear power plant will be open by the end of 1998, sources inside the company have expressed the opinion that the power plant will be delayed until at least the end of 1999.</p>
<p>PRAVO - Health Minister Jindrich Vodicka will propose four variants on Tuesday for changes to the current health care system which the minister sees as very unclear.</p>
<p>- Petrol and diesel fuel have once again increased in price by 0.30 to 0.40 crowns.</p>
<p>- The National Property Fund predicts that it will sell its block of Investicni a Postovni Banka shares all at once, perhaps even to one investor.</p>
<p>- Poldi Kladno may begin output again in December. The steelworks currently has enough orders to last for nine months.</p>
<p>- Ceska Sporitelna produced a net profit of 1.608 billion crowns in the first nine months of 1996, according to the company's press spokesman Pavel Jirousek.</p>
<p>- The management of the Czech Republic's big four banks see the entrance of large and fairly transparent foreign banks as desirable, according to Frantisek Kopriva, the deputy general manager of Ceska Sporitelna.</p>
<p>- Farmers who have contracts with the State Market Regulation Fund and do not fulfil the conditions of the contract could lose their claim to government subsidies or other state support in the coming year, according to Agriculture Minister Josef Lux. The president of the Agrarian Chamber, Jiri Netik, does not agree with the minister.</p>
<p>- Evrobanka, Ekoagrobanka and Bankovni Dum Skala will be incorporated under Ostrava's Union Banka by December 1. On this date all bank branches will go under the Union Banka name.</p>
<p>- British brewing company Bass is likely to use its option to increase its share in Prazske Pivovary to 51 percent at the beginning of November, according to Mervyn Childs of Bass.</p>
<p>- ING Bank has announced its interest in Investicni a Postovni Banka, the second foreign institution after Nomura International to do so.</p>
<p>- The crown's exchange rate strengthened on the interbank market in reaction to the positive news of the interest of foreign investors in the big four Czech banks.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, +42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
