<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133183" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PSE continues rebound,boosted by bank shares.</title>
<headline>Czech PSE continues rebound,boosted by bank shares.</headline>
<byline>Alan Crosby</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Prague Stock Exchange on Tuesday, buoyed by financial sector share gains, continued to rebound from its recent slump, closing higher for the third consecutive session.</p>
<p>Komercni Banka, IPB, Ceska Sporitelna and Zivnostenska Banka all gained ground as the PX50 index edged up 2.5 points, or 0.47 percent, to 537.1.</p>
<p>The Reuters RPIX index, measuring the seven continuously- traded equity issues on the bourse, climbed five points to 1,095.</p>
<p>Overall, 188 shares rose on the day, while 121 lost and 74 held steady. Total volume was 701,356 shares on turnover of 721.14 million crowns.</p>
<p>For IPB, which rose 15 crowns to 331, it was the second consecutive five percent gain, the maximum allowed by the bourse in a session, after the government said it would be the first of the big four banks to undergo privatisation.</p>
<p>On Friday, Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik gave investors the signal they had been looking for when he said that a strong foreign strategic partner would be the most likely beneficiary of any sell off.</p>
<p>Since the announcement, Nomura and ING Bank have been rumoured as the frontrunners in any bid to participate in the selloff. The government holds about a 30 percent stake in IPB.</p>
<p>&quot;If you were to bring in a foreign partner such as the caliber of the two banks mentioned, that addresses questions that have been hovering around IPB on its perceived lack of corporate structure and transparency,&quot; said Jay King of Wood and Company.</p>
<p>The bank has been widely-criticsed for being the least transparent of the four major Czech banks in its dealings, especially a recent spending spree that has seen it quietly buy large stakes in several firms.</p>
<p>Several utilities also fared well at the fixing, with Stredoceska Energetika, Prazska Teplarenska, Severomoravksa Energetika, Jihomoravska Energetika and Elektrarny Opatovice all rising.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
