<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133161" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish PM says cabinet overcoming budget rifts.</title>
<headline>Polish PM says cabinet overcoming budget rifts.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's prime minister said on Tuesday that the cabinet was overcoming rifts over spending levels in the 1997 budget and had worked out a plan to bail out the debt-ridden education system.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an increasing possibility that we will agree on matching revenues and spending,&quot; Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz told reporters during a break in Tuesday's cabinet meeting on the budget.</p>
<p>If the ministers agree on spending levels for their portfolios on Tuesday, the government is likely to approve the buddget and send it to parliament on Friday.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz earlier said that meeting ministers' demands for more spending would boost budget spending by several billion zlotys more than the finance ministry had proposed.</p>
<p>The finance ministry's budget draft provides for cutting annual inflation to 13 percent next year from 17 percent planned for 1996. Gross domestic product is forecast to grow by 5.5 percent and the budget deficit is planned at 2.6 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said the government had worked out a plan to bail out the public education system and was now to prepare a similar scheme for health care.</p>
<p>These issues are crucial for the budget because the two sectors owe the treasury, utility companies and other firms several billion zlotys and their workers have been staging repeated protests over low wages.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed upon a plan to bail out education but we have not discussed the financially more serious problem of the health care system's debt,&quot; Cimoszewicz said.</p>
<p>The prime minister said schemes for the two systems would not provide for directly injecting cash into them and were aimed at preventing the debt problem from recurring in future.</p>
<p>He did not give further details but said the education arrangement might be implemented this year or early in 1997.</p>
<p>-- Marcin Grajewski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
