<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133106" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- The U.N. General Assembly votes for Kenya to take up a non-permanent Security Council seat for the first time in more than 20 years.</p>
<p>- The Barclays Bank of Kenya drops over 20 established insurers from its list of approved risk management insurance companies, setting the stage for a bitter discord that is unfolding in the underwriting industry.</p>
<p>- President Daniel arap Moi says there is now an agreement with neighbouring states to extradite criminals back to their home countries to face trial.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- Armed gangsters unleash a night of terror and bloody mayhem on villagers -- stealing property worth hundreds of thousands of shillings in Kiambu district on the edge of Nairobi.</p>
<p>- Opposition FORD-Kenya faction leader Raila Odinga declares support for FORD-Asili chairman Kenneth Matiba as sole presidential candidate for the Opposition Solidarity Alliance in next year's General Election. Matiba said also ready to support him as the vice presidential candidate for the Opposition.</p>
<p>- Kenya, with 19 other Sub-Saharan countries, has the worst credit rating in the international capital market, says &quot;Institutional Investor&quot;, an international investment journal.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>-  Police in Nairobi have rounded up more than 400 suspects in the last three days in a crackdown on criminals in the city and its suburbs. They have also beefed up security across the country and particularly at trouble spots.</p>
<p>($1=56 shillings).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
