<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133143" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria govt cancels sale of ailing Economic Bank.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria govt cancels sale of ailing Economic Bank.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's cabinet has rejected Bulbank's plan to acquire a majority stake in troubled Economic Bank and will discuss ways to stabilise the bank this week, a central banker said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulbank's offer was considered a good option, but analysis showed that it would be better if the Economic Bank remained a separate bank and its foreign debt was transformed into a government one,&quot; economy minister Roumen Gechev said in an interview on national television.  </p>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) placed the Economic Bank in receivership a month ago along with eight other banks to establish their financial status and whether or not to seek their insolvency through the courts or sell them.</p>
<p>&quot;Under Bulbank's proposal the cost of salvaging Economic Bank was distributed between Bulbank, the central bank and the state budget,&quot; a BNB board member told Reuters.</p>
<p>The BNB and relevant cabinet members evaluated the plan and concluded that closing the bank or rehabilitating it might be cheaper, the board member said.  </p>
<p>Economic Bank's $170 million foreign debt, concentrated mostly in Austrian and Italian financial institutions, is quaranteed by the state, allowing future rescheduling with government creditors grouped in the Paris Club.</p>
<p>Central bank figures showed that, if the bank is closed, the budget has to cover personal savings of 4.6 billion levs and $10.7 million and companies accounts worth 3.6 billion levs and $28.4 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Cleaning the bank's portfolio would cost some 46 billion levs,&quot; a central bank's official said.  </p>
<p>Gechev said that, if the government decided to rehabilitate the bank, it would need some three billion levs of refinancing for a start.</p>
<p>Economic Bank, which was set up in the mid 1980s, made loans to big industrial enterprises that have accumulated heavy losses. The bank has already been bailed out by budget funds and by the central bank several times.</p>
<p>Last year, some 22 billion levs of its debt to the BNB and the State Savings Bank were transformed into a state debt and written off.</p>
<p>Economic Bank's loans in foreign exchange total some $150 million of which around $30 million are unrecoverable. &quot;The government will probably discuss on the matter on Thursday,&quot; the central banker said.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
