<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133170" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak shares mixed, VUB pulls SAX down 0.11 pts.</title>
<headline>Slovak shares mixed, VUB pulls SAX down 0.11 pts.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Slovak shares closed mixed in flat trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Tuesday, with losses to shares of VUB bank pulling the SAX index down 0.11 points to 203.01.</p>
<p>VUB closed down 20 crowns at 1,750, while oil and gas storage firm Nafta dominated trading on the bourse floor, closing up 30 crowns at 1,930, on floor volume of 10,100 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;I would call the current mood on the market as neutral,&quot; Libor Briska of Creditanstalt said adding that he expected the index would hover around current levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The gap between offered prices and those accepted by buyers currently narrowed, showing there is liquidity potential in Nafta as well as in other blue chips,&quot; Briska added.</p>
<p>Steel maker VSZ closed up seven at 646 crowns, with 4,316 traded shares.</p>
<p>Overall volume eased to 191,000 shares, from 561,755 shares traded on Monday, while turnover dipped to 168.09 million crowns, from 561.84 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
