<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133199" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks mostly lower, trend seen mixed.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks mostly lower, trend seen mixed.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks closed mostly lower on Tuesday, with some blue chip shares gaining and Istrian hoteliers losing, and traders predicted the mixed trend to continue.</p>
<p>They forcast drug firm Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka -- two flagship Croatian companies listed on the London Stock Exchange -- to continue rising slowly but steadily.</p>
<p>Pliva was the day's biggest earner, closing at 13,011 kuna, 111 kuna up from Friday, on volume of 616 shares.</p>
<p>During the relatively slow day, Zagrebacka was the most traded issue with 1,079 shares changing hands. It rose 10 kuna to an all-time high of 1,050 kuna.</p>
<p>&quot;After breaking the 1,000-kuna barrier, Zagrebacka will continue rising for a while,&quot; a trader at a large brokerage said. &quot;People like trading in Pliva and Zagrebacka because they have the shortest settlement period -- seven days.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the gainers was Zagrebacka E-series shares, gaining 30 kuna to close at 430 on small volume of 96 shares.</p>
<p>On the other hand, Istrian hoteliers continued losing after a month of spectacular gains, and analysts expect them to lose some more ground before recovering later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason for the correction in the hoteliers' shares is the large supply, as many investors concluded this was the right time to sell,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Laguna from Porec, which had so far resisted the downward turn of the other four major tourist companies from the northern peninsula, was the day's biggest loser. It fell 101 kuna from Friday to close at 1,439 kuna on 200 shares.</p>
<p>Istraturist lost 43 kuna, closing at 270, and Jadranturist edged down 10 kuna, to close at 350.</p>
<p>Of other popular issues, food processor Podravka eased one kuna to close at 273 with 436 shares traded, while confectioner Kras went to 695 from 700 on volume of 174 shares.</p>
<p>Of the nine active issues, two were up, five down, while one remained flat. Trading volume was slightly lower at 3,060 shares, but the turnover was up at 9.8 million kuna.</p>
<p>The central bank's exhange rate was up at 5.4928 kuna for the dollar.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
