<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13312" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jack Kemp preaches racial harmony in solo debut.</title>
<headline>Jack Kemp preaches racial harmony in solo debut.</headline>
<dateline>VASHON, Wash 1996-08-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican vice presidential candidate Jack Kemp set out on his own Saturday for the first time since his nomination this month, preaching a message of tax cuts and racial harmony.</p>
<p>Kemp, the main draw at an annual political picnic on bucolic Vashon Island near Seattle, called for an end to racial strife and declared that he and running mate Bob Dole intended to run what he called an &quot;inclusive campaign.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This country needs healing,&quot; he told thousands of party faithful. &quot;It needs reconciliation within races of people and ethnic groups of people. We need a message that can bring Americans together.&quot;</p>
<p>A former professional football player known for his garrulous personality, Kemp has a reputation for outspokenness and some Republicans feared he might have trouble playing second fiddle to Dole.</p>
<p>Since the party convention ended in San Diego a week ago, the two men had campaigned together with Kemp deferring at every stop to the No 1 man on the Republican ticket.</p>
<p>On Saturday, however, Kemp was the headliner among dozens of Republican candidates, including eight running for governor in a September primary, who were introduced to the nearly all-white crowd at the picnic.</p>
<p>The free carnival-like event was held on a 167-acre farm owned by businessman Thomas Stewart, who is under criminal investigation after admitting he secretly funnelled $60,000 into a losing campaign for a Seattle city ballot measure.</p>
<p>Kemp appeared on stage with his wife, Joanne, and his son Jeff and three grandchildren, who live in a Seattle suburb.</p>
<p>Speaking under a red-white-and-blue banner that called for Republicans to unite, Kemp addressed the campaign's economic theme, saying Dole's proposed 15 percent tax cut was essential to &quot;the future of our families.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to take the U.S. tax code, and we're going to repeal the whole monstrosity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Republican Party officials estimated 12,000 people attended the picnic, although that was the total number of people transported to the island by the Washington State Ferry system, officials said.</p>
<p>The island, which can only be reached by boat and has a population of about 10,000, is a popular day trip for Puget Sound area residents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VASHON, Wash"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
