<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133197" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Partnership needed even with expanded NATO - Joulwan.</title>
<headline>Partnership needed even with expanded NATO - Joulwan.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Supreme Allied Commander in Europe General George Joulwan said on Tuesday that cooperation programmes with non-members must continue no matter what deadline U.S. President Clinton sets for NATO expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure what the political decisions will be, but we will adjust,&quot; Joulwan said during a visit to Hungary, which is a member of NATO's Partnership for Peace (PFP) programme and a prime candidate for membership in an expanded NATO.</p>
<p>&quot;No matter what, PFP must continue in developing the way ahead,&quot; Joulwan told a news conference.</p>
<p>President Clinton was expected to announce on Tuesday that his target was to bring new members into the western military alliance no later than 1999, which is NATO's 50th anniversary.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic, Poland and Hungary are generally viewed as being first in line to join, although Russia has made clear that Moscow still views NATO's planned eastward expansion as a threat to its own security.</p>
<p>Joulwan also said he was ready for a decision over the postponement of municipal elections in Bosnia, where NATO's IFOR peacekeeping troops maintain order.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to support municipal elections if they're held in November but OSCE (Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe) has the lead, not us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Joulwan said NATO's land force command for central Europe, including IFOR, will move to Sarajevo from Heidelberg, Germany by the first week of November.</p>
<p>He said the mission would oversee the redeployment of IFOR forces at the end of the IFOR mandate, set for December 20.</p>
<p>He added that the headquarters would be expanded to include non-NATO members.</p>
<p>&quot;The mission will include 25 nationalities, including Hungarian officers,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
