<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133150" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: OSCE says Lithuania elections badly organised.</title>
<headline>OSCE says Lithuania elections badly organised.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>International observers on Tuesday said Lithuania's weekend parliamentary elections were badly organised, putting so much strain on the voting system that some irregularities took place.</p>
<p>Results from the Sunday polls, won by Vytautas Landsbergis's Homeland Union, came painfully slowly and the first figures were delayed by many hours.</p>
<p>A final tally had not been declared on Tuesday, more than 36 hours after the polls closed.</p>
<p>The Lithuanian electoral committee blamed a new computer system and the fact that voters had to make several choices on their ballot papers.</p>
<p>&quot;Sunday's elections here were free and fair but technical problems caused many deviations and irregularities,&quot; said Frank Aarebrot, head of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) mission observing the vote.</p>
<p>&quot;The deviations were not intentional or fraudulent. We observed no cases of intimidation or manipulation. They were the product of poor organisation and technical problems,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>He also said that not enough voting booths or polling stations were provided.</p>
<p>Lithuanians on Sunday were voting for two party lists, one of candidates chosen by proportional representation and one by a majority vote. They also had to answer three questions in two separate referendums.</p>
<p>Aarebrot said that people tired of waiting in queues started filling out their forms before entering the polling booth, meaning their vote could be seen by other people.</p>
<p>&quot;Open voting was a voluntary response to the circumstances in this election. Next time, there could be voter manipulation,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
