<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133102" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe civil servants strike again over pay.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe civil servants strike again over pay.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of Zimbabwean civil servants, mainly doctors and nurses, went on strike for a second day on Tuesday to demand more pay, ignoring a government promise to begin negotiations on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Unions representing state-employed doctors and nurses and affiliated to the general Public Service Association (PSA) told reporters their members would stay on the streets until President Robert Mugabe's government showed it was taking their grievances seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been duped before and that's not going to happen again,&quot; said a union official who refused to be identified.</p>
<p>The ministry of public service, labour and social welfare said talks would start on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Civil servants walked out of their jobs on Monday to press the government to address their demands, including the reinstatement of a year-end bonus which the cash-strapped government scrapped in 1995.</p>
<p>Some 10,000 workers were estimated to be on strike on Monday, with PSA officials expecting more from the 180,000-strong civil service to join the strike on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was not clear on Tuesday morning how many people were on strike. The main government teachers union said it would not join the industrial action immediately but give Wednesday's planned negotiations a chance.</p>
<p>The government ended a three-week civil servants strike last month by awarding workers 20 percent pay rises backdated to July, and promising to start open-ended talks on their demands for wage hikes of up to 60 percent.</p>
<p>The government has postponed the talks three times since September 27, pleading for more time to prepare its position.</p>
<p>---Cris Chinaka, Harare Newsroom +263 4 7252 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
