<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133153" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania upbeat on Clinton's stand on extended NATO.</title>
<headline>Romania upbeat on Clinton's stand on extended NATO.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania praised U.S. President Bil Clinton's announcement on Tuesday that he wanted a 1999 deadline for NATO's plans to take some former Soviet bloc states under its security umbrella.</p>
<p>President Ion Iliescu's spokesman said Romania, which is lobbying for first-wave admission to NATO, was eager for assurances on the Western alliance's planned eastward drive.</p>
<p>&quot;We hail all political statements and all steps taken regarding NATO's expansion,&quot; Traian Chebeleu told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be among the first countries admitted to the alliance, in which we see a pillar of security and a guarantee for further democratic development, above all in Romania.&quot;</p>
<p>Chebeleu made the remarks during Clinton's campaign speech at a Detroit rally, when the U.S. president backed for the first time a target date of 1999 for an expansion of the alliance expected to begin with former Soviet bloc states.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Iliescu sent Chebeleu as well as the foreign and defence ministers to hand over a message to leaders of the 16-member Western alliance, urging them to consider the Balkan country's plea for fast-track admission to NATO.</p>
<p>Romanian officials said their plea had been well received, particularly in the United States and France.</p>
<p>Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic are seen as heading the queue.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Mihai Rosca told reporters that Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu had briefed the cabinet saying Romania was now &quot;considered as a potential candidate for first-wave admission to NATO&quot;.</p>
<p>North Atlantic Treaty Organisation ministers are to meet in December to pave the way for an alliance summit in 1997 that is likely to name the first candidates for membership and lead to the opening of negotiations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
