<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133205" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo economists praise tight central bank policy.</title>
<headline>Yugo economists praise tight central bank policy.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Yugoslav central bank must stick to its tight monetary policy and not risk its key goals of maintaining currency and price stability, a group of leading economists said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Economists praised the National Bank of Yugoslavia's (NBY) tough monetary stance and warned any monetary relaxation or money supply expansion could lead back to hyperinflation, a slump in industrial production and chaos.</p>
<p>&quot;NBY must not give in to pressure and ease its policy in order to improve liquidity of banks and companies,&quot; Danijel Cvijeticanin of the Economics Institute told a news conference.</p>
<p>Cvijeticanin said calls for monetary easing, which advocates say would pave way to a stronger performance of the overall economy, could only result in chaos.</p>
<p>Monetary authorities must not stimulate growth by printing new money or by financing large public works, he said.</p>
<p>NBY tightened its grip over money supply and inflation by launching a 10 percent reserve requirement early in September.</p>
<p>M1 money supply grew by 148 million dinars to reach 4.486 billion dinars ($881.7 million) at the end of August.</p>
<p>The launch of the reserve requirement reduced the liquidity of the banking sector. In most cases, funds on banks' accounts have been halved, the Belgrade-based think-tank said.</p>
<p>In the case of Yugoslavia, the reserve requirement is not an obsolete monetary instrument and would be needed for many years, Zoran Jeremic of the same institute said.</p>
<p>Jeremic said the major problem of the economy and its banking sector was not restrictive monetary policy but a failure to collect payments on matured liabilities.</p>
<p>&quot;To a large extent, Yugoslav banks have companies' sight deposits in their balances. This reveals how poor their financial capacity is at present. And this fragile financial capacity must meet their high operating costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Calling for a deep restructuring, he said commercial banks would run aground once the government introduces strict budget limits and reduces public spending. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
