<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133237" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine sugar beet harvest at 17.32 mln T so far.</title>
<headline>Ukraine sugar beet harvest at 17.32 mln T so far.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine has harvested 17.32 million tonnes of sugar beets, down from 24.42 million tonnes at this time last year, an Agriculture Ministry official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Valentyn Tymoshenko, deputy head of the ministry's crop department, told Reuters that sugar beet yields were down to 19.6 tonnes per hectare from 22.0 tonnes per hectare in 1995.</p>
<p>This year's harvest started later to allow beets to mature and so far 882,000 hectares have been harvested compared to 1.11 million hectares at this time last year.</p>
<p>The deputy head of the state's Weather Forecasting Centre predicted favourable weather conditions through October, but said night frosts could hit the north at the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the dry weather which we are expecting through October will help our farmers collect the rest of the sugar beet harvest,&quot; Anatoly Prokopenko said.</p>
<p>Ukraine's beet harvest started two weeks later this year due to drought in the early part of the growing season and there are concerns that early frosts could endanger the crop.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Ministry has forecast total sugar beet output at a poor 26 million tonnes compared to 30 million tonnes in 1995.</p>
<p>Ukraine intends to produce about 3.20 million tonnes of refined sugar from this year's harvest, compared to last year's 3.49 million tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Yuri Kulikov, Kiev newsroom, +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
