<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133200" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL, TVK pull Hungary's BUX lower.</title>
<headline>MOL, TVK pull Hungary's BUX lower.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed lower for the third successive day on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Tuesday but traders said the pace had slowed and the market could rebound soon.</p>
<p>The BUX index ended at 3,615.75 points, down 30.85. BUX index futures ended mixed, closing higher for two maturities, remaining steady for one and closing lower for three.</p>
<p>&quot;The correction continued, and in addition in London all investors paid attention to the introduction of (Russia's) Gazprom shares,&quot; said Istvan Simon of Concorde Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;This left its mark on the market here, but I think the end of the fall in Hungarian shares could be seen,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Gazprom's introduction was one possible reason behind the low spot share turnover which totalled 654.2 million forints.</p>
<p>The two most actively traded issues, oil company MOL and chemicals company TVK both closed lower, although their falls were modest.</p>
<p>MOL closed at 1,640 forints, down 25, while TVK ended at 1,355 forints, down 10.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the Budapest bourse, and all other markets will be closed due to public holiday. The markets will resume trading on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
