<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133277" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Ion Tiriac, former tennis star turned businessman, is interested in buying into troubled  Banca Dacia Felix SA, the newspaper quotes government sources as saying.</p>
<p>- The leu currency fell below the 3,300 to the dollar level on the interbank market, as well as at retail currency shops.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Two companies in the Black Sea port of Constanta will export algae to Japan.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Currency shops trade the leu at over 4,000 to the dollar.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- A quota worth $5.0 million of cars of less than 3,000 cc can be imported free of taxes till the end of 1996.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The newspaper publishes excerpts from a list drawn by the ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) with judges, allegedly PDSR members, who were apointed presidents of the electoral bureaus across Romania in breach of the electoral law.</p>
<p>- The newspaper publishes excerpts from the first volume of the &quot;White book of the Securitate&quot; (secret police) launched in Bucharest on Monday. The book includes reports by former Securitate informers on representatives of the artistic elite.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Romanians abroad on the November 3 election day will vote only with their identity card as the passport is not recognised as a valid document. That affects the 190,000 Romanians working in Israel as most of them have no identity cards.</p>
<p>- Nine of 16 candidates for presidency in the November 3 polls will attend a two-hour debate with journalists from the Adevarul newspaper on October 25.</p>
<p>- The newspaper publishes excerpts from the political programme of the New Romania Party (NR).</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Drug and car trafficking, forgery, rackets and the Gypsy mafia are allegedly the forms of organised crime in Romania, says the newspaper.</p>
<p>- Police confiscated 13 tonnes of drugs in two years and sound the alarm over the appearence of synthetic drugs in Romania.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- The costs for a burial in Romania reach millions of lei with a coffin costing almost as much as a second-hand car, says the newspaper. ($=3,3011 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
