<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133263" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Salomon rates Surgutneftegaz, Chernogorneft buys.</title>
<headline>Salomon rates Surgutneftegaz, Chernogorneft buys.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Bros rated AO Surgutneftegaz, Russia's second biggest oil company by sales, a very attractive buy, saying it was well managed and was improving disclosures.</p>
<p>Compared with other West Siberian producers, Surgutneftegaz also offers the smallest risk to investors with the conversion of its shares to those of the parent, as vertically integrated companies (VICs) are formed, Salomon said in a research note.</p>
<p>It also rated AO Chernogorneft a buy, forecasting that the company's disclosure of joint-venture activities will boost value.</p>
<p>Nizhnevartovskneftegaz, whose fortunes could be transformed by a production-sharing agreement in the North Samotlor field, is rated a speculative buy, it said.</p>
<p>Noyabrskneftegaz, is also a speculative buy, as it improves management and prepares for a Western reserves audit with Miller and Lents and for presenting accounts according to International Accounting Standards by the end of next year.</p>
<p>But it is increasingly being run as a cost centre by its VIC, Sibneft, it said.</p>
<p>Salomon said it was downgrading Russia's third biggest producer, Yuganskneftegaz to hold, as it was being run as a cost centre by its VIC YUKOS, and its loss of autonomy had removed impetus for additional Western-style disclosures.</p>
<p>In general Salomon said the West Siberian companies were more prepared to admit to a need for external capital, and momentum towards IAS accounting and reserves audits was increasing.</p>
<p>Management was showing greater understanding of the importance of investment and returns on investment, and acknowledging Western reserves methodology.</p>
<p>The move to VICs was eliminating some of the problems with receivables within the industry, there was progress towards production-sharing agreements and cost inflation was subdued.</p>
<p>On the negative side production subsidiaries -- in which shares are still more actively traded than in VICs -- are run increasingly as cost centres, and many are losing their autonomy.</p>
<p>The basis for share conversions into VICs is unclear and domestic production economics have deteriorated over the last year, it said.</p>
<p>--Jonathan Lynn, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
