<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133272" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The Reform Party was satisfied with its win of 14 seats out of the 64 on Tallin city council and 14 out of 49 in Tartu. The Coalition Party, Pro Patria, the Moderates and the Central Party Union expressed satisfaction with the election results.</p>
<p>- Defence forces chief dismissed Edgar Haavik, the commander of a the Sulev minesweeper for abuse of power and discrediting the armed forces.</p>
<p>- Estonian consumer price index rose one percent in the third quarter of the year.</p>
<p>- Election results in Tallin show that negotiations over forming a new city government will be difficult. Reform Party leader Siim Kallas prefers the Rightwing and the Moderates for partners in city coalition.</p>
<p>SONUMILEHT</p>
<p>- A former member of the Estonian Monetary Reform Committee Rudolf Jalakas recommends the Bank of Estonia to cut the money in circulation to curb the inflation.</p>
<p>- Ex-prime minister Mart Laar drove his car into a tree on October 18 but was not hurt.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Company Gortigos has turned to court over privatisation of fuel company Esoil, asking to declare the deal invalid.</p>
<p>EESTI PAEVALEHT</p>
<p>- President Lennart Meri will start a three-day state visit to Latvia tomorrow.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
