<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133246" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chubais goes from strength to strength in Russia.</title>
<headline>Chubais goes from strength to strength in Russia.</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A series of Kremlin reshuffles by President Boris Yeltsin has brought presidential chief of staff Anatoly Chubais to the top of the pack and prompted speculation that he is ruling Russia behind the scenes.</p>
<p>Since the October 17 sacking of security tsar Alexander Lebed, even more power appears to be concentrated in the hands of Chubais and Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin as Yeltsin remains out of the Kremlin awaiting heart surgery.</p>
<p>Although Yeltsin has temporarily given some of his powers to Chernomyrdin, Russia's official &quot;number two&quot;, many officials and analysts say Chubais may be even more important.</p>
<p>&quot;It is no secret that...85 percent of decisions are being taken by Chubais,&quot; Vyacheslav Igrunov, a liberal deputy in the State Duma lower house of parliament, said in a television interview.</p>
<p>The boyish-looking Chubais, 41, presided over Russia's controversial privatisation and oversaw economic reforms from 1992 to 1996.</p>
<p>But the key to his rise to power was his role in helping plot Yeltsin's re-election in July on the campaign team which guided the 65-year-old president to a second term.</p>
<p>Some political analysts saw his naming on Monday in a four-man consultative council with Chernomyrdin and the speakers of the two houses of parliament as another significant step. The council is to improve cooperation in decision-making.</p>
<p>&quot;The creation of such a committee to a greater extent legitimises Chubais as the one who decides Russia's fate,&quot; Igrunov said.</p>
<p>Chubais is regarded by many political analysts as the closest of any Kremlin officials to Yeltsin and say he has a strong alliance with Yeltsin's daughter Tatyana Dyachenko, who also played a role in her father's campaign team.</p>
<p>The red-haired Chubais struck a deep blow soon after entering the president's entourage by taking on Yeltsin's long-time confidant, chief bodyguard Alexander Korzhakov. Chubais won the battle and Korzhakov was abruptly dismissed.</p>
<p>First deputy prime minister Oleg Soskovets, Federal Security Service chief Mikhail Barsukov and Yeltsin's Security Council secretary Oleg Lobov -- men with firmly entrenched views which Chubais opposed -- were also dimissed.</p>
<p>Yeltsin then promoted Chubais to become head of the Kremlin administration after he had ben re-elected.</p>
<p>But the climax came last Thursday when Yeltsin sacked the charismatic Alexander Lebed, a vociferous Chubais opponent, after only four months as secretary of the Security Council, an inner circle of defence, security and state officials.</p>
<p>&quot;I was an obstacle to plans by Chubais to set up a regency,&quot; Lebed said, blaming his dismissal on his rival.</p>
<p>Korzhakov has likened Chubais to Grigory Rasputin, the confidant of the last Russian tsar, Nikolai II, who became powerful through close personal ties with the royal family.</p>
<p>Foes said Rasputin, eventually assassinated in 1916, ruled without formal rights to do so, being a German spy and giving bad advice to the tsar which ultimately led to the Bolshevik revolution in 1917.</p>
<p>Opponents accuse Chubais of being in the pay of people in the West who want to ruin Russia and that he is manipulated by Russia's few new rich who want more money. He denies the charges and no evidence has been produced to back them up.</p>
<p>But many of Chubais' foes see him as a world of difference form the bearded and wild Rasputin and prefer to talk about him as a regent who rules Russia in the absence of Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Chubais, who is highly unpopular for tough and painful decisions he had to make during his government service, has little chance of winning a presidential election.</p>
<p>But his widely-acknowledged managerial talents and links with financial groups make him powerful behind the scenes.</p>
<p>&quot;In this country it does not matter what position you occupy,&quot; a Russian newspaper once remarked. &quot;What is important is how close you are to the sovereign's ear.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
