<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133271" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Skopje press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified them nor does it vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NOVA MAKEDONIJA</p>
<p>- Macedonian government will propose liberalisation of trade with all neighbouring countries. The government will also submitt the draft on foreign contracts to the parliament.</p>
<p>- Mandatory vaccination against polio in Macedonia for all children between three months and 16 years of age began on Monday. All citizens travelling to Albania should present a certificate on vaccination at least 15 days before the trip.</p>
<p>- The multinational excercise &quot;Savior 96&quot; started in Ohrid on Monday. The representatives of the United States, Albania, Turkey, Bulgaria, Slovenia, Italia, Romania, Greece and Macedonia will discuss ways of incorporating small countries in collective defence systems.</p>
<p>- Additional negotiations with the International Monetary Fund for new credits. The possibility of additional $80 million announced last summer. That would be the third ESAF arrangement. The annual interest rate would be 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>- There are 18 candidates for Skopje mayor elections.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- Macedonia finally eradicated hoof and mouth disease. The Veterinarian Institute said on Monday that the quarantine of several Skopje villages was no longer necessary.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- The Organisation of Security and Cooperation in Europe and UNPREDEP to monitor the local elections on November 17. -- Mircela Casule, Skopje newsroom +389 91 201196</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
