<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133253" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary marks '56 uprising amid political rancour.</title>
<headline>Hungary marks '56 uprising amid political rancour.</headline>
<byline>Michael Roddy</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary began marking the 40th anniversary of the 1956 anti-Soviet uprising on Tuesday in ceremonies pointedly shunning the former communists who now run the country.</p>
<p>&quot;It was the revolution of human dignity,&quot; Hungarian President Arpad Goncz said during an awards ceremony for those who fought in the uprising, which posed the biggest challenge at that time to Soviet domination of eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;I am happy, but there is also a touch of sadness in these celebrations,&quot; said Maria Wittner, who as a young woman joined demonstrations in 1956 and made petrol bombs to throw at Soviet tanks. She was sentenced to death but later released.</p>
<p>&quot;Quite a number of our comrades who are gone have still not been rehabilitated or received the recognition they deserve,&quot; Wittner told Reuters after the crowded ceremony for about 400 people at the Budapest General Assembly.</p>
<p>The first shots of the uprising were fired on October 23, 1956 as Hungarians fought in the streets with small arms and petrol bombs against Soviet tanks and troops. A Soviet invasion in November crushed the revolution, in which an estimated 25,000 people were killed.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Hungarians commemorated the events leading up to the fighting, with most ceremonies pointedly organised by associations of 1956 veterans and not by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;The current government is really not suitable to celebrate the 40th anniversary,&quot; Karoly Herenyi, spokesman for the conservative opposition Hungarian Democratic Forum party, said of the Hungarian Socialist Party, which took power in 1994 and is comprised largely of former communists.</p>
<p>&quot;This government is really not able to do a proper job,&quot; Herenyi said during a reception at the MDF's headquarters on Monday evening which brought together several ageing veterans and leaders of the uprising.</p>
<p>&quot;What we want to get across is the happiness of the victory of 40 years ago but we also must remember the treason (the communists) committed, as a consequence of which Hungary remained a Soviet colony for another 30-odd years,&quot; said Jeno Fonay, who was in prison for more than six years and heads an organisation of former political prisoners.</p>
<p>Fonay said that if Socialist Prime Minister Gyula Horn attended a reception at Parliament on Wednesday night, people would be watching to see who shook hands with him and Horn would be lucky if no one poured champagne on him.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that the communists are still here,&quot; Fonay told Reuters. &quot;They are just in sheepskins.&quot;</p>
<p>Horn served in a militia organised after the uprising to put down continuing anti-Soviet strikes and protests, but he has said he never used a gun.</p>
<p>President Goncz, who was sentenced to life imprisonment after the uprising, acknowledged in a television interview on Monday the rancour attending the anniversary and suggested it would be best if the government took a &quot;hands off&quot; approach.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to ignore the unnecessary legends of the 1956 revolutions and the celebrations have to be brought closer to the people,&quot; Goncz said.</p>
<p>&quot;We must end the official character of it and accept the idea that it is first of all the holiday of those who participated in it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
