<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133256" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak banks extend new loans despite c.bank curbs.</title>
<headline>Slovak banks extend new loans despite c.bank curbs.</headline>
<byline>Tatiana Vacova</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak central bank measures to curb domestic lending are having little effect, with banks continuing to dole out funds as they fight for the country's few lucrative clients, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Slovakia (NBS) ended credit limits at the start of 1996 after positive inflation figures allowed an easing of monetary policy. This was aimed at spurring lending to finance the country's economic restructuring.</p>
<p>Banks quickly took the move to heart by extending loans at a breakneck pace, pushing the total volume of loans more than 19 percent higher year-on-year by August and putting the NBS's year-end target of 7.2 percent all but out of reach.</p>
<p>The credit expansion has also pushed the money supply out of shape, forcing the NBS in August to raise key interest rates and implement other measures to limit market liquidity.</p>
<p>&quot;We have noticed no decline in loan extension since August. It continues at least as intensively as up to then,&quot; said one official at a large Slovak bank. &quot;We are slowly withdrawing our deposits with other banks, and boosting our loan portfolio, all in accordance with our financial plan,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The NBS measures included a Lombard rate hike to 15 percent from 13, a widening of the band for setting the daily crown rate and a rise in banks' minimum reserve requirements.</p>
<p>Growth in the key money supply measure, M2, dipped below 19 percent year-on-year in September after 19.5 percent in August. But the NBS said it was still too early to say whether the move was a reaction to its measures.</p>
<p>Some analysts, however, said it was a fall in the 12-month growth rate of net foreign assets that slowed down M2.</p>
<p>To fund the lending spree -- loans granted in 1996 totalled some 353.7 billion crowns ($11.28 billion) at the end of August -- local banks have been repatriating assets from abroad.</p>
<p>In reaction, the NBS also required banks to exclude foreign exchange assets held locally from their foreign exchange position for monetary purposes from December 31. They will also have to include crown liabilities to banks outside Slovakia.</p>
<p>Banks must also reach a minimum ratio of foreign exchange assets and liabilities of 0.65 by December 31, rising in steps to at least at least 0.8 by June 30.</p>
<p>But the moves have had little effect on the market, with interest rates falling as competition grows between banks to attract or hold on to existing clients by giving cheap loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite higher interbank money market rates boosted by the measures, interest rates (on corporate loans) have declined slightly since banks' non-interest revenue is increasing,&quot; Daniel Bytcanek, Polnobanka chief dealer, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Compounding the problem, some analysts say, is that with bigger banks withdrawing funds from the money market to lend to clients, smaller banks could face a liquidity crunch.</p>
<p>Sylvia Majlingova, head of the Liquidity Department at CSOB Bratislava, said the resulting lack of liquidity could force a merger of many smaller institutions. &quot;Client selection by a few (big) banks for future cooperation is happening now, and is likely to lead to mergers of some smaller banks,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Banks are also continuing to shell out new loans at a record pace to keep their overall percentage of bad loans down.</p>
<p>&quot;A lack of interest in central bank or state bills suggests that banks prefer lending to maintain clients, and new loans also help them to ease the burden of bad loans,&quot; said Pavol Simo of the Slovak branch of Czech Agrobanka.</p>
<p>Since banks' provisions are still taxed -- the government has been working for over a year on a tax deduction for provisioning -- banks must continue to lend to generate revenues to help pay the costs of reserves, he added.</p>
<p>It is also forcing banks to borrow further to pay maintenance costs on these loans, he added.</p>
<p>($1=31.35 Slovak Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
