<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133206" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: INTERVIEW-Espebepe needs debt deal to live.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Espebepe needs debt deal to live.</headline>
<byline>Tomasz Janowski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's troubled construction firm Espebepe SA needs to clinch a far reaching debt write-off deal with its creditors to secure its future operation, the company's chief executive said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Andrzej Hass, who took over as Espebepe's president three months ago, told Reuters in an interview the new management launched an overhaul of the company but the burden of old debts and bad contracts could derail its efforts.</p>
<p>&quot;The existence of this company depends on the success of debt settlement and if our...proposal of a debt reduction is rejected...this company will be unable to exist independently,&quot; Hass said, adding he would seek to write off as much as 90 percent of Espebepe's debt.</p>
<p>Espebepe filed for debt settlement proceedings with a regional court last August and Hass said he expected the company's 700-plus creditors to make the final decision on proposed debt-cutting deal in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The company owes about 35 million zlotys to its 28 largest creditors.</p>
<p>Hass said the previous management did not disclose the full extent of the firm's difficulties and Espebepe, which recorded a 17.9 million zloty loss in 1995, was likely to plunge deeper into the red.</p>
<p>Hass said the need to create more provisions against possible losses from bad contracts was likely to increase Espebepe's loss to 30 million zlotys at the end of the year.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the previous chief executive forecast that Espebepe, based in the western port city of Szczecin, would reach break-even his year and estimated its debts at 10 million zlotys.</p>
<p>Hass blamed inefficient management, bad investment and the company's too rapid expansion, which resulted in many bad contracts, for its present financial woes.</p>
<p>He also said Espebepe spread itself too thinly expanding into several non-core activities such as real estate and that one of the priorities for the present management was to spin off most of its 18 subsidiaries to leave three or four.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be selling our subsidiaries or pressing their managements to file for their bankruptcy if the situation calls for it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Renegotiation or termination of loss-generating agreements was another priority of the restructuring programme.</p>
<p>Hass said that out of 21 major contracts reviewed by Espebepe's new management seven had a negative operating margin and only three yielded an operating margin of more than 10 percent.</p>
<p>Hass said that if the debt deal went through, Espebepe would likely reduce the scope of its activities already next year with sales down to 70-75 million zlotys from this year's expected 120 million zlotys.</p>
<p>He said a complete turnaround of the company would take between two and three years and would result in a leaner company with about four subsidiaries, workforce reduced from the present 1,500 and reduced overhead costs.</p>
<p>Hass said he wanted to cut those costs from the present high of 15 percent of all costs to 10 percent next year, with a target of about seven percent.</p>
<p>He declined to give a results forecast for 1997 but said Espebepe would aim at as low a loss as possible and would aim to reach an operating break-even point by the end of next year.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
