<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133202" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia may bend on Caspian status issue -agency.</title>
<headline>Russia may bend on Caspian status issue -agency.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia is ready to compromise on sticky questions over the legal status of the Caspian Sea and control over its vast oil and gas resources, Interfax news agency quoted a government official as saying on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It quoted the official, who was not identified, as saying Moscow was ready to consider a limited sectoral approach to the energy-rich sea.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view, the compromise may be in considering the national sectors of the sea those areas 35-40 miles (20-30 km) from the shores of each Caspian state,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>He said the middle of the sea would be considered the common property of the five states bordering the Caspian -- Russia, Turkmenistan, Kazakhstan, Iran and Azerbaijan -- and would be open to joint use.</p>
<p>The Caspian ranks eighth in the world in terms of discovered oil reserves. Reserves in Kazakhstan's continental shelf of the Caspian alone are 10 billion tonnes.</p>
<p>The sea has not been fully studied and may hold much more.</p>
<p>Russia and Iran have previously said the Caspian is a lake, and not a sea, and that its resources should be developed and shared equally.</p>
<p>Azerbaijan, Turkmenistan and Kazakhstan have said that it is a sea that should be entirely divided into national sectors.</p>
<p>The government source said Russia's approach might not please Azerbaijan, since Baku had multi-billion dollar international oil projects, some with the participation of Russian oil firm LUKoil, in what Azerbaijan calls its sector -- outside the proposed 40-mile limit.</p>
<p>But the source said Iran and Turkmenistan had agreed with Russia's modified sectoral proposal.</p>
<p>Oil industry sources have said Moscow is willing to bend on the legal status in exchange for prominent roles by LUKoil in Caspian projects.</p>
<p>-- Moscow Newsroom +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
