<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133234" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugoslav Zastava Arms workers may resume protests.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav Zastava Arms workers may resume protests.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The independent trade union of Zastava Arms, Yugoslavia's biggest weapons manufacturer, will decide on Tuesday whether to resume protests after talks with the management failed, Belgrade newspaper Nasa Borba reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The management stuck by its decision on disciplinary measures against 146 workers who went on hunger strike or took an active role in the protests outside the town hall from August 19 to October 3,&quot; Zastava Arms trade union president Zoran Nedeljkovic was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The protests were suspended until October 22 pending talks with the management over workers' demands for unpaid wages and holiday pay, a programme to revive production and the sacking of top company managers.</p>
<p>Thousands of Zastava Arms workers, joined by their colleagues from other factories of the Zastava Group, left their jobs for an hour each day for six weeks to attend a rally outside the town hall in Kragujevac.</p>
<p>Like the rest of the Yugoslav economy, Zastava Arms was hit hard by sanctions and a shrunken market following the breakup of the former Yugoslav federation in 1991.</p>
<p>Independent trade union secretary Dragutin Stanojlovic accused Zastava Group president Srboljub Vasovic for the failure of the negotiations.</p>
<p>The trade union and the management failed to reach an agreement because Vasovic wants fierce action against Zastava Arms workers, Stanojlovic said.</p>
<p>The plant's management earlier said it would be hard to make up for damage as a result of more than 100,000 lost hours and called for &quot;disciplinary measures&quot; against the organisers of the protests.</p>
<p>Trade union officials said they would respond in kind if authorities took any repressive measures.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade union has stood up in the defence of its members and we are forced to continue our protests. If the workers accept the trade union's proposal, our protests will resume at 1100 on Wednesday,&quot; Nedeljkovic said. -- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
