<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133217" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Firms for Slovak P-bonds fails to impress analysts.</title>
<headline>Firms for Slovak P-bonds fails to impress analysts.</headline>
<byline>Peter Javurek</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak National Property Fund (NPF) on Tuesday announced the names of 155 companies whose shares will be on offer in bond privatisation, in an attempt to jump-start the ailing scheme.</p>
<p>The NPF, a state privatisation agency, said minority shares worth some 7.9 billion crowns ($254 million) in the firms would be made available for those citizens who wished to exchange their bonds for equity holdings.</p>
<p>But analysts were sceptical that the share offer will help generate interest in the plan, which has suffered from a lack of interest and trust, saying companies and individuals who owed the NPF money would be the only major group buying the bonds with the hopes of getting equity.</p>
<p>&quot;These bonds were simply an unhappy product. I don't expect anything to set silent trading with them in motion,&quot; Jozef Cimra of ING Barings told Reuters.</p>
<p>Under the bond privatisation scheme, over 3.33 million citizens who remained registered from the cancelled voucher privatisation programme were given five-year bonds with a nominal value of 10,000 crowns ($331).</p>
<p>They can sell their bonds before their maturity for a state-guaranteed price of no less than 75 percent of their nominal value, or they can exchange the bonds for shares offered by the NPF.</p>
<p>Trading of the bonds kicked off to much fanfare but little else in August as thousands of Slovaks lined up to sell paper they regarded as worthless.</p>
<p>Difficulty in selling the bonds and a lack of trust in the scheme pushed many to sell the bonds at almost any price.</p>
<p>As of Tuesday, only 4,040 bonds had been traded in anonymous over-the-counter auctions and 107,880 bonds were sold directly, mostly at a price equal or close to 7,500 crowns, the state-guaranteed minimum.</p>
<p>&quot;This list is not very attractive to foreign investors as most of the issues already have a strong majority owner,&quot; Peter Krutil of Creditanstalt said. &quot;NPF debtors may be the only group which might be able to revive the bond market.&quot;</p>
<p>Brokers said the move might bring some liquidity to the starving capital market, but added they were slightly dissapointed with the quality of issues on offer and the size of stakes available.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687 ($ = 31.15 Slovak Crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
