<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133295" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz said in an interview on Hungarian Television that all superfluous legends must be peeled off the 1956 revolution, commemorations should maintain a human perspective, and the idea accepted that it is primarily the holiday of those who were actively involved.</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz presented Imre Nagy Memorial Plaques yesterday to figures involved in the 1956 Revolution, ahead of the forthcoming 40th anniversary.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Gabor Kuncze and his Croatian counterpart Ivan Jarnjak Monday signed a protocol on the exchange of the ratification documents of an agreement on expelling illegal immigrants.</p>
<p>- Free Democrat President Ivan Peto announced Monday that the party MPs have decided to make public their statement of assets for 1994 and for this year.</p>
<p>- The opposition Monday heavily criticised the government for the way it selected the executives of the State Privatisation and Holding Co.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Jozsef Szogyenyi, the lawyer representing Marta Tocsik, said that both his client and himself have received death threats in recent days.</p>
<p>- The parliamentary group of the Smallholders Party expelled deputy faction leader Gyorgy Schamschula from the party after the State Audit Office raised questions about Schamschula's handling of the 1993 GSM tender when he was minister in the Antall administration.</p>
<p>- Hungary's GDP in the first quarter of this year stood at the same level as in January-March 1995, the Central Statistics Office reports.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Minister of Environmental Protection Ferenc Baja and Tom Cornell, of the USAID signed a statement of intent yesterday on $1 million in support to be extended to Hungary.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- Ministries will receive an average of 26 per cent more money from the central budget in 1997 than this year.</p>
<p>- Energy prices will go up by an average of 20-25 per cent on January 1, according to a proposal to be submitted by Imre Karl, the government commissioner for reviewing energy prices.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Parliament with a 58 per cent majority asked that a bill aimed at amending the Penal Code be debated with urgency.</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz meeting New York Governor George Pataki proposed that the state of New York follow some other American states and open an office in Budapest.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy conferred with Irish Finance Minister Ruari Quinn in Budapest yesterday regarding ways to develop bilateral economic ties.</p>
<p>- Retail trade fell by 3.4 per cent in the first half of this year compared to the same period of 1996.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Matav's majority shareholders signed an agreement with the State Privatisation and Holding Co. to introduce Matav shares onto the Budapest Stock Exchange by 1988 at the latest.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The German company Siemens as the largest subcontractor can begin work on the electrification of the Hungarian railway company MAV next year after the concession contract is signed by the winning Italian company.</p>
<p>- The Magyar Kulkereskedelmi Bank announced that it will soon launch its Visa gold card on the market and contemplating telephone banking and current account credit services. @</p>
<p>			   -- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
