<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133281" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Small Russian grain imports likely - Moscow trade.</title>
<headline>Small Russian grain imports likely - Moscow trade.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moscow trade and agricultural sources shrugged off market talk that Russia was soon planning to import large quantities of North American or Australian wheat for its far east, but did not rule out small buys over a period.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been importing only soybeans, and we don't plan to buy any grain,&quot; said OGO president Arkady Zlochevsky.</p>
<p>&quot;It is nonsense to talk about any one company importing millions of tonnes for the far east -- it's just rumours, a fairy-tale,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>OGO is one of Russia's largest private grain traders and is in contact with Western trade and industry sources.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, we're planning to sell 15,000 tonnes of Russian feed grain to Poland,&quot; Zlochevsky said, adding that he thought Russia had enough domestic wheat to meet demand.</p>
<p>Western trade sources have said some private Russian banks and trading organisations may be trying to put together grain import deals, but no big contracts have emerged.</p>
<p>One Russian source, who declined to be identified, said that there was a lot of loose talk but no deals.</p>
<p>Pyotr Shcherbakov, an aide to Deputy Prime Minister Alexander Zaveryukha, who is in charge of the harvest, said Moscow would not be involved in grain imports by the regions.</p>
<p>&quot;You know what Zaveryukha and (Agriculture Minister Viktor) Khlystun have said -- that private or contract agencies may import for delivery to the far east,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the government is not buying and has not been buying for three years, and there are no state orders to contract agencies (like Roskhleboprodukt) to buy for the regions.&quot;</p>
<p>Khlystun has said Russia may buy 500,000 tonnes of food wheat over an unspecified time from Canada, the United States and/or Australia, because imports to Vladivostok would be cheaper than hauling domestic grain by rail across Russia's vast distances to needy, far-flung regions.</p>
<p>Officials at Roskhleboprodukt, the semi-state grain buying agency that fills orders made by the federal or regional governments, declined to comment.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure, Russia could import over the course of a year, and from many different sources, two million tonnes of grain,&quot; OGO's Zlochevsky said.</p>
<p>Russia's total wheat imports over the July 1995-June 1996 crop marketing year soared to 3.15 million tonnes, with wheat flour imports comprising an additional one million tonnes, according to independent consultancy SovEcon Ltd.</p>
<p>But about 70 percent of wheat imports came from Kazakhstan, while the United States, the only Western exporter represented in SovEcon's total, sent only 113,000 tonnes over this period.</p>
<p>Officials have said private or contract traders may raise money for any deals by selling or bartering some of their own grain to former Soviet republics or Eastern European countries.</p>
<p>Roskhleboprodukt has said that it is trying to barter domestic grain for Uzbek cotton, but no deals have emerged.</p>
<p>-- Lynnley Browning, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
