<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13321" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: UNITA to accept Angolan vice-presidency - agency.</title>
<headline>UNITA to accept Angolan vice-presidency - agency.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angola's former rebel movement UNITA will accept the offer of a vice-presidency in a new unity government but will not appoint its leader Jonas Savimbi to the post, the Portuguese news agency Lusa reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;UNITA will accept an Angolan vice-presidency but will not designate its president Jonas Savimbi to take this position,&quot; Lusa quoted the movement's spokesman Marcial Dachala as saying.</p>
<p>UNITA has been holding a congress in its northern stronghold of Bailundo since Tuesday to decide whether Savimbi should join the ruling MPLA to form a unity government of old foes and help cement a fragile two-year-old peace.</p>
<p>On offer is one of two vice-presidencies which Savimbi, 63, has said his UNITA colleagues must accept or decline for him.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, the congress loudly rejected the vice-presidency, shouting &quot;negative, negative&quot; when the topic was raised.</p>
<p>There was no official vote and Savimbi later warned delegates against making &quot;extreme decisions.&quot;</p>
<p>He also told the congress that war was no longer an option and that they would have to prepare for opposition politics.</p>
<p>Some party officials have suggested UNITA's chief constitutional negotiator Abel Chivukuvuku could become vice-president instead.</p>
<p>Political analysts and diplomats said that the 20-month peace could survive even if Savimbi declined the government job.</p>
<p>Lusa said Savimbi would hold a news conference on Tuesday to present the congress's conclusions.</p>
<p>UNITA and the once Marxist MPLA government, who fought for two decades after the colonial power Portugal pulled out, signed a peace pact in 1994.</p>
<p>Since then Angola has remained largely divided into MPLA-controlled areas centred on the capital Luanda, and UNITA-held territory which includes northern diamond areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
