<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133298" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Anti-drug chief says U.S. cocaine market shrinking.</title>
<headline>Anti-drug chief says U.S. cocaine market shrinking.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>AYACUCHO, Peru 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. anti-drug chief Barry McCaffrey said on Tuesday cocaine producers would have to look for new markets because within a decade the United States would stop being a major consumer of the drug.</p>
<p>&quot;Cocaine producers will soon be looking for a new market. It could be Brazil, Poland or Hong Kong but not the United States. Ten years from now the United States will not be a major cocaine consumer,&quot; McCaffrey told Reuters during a visit to Peru to evaluate the country's anti-drug efforts.</p>
<p>McCaffrey said the fact that U.S. drug consumers were increasingly abandoning cocaine for &quot;different manufactured drugs&quot; would reduce producers' profits as the drug would become cheaper on world markets.</p>
<p>U.S. consumers spend $49 billion annually on illegal drugs, half the amount spent only a few years ago, he added.</p>
<p>The drug czar made his comments as he tried to inspect U.S.-funded alternative crop programmes in Peru's lush River Apurimac valley.</p>
<p>Accompanied by President Alberto Fujimori he flew over the jungle region where the government is encouraging local farmers to substitute fields of coca, the raw product for cocaine, for other products like cocoa, coffee, cotton and corn.</p>
<p>Peru, whose economy receives around $400 million each year from the illegal drugs trade, is the world's largest grower of coca leaf, accounting for 50 percent of total production, Interior Minister Juan Briones Davila said.</p>
<p>McCaffrey could not inspect the projects due to thick cloud in the low-lying jungle area and was forced to fly back to the highland city of Ayacucho, 360 miles (575 km) east of Lima. Another attempt to visit the Apurimac projects was scheduled for Wednesday.</p>
<p>McCaffrey, a former commander-in-chief of the United States Southern Command, arrived in Peru late on Monday for what he termed &quot;a purely fact-finding visit&quot; from Panama and was due to return to the United States late on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AYACUCHO, Peru"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
