<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133230" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Doctors say Russian medicine in terminal decline.</title>
<headline>Doctors say Russian medicine in terminal decline.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>While President Boris Yeltsin looks abroad for the best the world can offer for his heart disease, Russian doctors say his nation is beginning to die out for lack of basic medical care.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to the stage where we can't keep quiet any more,&quot; said Mikhail Kuzmenko, leading a demonstration by medical workers outside the White House government building on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we carry on like this we will be a dying nation.&quot;</p>
<p>The picket was part of a string of protests across Russia by doctors and nurses who, like millions of public sector workers, have not been paid for months and say they have not enough medicines, equipment or even food for their patients.</p>
<p>&quot;Homeless and hungry medical workers are dangerous,&quot; said one of the placards held by the Moscow demonstrators, who said medical staff were forced to live in overcrowded hostels.</p>
<p>&quot;If a nurse hasn't slept or eaten properly, how can she be expected to assist in an operation or look after someone in intensive care?&quot; said Vera Sklyarovna, sister at the Odinstovski regional hospital west of Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Patients sleep in the corridors in our hospital and this summer there was only one doctor for 90 patients,&quot; she said, adding that many had fled medicine for private business.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has a team of doctors monitoring his progress as he prepares for heart surgery next month and equipment is expected to be flown in from the United States for the operation, which is likely to take place in one of Moscow's top hospitals.</p>
<p>But effective medical treatment in Russia is largely reserved for those with influence or money, even though the 1993 constitution promises free care for all.</p>
<p>&quot;People don't pay for treatment as such, but for food, medicine, everything, maybe even for the doctors, who don't get paid and look for a way to make some cash,&quot; said Kuzmenko, a senior doctor and the head of Russia's medical trade union.</p>
<p>He admitted that corruption was also a drain on resources.</p>
<p>Official statistics show deaths exceeding births in Russia over the past few years, leading to annual population drops of more than half a million people.</p>
<p>&quot;Imagine what will happen if that goes on? What will happen to the economy if today, according to the prosecutor general, 80 percent of children finishing school are ill,&quot; said Kuzmenko.</p>
<p>Health Minister Tatyana Dmitrieva said on Monday that her ministry had so far received only 38 percent of the sum budgeted for this year, which is itself far below ministry estimates of what is needed.</p>
<p>Kuzmenko said Yeltsin had gone back on a pledge made at his August inuguration for a second term in the Kremlin to soften the blow of market reforms with a bigger emphasis on social protection.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very sorry that the president is seriously ill, as I would be with anyone. He obviously can't just cough up two trillion roubles ($400 million), but as head of state he should ask his structures to address the issue,&quot; said Kuzmenko.</p>
<p>&quot;At least they could listen...at least explain that they can't do anything, if they can't, but explain why the elite can get good treatment and all the rest can't.&quot;</p>
<p>The demonstrators, who threatened strikes if their protest went unanswered, held out little hope of a response from the towering white government building with mirrored windows.</p>
<p>&quot;They're all wearing rose-tinted glasses in there, they don't see us through that glass,&quot; said Kuzmenko.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
