<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13322" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: New German trains seen earning $670 mln/yr - paper.</title>
<headline>New German trains seen earning $670 mln/yr - paper.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transrapid, Germany's futuristic, high-speed magnetic railway project, should generate an annual income of one billion marks ($670 million), chief executive Dieter Baum said in a newspaper story published on Sunday.</p>
<p>He told the Welt am Sonntag newspaper that contracts were almost complete to build and service the magnetic levitation trains that will cover the 290-km (180 mile) Hamburg-Berlin route in about an hour when they start running in 2005.</p>
<p>Bonn hopes the Transrapid will become a standard-bearer for the world's next generation of high-speed trains, giving Germany a lead over Japan in rail technology's challenge to regional airline traffic in the next century.</p>
<p>Baum, the designated head of its future operating firm, told the newspaper that the Transrapid operator, Magnetschnellbahn Berlin-Hamburg Betriebsgesellschaft mbH, would be founded officially in Berlin this year or early in 1997.</p>
<p>It would go public by autumn 1998 with starting equity capital of 500 million marks.</p>
<p>Using so-called magnetic-levitation propulsion technology developed by Thyssen, the Transrapid will hover above a slim rail.</p>
<p>The project, with trains racing between Germany's two largest cities at top speeds of 400 km (248 miles) an hour, will be the first of its kind in commercial operation if it starts on schedule.</p>
<p>Baum said building work would begin next year with the main contracts to build and service the track and trains to be spread among members of a consortium financing half of the semi-state project.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course we are seeking tenders Europe-wide. But it is not conceivable that any other firm could provide the standards needed,&quot; he told the newspaper.</p>
<p>Transrapid is 50 percent-financed by a consortium comprising Thyssen, Siemens, Daimler-Benz, Hochtief, Holzmann, Bilfinger &amp; Berger AG and Deutsche Bahn AG, the German railway operator.</p>
<p>Baum added that it would be simplest to give Deutsche Bahn the role of monitoring the track, trains and personnel.</p>
<p>Annual operating costs for the venture would be around 280 million marks a year, Baum said. In addition, Deutsche Bahn would receive around 130 million marks a year for use of the tracks and another 170 million marks once the venture is in profit. He declined to forecast profit figures.</p>
<p>Estimated to cost at least nine billion marks, Transrapid is going ahead amid harsh criticism from environmentalists who say Germany's existing ICE high-speed trains use a third of the energy the magnetic levitation trains will need.</p>
<p>Embarrassed by the failure of the ICE high-speed rail to compete internationally against the TGV of France, Bonn hopes Transrapid will boost Germany in the global battle for innovative technology,</p>
<p>Baum, a 56-year-old engineer, said he was preparing for his role at the helm of the Transrapid project by discussing similar ventures in other countries, primarily the Eurotunnel project, the undersea rail link between Britain and France.</p>
<p>&quot;I recently spoke with the Eurotunnel head Alistair Morton in London and went through some of his company's teething problems,&quot; Baum said, commenting that Eurotunnel was a riskier venture because the state had no involvement.</p>
<p>Baum said the existence of an operating firm for Transrapid would make it easier to monitor building schedules and pricing and said the German project would not be hit by price-slashing by competitors, as Eurotunnel was.</p>
<p>In addition, while Eurotunnel was confronted continually with fresh security demands as building went on, Baum said he planned to finalise security issues by the end of next year.</p>
<p>The main risks for Transrapid were a lower-than-expected demand for the service or a delay in construction.</p>
<p>&quot;The worst would be delays. One year would mean a loss of 700 million marks,&quot; Baum said.</p>
<p>Transrapid is targeting annual passenger numbers of 14.5 million. However Baum said the venture could still turn a profit by 2010 if numbers were as low as 12.5 million. ($1=1.4895 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
