<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133270" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- An International Monetary Fund mission is expected to visit Bulgaria after the presidential elections on October 27, to review the implementation of the cabinet's structural reform programme, the newspaper said without quoting sources.</p>
<p>-- The World Bank wants an electricity price increase from $0.027 to $0.035 per kWh, a World Bank representative said at a meeting with the president of the Competition Protection Committee, Stephan Nechev.</p>
<p>-- The Board of Directors of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development will review in November an investment programme to extend funds to Bulgaria in return for closure of old reactors at Kozloduy nuclear power station.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- The Chief Prosecutor's Office advised the Bulgarian National Bank to enforce strict control to preserve the credit files of commercial banks placed under special supervision, the head of the investigation supervision department Angel Ganev said.</p>
<p>-- The Dutch ING Bank and German bank VNF extended a $3.5 million credit line to the Bulgarian Expressbank to secure payments for 4,000 tonnes of raw tobacco contracted between the U. S. concern Socotab and Bulgarian state company Gotse Delchev BT, Gotse Delchev BT director Assen Ilchev said.</p>
<p>-- A Russian financial group is expected to buy the state company Balkancar, deputy Industry Minister Stanislav Dimitrov said. Some foreign firms including the South Korean Daewoo are also interested in the privatisation of Balkancar, whose fork lift trucks sell well in Russia.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's wheat and barley sown areas this autumn will not exceed 600 000 to 700 000 hectares, an Institute of Agricultural Economics official told journalists. The minimum required to meet the country's needs is 1.6 million hectares.</p>
<p>-- The South Korean Daewoo corporation is interested in buying the Russe state shipbuilding yard on the Danube river, information agency Balkan said.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- Businessman Dilyan Bunovsky-Dorn, convicted of siphoning some $17 million abroad from the state owned INCO company in 1993-94 was released on bail of 500,000 levs.</p>
<p>-- Sofia newsroom 359 2 84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
