<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133285" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified them and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Yugoslav Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic will visit Austria on October 23 and 24.</p>
<p>- The assembly of the Serb-held region of Eastern Slavonia in Croatia reiterated its commitment on Monday to a declaration passed in June demanding that the region be granted special status within the republic.</p>
<p>- Yugoslav October average wages are 707 dinars, up 0.9 percent against previous month, said the federal statistics office.</p>
<p>- American Express travellers cheques will be available in four Yugoslav banks -- Komercijalna banka, Beobanka, Jugobanka and Karic banka -- as of Wednesday, said Vladimir Zimonjic, director of American Express for Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Head of provincial government of Vojvodina in Serbia, Bosko Perosevic, called on central bank to support major exporters.</p>
<p>- Number of visitors in Serbia in January-September period fell 11 pecent against the same period last year, the republic's statistics office said.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- U.S. special envoy John Kornblum to exert pressure on Bosnian Serb leadership and return them on &quot;Dayton track&quot;. -- Belgrade Newsroom 381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
