<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133203" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian stocks off as foreigners pull plug.</title>
<headline>Slovenian stocks off as foreigners pull plug.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares dropped two percent on Tuesday, extending recent losses sparked by the withdrawal of foreign money from the nation's equity market.</p>
<p>&quot;This market has become dependent on foreign investors, whose future steps are hard to predict,&quot; said Karmen Cerar a trader at brokerage Poteza.</p>
<p>An influx of foreign funds had driven Slovenian share prices up some 45 percent since early September but at the end of last week investors began taking profits out of the rally.</p>
<p>On Tuesday the seven-share SBI index 24.96 points to 1,224.8.</p>
<p>Overall 12 shares fell, six rose and three were unchanaged while three were untraded.</p>
<p>Turnover fell to 304.4 million tolars from 399.3 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in turnover is a clear sign that foreigners are not as active as they were,&quot; Cerar added.</p>
<p>Others predicted that foreign investors would remain the driving force on the Ljubljana bourse for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;It may be that they have changed their strategy or are waiting for newly listed shares,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Bank SKB was the most actively traded share. It firmed 0.02 percent to close at 40,030 tolars on volume of 4,046 shares for total turnover of 162.1 million tolars.</p>
<p>Food producer Droga was the leading decliner, falling 12.13 percent to close at 21,520 tolars on volume of 160 shares for total turnover of 3.7 million tolars.</p>
<p>Financial consultancy Primofin was the biggest gainer, firming four percent to 26,000 tolars on volume of 11 shares for total turnover of 287,000 tolars. -- Novica Mihajlovic, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
