<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133211" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechen rebels explore chances for Moscow mission.</title>
<headline>Chechen rebels explore chances for Moscow mission.</headline>
<byline>Oleg Shchedrov</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chechen separatist leaders dispatched a representative to Moscow on Tuesday to try to grab the initiative in the shaky peace process which has stopped 21 months of fighting in the southern region.</p>
<p>Ruslan Khutayev, responsible for links with Russia in a newly-formed cabinet set up by the separatists, headed for the capital to try to set up a mission, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>The cabinet has not been recognised by Moscow and Khutayev's visit appears designed to force Moscow's hand following the dismissal of the Kremlin's key peacemaker Alexander Lebed, whose departure has sparked concern in the rebel camp.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin cast a shadow over the peace deal signed by Lebed and the rebels on August 31 when he sacked the former paratroop general last Thursday, accusing him of cherishing premature presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>Lebed agreed with rebel chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov to withdraw Russian troops sent in December 1994 to crush Chechen separatism in return for a five-year deferral on a decision about the region's future political status.</p>
<p>After the deal, the rebels confirmed their plans to seek independence, took Chechnya under their control and unilaterally formed a &quot;coalition government&quot;, defying an earlier agreement to cooperate with Russia in creating a post-war authority.</p>
<p>Separatist leaders have also called polls for January 27 to elect a regional parliament and new regional leader.</p>
<p>Interfax quoted the pro-independence Congress of the Chechen People movement as saying that more than 1,500 of its delegates would meet on Sunday to discuss preparation for the polls.</p>
<p>Moscow opponents of the peace agreement struck by Lebed and Maskhadov -- who was named head of the separatist government on Saturday -- say that the agreement meant capitulation for Russia and that it might encourage separatism elswhere in the country.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin on Monday ruled out granting full independence to Chechnya but Moscow has taken steps to keep up negotiations.</p>
<p>Interfax said a bilateral commission, set up to promote the peace process, would meet on Saturday.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted Ivan Rybkin, named by Yeltsin as his new Chechen negotiator, as saying the Russian government had prepared an amnesty for all participants in the Chechen conflict.</p>
<p>Experts see an amnesty as the only possible way to end legal problems of dealing with separatist leaders, most of whom are wanted by Russian police on mutiny charges.</p>
<p>The rebels have appeared unimpressed by Moscow's tough line on the future political status of the region.</p>
<p>Moscow for its part has so far done little to counteract the creation of a new separatist government or protest at a string of pro-independence remarks by rebel leader Zelimkhan Yandarbiyev.</p>
<p>Chechen envoy Khutayev said he supported the idea of setting up a permanent mission of Yeltsin's Security Council in Chechnya and said he hoped there would be no problem with the rebel mission in Moscow.</p>
<p>He suggested that the rebels might simply take over the premises currently occupied by pro-Russian Chechen government of Doku Zavgayev, which was sidelined in the latest peace deal and apparently abandoned by Moscow.</p>
<p>Khutayev said he would hand his proposals to Chernomyrdin but made clear a personal meeting was up to the premier. A government spokesman said no meeting had been planned for now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
