<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133296" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: FEATURE - Bulgaria's monarchists boycott presidential poll.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bulgaria's monarchists boycott presidential poll.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Supporters of Bulgaria's King Simeon II are calling for a boycott of Sunday's presidential elections and say the exiled monarch can unite the crisis-ridden country where politicians have failed.</p>
<p>Simeon, a Madrid-based business consultant, returned to Bulgaria for the first time in 50 years for a three-week visit in May and was mobbed by ecstatic flag-waving royalists wherever he went.</p>
<p>Posters bearing his face and the legend &quot;No to a presidency, yes to a Tsar&quot; have appeared in Sofia's streets in the past few days and are plastered particularly thickly outside the modest offices of the Kingdom of Bulgaria Federation in central Sofia.</p>
<p>&quot;We have appealed to all our supporters in the whole country, to all those who love King Simeon, all those who greeted him in the streets when he came to Bulgaria, if they love him, not to vote in the coming election,&quot; said Federation council member Konstantin Halachev.</p>
<p>&quot;When the country is in a hopeless situation and political parties are blaming each other, you need a figure to unite the nation.&quot;</p>
<p>Halachev, who was born in 1926, speaks nostalgically of the rule of Simeon's father, King Boris III, who died in 1943. &quot;When Tsar Boris was king, there was no corruption in this country,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Now 59, Simeon fled Bulgaria as a child in 1946 after the Soviet Red Army installed a puppet communist regime. Halachev said he had met Simeon in Madrid in 1990 and during his visit to Sofia but the king had no particular contact with monarchist movements in his homeland.</p>
<p>Halachev said Simeon had told the monarchists Bulgaria's social and economic crisis required everyone to work together. &quot;I cannot help you, you should help yourselves and all together we shall overcome this crisis,&quot; he quoted the king as saying.</p>
<p>Even without a formal election boycott, many Bulgarians disillusioned with politicians' inability to improve their daily lives have told opinion pollsters they will not vote.</p>
<p>Most people are more concerned with soaring prices and bread and fuel shortages looming in the coming Balkan winter than with elections to what is a largely ceremonial post.</p>
<p>Under its post-communist constitution, Bulgaria is a parliamentary republic in which the president's powers are limited to vetoing legislation once, appointing ambassadors and some state officials, and commanding the armed forces.</p>
<p>Fading posters publicising Simeon's May visit still hang on lampposts around town next to election posters for the two main presidential candidates, Petar Stoyanov of the opposition Union of Democratic Forces and the Socialist Ivan Marazov.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not going to vote for anybody, they are all lying to us because they want the power and the money,&quot; 63-year-old pensioner Georgi Nachev said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the king should come back because he's rich and well-educated and he's the man we need.&quot;</p>
<p>Outgoing president Zhelyu Zhelev, a former dissident philosopher and a staunch republican, has said he regards Simeon as an important part of Bulgaria's history.</p>
<p>The Socialist government for their part avoided any contact with the king during his visit.</p>
<p>State media refer to him as Simeon Coburgotski, the name in his Bulgarian passport. As a Saxe-Coburg, he is related to other European royal families, including Britain's House of Windsor.</p>
<p>Bulgarians voted for a republic in a rigged referendum in September 1946 but Simeon never renounced his claim to the throne. The balding, bearded monarch is respected even by republicans as a serious, hard-working businessman who eschews the playboy lifestyle of some exiled royals. He is married to a Spanish aristocrat and his five children have Bulgarian names.</p>
<p>Many Bulgarians say they admire the king personally but have mixed feelings about reinstating the monarchy as an institution.</p>
<p>&quot;The king has proved that he cares for Bulgaria, it is good to have such a person in charge because in that way we are going to stop the corruption, but still I think it is too early to have the king back,&quot; said 26-year-old teacher Chavdar Angelov.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they all have had their chances and now the king should have his chance as well,&quot; said nurse Svetla Ivanova, 32. &quot;But on the other hand, how can one be sure that his son will be just like him?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
