<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133276" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: U.S. said worried by &quot;low&quot; Czech defence spending.</title>
<headline>U.S. said worried by &quot;low&quot; Czech defence spending.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher has privately expressed concern to the Czech Republic, a frontrunner for early NATO membership, that its defence spending may be too low, Czech officials say.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton is expected to call later on Tuesday for NATO to recruit some former Soviet Bloc countries by 1999, the 50th anniversary of the Western defence alliance.</p>
<p>But military spending has become a controversial issue within the Czech coalition and the increase in the 1997 defence budget falls well short of the rise in overall state spending.</p>
<p>Officials close to the Czech Foreign Ministry said Christopher had raised the issue with Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus when he visited Washington last month.</p>
<p>Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott and the Czech-born U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, Madeleine Albright, had also indicated their worries either to Klaus or Foreign Minister Josef Zieleniec, they said, requesting anonymity.</p>
<p>&quot;When Mr Klaus recently visited the U.S. he had a discussion with Warren Christopher about the low expenditure on the army. Mr Talbott and Madeleine Albright have also expressed their worries on this issue,&quot; said one official.</p>
<p>A U.S. embassy spokeswoman in Prague declined comment.</p>
<p>Prague and Washington enjoy warm relations and Christopher indeed said that Prague was taking &quot;all the right steps to prepare for possible NATO membership&quot; when he met Klaus.</p>
<p>The alliance is expected to decide on which former East Bloc countries to recruit and when by early next year. In Detroit, U.S. officials said Clinton would set the 1999 target on Tuesday but not name any preferred countries.</p>
<p>NATO officials have said that post-communist countries do not necessarily have to spend vast sums on defence to join. But they cannot expect a free ride financed by the West and must ensure that their armed forces can work to NATO standards.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic, keen to end a security limbo since the fall of communism, needs to modernise its Soviet-era equipment along with other NATO hopefuls such as Poland and Hungary.</p>
<p>So far the issue does not seem to have soured U.S.-Czech relations. One diplomatic source said the U.S. concern had been expressed fairly obliquely. &quot;It was not a hard pitch,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the 1997 budget, which faces two more parliamentary readings, defence spending at 32 billion crowns ($1.2 billion) is only 4.8 percent higher than the original 1996 budget.</p>
<p>But the government recently cut 1996 spending across the board due to lower than expected revenue. This makes proposed 1997 defence spending 8.5 percent above the revised level.</p>
<p>This is in line with forecast inflation for next year but well short of the 18.4 percent increase in the overall budget.</p>
<p>The Czech Defence Ministry rejected any suggestion that military spending was too low. &quot;We have not had any official signals of this kind,&quot; said ministry spokesman Milan Repka.</p>
<p>Altogether two percent of the Czech gross domestic product would be go on defence spending in 1997, he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The issue is also linked to Czech politics as the Foreign Ministry is controlled by Klaus's Civic Democratic Party and the Defence Ministry by the Christian Democrats.</p>
<p>Last month Klaus returned a plan from Defence Minister Miloslav Vyborny on cutting the size of the army, apparently because it was too severe, and ministers requested a new one.</p>
<p>Some NATO countries are less insistent on the issue. &quot;If you're eliminating waste you're not diminishing effectiveness,&quot; said one senior diplomat from a leading NATO country.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We would be worried if it did diminish effectiveness...We'll be watching this point.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
