<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133268" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Takeover rumours spur Czech IPB shares.</title>
<headline>Takeover rumours spur Czech IPB shares.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Czech IPB rose the maximum allowed five percent on the Prague bourse on Tuesday, spurred by reports that Nomura and ING are leading candidates to take a government-held stake in the bank.</p>
<p>IPB shares rose 15 crowns to 331 at the bourse's daily price fixing, their second consecutive five percent jump after several months of holding steady at the 300 crown level.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you were to bring in a foreign partner of the caliabre of the two banks mentioned, that addresses questions that have been hovering around IPB on its perceived lack of corporate structure and transparency,&quot; said Jay King of Wood and Company.</p>
<p>The bank has been widely criticised for being the least transparent in its dealings of the four major Czech banks, especially during a recent spending spree that has seen it quietly buy large stakes in several firms.</p>
<p>The rumours began last weekend after Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik said IPB was first in line among the big Czech banks for further privatisation, adding that a strong foreign strategic partner would be the most likely beneficiary of any selloff.</p>
<p>He did not give any timetable for the selloff. The government currently holds about a 30 percent stake in the bank, the country's fourth largest.</p>
<p>-- Alan Crosby, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
