<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13325" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Developing countries boost global debt markets-BIS.</title>
<headline>Developing countries boost global debt markets-BIS.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record volume of debt issued by developing countries in the second quarter of 1996 helped propel the international debt securities market to a record high, the Bank for International Settlements (BIS) said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Despite less favourable market conditions, BIS said the issuance of bonds and Euronotes by developing countries was highly resilient, hitting a record $20 billion in the second quarter with two-thirds from Latin American borrowers.  </p>
<p>The global bond market reversal of early 1994, the Mexican crisis in early 1995 and turbulence in financial markets at the beginning of 1996 had only a temporary, localised influence on debt issuance, BIS said in its quarterly report on bank and financial market developments.</p>
<p>The BIS, central bank to the world's central banks, said total new issuance of international bonds and Euronotes rose to $127.7 billion, marking an annualised rise of 18 percent in stock outstanding, against a backdrop of lower volatility in currency and bond markets.  </p>
<p>Although a high proportion of floating rate and short-term paper showed the defensive attitude of investors toward market risks, BIS said a growing number of lower-rated borrowers had tapped the market at favourable terms, illustrating a greater tolerance for credit risks.</p>
<p>&quot;While illustrating in part a recovery of confidence on the part of international investors, active borrowing by lower-rated and non-rated names may also reflect a more general loosening of credit risk standards,&quot; BIS said.  </p>
<p>This development, which originated in the syndicated loan market, is not without risks, BIS warned. It noted the recent default of a Bulgarian state-owned bank on a yen-denominated private placement.</p>
<p>Syndicated bank loans also rose to a record $120.3 billion in the second quarter, boosted by merger and acquisition deals in the United States, the United Kingdom and the French state's facility to finance the country's social security system.  </p>
<p>First quarter figures showed the ongoing retreat by Japanese banks from the international bank credit market. Their market share dropped to 24 percent, the lowest level in more than a decade, from a peak of 38 percent in 1988.</p>
<p>The pull-back by Japanese banks resulting from the so-called Japan premium in the summer of 1995 was also reflected in a shift away from the use of the yen and dollar in international bank lending in favour of the German mark, BIS said.  </p>
<p>In a look at national banking groups, BIS found the combined share of European banks rose to 58 percent at end-1995 from 41 percent at end-1985. German banks emerged as the dominant European group in cross-border lending, replacing French banks which had been the most important in 1985.</p>
<p>The relative importance of U.S. banks has been seriously eroded over the last decade with their share falling to 10 percent at the end of 1995 from 22 percent at end-1985.  </p>
<p>U.S. banks have recently capitalised on their renewed financial strength to rebuild their foreign presence, particularly in European currency banking and securities rather than local or trade-related business, the BIS said.</p>
<p>The resilience of borrowing by developing countries despite less favourable market conditions was reflected by the fact that net issues of securities in the first half of 1996 exceeded the previous annual record set in 1994.</p>
<p>Although the impact of Mexico's financial crises in early 1995 was only temporary on the volume of developing country debt, there were significant regional shifts.  </p>
<p>In Latin America, the net issuance by entities in Argentina and Brazil rose strongly, while Mexican borrowers all but withdrew from the market, BIS said.</p>
<p>Together these three countries accounted for more than 90 percent of the stock of outstanding Latin American debt of $91 billion at the end of June 1996.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
