<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133299" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks end down on Dow, rates and peso woes.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks end down on Dow, rates and peso woes.</headline>
<byline>Martin Roberts</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed lower for the second day Tuesday, after being hit by a falling Dow Jones industrial average, prospects of interest rate hikes at the forthcoming primary auction and renewed peso instability.</p>
<p>&quot;Weakness in the peso made the market discount bigger Cetes (Treasury bill) rate hikes than we were expecting,&quot; said Esteban Rojas, deputy research director at the Arka brokerage.</p>
<p>The blue chip IPC index closed down 38.20 points, or 1.16 percent, at 3,247.84. The Dow Jones meanwhile closed down 29.07 points, or 0.48 percent, at 6,061.80.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey showed an average forecast of a 1.69 percentage point hike for benchmark 28-day Cetes rates, to 27.59 percent, at Tuesday evening's central bank auction</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso closed 4.4 centavos weaker at 7.7900 per dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow Jones also dragged us down. Most Mexican ADRs were hit very hard in New York,&quot; Rojas said.</p>
<p>Telmex ADRs, for example, fell 1/2 to 30-3/4, and their heavyweight L series shares fell six centavos (1 cent) to 12.04 pesos ($1.55).</p>
<p>Traders said that market volatility had kept foreign investors on the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;Most foreign investors have shied away from trading, they're not taking earnings reports into account and some are even stepping out, but I think they'll buy back at lower prices when the month ends,&quot; said a floor trader.</p>
<p>Lack of foreign traders could be seen in mediocre trading volume of 59.2 million shares for the session.</p>
<p>On the broad market scoreboard, losers outnumberd gainers by 71 to 13, out of a total of 105 stocks traded.</p>
<p>Cement makers GCC fell two centavos (1 cent) to 8.84 pesos ($1.13) on disappointing results, though holding company Moderna fell 15 centavos (2 cents) to 36.60 pesos ($4.62) despite favourable earnings.</p>
<p>Financial stock GFInver LCP and ACP series headed the losers, down seven centavos (1 cent) and six centavos (1 cent), respectively, to 1.00 (13 cents) and 1.05 pesos (13 cents), in what traders described as profit-taking after the shares had recently gained on rumours of an association with Banco Santander.</p>
<p>Technical analysts expected the IPC to fall further on Wednesday and test support at 3,220 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
