<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133289" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- The way local elections were conducted showed the opposition remained unable to compete with the ruling party and that nothing could be gained by merely complaining, newspaper editorial says.</p>
<p>- October 20 local elections were a confirmation of the results of the May general election, President Sali Berisha said at a news conference the day after voting closed.</p>
<p>- The opposition says Sunday's poll was another example of voter manipulation, which it claims were a feature of May 26 general elections.</p>
<p>- Most Tirana university students did not vote on Sunday.</p>
<p>- The ethnic Greek Human Rights Party suffered heavy losses and did not match the results of local polls four years ago.</p>
<p>- Albania started a partial privatisation of the chromium industry. German firm Preussag, which won the tender, plans to invest 80 million marks.</p>
<p>- Police have arrested 21 people suspected of belonging to a guerrilla group, which they say has committed many crimes in the last four years.</p>
<p>- Ethnic Greek organisation Omonia attacked Greece for not giving Albanian immigrants a guarantee they could return if they voted in Albanian polls on Sunday.</p>
<p>- Astrit Hafizi was elected coach of the Albanian national soccer team to replace Neptun Bajko, who resigned after a poor result against Portugal in a World Cup group nine qualifier.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Ruling Democratic Party candidate for the post of Tirana mayor Albert Brojka won 54 percent of the votes and his opposition Socialist rival 38.4 percent.</p>
<p>- European observers said Sunday's local polls were free and fair.</p>
<p>- Three bombs exploded in three towns at the weekend, causing panic but no one was hurt.</p>
<p>- Lawyers of Klement Kolaneci, son-in-law of the late communist dictator Enver Hoxha, who was arrested last week on suspicion of having guerrilla links, say they are not allowed to meet him.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
