<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133283" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Tuesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Coop eration Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Deputy Prime Minister and leader of the Democratic Party Saimnieks Ziedonis Chevers tendered his resignation to Prime Minister Andris Shklele who later accepted it. Chever's party expressed support for its leader but said it would stay in the government.</p>
<p>- The executive director of Riga City Council Andris Grinbergs issued an order to turn on the city heating for houses.</p>
<p>- The parliamentary faction of the Fatherland &amp; Freedom party said it was against shortening the deadline for the use of privatisation vouchers and reducing their value.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- Interior minister Dainis Turlais ordered an investigation after a TV programme showed the imprisoned head of the collapsed Banka Baltiya speaking on a mobile phone from his cell.</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs is on an official visit to South Korea, Vietnam, Thailand and Indonesia from October 23 to Nobember 10.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- In a press conference after his party's victory in Lithuania's elections, the leader of Lithuania's Fatherland Union, Vytautas Landsbergis, announced that parliament will unilaterally proclaim the country's maritime border with Latvia.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
