<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13327" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria to hold conference over future within days.</title>
<headline>Algeria to hold conference over future within days.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian authorities and opposition groups will hold a national conference, a milestone in President Liamine Zeroual's drive to reshape the country's future, in the &quot;next few days&quot;, an official spokesman announced on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The unfolding of this conference is expected in the next few days&quot;, said Amar Tou, a spokesman of a joint committee set up by the presidency and comprising over 20 opposition parties to prepare details of a &quot;national conference of harmony&quot;.</p>
<p>Algeria has been seeking a way out of civil strife which has racked the country since the authorities in 1992 cancelled a general election in which the fundamentalist Islamic Salvation Front (FIS) took a commanding lead. An estimated 50,000 people have been killed in the violence.</p>
<p>Among the political parties represented in the committee are the former sole ruling party, the National Liberation Front (FLN), two legal Islamist groups, Hamas and Nahda, and the secular anti-Islamist Rally for Democracy and Culture (RCD).</p>
<p>The FIS is outlawed and was not involved.</p>
<p>&quot;Political parties' representatives and (presidency) officials reached an accord over a proposal making the national conference of harmony the crowning of the dialogue process&quot;, said Tou, quoted by Algerian state-run radio and television.</p>
<p>Zeroual started a dialogue with opposition parties, after an election last November confirmed him in power, to try to rally support for his plan to hold a referundum to amend the constitution this year and then hold general elections in 1997.</p>
<p>The joint committee for the national conference was one of four bodies, grouping Zeroual's aides and party officials, set up in mid-August in the wake of a marathon dialogue.</p>
<p>The three other committes have finalised draft new election and party laws and proposed changes to the constitution.</p>
<p>The national conference will mainly adopt a kind of code of political conduct, banning the use of violence as a way to seek or hold power, said Tou, who is FLN's official.</p>
<p>The secular opposition Socialist Forces Front (FFS) walked out early this month from Zeroual's talks alleging he intended mostly to build an &quot;anti-Islamist front&quot;.</p>
<p>Presidency officials and political parties, taking part in the talks, on Saturday drew up an election law to introduce proportional representation instead of the two round majority system that brought the FIS close to power.</p>
<p>Earlier last week they also drafted a law governing political activities that would eventually ban Islamists parties.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
