<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133282" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian lev eases despite c.bank support.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian lev eases despite c.bank support.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev eased to 226.50-228 per dollar in morning interbank trade from 224.50-226 at the close on Monday despite central bank support as dollar demand heavily outweighed supply, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign currency demand is much higher than supply and central bank dollar sales are the only factor that prevents a lev slump so far,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The central bank (BNB) was offering dollars only to final clients near 226.50 levs since the opening, traders said.</p>
<p>Central bank officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The market was driven by dollar-bullish sentiment this week after the central bank cut the main rate and due to uncertainty whether Bulgaria will win the second tranche of funding from the International Monetary Fund, traders said.</p>
<p>Banks and financial houses now build up forex positions, which they had pared for nearly a month under the previous record high main rate, traders said.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) cut its central interest rate to 20 percent monthly or 240 percent annually from 25 percent per month or an annual 300 percent, effective from last Friday.</p>
<p>The lev traded at 222-223 on Thursday before the rate cut was announced.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has twice delayed a much needed $115 second tranche of funding until Bulgaria meets reform targets under a funding deal sealed in July.</p>
<p>An IMF mission is expected to arrive in Sofia by the end of the month to review the government's reform performance in closing down loss-makers and speeding up privatisation. -- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
