<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133220" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia raises Oct T-bill mkt limit for foreigners.</title>
<headline>Russia raises Oct T-bill mkt limit for foreigners.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's central bank has raised the limit for non-residents on the government securities market for October to $1.5 billion from $1.0 billion, the bank's first deputy chairman Sergei Aleksashenko told Reuters on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The central bank has not yet set a November limit, he said.</p>
<p>The authorities control the amount which non-residents can invest in the government securities market by limiting the total amount of foreign currency which Russian banks can buy from non-residents investing in the market.</p>
<p>Inflows in this way had already reached $850-900 million by October 15, compared with the limit for the month of $1 billion, central bank officials said.</p>
<p>Investment in August had totalled $350-$400 million against a limit of $700 million, and in September totalled $850 million against a limit of $1 billion.  </p>
<p>Foreign investment in the market rose substantially in early October after the central bank announced it was reducing the guaranteed dollar yield to non-residents to 16 percent from 19 percent as of October 16.</p>
<p>Since August non-residents have been able to invest in Russian GKO T-bills and OFZ government bonds by opening special &quot;S&quot; rouble accounts with designated Russian banks.</p>
<p>They can use these accounts to buy government securities at auction or buy and sell them in the secondary market.</p>
<p>There is no limit on the amount which can be repatriated from these accounts, and no limit on the amount of each individual issue which foreigners can buy.</p>
<p>But non-residents have to buy foreign currency from these accounts using forward transactions or options with a term of at least three months.</p>
<p>The central bank regulates the guaranteed dollar yield available to non-residents buying securities at auction and holding them to maturity by requiring Russian banks to offset a proportion of these forward deals with the central bank, at rates determined by the central bank.</p>
<p>The guaranteed yield of 16 percent in dollar terms is still one of the highest available for fixed-income instruments, but Russian bankers say non-residents can raise their return by playing the secondary market aggressively.</p>
<p>--Anna Smirnova, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
