<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133360" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba details agriculture damage caused by Lili.</title>
<headline>Cuba details agriculture damage caused by Lili.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba on Tuesday gave details of extensive damage caused to agriculture by Hurricane Lili, saying the storm had destroyed almost all crops in eight of the country's 14 provinces.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Roberto Robaina met the diplomatic corps in Havana to give foreign envoys details of the storm, which swept through western and central areas of the country Thursday night and Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the hurricane) destroyed almost all crops in eight of the 14 provinces,&quot; said a statement given to the diplomats at the meeting, adding that in the affected area, every single banana plantation was damaged.</p>
<p>&quot;There was also damage to schools, health centres and industry,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It said some 656,138 hectares (1.62 million acres) of sugar cane had been affected. Sugar is a key foreign exchange earner for the communist-ruled island and the crop is due to be harvest in just two or three months' time.</p>
<p>However, it appears the affected cane will be useable, at least partly, for the harvest. Sugar Minister Nelson Torres told state television Monday night that Cuba still aimed for an increase in production in the 1996-97 sugar harvest over last year's production of 4.45 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The statement given to diplomats said the hurricane had destroyed 21,563 hectares (53,284 acres) of bananas, a staple in the Cuban diet. And some 36,181 hectares (89,403 acres) of other fruits and vegatables had been affected.</p>
<p>No casualties were reported, but the storm was a severe blow to Cuba at a time when the island is struggling to emerge from a five-year economic crisis caused by the collapse of its old economic partner the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Diplomats who attended Monday's meeting stressed Cuba was not asking for aid, but wanted to give a clear picture of how bad the damage was.</p>
<p>Robaina Monday asked the United Nations to provide humanitarian asistance to help the island recover from the effects of Hurricane Lili, saying the storm had caused a &quot;national tragedy&quot;.</p>
<p>In a meeting with representatives of U.N. agencies, Robaina said Cuba urgently needed food, medicines, construction and agricultural material.</p>
<p>The government statement said that in addition to damage to farmland, the hurricane destroyed 5,640 houses and partially affected some 78,855 other homes. It cut communications to some areas and contaminated some water sources. Some areas of the country were still without power because of damage to electricity cables.</p>
<p>Investment Minister Ibrahim Feradaz, who was also at Tuesday's meeting with the diplomats, told reporters afterwards that it was too early to evaulate the overall cost of the damage caused by Lili.</p>
<p>But he said the effects would have to be taken into account as the government draws up its economic plan for 1997. Before the hurricane, authorities had predicted Cuba was heading for Gross Domestic Product growth of some five percent thie year, following growth of 2.7 percent last year, and a steady slump from 1990-94.</p>
<p>Ferradez said the effect of the hurricane was serious, especially when Cuba's economic situation is still &quot;complicated&quot;.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the Cuban officials appeared particularly worried about the food situation following the hurricane. Meat is a luxury for most Cubans, so the damage to fruit and vegetables such as bananas, that generally accompany meals of rice and beans, will be felt by everyone.</p>
<p>The authorities are also worried about health problems that might emerge from contaminated water supplies, the envoys said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100216">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
