<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133390" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Serfin Q3 results show woes deepen.</title>
<headline>Serfin Q3 results show woes deepen.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's Grupo Financiero Serfin SA de CV turned in disappointing third quarter results due to weaker margins and continued losses due to provisions, analysts said.</p>
<p>Serfin reported a third quarter loss of 507 million pesos, mostly due to provisions for bad loans at its bank unit Banca Serfin of 700 million during the quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;These were weak results ... This bodes ill for the future,&quot; said Carlos Gomez, a bank analyst at Paribas in New York.  </p>
<p>Although the high level of provisions caused the loss, analysts welcomed the bank's move to clean up its balance sheet ahead of 1997, when Mexican banks will begin to report according to U.S. GAAP.</p>
<p>What worried analysts was an unexpected fall in the bank's net interest margin, the difference between its cost of raising money and the interest it pays customers.</p>
<p>Serfin's interest margin fell to 2.0 percent of average total assets from 2.9 at the end of the second quarter, according to Bear Stearns.  </p>
<p>&quot;We were surprised by this drop ... In our view, the bank has here a serious structural problem,&quot; Bear Stearns analyst Alberto Sanchez said in a report.</p>
<p>Bank officials explained the drop in part because of a decrease in customers using credit cards as a means of financing, a reduction of 500 basis points in the yield of commercial loans, and a restructuring of mortgage loans with lower spreads.</p>
<p>Serfin officials have said they want to use their existing network to capture deposits at low cost and improve margins.  </p>
<p>But only about 28 percent of Serfin's funding was low cost during the third quarter, compared with about 35 percent in the second quarter, according to Rogelio Urrutia, a bank analyst at Valores Finamex in Mexico City.</p>
<p>And Serfin officials on Monday said it would take until 1999 to raise the percentage of low cost funding to half the total funding.</p>
<p>Bear Stearns said &quot;significant downsizing&quot; is needed to make Serfin viable.  It has Serfin rated as &quot;unattractive.&quot;</p>
<p>Serfin's rate of growth in past-due loans fell sharply from 27.5 percent in the second quarter to about 8.5 percent during the third quarter.  But that still compares unfavorably with other Mexican banks, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- David Luhnow, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9565</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
