<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133315" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile shares end softer on power sector jitters.</title>
<headline>Chile shares end softer on power sector jitters.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean blue chips limped to a weak close as gloom continued over the spat between the government and power companies over new electricity rates.</p>
<p>The bolsa is expected to resume its downward drift at the opening with the spotlight remaining on electricity stocks, which account for 40 percent of the weighted IPSA index.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is being moved solely by news from the electricity sector,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The IPSA index ended unofficially down 0.38 percent at 100.15 points. The general IGPA index shed 0.48 percent to 5,457.72 points.  </p>
<p>Volume shrank to around seven billion pesos from 9.2 billion pesos Monday.</p>
<p>The light turnover reflected the apathetic mood of the market with investors disillusioned by the dispute over electricity prices which has undermined stocks for two sessions in a row, said dealers.</p>
<p>Leading decliners included power investment company Enersis on fears the firm will suffer a double hit as generation and distribution prices are both set to fall sharply in the government's review, said traders.  </p>
<p>Enersis, which controls generator Endesa and distributor Chilectra, lost 0.9 percent to 246-1/2 pesos. Endesa shed 0.68 percent to 257 pesos.</p>
<p>Investors will also be looking to see whether the government succeeds in negotiations to find a strategic partner to buy a 37.5 percent stake in power utility Colbun, said traders.</p>
<p>State board Corfo has set Wednesday as the deadline for agreeing a deal with a Chilean/Belgian group which was the only consortium to bid for the utility last week.  </p>
<p>The government originally spurned the offer as too low, but later backpedalled, saying it would enter talks with the group.</p>
<p>Winners included pulp producer Copec, up 0.56 percent at 1,790 pesos, fertilizer producer Soquimich, up 0.41 percent at 2,425 pesos, and telecom Entel which rose 0.26 percent to 3,860 pesos.</p>
<p>-- Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
