<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133351" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil states prepare debt-deal bill for Congress.</title>
<headline>Brazil states prepare debt-deal bill for Congress.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governor of Brazil's federal district, Cristovam Buarque, is acting as coordinator for 19 states which intend to present a debt-deal bill to Congress, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said Buarque had drafted a list of demands and prepared four bills, which he had sent back to other governors for their suggestions before presenting them to the Senate.</p>
<p>Among the key items of the bills is a legal obligation for the National Treasury to set up a plan to refinance the rapidly-rising debts of near-bankrupt states.  </p>
<p>The government has been bracing for a showdown with the states following a gathering of governors on October 14 at which they broke off talks with the tight-fisted Finance Ministry.  President Fernando Henrique Cardoso has vowed not to bow to pressure or blackmail.</p>
<p>Brasilia has started refinancing the debts of the states, which in total, including the municipalities, reached 83.99 billion reais in July, up from 81.926 billion reais in June.</p>
<p>In September, Finance Minister Pedro Malan signed deals with Minas Gerais and Rio Grande do Sul to restructure 8.6 billion reais and 6.0 billion reais respectively.  </p>
<p>Both involved 30-year refinancing terms and interest per year of 6.0 percent, adjusted for inflation. In return, the states must carry out fiscal adjustments and retire 20 percent of their debt stock through asset sales.</p>
<p>But smaller states complain they feel discriminated against and say they have not been offered the same terms.</p>
<p>The finances of the states are considered the main contributor to an expected public sector operational deficit this year of 3.5 percent of gross domestic product, down from 5.0 percent in 1995 but up from an original target of 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
