<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133353" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Famed forensic expert joins Raul Salinas defense.</title>
<headline>Famed forensic expert joins Raul Salinas defense.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading forensics expert has joined the defence team of Raul Salinas, the jailed brother of disgraced former Mexican President Carlos Salinas, the defence said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>William R. Maples, a forensic anthropologist who has examined the remains of Czar Nicholas II and Joseph Mengele, told a news conference he would attempt to identify remains found buried at Salinas's country home.</p>
<p>&quot;The team that I am putting together will be a team of world-known experts, very similar to the team that I used to examine the remains of Czar Nicholas II in Russia and ... the identification of (former Nazi leader) Joseph Mengele in South America,&quot; Maples said.</p>
<p>Raul Salinas is in jail on charges he masterminded a political murder and illegally obtained hundreds of millions of dollars while his brother was in office from 1988 to 1994.</p>
<p>Raul Salinas's legal troubles deepened early this month when skeletal remains were found on one of his ranches, although so far he has not been charged.</p>
<p>Speculation swirled that the body belonged to Manuel Munoz Rocha, a Salinas ally and former congressman who witnesses linked to the 1994 murder of Jose Francisco Ruiz Massieu who was secretary-general of the ruling party, the PRI.</p>
<p>Raul Salinas is accused of ordering the killing of Ruiz Massieu, his own former brother-in-law. Munoz Rocha has been missing since that murder.</p>
<p>But government experts have ruled out that the remains are of Munoz Rocha, generating a new mystery as to who it is. The defence claims the body was planted on Salinas's property.</p>
<p>Maples, of the C.A. Pound Human Identification Laboratory at the University of Florida, also has worked on several high-profile U.S. cases in recent years such as serial murders and the assassination of civil rights leader Medgar Evers.</p>
<p>Maples said that once he has access to the remains found on Salinas's ranch -- they are still in the hands of federal authorities -- he would attempt identification using the DNA.</p>
<p>&quot;This has nothing to do with international politics,&quot; Maples said. &quot;We do the same thing in the United States when DNA is used in identification.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
