<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133366" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Moderna Q3 net, sales rise as expected.</title>
<headline>Moderna Q3 net, sales rise as expected.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Empresas La Moderna SA posted improved profits and sales with healthier margins in its third quarter, as forecast by analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a seasonal company, but third quarter results were good and in line with our expectations,&quot; said Georgina Gutierrez, equity analyst at the BBV-Probursa brokerage.</p>
<p>La Moderna reported a nine-month net profit of 1.294 billion pesos, up 17 percent over the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>The third quarter usually represents a seasonal low point for the company, due to the crop cycle affecting its agrobiotechnology division.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures are good, slightly less than I had estimated,&quot; said Rolando Calderon, analyst at the Santander brokerage. He said non-cash items accounted for the difference.</p>
<p>Moderna posted nine-month net sales of 10.449 billion pesos. Hard currency sales totaled $668 million, or 48 percent of total sales, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>La Moderna said that nearly half, or 48 percent, of its net revenues were generated outside Mexico.  </p>
<p>Agrobiotechnology eclipsed cigarettes as the largest source of revenues -- accounting for 47 percent of sales versus 44 percent of sales for cigarettes, the company said. The packaging division accounted for the rest.</p>
<p>Operating earnings for the nine-month period totaled 1.294 billion, up 17 percent compared to 1995 figures. Agrobiotechnology contributed 47 percent of operating earnings, with cigarettes and packaging accounting for 31 and 22 percent, respectively.  </p>
<p>In the agrobiotechnology division, the company drew attention to the recent merger between Bionova, its fresh produce subsidiary, and DNAP Plant Technology. La Moderna had sold the grain seeds part of another subsidiary, Asgrow Seed Co, to U.S.-based Monsanto in September.</p>
<p>La Moderna noted that sales volumes of cigarettes had been boosted by economic recovery in Mexico, and that the sales mix of different brands was stabilizing. Export sales of cigarettes for the year to date were up 81 percent from year-ago figures.</p>
<p>La Moderna noted that it had sold two wood products companies in June that had belonged to its packaging division, in order to concentrate production on recyclable cardboard.</p>
<p>The sale boosted the operating margin for the packing division to 34 percent of sales in the third quarter, up from 28 percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>-- Claudia Villegas in Mexico City +525 728-9549</p>
<p>and Daniel Perez in Monterrey +528 345-7677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
