<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133325" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Telefonica Argentina proposes new rates.</title>
<headline>Telefonica Argentina proposes new rates.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Telefonica de Argentina said Tuesday it presented the government with a proposed new structure of telephone charges that would cut long-distance costs but make some local calls dearer.</p>
<p>Telefonica wants to reduce the cost of long-distance calls within Argentina by an average 40 percent, and international long-distance calls by a weighted average of 64 percent.</p>
<p>But residential subscribers would see their monthly telephone rental almost double to $16.08 from $8.60. Other users would also have to pay more.  </p>
<p>Local call costs would also double during peak hours to $0.044 a minute.</p>
<p>Telefonica and Telecom de Argentina have tried to obtain government approval for changes in the structure of telecommunications charges since last year, but have so far failed under pressure of public criticism.</p>
<p>While the firms argue that the changes would make telephone charges fairer and reduce costs for businesses in the provinces, opponents say the new rate structure would swell the firms' profits.  </p>
<p>But Telefonica said Tuesday, &quot;The total effect of these variations on the results of Telefonica de Argentina is negative by 134 million pesos.&quot;</p>
<p>It added, &quot;If in subsequent audits it is demonstrated that the changes mean a temporary increase in the company's revenues, Telefonica de Argentina assumes the committment to refund it in further discounts in telephone charges.&quot;</p>
<p>Telefonica said it had presented its proposals at the request of the government's Communications Secretariat. Telecom's press office said it had no information on whether Telecom had made a similar move.  </p>
<p>Telefonica is controlled by Telefonica de Espana and Telecom by France Telecom  FTA.PA.</p>
<p>Under their 1990 privatization agreements, the two firms were each granted territories within which they can operate under near-monopoly conditions until 1997. This arrangement may be extended for two years if they meet requirements of investment and extension of their services.</p>
<p>-- Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
