<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133399" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico same-day peso ends weaker, Cetes forecast.</title>
<headline>Mexico same-day peso ends weaker, Cetes forecast.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's same-day peso closed 2.6 centavos weaker at 7.7460/7.7510 per dollar on Tuesday due to mixed forecasts about the results of the primary Cetes auction failing to buttress the peso, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The peso is still under pressure after fluctuating during the session...the outcome for primary  Cetes rates will continue to determine how difficult the foreign exchange market will be,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour and 24-hour peso contracts were meanwhile 3.2 and 2.8 centavos weaker, respectively, at 7.7730/7.7780 and 7.7630/7.7680 per dollar.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected hikes of about 100 basis points on bellwether 28-day Cetes rates at Tuesday evening's primary auction, and longer term rates to be unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't feel there's much interest in peso-denominated returns at these levels, so we have seen demand (for dollars) prevailing in a somewhat erratic (foreign exchange) market,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Traders located a strong support for the 48-hour peso at 7.80 per dollar which, if broken, could take the peso to its weakest level of the year at 7.8450 per dollar, they said.</p>
<p>-- Alexis Quinones, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
