<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133308" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: In Nicaragua vote, Ortega refuses to concede.</title>
<headline>In Nicaragua vote, Ortega refuses to concede.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Left-wing Sandinista leader Daniel Ortega on Monday threw Nicaragua's presidential vote in doubt by refusing to recognise official partial returns that showed his right-wing rival to have won.</p>
<p>Surprising reporters, who had expected to hear the former revolutionary leader concede defeat, Ortega told a news conference that &quot;serious irregularities&quot; had marred the vote.</p>
<p>&quot;On this occasion we would have liked to have recognised (the results) but we feel we cannot,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ortega's challenge threatened to disrupt a hard-fought election that hundreds of observers from the United States, Europe and Latin America had termed legitimate, despite some technical hitches.</p>
<p>Arnoldo Aleman, the portly ex-mayor of Managua who claimed victory with a nine-point margin over Ortega, revelled in his triumph, staging television interviews in which he was routinely addressed as &quot;president-elect.&quot;</p>
<p>His supporters celebrated wildly overnight with salsa music and dancing girls.</p>
<p>By Monday night, with 54.22 percent of the vote tallied, Aleman led Ortega by 48.54 percent to 38.96 percent -- well clear of the 45 percent hurdle the victor needs to avoid a second-round runoff.</p>
<p>Reflecting the passions generated by the bitterly fought contest, election authorities said more than 80 percent of the 2.4 million registered voters had cast a ballot.</p>
<p>Aleman, whose Liberal Alliance party is backed by allies of former dictator Anastasio Somoza, urged the Sandinista Front to support his government and help rebuild Latin America's second-poorest country after Haiti.</p>
<p>But Ortega's protest appeared to scotch any hope of allegiance. On hearing his allegations a group of Sandinista supporters shouted angrily in support of new elections.</p>
<p>The former president, who painstakingly cast himself as a moderate during the campaign, sought to emphasise that he willingly accepted the election result that threw him from power in 1990.</p>
<p>But this time, he said, the number of votes in telegrams of voter tallies sent by polling stations to the Supreme Electoral Council did not square with Sandinista figures of the number of votes cast. He said officials should check their numbers.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are saying is that they should carry out a count ... based on the (voting) acts.&quot;</p>
<p>Ortega led Nicaragua from the triumph of the Sandinista Revolution in 1979 through a bitter war against U.S.-backed Contra rebels before losing power in an election in 1990 to incumbent President Violeta Chamorro, a centrist who is not eligible for re-election.</p>
<p>Aleman campaigned on a fiercely anti-Sandinista ticket, playing on fears that they would return Nicaragua to its violent past.</p>
<p>On Monday he won the backing of the Clinton administration. &quot;We would like to work very closely with Arnoldo Aleman to spur economic growth -- that is, if he wins of course,&quot; said Brian Atwood, U.S. President Bill Clinton's envoy to the elections.</p>
<p>Both sides demonised each other during the campaign, the Sandinistas playing up Aleman's links to the oppressive Samoza dynasty, and Aleman smearing Ortega as a closet Marxist thinly disguised as a social democrat.</p>
<p>The ugly campaign reignited the smouldering right-left political divide in Nicaragua, and fanned fears of unrest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
