<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13333" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy PM Prodi's government marks 100 days.</title>
<headline>Italy PM Prodi's government marks 100 days.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi marked his 100th day in office at the weekend amid signs it could face a difficult autumn of economic and political challenges.</p>
<p>One hundred days is about a third of the average life span of Italian governments in past decades. They have lasted anywhere from nine days to three years.</p>
<p>Prodi is determined to make his government, the first to include former communists since the end of World War Two, endure the full five years of the legislature elected at last April's national poll.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly. I have never put this in doubt,&quot; Prodi told a private television interviewer who asked him if he hoped to stay for the duration.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always worked for this. The work I do here wouldn't make any sense if it were for the short term. I don't know when all this will bear fruit but I am convinced that I will be around to pick that fruit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prodi's problems may begin with a challenge to the very fabric of the country expected on September 15 when Umberto Bossi, the seperatist Northern League leader is due to make a symbolic &quot;declaration of independence&quot; for northern Italy.</p>
<p>Prodi, who is from the north and has called himself more of a northerner than Bossi, has suggested the day will be a flop for the League and has warned Bossi the government will not tolerate anything illegal.</p>
<p>Prodi's government, formed on May 17, has seen some economic success. Inflation has fallen, leading the central bank to cut the discount rate, a move industrialists had been clamouring for.</p>
<p>Another success for the centre-left coalition was a deal with the opposition for a parliamentry commission to pave the way for much-needed constitutional reform.</p>
<p>But unemployment has been a nagging problem and on Sunday deputy prime minister Walter Veltroni suggested that a recession in Europe would mean countries should consider the possibility of re-thinking the criteria for European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>The government's brief vacation ends on Wednesday when the cabinet meets and is expected to start work on the budget, expected to cut 32.4 trillion lire ($21.34 billion) off next year's deficit.</p>
<p>Commentators believe the resumption of political activity in the autumn could present snares for the government, particularly because of its reliance in the lower house on the hard-left Communist Refoundation party.</p>
<p>Just before the government went on holiday, Communist Refoundation threatened to bring down the coalition if it pressed ahead with plans to privatise telecoms holding company Stet, which Refoundation strongly opposes.</p>
<p>Refoundation lies outside the ruling centre-left Olive Tree government but has always voted with Prodi and ensured he won confidence debates.</p>
<p>Refoundation leader Fausto Bertinotti has said the government would be taking a great risk if it looked to the centre-right opposition for parliamentary comfort on Stet.</p>
<p>Besides Stet, Bertinotti said his party would also bring its influence to bear on the 1997 budget, saying he wanted to see a new tax introduced on personal wealth. The government has already said there will be no new taxes and has promised to put the emphasis on state spending cuts.</p>
<p>Union leaders have threatened the government with mass strikes if their pay claims are not met in the coming round of large-scale wage negotiations. They are demanding compensation for higher-than-expected inflation over the past two years. ($1=1518 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
