<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133301" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela prisoners hold dead after fire kills 30.</title>
<headline>Venezuela prisoners hold dead after fire kills 30.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 30 inmates of a Venezuelan jail were burned to death on Tuesday in a fire apparently caused by tear gas canisters fired by guards, prison officials said.</p>
<p>The prisoners refused to allow the charred bodies of dead inmates to be removed until the fire was investigated.</p>
<p>More than 10 hours after the fire had been put out prison officials were still trying to determine exactly how many had died in one of Venezuela's worst prison tragedies.</p>
<p>&quot;We are making a list ... There are about 25 to 30 dead ... There are burned bodies on top of each other,&quot; National Prisons Director Antonio Marval told reporters outside La Planta jail on the southwestern outskirts of the capital.</p>
<p>Human rights activists and some officials earlier said the death toll could be as high as 40.</p>
<p>The fire started when national guardsmen closed off a wing of the prison and the used tear gas on the inmates, Marval said. &quot;We could be talking about murder here,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A Reuters photographer who entered the cramped and blackened area where the fire occurred counted more than 20 bodies, many of them burned beyond recognition. Several prisoners had tried in vain to escape the flames by hiding under beds. Others were fused together from clinging to one another as they waited to die.</p>
<p>Prison inmates insisted that the guards had started the fire without cause and refused to allow the bodies to be removed until the press had seen what had happened and the National Guard had left the jail.</p>
<p>Three guards involved in the incident had already been identified, said Marval.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear why the guards locked up the prisoners or how the tear gas canisters started the fire.</p>
<p>&quot;It has to be studied. But it wouldn't make sense for the prisoners to start the fire themselves unless they wanted to commit suicide,&quot; Justice Minister Henrique Meier told Reuters in a brief telephone interview.</p>
<p>Outside angry family members clashed briefly with police who fired several tear gas canisters into a crowd of about 100 to prevent them from approaching the prison.</p>
<p>&quot;They haven't told us anything. We want to know what has happened to our relatives. We are desperate,&quot; one woman told the Globovision television station.</p>
<p>Prisoners waved shirts and knives through the bars and held signs which said: &quot;The guards are killing us.&quot;</p>
<p>Hours after the fire several gunshots were heard from inside the prison and there were reports of several prisoners with bullet wounds.</p>
<p>Venezuela's overcrowded and decaying prisons, where arms and drugs are widely used, are frequent scenes of violence between inmates and clashes with guards.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the problems in our prisons, apart from the overcrowding, is the excessively hostile treatment by some guards,&quot; said Meier, who was openly critical of the National Guard's actions.</p>
<p>The tragedy at La Planta would be the worst in Venezuela's jails since about 120 prisoners were burned or hacked to death with machetes during a gang fight at the Sabaneta jail in the western city of Maracaibo in January 1994.</p>
<p>La Planta was built for 300 prisoners but currently holds about 900.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
