<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133323" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil coffee auction likely to see good demand.</title>
<headline>Brazil coffee auction likely to see good demand.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian coffee roasters expect to see good demand at a auction Wednesday of government coffee stocks and are already concerned about supply until May and June next year, a roasters' official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry is beginning to worry about the amount of coffee available until May and June of 1997 because the quantity is insufficient to meet export demands, internal consumption and the soluble industry,&quot; Nathan Herszkowicz, president of the Sao Paulo State Coffee Industry Union, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Average production by Sao Paulo roasters reached 325,000 bags per month between January and August 1996, up 26.00, percent from the corresponding period in 1995, Herszkowicz said,</p>
<p>&quot;This...leads us to believe we will reach, if not pass, projected consumption of 11 million bags this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This on one side makes us very happy and on the other side leaves us worried - exactly because of the problem with supply,&quot; Herszkowicz said.  </p>
<p>Even if the Industry and Commerce Ministry increases monthly auctions of its stocks to the current limit of 200,000 60-kg bags, this would mean only a total of 1.6 million which still seems too little for total requirements, Herszkowicz said.</p>
<p>The government will at 1400 local/1600 GMT tomorrow put up 69,783 bags for auction in the largest so far in a program of monthly sales until June 1997.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
