<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133337" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine stocks fall on bonds, other markets.</title>
<headline>Argentine stocks fall on bonds, other markets.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine stocks fell 0.55 percent Tuesday in cautious, slim dealings in continuation of Monday's session.</p>
<p>Traders said the market fell on slumps in Brady bonds, U.S. stocks and other Latin American bolsas.</p>
<p>Persistent rumors, officially denied at the end of the day, surrounding possible resignations in President Carlos Menem's cabinet added to the declines.</p>
<p>The leading blue-chip  Merval stock index closed at 554.33 index points, taking its two-day decline to 2.69 percent.  </p>
<p>Trading volumes rose to $17.9 million in the session.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was looking for a floor for the Merval between 540 and 547 points. That level was touched and the market reacted,&quot; said Jorge Bonanno, a trader at Interfin.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is agitated by questions surrounding the internal political situation and pressured by possible rises in long U.S. rates,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Another trader said &quot;bonds fell and triggered the depression in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very erratic and speculative and is not very conducive to long-term investment,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>According to traders, the market is set to be volatile in coming sessions with a likely ceiling of between 560 and 565 for the Merval.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Adam, Buenos Aires Newsroom 541 3180654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
