<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133303" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Carter seeks to untangle Nicaragua election muddle.</title>
<headline>Carter seeks to untangle Nicaragua election muddle.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. President Jimmy Carter tried on Tuesday to defuse an election crisis in Nicaragua after Sandinista candidate Daniel Ortega refused to accept defeat, alleging fraud in the count.</p>
<p>With more than half the vote counted, official results pointed to a big victory for right-wing lawyer Arnoldo Aleman, who told the Sandinistas to accept the voters' verdict.</p>
<p>But Ortega, who headed Nicaragua's leftist revolutionary government from 1979-90, said his supporters had found &quot;serious irregularities&quot; in the vote and demanded a full-scale revision of the results.</p>
<p>Carter, the highest-profile member of a group of observers monitoring the vote, met late on Monday with Ortega, Aleman, President Violeta Chamorro and electoral authorities to try and untangle the mess.</p>
<p>&quot;The general consensus among all of the observers...is that the election didn't have any degree of fraud that would subvert the decision of the Nicaraguan people,&quot; he told a news conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Many Nicaraguans agreed with Carter and criticised Ortega's party for being bad losers. &quot;The Sandinistas don't want to accept that the people will never vote them back into power again,&quot; said Luis Flores, a Managua taxi driver.</p>
<p>With almost two-thirds of the votes tallied, Aleman led Ortega by 48.70 percent to 38.88 percent -- well clear of the 45 percent hurdle he needs to avoid a second-round runoff.</p>
<p>Aleman's Liberal Alliance also looked set to win the lion's share of seats in the National Assembly -- though perhaps not an overall majority -- and a clutch of town halls across the country, including the capital Managua.</p>
<p>Carter did acknowledge at his news conference that defeated parties had &quot;a legitimate concern&quot; about the election results.</p>
<p>The losers -- Sandinistas and other small parties -- alleged that results from their representatives at polling stations conflicted with the preliminary count of the Supreme Election Council, which was tallying results based on telegrams sent in by the heads of each polling station.</p>
<p>In one northern province, Matagalpa, 14 opposition parties, including the Sandinistas and third-ranking party Nicaraguan Christian Way, said the irregularities were so wide-ranging the election there should be annulled.</p>
<p>Carter said the Supreme Election Council had agreed to provide copies of the telegrams to the political parties to enable them to double-check the results, and to carry out its own revision of the results.</p>
<p>He said the process would delay a final official result by several days and urged the heads of the political parties to &quot;approach the issue in a constructive and cooperative way&quot;.</p>
<p>Nicaraguans, however, took the post-election conflict less calmly. Angry opponents of the Sandinistas said the protest was a stalling tactic to spare the left-wing party from accepting its second ballot-box defeat in six years.</p>
<p>For their part, Sandinista supporters jammed the switchboards of television talk shows, attacking the election as fraudulent and calling for the vote to be annulled.</p>
<p>In a polarised country where memories of civil war bloodshed in the 1980s are still fresh, the row raised fears that Nicaragua's highly-organised Sandinista Front could take to the streets to protest.</p>
<p>Aleman, whose supporters danced to brass bands all night in celebration, played down Ortega's charge and said he hoped the Sandinistas would end up backing him. &quot;I hope that Comandante Ortega has matured,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the Sandinistas, who during the campaign accused Aleman of being backed by supporters of Anastasio Somoza, the dictator they ousted in 1979, are not likely to be easily wooed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
