<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133369" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST-Cemex Q3 profits seen solid.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Cemex Q3 profits seen solid.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Perez</byline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican cement giant Cemex's third quarter earnings are seen solid by analysts, but opinions differ about its operating performance, especially in Mexico.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey of six analysts predicted average third quarter earnings per share of 1.03 pesos. Cemex reported a net profit of 4.233 billion for the first six months of the year.</p>
<p>Analysts added, though, that working out the number of shares outstanding is particularly key in the case of Cemex, whose treasury is very active with the company's own shares.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think (the earnings report) will be very good.  People are saying that sales in Mexico are going to show recovery, not only against the third quarter of 1995 but against the second quarter of 1996,&quot; said Paul Rodriguez of Caspian Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said that because it is easier to estimate the results of the company's units in Spain, Venezuela, the United States and Colombia than estimating results for Mexico, the issue of a recovery at home has become key to analysts.  </p>
<p>&quot;The (consolidated) report will not be very good. Spain is weak, and Venezuela may have attractive margins, but Mexico I don't think will have the strength that the market anticipates,&quot; Gordon Lee of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said.</p>
<p>&quot;Margins will be good, but on the industry level the rhythm of growth of volumes in Mexico fell in the (third) quarter, which is usually seasonally weak,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>To evaluate the Mexico unit's performance, analysts looked at the company's market share, which fell to 56 percent in the first half, while rival Apasco SA de CV raised its own to 26 percent.  </p>
<p>Rodriguez said Cemex was winning market share (in the third quarter), because with any recovery in the formal construction sector Cemex will grow more quickly.</p>
<p>Sobani Warner at Bear Stearns saw &quot;potential for (Cemex Mexico) to have gained market share.  I expect better volume than in the second quarter, and its market share could reach 58 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes will be higher compared to the second quarter,&quot; said Carmen Slade of Salomon Brothers.  &quot;They may gain market share, but at the cost of putting up prices less than Apasco.&quot;  </p>
<p>Slade said Cemex raised prices only eight percent in the third quarter compared with Apasco's 15 percent.</p>
<p>With regard to the company's international operations, most analysts had uniform views.  Cemex itself has made clear that cement demand in those countries is falling.</p>
<p>Ben Uglow of Flemings Research wrote in a report that &quot;there may be still more evidence of weak volumes in Spain and in Venezuela.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Venezuela, Spain and Colombia are not bringing in spectacular results, but that is something we were already expecting,&quot; said De Leon.</p>
<p>--Monterrey newsroom (528) 345-7617</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
