<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133333" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: New Brazil coffee council may be ready next week.</title>
<headline>New Brazil coffee council may be ready next week.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government hopes to complete by next Tuesday interministerial talks on the creation of a new coffee policy-making council, the official coordinating the negotiations said.</p>
<p>Wilson Calvo Mendes de Araujo, an official of the President's chief of staff, told Reuters preparations for the esstablishment of the Deliberative Council for Coffee Policy (CDPCC) were in the final stages of technical analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;The council is likely to be exactly as originally sugggested,&quot;&quot; he  said.</p>
<p>According to the original proposal, which came from a parliamentary committee, the CDPC was to have up to 20 members, divided between the private and public sectors.</p>
<p>Its function will be to determine future Brazilian coffee policy, which the private sector claims has lacked focus in recent years.</p>
<p>Early this month, the government published a decree allowing the council to be set up under the auspices of the Ministry of Industry and Commerce.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
