<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133322" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST-Apasco Q3 seen flat, future cloudy.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Apasco Q3 seen flat, future cloudy.</headline>
<dateline>MONTERREY, Mexico 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican cement maker Apasco is expected to report steady third quarter earnings, but some analysts say the company may be losing its recent momentum.</p>
<p>A survey of five analysts predicted an average 0.91 pesos earnings per share in the third quarter, with estimates ranging from 0.78 pesos to 0.99 pesos. Apasco reported first half earnings per share of 1.91 pesos.</p>
<p>Despite the near consensus on per share earnings, analysts disagreed on whether Apasco can continue the growth pace which has seen it gain market share against rival Cemex SA.  </p>
<p>Analysts gave widely differing slants on what Apasco's earnings might reveal on the company's prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakest (report in the sector) I believe will be Apasco's,&quot; said Gordon Lee, an analyst with Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;The market became nervous after an excellent second quarter, and in July through September the rains affected them,&quot; he said. Heavier-than-normal rain in central Mexico during the summer months probably delayed some construction projects, he said.</p>
<p>But other analysts disagreed.  </p>
<p>&quot;Apasco's should be the best report (of cement companies), due to its better prices, better margins, greater concrete volume,&quot; said Carlos Perezalonso, analyst at Santander Investment.</p>
<p>Perezalonso said Mexico's second largest cement company will see third quarter operating profits soar 356 percent from last year's recessionary trough.</p>
<p>Still, some analysts said Apasco's market share slipped in the third quarter after climbing to 26 percent in June, compared to rival Cemex's drop to 56 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Tonnage will be below the second quarter, but better than the third quarter of 1995,&quot; said Paul Rodrguez, an analyst with Caspian Securities. &quot;It seems Apasco has been losing market to Cemex.&quot;</p>
<p>The difference in price per ton of cement between the two companies narrowed in the third quarter, analysts said, with Cemex charging about 590 pesos to Apasco's approximately 575 pesos per ton.  </p>
<p>Despite an increasingly competitive market, analysts said Apasco's operating profit margin remains attractive at about 29 percent. A 6.5 percent price hike above the approximately 4.8 percent third quarter inflation should improve the company's margins, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Monterrey newsroom +528 345-7617</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTERREY, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
