<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133359" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONDURAS: Unions, business say Honduras on brink of explosion.</title>
<headline>Unions, business say Honduras on brink of explosion.</headline>
<byline>Gustavo Palencia</byline>
<dateline>TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honduras, the relatively quiet neighbour in the political minefield of Central America, is on the brink of a social explosion because of worsening poverty, business, labour and peasant leaders say.</p>
<p>Consumer prices creep higher each day with real wages lower than ever, adding to the pressure cooker for President Carlos Roberto Reina, who has survived two assassination attempts and angered the powerful military with budget cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;The people are tired and the politicians here don't want to face it,&quot; said Adolfo Facusse, president of the National Association of Industrialists (ANDI). &quot;Stop needling these people because they are going to respond violently.&quot;</p>
<p>Facusse, an important business leader, issued his warning to reporters on Monday amid growing popular discontent over higher prices for basic consumer goods and fuel.</p>
<p>Adding to the tension, a bomb exploded in the legislative palace on Oct. 4, shattering windows but causing no injuries. A similar device was defused the same day outside Reina's Liberal Party headquarters. No one claimed responsibility.</p>
<p>Second-hand clothes seem to be the only boom industry in Honduras, where about 80 percent of the 5.9 million people live in poverty. The minimum wage of about $65 per month, last raised in December, has lost purchasing power as prices rose 19.9 percent through September. That amount covers only half of the basic consumer goods needed for a family of four.</p>
<p>&quot;The price of basic consumer goods is out of reach,&quot; Felicito Avila, secretary-general of the the General Workers Central (CGT), a labour confederation, told Reuters. &quot;What family really has the means to buy half a kilo of beans at these prices with the minimum wage so low ?&quot;</p>
<p>Even with low wages, about 40 percent of the workforce is out of a job or underemployed, presenting new challenges for Reina, who abolished the military draft and has scaled back greatly the military budget during these lean times, angering traditionally cosseted generals.</p>
<p>Honduras' history of military dominance and its top export product made the country the quintessential banana republic, an image reinforced in the 1980s when the country's leaders allowed the United States to use Honduras as a military base for anti-communist campaigns in the civil wars of neighbouring Nicaragua, El Salvador and Guatemala.</p>
<p>In the post-Cold War era, the country is just poor. The largely Lenca Indian population of rural Honduras is the hardest hit, raising the prospect of an armed uprising similar to the Indian-based Zapatista movement in the southern Mexican state of Chiapas, one analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go to La Esperanza or any one of the poor areas, you'll find the pot boiling in the indigenous sector, which faces discrimination,&quot; German Leitzelar, a prominent lawyer and political analyst, told reporters.&quot;We could have a situation very similar to that of Chiapas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're coming to the moment when the attitude of the people is ready to go beyond the normal channels of protest, and if that happens in a disorganized way it will be chaos for the country. People could explode uncontrollably,&quot; Avila said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEGUCIGALPA, Honduras"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONDURAS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
