<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133332" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil seeking to negotiate alternative tax bills.</title>
<headline>Brazil seeking to negotiate alternative tax bills.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government wants to negotiate an alternative to controversial legislation that, in its current form, would completely exempt small companies from tax, a Finance Ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government considers this legislation to be flawed,&quot; the spokesman said, referring to two bills the Chamber of Deputies voted to give priority treatement to earlier on Tuesday. Government economists have said the changes would cut about $4.0 billion from annual tax revenues. Leaders are expected to scupper attempts to vote on the bills on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry spokesman said talks were taking place between National Tax Secretariat officials and aides of Sen. Jose Sarney, who presides over Congress and says the legislation, which he drew up, would create five million jobs.</p>
<p>News reports have said the government is willing to set up a single tax band for small companies that would levy a 10 percent charge on turnover.</p>
<p>Sarney's legislation, which has already cleared the Senate, would exempt small companies with turnover of up to 204,000 reais a year from all tax and employer contributions.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
