<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133370" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Stray bullets are growing danger in Brazil.</title>
<headline>Stray bullets are growing danger in Brazil.</headline>
<byline>Simona de Logu</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The picture of a baby boy shot in the right arm at a circus was on the front-page of almost every Brazilian newspaper on Tuesday, the latest casualty on a growing list of stray bullet victims.</p>
<p>Stray bullets have become a growing danger as Brazil's criminals arm themselves with ever more sophisticated weapons that often miss their targets and hit innocent bystanders.</p>
<p>Lucas Cabral Albano, 9 months old, was hit in the arm as he slept in his father's arms at a circus performance in Rio. Where the bullet came from and who fired it remain a mystery.</p>
<p>Almost every week Brazilian newspapers tell of another stray bullet victim like Katia Munhoz Liardo, who was enjoying a picnic with her 7-year-old daughter on Rio's famous Copacabana beach when a bullet hit her in the armpit and killed her instantly.</p>
<p>&quot;Stray bullets are (leading) to a general paranoia,&quot; said Rubem Cesar Fernandes of the non-governmental anti-violence organisation Viva Rio. &quot;But stray bullets aren't really a serious problem for the middle classes and the rich. They mainly affect the poor in the favelas (shantytowns).&quot;</p>
<p>In Vigario Geral, a Rio favela that made international headlines when military police opened fire on its inhabitants and killed 21 people in 1993, a sculptor collected some 12,000 bullet casings and worked them into a statue to commemorate the massacre's third anniversary in August.</p>
<p>Fernandes, who blames the stray bullet phenomenon on drug trafficking that has mushroomed in shantytowns over the last 10 years, believes Rio is being turned into a 20th Century Wild West by the soaring use of guns by criminals and police.</p>
<p>&quot;Drug trafficking in Rio is controlled by very young people, adolescents, who see guns as a status symbol. On the other hand, the authorities encourage the police to shoot first and ask questions later. This cowboy logic of who pulls their gun quicker wins also trivialises the use of firearms.&quot;</p>
<p>The Jornal do Brasil newspaper recently estimated that at least 103 people have been killed or seriously wounded by stray bullets in the past 2 1/2 years in Rio alone. But Rio's state Security Secretary Nilton Cerqueira claims there have been only 18 stray bullet casualties in that period, of which only five have been fatal.</p>
<p>The statistics are as difficult to compile as finding those responsible for firing the errant projectiles. What is clear is the growing number of heavy weapons primarily in the hands of drug traffickers, who are often still in their teens.</p>
<p>The number of illegal heavy weapons confiscated by police in Rio has risen in the past 2 1/2 years from 892 in 1994 to 746 in the first six months of this year, Cerqueira said.</p>
<p>&quot;Stray bullets are not a growing problem,&quot; he said. &quot;The most serious problem are the highly sophisticated heavy weapons smuggled in illegally by international drug traffickers, which are used by their 'soldiers' in the battle for a bigger market share.&quot;</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso has tried to stem the growing use of firearms, urging Congress to give speedy passage to a bill making illegal gun possession a criminal offence subject to jail sentences.</p>
<p>Brazil has long complained that most illegal weapons used by criminals are smuggled in from neighbouring Paraguay and it welcomed a U.S. ban on gun sales to Paraguay, hoping this will sharply reduce the flow of contraband weapons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
