<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13338" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Andreotti lawyer says Mob turncoat may help him.</title>
<headline>Andreotti lawyer says Mob turncoat may help him.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top Mob boss Giovanni Brusca's decision to collaborate with investigators may help the defence in the Mafia trial of Giulio Andreotti, the former Italian prime minister's lawyer said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Brusca, one of the Mafia's most fearsome bosses before his arrest in May, has dominated the headlines of Italy's newspapers since Friday, when magistrates confirmed he had decided to join a growing list of Mafiosi to turn state's evidence.</p>
<p>While Italians were still debating if Brusca could be trusted, Andreotti and his lawyers jumped on media reports that Brusca had told investigators that he knew nothing about the statesman's alleged ties to the Mafia.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the perfect truth,&quot; said Andreotti, who has denied charges against him as part of a plot by some lying Mafia turncoats to punish him for crackdown on crime by the seven governments he headed.</p>
<p>&quot;If a Mafia boss, who was effectively 'on duty' until three months ago, maintains that he never knew anything about Andreotti, this will have to be taken into consideration,&quot; his lawyer, Francesco Coppi, told Corriere della Sera newspaper.</p>
<p>Coppi said he would ask that Brusca be called as a witness at the trial of Andreotti, who is accused of being the Mafia main political protector for years.</p>
<p>But Luigi Li Gotti, the lawyer assisting the 36-year-old Brusca since he decided to collaborate, said he was not aware that Brusca had discussed Andreotti with investigators.</p>
<p>The case against Andreotti is based in part on testimony from a turncoat who claims he saw the life senator meet secretly with Mafia boss Salvatore Riina in 1987 and exchange a kiss of respect in Palermo.</p>
<p>Andreotti says it would have been impossible to him to evade his police escort.</p>
<p>Riina was arrested in 1993 after nearly a quarter of a century on the run and Brusca was widely believed to have taken his place at the top of the Corleonese clan until his arrest.</p>
<p>Magistrates said they would treat Brusca cautiously, aware his &quot;repentance&quot; may be an attempt to take advantage of a generous witness protection programme that includes reduced sentences, a salary and the chance to change identity.</p>
<p>Italy has for years debated the trustworthiness of once-bloodthirsty mobsters who swore religious allegiance to an organisation committed to fighting the state.</p>
<p>Brusca gave investigators proof he was telling at least part of the truth when he directed them to an elaborate underground bunker hideout he and other Mafiosi had used in the past.</p>
<p>The reinforced concrete bunker was connected to a house via a 60-metre (yard) tunnel in the Sicilian countryside.</p>
<p>Investigators told Italian television on Sunday the hideout may be where Brusca allegedly strangled and disposed of in a vat of acid the 12-year-old son of a boss who had talked to police.</p>
<p>Brusca is accused of pushing the button detonating a bomb under anti-Mafia magistrate Giovanni Falcone's motorcade on a motorway near Palermo in 1992. Falcone, his wife and three bodyguards died in the explosion.</p>
<p>He is also accused of involvement in planning 1993 Mafia bombings against cultural monuments in Rome, Milan, and against the Uffizi art gallery in Florence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
