<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13334" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek PM Simitis seen favourite to win snap poll.</title>
<headline>Greek PM Simitis seen favourite to win snap poll.</headline>
<byline>Costas Paris</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis is seen as favourite to win next month's snap poll against a disoriented conservative opposition which offers voters few policy alternatives, analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Simitis, 60, called the September 22 election last week while enjoying an approval rating of 70 percent, well ahead of his main opponent, New Democracy party leader Miltiadis Evert, who seems disputed even within the conservative camp.</p>
<p>&quot;Costas Simitis' PASOK party has all the prerequisites for a comfortable victory as his top rival (Evert) has not managed to convince even the most committed New Democracy voters,&quot; the independent Athens daily Eleftherotypia said in an editorial.</p>
<p>Simitis has shown that his mild manner masks a strong political will since succeeding his political mentor and PASOK party founder, the late Andreas Papandreou, in January.</p>
<p>He won the premiership in a close parliamentary vote and then went on to become PASOK's president at a party congress in June, dispelling fears that PASOK would split up after Papandreou's departure.</p>
<p>Simitis tells Greeks their future lies firmly inside the European Union and that they must make sacrifices to catch up with the rest of the group.</p>
<p>The snap vote comes two months before the presentation of next year's budget. Simitis wants to cut spending by $1.2 billion to trim the public debt and persistently high inflation.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Alexandros Papadopoulos has sent out special commando groups to arrest tax evaders, who officials say account for 30 percent of the country's total workforce. He also wants curbs on state hirings and below-inflation pay rises.</p>
<p>&quot;Many things will change next year that will make many people angry,&quot; a senior PASOK official told Reuters. &quot;We must admit that if the election was held as scheduled in October 1997 it would have been more difficult for us.&quot;</p>
<p>Simitis has cleverly adopted most of the pro-EU policies of New Democracy, which led the country into the 15-member EU, leaving Evert with little new to tell the voters.</p>
<p>&quot;Evert agrees on the need for unpopular measures for the economy and generally adopts the government's foreign policy. He tells the voters I'll do it better but Simitis is more popular,&quot; a poll analyst said.</p>
<p>Evert took over New Democracy's helm from former prime minister Constantine Mitsotakis who lost elections to Papandreou in 1993. The two men dislike each other and polls this summer showed the veteran Mitsotakis making a comeback and even being more popular than Evert among New Democracy voters.</p>
<p>&quot;Today New Democracy looks divided as the differences between Mr Evert and Mr Mitsotakis are deeper than the average Greek knows.&quot; Eleftherotypia said.</p>
<p>Mitsotakis pledged on Saturday that he would fight for a New Democracy win and conservative newspapers had pictures of him shaking hands with Evert at a party meeting.</p>
<p>But Mitsotakis' associates said the veteran leader has made clear that Evert will bear the full responsibility in the case of an election loss.</p>
<p>Poll companies were caught off guard by Simitis' snap election decision and the first countrywide opinion surveys are expected around September 10.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
