<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133387" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil Oct coffee exports may set three-year high.</title>
<headline>Brazil Oct coffee exports may set three-year high.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rush of Brazilian coffee sales once an export tax was lifted in mid-September should spill over into October, with officials expecting possibly the highest level of monthly shipments for more than three years.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks very big...I think it will probably be around 1.8 million (60-kg) bags but it could reach two million. There are lots of sales,&quot; said Oswaldo Aranha, president of the Brazilian Coffee Exporters' Federation (FEBEC).</p>
<p>Coffee exports in the first two weeks of this month were already twice those seen in first half of September, reflecting the lull in the wait for the export tax exemption, traders said.  </p>
<p>According to today's bulletin from Rio de Janeiro Coffee Business Center, shipments based on certificates of origin which indicate the intention to export totalled 1.16 million bags to Oct 17 against 644,797 bags to Sept 17.</p>
<p>Exports based on bills of lading reached 832,797 bags against 413,948 bags to the same period in September.</p>
<p>The so-called ICMS state tax was only officially removed in the middle of September so exports in the first two weeks of the month were much lower than normal, traders said.</p>
<p>But shipments are also high when compared to mid-August when 765,383 bags based on certificates of origin and 482,538 bags based on bills of lading had been exported as of Aug 16.  </p>
<p>Total shipments in August reached 1.56 million bags, the highest since the 1.65 million bags exported in November 1994, according to FEBEC figures.</p>
<p>Should Brazil ship in excess of this figure in October, as widely anticipated, exports will be the highest since September 1993 when they reached 2.06 million bags.</p>
<p>Under a plan agreed with members of Association of Coffee Producing Countries (ACPC), Brazil can still ship an average of around 1.7 million bags a month in the final quarter to keep within its nine million bag limit for July to December.  </p>
<p>Shipments in November and December are not expected to equal those of October given that this month's figures will be boosted by the carry-over from September.</p>
<p>Moreover, Brazilian exports should then fall back in the next six months from January to June 1997 given that its quota in this period under the ACPC plan is for six million bags.</p>
<p>The question of exports in January to June is to be discussed by ACPC members at a meeting in Costa Rica at the beginning of November, traders said.</p>
<p>However there is currently no question of Brazil looking to increase its share.</p>
<p>&quot;I think six million bags will be sufficient,&quot; Aranha said.</p>
<p>--Caroline Bulloch, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 5074151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
