<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133357" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazilian shantytown to be painted in bright colors.</title>
<headline>Brazilian shantytown to be painted in bright colors.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rocinha, Rio's biggest shantytown, will get a facelift thanks to the Rio 2004 Olympic campaign and a film-maker who want to paint the ramshackle houses in bright colours, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Rio 2004 is coordinating a project to train and pay 100 residents of the slum to paint and repair their houses to help improve Rio's image in its bid to host the 2004 Olympic Games.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider it important to improve the living quality and the infrastructure of the favela (shantytown),&quot; said Andrea Siqueira of Rio 2004. &quot;The plan is to paint part of the favela in coming weeks and if it proves to be successful other favelas might be included in the programme.&quot;</p>
<p>Rio 2004 has yet to choose the colours, but film-maker Sergio Peo also has multicolored plans for Rocinha.</p>
<p>He wants to paint the town red, green and blue and any other colour in the rainbow to provide the setting for his new film &quot;Rocinha Night and Day&quot;, which starts filming in January.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be the language of pop with strong colours,&quot; Peo said. &quot;We want to paint a stretch of houses along the road at the bottom of the favela.&quot;</p>
<p>His movie tells the story of a pirate radio station which mobilises the residents of the shantytown to paint their houses as a symbol of community spirit in defiance of public neglect.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
