<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133345" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds fall sharply on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds fall sharply on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds fell sharply Tuesday amid a combination of growing concerns over corruption accusations and profit-taking by U.S. funds after a year of solid gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are looking for excuses to sell,&quot; said one trader at a large Argentine bank, referring to the large gains clocked up by emerging markets this year.</p>
<p>The dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 slumped $0.70 to 117.50, while Argentina's FRB due 2005 plunged 1-5/8 to 80-1/2.  </p>
<p>The dollar-denominated Bocon Provisional 2 due 2007 shed $1.50 to 100.30.</p>
<p>Increasing attention on corruption accusations by former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo, including rumours of the resignation of a cabinet minister, gave investors an excuse, said traders.</p>
<p>The government denied the rumours, which centered on Interior Minister Carlos Corach, Justice Minister Elias Jassan and presidential chief of staff Alberto Kohan. A presidential spokesman told Reuters &quot;it's totally false. There is no movement. There will be no resignations.&quot;</p>
<p>However, traders pointed out that the market fell in sympathy with similar downward moves in other Latin American markets.</p>
<p>&quot;There is selling pressure. The market is seeking trading levels where there will be no doubt that buying will emerge,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>The first trader predicted prices could slip for another couple of sessions. He added that so far there were no large selling flows.</p>
<p>Market players underlined that the market fell in tandem with other Latin American markets, adding weight to the argument that the declines were part of general profit-taking by overseas funds.</p>
<p>In the money markets, call money rates fell to 7.35 percent from 7.55 percent Monday.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
