<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133372" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine top aide denies knew of alleged bribes.</title>
<headline>Argentine top aide denies knew of alleged bribes.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Carlos Menem's chief of staff Tuesday denied press reports that he knew about alleged bribes in a scandal involving a key Argentine state-owned bank and the U.S. computer giant IBM's local branch.</p>
<p>&quot;I have all the necessary elements to prove I have nothing to do with it,&quot; Alberto Kohan told a radio interviewer.</p>
<p>Major dailies reported on their front pages Tuesday that former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo told a judge that Kohan knew government officials paid bribes to secure the deal between state-run Banco Nacion and IBM to install computers.  </p>
<p>According to the papers, Kohan told Menem and Cavallo at a meeting last year that his aide, deputy chief of staff Carlos Cattaneo, had paid bribes in the $250 million, 1993 deal.</p>
<p>&quot;That meeting never took place,&quot; Kohan said.</p>
<p>Cavallo is abroad and his spokesman said he could not confirm or deny that the minister made the allegations in testimony to federal judge Adolfo Bagnasco Monday.</p>
<p>Kohan indicated he may sue Cavallo. &quot;What he have here is alleged declarations. If those declarations are real, I will also go to court.&quot;  </p>
<p>A federal court last month confirmed the indictment of 11 of the 30 former IBM Argentina and former Banco Nacin employees who Bagnasco had indicted in the case.</p>
<p>Banco Nacin last June canceled the deal and demanded that IBM refund $82 million in payments, but the company fired back, suing the bank in July for more than $86 million alleging &quot;wrongful revocation&quot; of the contract.</p>
<p>Then in August, Banco Nacin countersued the firm for $174 million. IBM denies any malicious intent, although it has admitted to errors. Other IBM Argentina deals are under separate court investigations.</p>
<p>Cavallo, fired in July by Menem, earlier this month launched a drive against alleged corruption in the government, accusing two ministers of manipulating judges and trying to cover up graft investigations.</p>
<p>-- David Haskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
