<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133365" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Syndicated loans growing in importance in Mexico.</title>
<headline>Syndicated loans growing in importance in Mexico.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kozak</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The syndicated loan being negotiated by Mexican packaging firm Empaques Ponderosa SA is another example of a growing trend in Mexico and other parts of Latin America: the rise of the syndicated loan at the expense of corporate paper, analysts said.</p>
<p>Empaques Ponderosa said on Monday it was negotiating a syndicated loan for three years worth $70 million.</p>
<p>The company said the funds would be used to refinance $50 million worth of Eurobonds coming due in December, and for internal project financing.  </p>
<p>With spreads tightening, corporate issuers are tilting more towards borrowing from banks than issuing bonds, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you issue bonds you are going to pay more, 50 to 100 basis points more, than if you buy bank debt.  Until those two markets move in line, why would companies issue bonds if they can get cheaper bank debt?&quot; said Bankers Trust corporate debt analyst Christopher Taylor.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of companies have been getting syndicated loans, usually backed with some collateral behind it, some sort of export receivable.  The banks have been a little bit generous on the pricing side,&quot; said Santander Investment debt analyst Jim Garvey.</p>
<p>Some of the commercial loans are being negotiated for about LIBOR plus 225 to 250 for a three-year tenor.</p>
<p>Most top-flight corporate paper in the three-year tenor is trading at a wider spread than that.  </p>
<p>In another example, Mexican retailer El Puerte de Liverpool is said to have refinanced its $100 million bond that came due on October 19, with bank debt.  The company has declined to comment.</p>
<p>The trend is more pronounced with corporate borrowers in Argentina and Chile, where the currencies are more stable, which helps companies to negotiate longer-term loans, analysts said.</p>
<p>But blue-chip Mexican companies with a good export base are having little trouble finding an ever-growing number of banks in Mexico ready to lend.  </p>
<p>That growing reliance on the commercial loan market in Mexico could also serve to help the bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the stuff that is maturing will be refinanced by bank debt rather than bond debt, so the supply of bond debt will definitely decrease; or conversly even if supply does increase it will not rise as rapidly as the total borrowing by Latin companies,&quot; said Bankers Trust's Taylor.</p>
<p>Structuring a bond deal is also more more expensive and time-consuming than negotiating a syndicated loan, adding to the loans' attractiveness, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Bank deals tend to be more flexible.  You can just put your 10 bankers in a room and lock them up until they renegotiate,&quot; Taylor added.</p>
<p>However, bonds usually allow for long maturities that can reduce refinancing risks, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Mexico City newsroom (525) 728 9559</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
