<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133396" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST - Penoles 9-mo results seen lackluster.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Penoles 9-mo results seen lackluster.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico mining giant Industrias Penoles SA is seen posting luckluster third quarter results on the back of mostly weak metals prices compared with the same period last year, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not going to get any help from metals prices, apart from lead, which has gone up 30 percent year-on-year,&quot; said Jim Rutherford, mining analyst with HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>Penoles, the world's largest refined silver producer, only receives around 15 percent of revenues from lead sales.  </p>
<p>An average of five analysts' projections has the company's accumulated nine month month earnings coming in around 1.88 pesos per share. In the first six months of the year, Penoles posted net earnings of 477.97 million pesos against 559.6 million pesos in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>One factor in Penoles' favor is the company should see lower minority interest charges this quarter following the acquisition of minority mine stakes from long-time partner Alumax Inc.  </p>
<p>Penoles bought up Alumax's 40 percent stake in the mine Compania Fresnillo in Zacatecas state and a 14.1 stake in Compania Minera Las Torres in Guanajuato state on June 30 for $160 million, so these minority charges should be off the balance sheet this quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Fresnillo accounted for a good part of the minority charge,&quot; Rutherford said, commenting on the accounting factor that is one widely-expected plus factor for Penoles.</p>
<p>Penoles faced an uphill battle this last quarter trying to match record earnings and production posted in 1995.  </p>
<p>Analysts expect net sales to be slightly down, which on top of lower prices, would likely squeeze margins even further.  Robert Fleming mining analyst Warwick Jones estimated sales would drop and that inflation would also hurt slightly given the peso has not devalued in line with higher prices in Mexico.</p>
<p>He too said the plus factor to watch out for was the lower minority interest charge because of the acquisitions.</p>
<p>Echoing the general sentiment was Interacciones mining analyst Sebastian Barry-Taylor. &quot;The third quarter is not going to be very hot for Penoles,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He estimated sales would be down four percent year-on-year, predicting that higher sales volumes, which he saw rising by three percent year-on-year, would not offset lower prices.  &quot;Gold and silver are very weak compared to last year,&quot; Barry-Taylor said.</p>
<p>-- Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom 525 7289530</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
