<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133373" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOLIVIA: Bolivia may cancel Sustainable Development summit.</title>
<headline>Bolivia may cancel Sustainable Development summit.</headline>
<dateline>LA PAZ 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bolivia may have to cancel a regional development summit in December because of disagreement between the United States and Latin America on the focus of the talks, a government minister was quoted on Tuesday as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is agreement on the basic agenda, the summit goes ahead; if not, it won't, that's quite clear,&quot; Foreign Minister Antonio Aranibar said in comments reported by the Bolivian press.</p>
<p>La Razon newspaper said the United States and some other countries believed the talks should focus exclusively on the environment, while most Latin American nations wanted a broader discussion of sustainable economic and social development.</p>
<p>Thirty-four Western Hemisphere nations are due to attend the summit in the eastern Bolivian city of Santa Cruz on December 7-8, a result of the Summit of the Americas held in Miami in December 1994. Cuba has not been invited.</p>
<p>&quot;For any meeting of this kind there has to be consensus. It is not up to Bolivia to insist on a summit taking place, but up to all these countries together,&quot; said the minister.</p>
<p>He said Bolivian President Gonzalo Sanchez de Lozada had made it &quot;very clear that the fight against poverty is an essential part of the concept of sustainable development.&quot;</p>
<p>And Congressman Miguel Uriosta, acting head of the leftist Free Bolivia Movement to which Aranibar belongs, said Monday: &quot;If poverty is not included, there will be no summit.&quot;</p>
<p>But Aranibar said the issue might be resolved at a meeting of the permanent council of the Organisation of American States due to take place in Washington this week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA PAZ"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOLIVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
