<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133368" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Cardoso defends fiscal package.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Cardoso defends fiscal package.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso took to the airwaves on Tuesday to muster public support for a package of fiscal measures designed to cut federal costs and raise revenue.</p>
<p>Cardoso, using his weekly radio address, said the measures would help Brazil &quot;grow more, and more quickly&quot; and allow the government to &quot;spend less and better the taxpayer's money&quot;.</p>
<p>Announced on October 11, the cost-cutting and revenue-raising plan allows for up to 200,000 federal government posts to be eradicated, ends some public sector salary benefits, and obliges state-owned firms to sell non-operational assets.  </p>
<p>&quot;We could have made the adjustments by reducing investment and increasing taxes,&quot; Cardoso said. &quot;But we chose the other route, we cut privileges.&quot;</p>
<p>Some in Congress, not informed about the fiscal measures ahead of time, have started mumbling that the package represents a slap in the face of parliamentary sovereignty.</p>
<p>Officials say it was partially designed to show Brazil could tackle the public sector deficit without relying entirely on an at times recalcitrant Congress to approve key fiscal reforms.  </p>
<p>Newspapers report that congressmen are displeased about a vow from Finance Minister Pedro Malan to reserve all the proceeds from privatizations for internal debt retirement.</p>
<p>Cardoso said it was not acceptable normal people work an eight-hour day and have 30 days holiday a year while government lawyers work four hours a day and have 60 days annual leave.</p>
<p>&quot;I know a lot of people might be unhappy, believing that we are damaging the civil service,&quot; he said. &quot;But (we) had to take these measures to raise salaries of civil servants who continue to work, to improve the quality of service and above all, to stop spending more than we earn, to reduce the public deficit.&quot;  </p>
<p>The cost-cuts and revenue-boosters are intended to save a net 6.5 billion reais next year.</p>
<p>The measures aim to reduce the public sector operational deficit -- the shortfall between revenues and expenditures excluding capital items -- to some 2.5 percent of gross domestic product from an expected 3.5 percent of GDP this year.</p>
<p>Cardoso said this would help reduce interest rates, currently among the highest in Latin America, create conditions for investment and foster growth, which in turn would generate jobs and improve wealth distribution.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
