<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133354" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima shrs close lower, investors remain sidelined.</title>
<headline>Lima shrs close lower, investors remain sidelined.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Lima stock exchange closed lower Tuesday as investors remained sidelined waiting for third quarter earnings reports, brokers said.</p>
<p>A rebound Wednesday was unlikely as the economy's slower- than-expected growth has also made investors reluctant to enter the market, they added.</p>
<p>Tuesday, the General Index  .IGRA fell 0.82 percent to 1,554.25 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index  .ISEL dropped 1.12 percent to 2,098.64 points, according to preliminary stock figures.  </p>
<p>&quot;Investors showed they prefer to see financial results and improved (gross domestic) product figures before deciding to enter the market,&quot; said Luis Ramirez of local brokerage Macrovalores.</p>
<p>Only one blue-chip stock has so far published its third quarter results -- tin-miner Minsur, which remained stable Tuesday at 25.00 soles in 5.24 million soles worth of trade.</p>
<p>The Peruvian economy grew 2.0 percent in the first eight months of the year, compared to 8.4 percent in the same period of 1995, the government announced.  </p>
<p>While investors recognized as prudent the government's policy of slowing the economy down at the beginning of the year, they had been hoping for a quicker recovery in the second half than has so far been seen, brokers said.</p>
<p>In a total of 2,143 trades, 36 stocks fell, 35 were stable and 25 rose in volume of 64.2 million ($25.0 million). A single cross-trade between local brokerages Argos and Surinvest in the shares of pension fund AFP Horizonte accounted for 55 percent of the day's total volume.  </p>
<p>Accounting for 11 percent of the market's volume, benchmark Telefnica del Per was the most heavily traded stock after this cross-trade, as it fell 0.88 percent to 5.65 soles.</p>
<p>-- Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
