<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133305" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuelan jail fire kills at least 30 - official.</title>
<headline>Venezuelan jail fire kills at least 30 - official.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 30 inmates of a Venezuelan jail were burned to death on Tuesday in a fire apparently caused by tear gas canisters fired by guards, prison officials said.</p>
<p>Human rights activists put the toll at 40 and some officials earlier said the number could be as high as that.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working with a figure of 30 prisoners that were burned alive, but we have still not identified them,&quot; National Prisons Director Antonio Marval told reporters outside La Planta jail on the southwestern outskirts of the capital.</p>
<p>The fire started when national guardsmen closed off a wing of the prison and threw in tear gas canisters, Marval said. &quot;We could be talking about murder here,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear why the guards had locked up the prisoners or how the tear gas canisters started the fire, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The version that the prisoners are telling me is that about 40 were burned to death,&quot; human rights activist Olimpia Hung told reporters. Justice Minister Henrique Meier said earlier that the toll could be as high as 40. &quot;Yes, it could be,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Meier said in a telephone interview that the government would launch an investigation into the cause of the fire. &quot;It has to be studied. But it wouldn't make sense for the prisoners to start the fire themselves unless they wanted to commit suicide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One prisoner who called Radio Caracas Radio from inside the jail said the bodies were fused together, showing that the inmates had clung to one other as they waited to die. More than five hours after the fire was brought under control no bodies had been brought out of the jail, which was surrounded by national guardsmen.</p>
<p>Angry family members clashed outside with police who fired tear gas into the crowd of about 100 people to prevent them from approaching the prison.</p>
<p>&quot;They haven't told us anything. We want to know what has happened to our relatives. We are desperate,&quot; one woman told the Globovision television station.</p>
<p>Prisoners waved shirts and knives through the bars and held signs demanding that families and journalists be let in. Female inmates housed in a nearby wing shouted through the bars: &quot;They're killing the prisoners.&quot;</p>
<p>Hours after the fire several gunshots were heard from inside the prison and there were reports of several prisoners with bullet wounds. Hung said one body had bullet wounds.</p>
<p>Venezuela's overcrowded and decaying prisons, where arms and drugs are widely used, are frequent scenes of violence between inmates and clashes with guards. &quot;One of the problems in our prisons, apart from the overcrowding, is the excessively hostile treatment by some guards,&quot; Meier said.</p>
<p>The tragedy at La Planta would be the worst in Venezuela's jails since about 120 prisoners were burned or hacked to death with machetes during a gang fight at the Sabaneta jail in the western city of Maracaibo in January 1994.</p>
<p>La Planta was built for 300 prisoners but currently holds about 900.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
