<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133355" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile's Soquimich brings lithium online.</title>
<headline>Chile's Soquimich brings lithium online.</headline>
<byline>Margaret Orgill</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Sociedad Quimica y Minera de Chile SA (Soquimich) will start producing lithium in November at its Minsal salt lake mine in northern Chile, said Minsal's general manager Felipe Anguita.</p>
<p>&quot;We have completed 50 percent of the startup and should be in a position to produce our first samples next month,&quot; Anguita told Reuters. &quot;Everything is going tremendously well.&quot;</p>
<p>Startup of the lithium plant, which has installed capacity of 40 million pounds, began two months ahead of schedule in late September, he said.  </p>
<p>Minsal plans to start commercial production in December and start shipping lithium to clients in January, said Anguita.</p>
<p>Built on a sprawling mineral-rich saltpan in the Atacama Desert close to the Bolivian and Argentine borders, Minsal is the largest non-metallic mining project in Chile.</p>
<p>Moving into lithium is part of an agressive expansion plan by Soquimich, Chile's biggest fertilizer producer, which include boosting its output of specialist fertilizers and iodine.  </p>
<p>Minsal officials have said the company aims to shake up the world lithium market by selling the mineral at around $1 a pound -- 30 percent below current prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It's proving a very good strategy -- clients are keen to buy our lithium,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Minsal will produce 20 million pounds of lithium next year with output rising to 40 million pounds within the next three to four years, said Anguita.  </p>
<p>Largest consumers of lithium carbonate, a fine white powder, are the glass, ceramics and primary aluminium industries. Demand is also strong from older U.S. smelters where lithium is used for improving energy efficiency.</p>
<p>Soquimich, Chile's largest fertilizer producer, will also mine 300,000 tonnes of potassium chloride this year at Minsal which started operating last year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is 50 percent over budget for the year as 1996 was considered a startup year,&quot; said Anguita.  </p>
<p>Output of potassium chloride, which is used in specialized fertilizers, is expected to rise to 500,000 tonnes by the end of the decade, he said. The company will have to invest $35-40 million in expanding its plant to cope with the increase.</p>
<p>Other projects include investing $120 million to build a plant to produce potassium sulphate and boric acid which will come on stream in early 1998.</p>
<p>Soquimich plans to produce 250,000 tonnes a year of potassium sulphate and 16,000 tonnes of boric acid a year.</p>
<p>--Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22470">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
