<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133311" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela discreet on possible Brady buyback plan.</title>
<headline>Venezuela discreet on possible Brady buyback plan.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela is studying several proposals to improve the profile of its foreign debt, Finance Minister Luis Raul Matos Azocar said, but to release details now would be premature and only jeopardise the final scheme.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise the price of our debt would rise so that when we buy it -- if we buy it -- it would be trading near its face value and there would be no gain for the country,&quot; Matos told reporters.</p>
<p>Matos said the government was working to convince congressmen of the value of an autonomous Debt Rescue Fund that would be able &quot;to work independently, although with prudence&quot;.</p>
<p>Currently the government must get congressional approval each time it wants to pay down debt.</p>
<p>The proposed Debt Rescue Fund, which will probably be managed by the Venezuelan Investment Fund (FIV), will be able to act more discreetly when using windfall oil revenues to extend debt maturities and buy back Brady debt, Matos said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our debt servicing is particularly heavy in 1997, '98 and '99,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
