<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133364" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican peso hit badly by anxiety, speculators.</title>
<headline>Mexican peso hit badly by anxiety, speculators.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican peso closed down across the board Tuesday, battered again by anxiety and speculation that expectations of higher rates at today's T-bill auction did nothing to arrest, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;What triggered the speculation and jitters that led to a run on the peso? That's quite a question when you consider that such sharp changes in the exchange rate are unnerving when interest rates are on their way up,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders expected Cetes rates to gain on the bellwether 28-day issue, but to be mixed on other issues at the primary auction being held today.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso and its 24-hour counterpart closed 4.4 and 4.3 centavos weaker, respectively, at 7.7820/7.7900 and 7.7730/7.7830 per dollar.</p>
<p>The same-day peso had earlier closed 2.6 centavos weaker at 7.7460/7.7510 per dollar.</p>
<p>Some traders said a local bank stepped into the market to buy substantial amounts of dollars, which triggered a run on the peso.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a bank out there that was very short (dollars), and the market got out of hand when it stepped in to cover positions,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders said that rates assigned by Banco de Mexico at the primary Cetes auction would be crucial to how the peso would fare on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Alexis Quiones, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
