<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133313" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru lowers minimum bid price for Yauricocha mine.</title>
<headline>Peru lowers minimum bid price for Yauricocha mine.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's state mining company Centromin said Tuesday it had lowered the minimum bid price for the December privatization of its polymetallic mine Yauricocha to $8.5 million, from an original $10 million.</p>
<p>Centromin has also lowered the minimum investment that will be required of the auction winner to $10 million over five years, from $18 million over three years originally asked for at the unit's September auction, which was declared void due to a lack of bidders, spokesman Enrique Olivares said.</p>
<p>Centromin hoped to receive offers for the unit on December 2, and announce the auction winner on December 6, he said.  </p>
<p>Ten companies from countries including Peru, Canada and Mexico had bought bidding details ahead of the first auction, Olivares added.</p>
<p>Yauricocha, which lies 220 miles (350 km) southeast of Lima, currently produces 30,000 tonnes of mineral per month and has proven and probable reserves of 2.8 million tonnes and potential reserves of six million tonnes.</p>
<p>The proven reserves have grades of 1.1 percent for copper, 2.8 percent for lead and 5.3 percent for zinc. The mineral also contains 132 grams of silver and 0.8 grams of gold per tonne, according to Centromin.  </p>
<p>Yauricocha's auction forms part of the ongoing piecemeal privatization of Centromin, whose most important asset, the La Oroya metallurgical complex, is set to be sold in the first quarter next year, Olivares said.</p>
<p>But neither a date nor a minimum bid price has been set for the La Oroya auction, he added.</p>
<p>In July, the state miner launched its sell-off with the successful sale of two of the company's major assets.</p>
<p>First, a Canadian consortium of Rio Algom Ltd and Inmet Mining Corp agreed to invest $2.52 billion over the next five years to become owner of the copper-rich Antamina prospect.</p>
<p>Also, Canada's Barrick Gold Corporation won the option to buy Peru's Quicay gold prospect by offering at an auction to pay $202 million should the company decide to develop the asset after feasibility studies.</p>
<p>The government also plans to sell Centromin's other six mines, a railroad network, port facilities, four hydroelectric plants and several prospects by the middle of 1997.</p>
<p>-- Saul Hudson, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134 REUTER SH</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
