<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13336" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac, Juppe skip church trip after Africa roundup.</title>
<headline>Chirac, Juppe skip church trip after Africa roundup.</headline>
<byline>Helene Fontanaud</byline>
<dateline>BREGANCON, France 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac and Prime Minister Alain Juppe avoided a public outing to worship on Sunday as they discussed policy amid criticism of a police roundup of African migrants from a Paris church.</p>
<p>Chirac and Juppe met for a second day in a Riviera fortress on issues ranging from immigration to record unemployment and the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>They did not accompany their wives Bernadette and Isabelle who attended mass at Le Lavandou.</p>
<p>Last year, both couples attended a Sunday service during a similar weekend of talks by the conservative leaders at the presidential retreat by the Mediterranean. Sunday's mass was given by a Zairean priest.</p>
<p>Chirac and Juppe skipped going to church after riot police smashed their way into the Saint Bernard church in Paris and arrested 210 African immigrants protesting against expulsion orders.</p>
<p>The often staid Le Monde newspaper carried a front-page cartoon in its weekend edition of Chirac and Juppe by the seaside in Bregancon with Chirac asking &quot;Shall we go to church on Sunday?&quot; Juppe replies: &quot;Ah, have you got your axe?&quot;.</p>
<p>Chirac and Juppe, due to end their talks on Sunday evening, were discussing issues including the 1998 budget, immigration and fiscal reform amid union threats of unrest.</p>
<p>Aides said that no decisions would be announced after the informal talks, partly aimed at underlining cohesion between the two men before a first cabinet meeting after the traditional summer break on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government faces a tightrope over the budget with unions trying to talk up a wave of public resistance for the autumn to repeat a crippling string of strikes in late 1995.</p>
<p>The government has to curb public deficits to qualify for a single European currency from 1999 while delivering on promises of income tax cuts for 1997. The government is due to be unveiled on September 18.</p>
<p>The two men got some encouragement from an opinion poll on Sunday, showing that voters were slightly less dissatisfied with their performance.</p>
<p>The IFOP survey, for the Journal du Dimanche weekly, showed 38 percent were satisfied with Chirac's performance against 50 percent dissatisfied. In July, the split was 35-53. Juppe's less favourable rating improved to 31-57 percent from 30-59.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BREGANCON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
