<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133361" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba says sugar harvest will improve despite storm.</title>
<headline>Cuba says sugar harvest will improve despite storm.</headline>
<byline>Frances Kerry</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuban authorities said Tuesday that the island still aimed to increase sugar production in the upcoming 1996-97 harvest despite large areas of cane being flattened or flooded by Hurricane Lili.</p>
<p>Sugar Minister Nelson Torres told state television Monday night that &quot;We are convinced that we will improve in the coming harvest&quot;. Production in 1995-96 was 4.45 million tonnes, halting a steady decline that had begun in 1990.</p>
<p>Until the hurricane, sugar experts had thought Cuba could produce a harvest of around 5.2 million-5.3 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Authorities have not given any official target for the harvest, due to start in December and last until May or June.</p>
<p>A statement given to foreign diplomats Tuesday by the government said some 656,138 hectares (1.62 million acres) of sugar cane had been affected by the hurricane, which tore through central and western areas of the country Thursday night and Friday.</p>
<p>However, it appears much of the cane flattened or flooded by the storm could be useable for the harvest.</p>
<p>Quoted by the ruling Communist Party newspaper Granma Tuesday, Torres reiterated that the country could not give up on its plan for a better harvest this year.</p>
<p>Torres said that once flooded cane fields had been drained some cane would stand again. The cane that remained on the ground would just have to be cut as it was, he said, adding that a good part of the affected cane would be recoverable.</p>
<p>A priority would be draining flooded fields, he said, adding it was too early to say how much cane was actually destroyed.</p>
<p>Hurricane Lili also caused partial damage, mainly to roofs, at 56 of the country's 156 sugar mills. But Torres said it was too early to predict if this would end up afecting production.</p>
<p>It was not clear what percentage of Cuba's overall cane fields had been affected.</p>
<p>Last year's sugar harvest marked the end of a steady decline in the sector since Cuba lost its main economic partner the former Soviet Union. Production in 1994-95 was 3.3 million tonnes, the lowest in 50 years.</p>
<p>Recovery in the sugar sector, a key foreign exchange earner, has been due in part to financing from a string of foreign banks and trading houses, for input such as fertiliser and pesticides. Authorities have not given a figure for how much credit was obtained for the coming harvest, but have said it is more than last year, which was some $120 million.</p>
<p>Such credit puts the onus on Cuba to improve production in order to pay back the loans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
