<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133363" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Caracas stocks rise as privatisation goals clear.</title>
<headline>Caracas stocks rise as privatisation goals clear.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Caracas share prices, bouncing back from support levels, were given further heart by increased confidence in the government's privatization plans and expected falls in interest rates, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign demand was up, in part because stock prices are attractive and in part because the privatizations of Bancos Consolidado and de Venezuela look set to go ahead,&quot; said Vencred broker Geronimo Paolini.</p>
<p>The bolsa's 19-share  .IBC index rose 3.9 percent as 22 million shares traded worth 3 billion bolivars ($6.4 million).  </p>
<p>Rising foreign demand spurred local investors, traders said, with the spree possibly sustained through the week by expected falls in interest rates at Wednesday's auction of Central Bank TEM bills.</p>
<p>Among traded issues, 32 rose, five closed flat and five fell. Market leader Electricidad de Caracas rose 27.50 bolivars to close at 519.00 bolivars, while foods company Mavesa gained 10.00 bolivars to finish at 150.00. Steel company Sivensa rose 8.95 bolivars to end at 358.95.  </p>
<p>The government said Wednesday 20 investors had been short- listed for the privatizations of Bancos Consolidado and Venezuela expected later this year.</p>
<p>-- Silene Ramirez, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
