<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133317" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FORECAST- Televisa Q3 picture improving.</title>
<headline>FORECAST- Televisa Q3 picture improving.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican media firm Grupo Televisa SA's third quarter earnings this week are expected to show a continuing recovery, analysts said.</p>
<p>The television and publishing group's earnings, expected late on Wednesday or early on Thursday, will benefit from contiuing cost-cutting.</p>
<p>&quot;We are definitely starting to see some of the benefits from the cost reductions and are starting to see a little bit more ad spending going into the second half of the year,&quot; said Alexander Ryshawy, an analyst at DA Campbell. Televisa's earnings are considered extremely difficult to forecast.  </p>
<p>One analyst forecast a third quarter net loss of 156 million pesos, another a loss of 12 million pesos, and a third a net profit of 128 million pesos.</p>
<p>Discrepancies in forecasts could be due in part to differing expectations on foreign exchange or monetary gains or losses and by accounting changes.</p>
<p>The three forecasts for the nine-month figure are all losses:</p>
<p>- 554 million pesos.</p>
<p>- 693 million pesos.</p>
<p>- 838 million pesos.  </p>
<p>The company first announced a 1995 nine month profit of 1.24 billion pesos. In the second quarter, Televisa reported a loss of 232.39 million pesos. But the company said this was generated mainly by a loss in non-financial items and by extraordinary expenses.</p>
<p>The company could also see slightly better advertising revenue, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally the third quarter is stronger than the second quarter because many companies make their payments for the &quot;top offs,&quot; said Abaco analyst Claudia Gonzalez.  </p>
<p>&quot;It will be similar to the second quarter, but a little better, but where we will see the strongest recovery will be in the fourth quarter.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Top offs&quot; are additional advertising payments on top of the company's French Plan advertising. The French plan is a multi-media package offered to clients, whereby advertisers prepay advertising for the following year. Most deposits are made in October and November.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect third-quarter results (to be) relatively flat compared with second-quarter performance, with a slight margin improvement as a result of operating expense reduction,&quot; said Santander Investment analyst Jim Garvey in a report.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the operating margin to be from 6.5 percent to 8.0 percent in the third quarter versus 4.8 percent in the same period last year, and 3.0 percent in the second quarter this year.</p>
<p>In the first two quarters, the company had some large restructuring costs that will be smaller in the third quarter, analysts added.</p>
<p>-- Robert Kozak, Mexico City newsroom (525) 728 9559</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
