<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133436" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ economists' growth expectations rise - survey.</title>
<headline>NZ economists' growth expectations rise - survey.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand economists expect the rate of growth of real GDP in a year's time to rise to 2.77 percent, up from their forecast in July of 2.25 percent, according to a survey by the Alexander Consulting Group.</p>
<p>Production-based GDP in the year to June grew an actual 2.6 percent.</p>
<p>The Alexander Economists Survey, published on Wednesday, also showed a rise in expectations for the New Zealand dollar Trade-Weighted Index, compared to the group's July survey.  </p>
<p>The TWI was picked at 65.5 in a year's time, up from the economists' average expectation in July of 64.9. It is currently at 67.6.</p>
<p>The inflation rate, as measured by the Consumers Price Index, was seen at 1.14 percent a year out. In July, the economists had on average picked headline inflation at 1.49 percent in a year's time. In the September year it was 2.4 percent.</p>
<p>The average weekly wage was seen growing at a rate of 2.82 percent, compared to 2.72 percent.  </p>
<p>The economists' forecasts for real interest rates a year out slipped very slightly in October. They now see the yield on 10-year government stock, in excess of inflation, at 6.14 percent in a year's time, against their July forecast of 6.19 percent.</p>
<p>The stock is currently yielding 7.39 percent, while annual underlying inflation was at 2.34 percent in the September year. ----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>		     Alexander Economists Survey</p>
<p>Table of results for October 1996</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>			  1 year's time   4 years' time  7 years' time</p>
<p>Inflation rate	   1.14		 1.70	     1.71</p>
<p>as measured by	  *1.49		*1.42	    *1.53</p>
<p>CPI, pct</p>
<p>Rate of increase	 2.82		 2.76	     2.83</p>
<p>of average		*2.72		*2.57	    *2.64</p>
<p>weekly wage, pct</p>
<p>Real interest rate     6.14		 5.09	     4.67</p>
<p>(ie yield on 10 yr    *6.19		*5.16	    *4.56</p>
<p>govt stock, in excess</p>
<p>of inflation, pct</p>
<p>Rate of growth of	2.77		 2.98	     3.03</p>
<p>real GDP, pct	   *2.25		*3.17	    *3.23</p>
<p>Trade Weighted	   65.5		 68.2	     70.5</p>
<p>exchange rate (TWI)   *64.9		*67.9	    *70.6</p>
<p>Note: asterisked figures are the result of the Alexander Consulting Group's July 1996 survey.</p>
<p>The October survey canvassed 17 New Zealand banks, investment managers and forecasting groups.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
