<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133433" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New Zealand newspapers - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE DOMINION</p>
<p>A fisheries dispute over two seized Russian trawlers that could lead to the Government being taken to an international tribunal escalated on Tuesday when inspectors seized three more ships. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National MPs were told on Tuesday they would not be given regular briefings on the progress of coalition talks because they were too secret. National and NZ First MPs held caucus meetings but National MPs were not briefed on Monday's coalition talks. However, MPs were told they would, from time to time, be given updates on progress, but warned that any leaks from the caucus would be damaging. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Counties' Jonah Lomu's appearance in Sunday's national championship final at Eden Park was put in doubt on Tuesday when he was cited for a spear tackle in last weekend's semifinal against Cantebury. Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Maverick National cabinet minister John Banks was told on Tuesday night after special votes had been counted he had held his seat, increasing his slim election night majority for his Whangarei seat to 383 from 196. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Alliance and Council of Trade Unions have criticised reports that unions might accept a coalition government only amending the Employment Contracts Act. CTU secretary Angela Foulkes said accepting amendments rather than a full repeal of the act as the price of a non-National led coalition was not the position of the union organisation. Alliance leader Jim Anderton said union leaders could not seriously think they could bring about repeal of the act by giving away their negotiating position before negotiations even start. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Retiring Christian Coalition co-leader Graeme Lee has blamed homosexuals and the media for his party's poor election-night showing. Page 2.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Todd Corp managing director John Hunn has made a stinging attack on Telecom, accusing it of serious abuse of its &quot;monopoly&quot; position. Hunn also hit out at government failure to ensure a competitive telecommunications market and implied the first MMP government might intervene. Todd Corporation owns shares in Telecom competitor Clear Communications and in Sky TV. Page 19.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Heinz-Wattie subsidiary Tip Top Ice Cream has scaled down its bid to buy Dairy Group's New American Ice Cream in the wake of the Commerce Commission's refusal to clear a full takeover. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The dollar continued to rise on Tuesday and interest rates fell, with analysts warning of Reserve Bank action if 90-day bills fell below nine percent. Page 20.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>The existing 12 dairy companies were likely to be reduced to &quot;somewhere between three and seven&quot;, Dairy Board chairman Sir Dryden Spring said on Tuesday. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New car makers and importers are unlikely to cut prices immediately, despite the continued rise of the dollar. Companies said they wanted to see if the currency's trend was maintained and whether the Reserve Bank would ease interest rates. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Pay-television company Sky has a healthy operating cashflow, according to chief executive Nate Smith. Page 22.  </p>
<p>THE NEW ZEALAND HERALD</p>
<p>An Auckland man says he is prepared to pay someone $10,000 for a kidney to give him a new lease of life, but doctors warn he is wasting his time. Physicians insist he will find no doctor willing to transplant an organ bought at a price.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The punishing effects of a soaring currency on an already-stressed export sector will put pressure on New Zealand First to bring its coalition talks to a speedy conclusion. The NZ dollar closed on Tuesday at 67.8 on the trade-weighted index, its highest level for more than eight years. It is expected to continue to rise as overseas investors seek to capitalise on New Zealand's high bond yields. Local interest rates are being held up against a falling international trend in part because the Reserve Bank is reluctant to condone an easing until it knows the composition - and therefore spending intentions - of the next government.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Holding coalition talks in confidence is the only approach to take, New Zealand First leader Winston Peters said on Tuesday after criticism of secrecy surrounding the negotiations. Labour leader Helen Clark on Tuesday night endorsed the need for confidentiality. But to demystify the process, Labour is seeking agreement from New Zealand First to announce its talks venue for the meeting at 10 a.m. today.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Financial market dealers and commentators preoccupied themselves trying to second-guess the Reserve Bank on Tuesday as the rise in the New Zealand dollar and fall in wholesale interest rates continued apace.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tranz Rail is looking at spending $600 million over the next 10 years upgrading its interisland ferry operation, the company's annual report said.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Dublin-based Independent Newspapers Plc has declared its takeover offer for Wilson and Horton unconditional after receiving stock exchange approval to list its exchangeable shares. The shares are expected to be quoted shortly after the offer closes on November 8, Independent Press Communications' Michael Walls said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>South Eastern Utilities was on track to met a forecast tax-paid profit of $4.5 million this year, chairman Sir Roderick Weir said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
