<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133487" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Astra revises up 1996 net forecast.</title>
<headline>Astra revises up 1996 net forecast.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's largest vehicle manufacturer Astra International raised its 1996 net profit forecast on Tuesday, saying the fall-out from the country's controversial national car policy was less than feared.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on our nine-month net profit, we revised up our target to 450 billion rupiah ($193.55 million) from 300 billion rupiah. We believe we can achieve this target,&quot; Astra Financial Director Rini Suwandi told a news conference.</p>
<p>She said the original net profit target for 1996 was 425 billion rupiah before the government said in February that it would grant tax and tariff breaks to PT Timor Putra Nasional, a firm controlled by one of President Suharto's sons, to produce a national car.</p>
<p>Astra then downgraded its net profit forecast for the year to 300 billion rupiah, fearing a sharp fall in sales. Because of the tax breaks, Timor Putra is selling its 1500 cc sedans at about half the sticker price of comparable vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;At that time we were not sure of the impact of the national car programme on Astra sales,&quot; Suwandi said. &quot;But, by June 1996, we could perform very well, especially in the motorcycle division.&quot;  </p>
<p>Astra president director T.P. Rahmat said the company was looking into the possibility of floating its agribusiness and banking subsidiaries within the next 12 to 18 months.</p>
<p>Rahmat declined comment on newspaper reports of a wave of buying into the company and comments by Indonesia's biggest cigarette firm Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna that it was prepared to sell a 2.85 percent stake in Astra.</p>
<p>PT Sampoerna bought a 2.85 percent stake in Astra last month at the height of a wave of buying into the firm. President director Putera Sampoerna bought an additional 9.81 percent on his own account, giving him effectively the single largest shareholding in Astra.</p>
<p>The market did not approve of the company's move, sending Sampoerna shares tumbling as ratings agencies Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's downgraded the company's debt on the grounds that it was moving out of its core business.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Sampoerna spokesman Jonathan Zax said the firm was prepared to sell its stake in Astra but declined to comment on speculation that the buyer could be Putera Sampoerna himself.</p>
<p>Separately, the Nusamaba group, with which President Suharto is connected, has announced that it is interested in acquiring a stake in Astra.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
