<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133478" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo Disneyland firm may list on TSE in Dec - paper.</title>
<headline>Tokyo Disneyland firm may list on TSE in Dec - paper.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oriental Land Co Ltd, which operates Tokyo Disneyland, will have its shares listed on the second section of the Tokyo Stock Exchange (TSE) possibly as early as December, a Japanese newspaper said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The economic daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun said that at the time of the listing, 23 million to 25 million Oriental Land shares will be sold on the market. They will include 15 million to 18 million new shares to be issued to raise the company's capital, the paper said.</p>
<p>An Oriental Land spokesman was not immediately available for comment on the report.  </p>
<p>Of the shares to be sold, six million to eight million will be those currently held by Oriental Land's existing major shareholders, the paper said.</p>
<p>The paper did not specify which shareholders would sell shares at the time of the listing.</p>
<p>The funds to be raised through the planned capital increase will be used to build a second Disney theme park next to the existing Tokyo Disneyland, the paper said. Oriental Land plans to open the second park in 2001, it said.</p>
<p>Investment in the second park is expected to be nearly 300 billion yen abd Oriental Land hopes to raise more than 160 billion yen through the capital increase, the paper said.</p>
<p>Oriental Land has said it wants to go public but it has not provided details of its listing plan.</p>
<p>The company declined to comment on the date of the share listing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
