<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13349" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian army rescues 2,000 pilgrims in Himalayas.</title>
<headline>Indian army rescues 2,000 pilgrims in Himalayas.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian army helicopters plucked some 2,000 Hindu pilgrims stranded by icy rain and snow on Sunday from a rugged Himalayan trail where at least 121 have died, officials said.</p>
<p>For the first time in four days the weather improved, allowing helicopters to reach pilgrims who included &quot;sadhus&quot;, Hindu holy men who made the trek in Jammu and Kashmir state naked, their bodies smeared with ash.</p>
<p>Up to 70,000 pilgrims, caught by a sudden onset of bad weather, were stranded for a fourth day at heights of up to 3,700 metres (12,136 ft), the officials said.</p>
<p>Some 112,000 Hindus arrived in Kashmir this year to visit the holy Amarnath cave, where devotees worship an ice stalagmite believed to be a manifestation of the &quot;lingam&quot;, or phallus, of the Hindu God Shiva.</p>
<p>The Press Trust of India put the toll, resulting from high monsoon rains, snow and sub-zero temperatures, at 160. Officials in Srinagar, Jammu and Kashmir's summer capital, put the death toll at 121.</p>
<p>State government spokesman K.B. Jandial said 2,000 people were flown to Srinagar and other Kashmiri towns by three military helicopters which carried out 50 sorties.</p>
<p>One eyewitness said officials faced protests as army helicopters moved people to safety from one area.</p>
<p>S. Tariq, a cameraman with the New Delhi-based Asian News International news agency, told Reuters: &quot;There were 38 dead bodies laid out on the ground in a row.&quot;</p>
<p>Tariq said some pilgrims complained that help had come slowly. He quoted a middle-aged woman, as saying: &quot;If my parents are left behind the government would be held responsible.&quot;</p>
<p>Some 650 people were still stranded around the high-altitude lake of Sheshnag, 60 km (38 miles) from Srinagar, and Panchtarni, nine km (six miles) beyond, only six km (four miles) from the holy cave of Amarnath, Jandial, the spokesman, said.</p>
<p>Thousands had trekked down to the base camp at Pahalgam, some 100 km (62.5 miles) by road from Srinagar. The number of stranded there had risen by 5,000 to 60,000, Jandial said.</p>
<p>Floods made impassable all roads leading to the town.</p>
<p>Those stranded included people strung out along the 50-km (30-mile) route from Pahalgam to the 3,880 metre (12,725 ft)-high Amarnath cave, officials said.</p>
<p>Between 300 and 400 soldiers were detailed to escort pilgrims trekking down the sides of the Kashmir valley, Jandial said. He said there were no pilgrims left at the cave.</p>
<p>The helicopters also dropped food, medicine and blankets to help some 3,000 people on a thickly-forested part of the route near the frozen Sheshnag lake.</p>
<p>&quot;The priority was to bring back ailing pilgrims,&quot; added Jandial, who said helicopters also took oxygen cylinders to pilgrims near the lake.</p>
<p>The lake is about 15 km (nine miles) south of Amarnath and is normally the third stage of a five-day trek to the cave.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
