<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133456" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Banks says won't join cabinet if NZ's Peters does.</title>
<headline>Banks says won't join cabinet if NZ's Peters does.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tourism Minister John Banks said on Wednesday he would refuse to be part of a cabinet which included New Zealand First leader Winston Peters.</p>
<p>&quot;I will not sit around a cabinet table with Winston Peters, because what Winston Peters stands for, I don't,&quot; the New Zealand Press Association reported Banks as saying.</p>
<p>National is negotiating with NZ First, hoping to form a coalition government. If that happens, Peters is likely to become deputy prime minister.  </p>
<p>Banks, who is not expected to be re-appointed to cabinet anyway, said he could accept NZ First MPs Jack Elder and Peter McCardle as fellow ministers, but not Peters.</p>
<p>&quot;I could sit around the cabinet table with Jack Elder and Peter McCardle because they are honourable Members of Parliament. Winston Peters -- no,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what Winston Peters is up to. All I know is that Winston Peters will be interested in doing the best business he can for Winston Peters, in the finest tradition of Winston first.&quot;  </p>
<p>Final results for the Whangarei electorate were announced late on Tuesday, and Mr Banks increased his election night majority of 196 to 383.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
