<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133470" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL palm oil ends marginally down, trade cautious.</title>
<headline>KL palm oil ends marginally down, trade cautious.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES     PALM OIL PHYSICAL</p>
<p>Jan (3rd pos)  1,102 rgt/tonne	Oct (south) 1,130</p>
<p>Open/Hi/low    1,111/1,112/1,094    Prev close 1,135</p>
<p>Prev settlement 1,104		  * sellers prices</p>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES -Prices ended with smaller losses on late covering after falling in early afternoon on Pakistani rupee devaluation. There were no results on Pakistan's tender. Trading was cautious with morning prices rising on higher soyoil and a fresh Pakistanis tender.</p>
<p>PALM OIL PHYSICAL - Interest was seen among CPOS and RBD palm olein. Market is watching closely fundamentals factors.  </p>
<p>The State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) devalued the rupee by 7.86 percent against the dollar and the news came in towards the close of the morning session.</p>
<p>The SBP moved the rupee down to 40.1200/40.3206 to the dollar from 36.9700/37.1549.</p>
<p>&quot;The rupee devaluation means that Pakistan has to cough out more money to buy palm oil,&quot; a trader said, adding this would surely slow down Malaysia's export of palm oil to Pakistan.</p>
<p>&quot;But if they (the Pakistanis) need to buy urgently for their consumption, then they have no choice but to buy at current levels,&quot; a trader said. &quot;The amount will possibly be small.&quot;  </p>
<p>Another trader said: &quot;Other vegetable oils are also attractive and palm has to be priced more competitive in order to attract the Pakistanis.&quot;</p>
<p>Trading was cautious with players still waiting for the outcome of Pakistan's tender, traders said.</p>
<p>Pakistan received three bids on Tuesday in response to its tender for 9,000 tonnes of RBD palm oil.</p>
<p>Pan Century offered a rate of $505.40 per tonne FOB and Felda $508 per tonne FOB for 9,000 tonnes of palm oil in the first half of November. Cargill offered $511.88 for 3,000 tonnes of palm oil for shipment by November 20, one dealer said.  </p>
<p>Small losses were seen in the futures market.</p>
<p>By the close, third month January futures contract was down two ringgit at 1,102 ringgit ($439.92) a tonne after trading between 1,094 and 1,112 ringgit.</p>
<p>The contract's next support will be 1,090 and resistance of 1,130, they said.</p>
<p>Turnover on the futures market was 1,895 lots against 2,563 on Monday  Physicals saw active dealings in October (south) crude palm oil which was offered at 1,130 ringgit a tonne after trading from 1,125 to 1,127.50 ringgit.  </p>
<p>Oct (central) was offered at 1,110 and bids at 1,105 and Oct (north) at 1,110 against 1,105. Nov (south) crude palm oil was offered at 1,135 ringgit with bids at 1,130. Nov (central) saw offers at 1,120 and bids at 1,107.50.</p>
<p>In refined palm oil market, Nov/Dec RBD palm oil was offered at $485 a tonne FOB Malaysia, and Jan/Feb/Mch at $490.</p>
<p>Nov RBD palm olein saw offers at $517.50, and Dec at $515 and Jan/Feb/Mch at $517.50. Nov was traded from $515 to $512.50.</p>
<p>Nov RBD palm stearin was offered at $367.50, Dec at $370 and Nov/Dec palm fatty acid distillate saw sellers at $320. - Tan Lee Lee (603-230-7510) ($1=2.5050 ringgit).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
