<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13346" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FEATURE-Guardians of Portuguese on the offensive.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Guardians of Portuguese on the offensive.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The guardians of the Portuguese language are going on the offensive to halt the increasing use of foreign words.</p>
<p>The Society of the Portuguese Language (SPL), a non-profit foundation with no formal authority, has set up a commission of volunteers to monitor what it sees as the growing abuse of Portuguese by foreign expressions, mainly English.</p>
<p>The commission will monitor the media, state decrees and advertisements for the unjustified use of foreign words and plead with the authors to stick to Portuguese.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim of the commission is to make people write and speak their language well, and to love Portuguese,&quot; said SPL president Jose Antonio Camelo. &quot;But it is not going to police the language,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said Portuguese was in a chaotic state because grammar was taught inadequately in schools and teachers were not properly trained.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the use of English in international business, films, rock music and computer technology was making inroads into Portuguese, spoken by an estimated 200 million people around the world.</p>
<p>Camelo said he did not object to English usage where there were no Portuguese equivalents, such as &quot;video clip&quot; and &quot;leasing&quot;.</p>
<p>But he called for a language policy to invent Portuguese equivalents or give a Portuguese slant to foreign words, as in the present use of &quot;blusa&quot; for blouse and &quot;clube&quot; for club.</p>
<p>In his works early this century, the celebrated Portuguese author and former president Manuel Teixeira Gomes gave a twist to foreign words such as French's &quot;boulevard&quot;, which he called &quot;bulevar&quot;.</p>
<p>What Camelo objects to is the abuse of his language by foreign words that have a Portuguese equivalent.</p>
<p>&quot;Near Lisbon I know a garage with a 'car wash' sign in English. I think this is quite unreasonable, when in Portugal we say 'lavagem de carro',&quot; Camelo told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I have seen signs saying 'shop' in English, instead of using the Portuguese word 'loja' which is quite adequate.&quot;</p>
<p>The SPL's six-strong commission, due to be launched formally in September, would write to the owner of the car wash business and ask him to refrain from using the English expression, Camelo said. The same approach would be made to &quot;shop&quot; owners.</p>
<p>Camelo has asked a local lawyer to search Portuguese law to see if abusers of the language could be prosecuted, in which case the SPL would inform the authorities of any violations.</p>
<p>Camelo said he objected to the use of English as the language of tuition in mathematics courses by foreign teachers at the universities of the Algarve in southern Portugal and Covilha in the northeast.</p>
<p>Portugal's Academy of Sciences was drawing up a new dictionary of common Portuguese usage due for publication next year, estimated to contain at least 4,000 foreign words.</p>
<p>A generation ago, the number of foreign words used in Portuguese was far less, Camelo said.</p>
<p>He said he was worried about the declining use of Portuguese by descendants of Portuguese emigrants around the world and he hoped the new Commonwealth of Portuguese-Speaking Countries (CPLP) would defend the language.</p>
<p>The CPLP, launched in Lisbon last month, aims to unite the interests of Portugal and its former colonies of Angola, Brazil, Cape Verde, Guinea-Bissau, Mozambique and Sao Tome and Principe, which have all felt the pressing influence of English.</p>
<p>&quot;We realise this is a problem not just for Portuguese, but for other languages as well,&quot; Camelo said.</p>
<p>&quot;But some one has to draw the line and take a stand.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
