<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133430" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>A recent survey has found wage increases secured in enterprise bargaining agreements sat at 6 per cent a year during the June quarter. This figure remains well above the &quot;comfort zone&quot; level needed for an interest rate cut by the Reserve Bank. Industrial Relations Minister, Peter Reith, seized the opportunity to demand unions slow down any wage outcomes not linked to productivity gains. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Opposition has demanded a full inquiry into the awarding of a A$1 million Government advertising contract to an ad agency with strong Liberal Party connections. In a letter signed by Prime Minister Howard's political adviser, Grahame Morris, it has been revealed that Morris intervened in the advertising agency selection process. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Qantas Airways has joined the growing chorus of tourism operators appealing for urgent action to revitalise tourism from Japan and to stop the general decline of Japanese tourists. Senior tourism authorities have cited steep air tickets, visa problems and a shortage of hotel infrastructure for the decline in Japanese travel. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The humiliating diplomatic setback suffered by Australia's failed bid to gain a seat on the United Nations Security Council has resulted in the Foreign Affairs Department accusing competing nations Sweden and Portugal of bribery. UN observers claim a tide of personal gifts -including gold Rolex watches - were circulating the UN General Assembly in the lead-up to the vote. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard has expressed his disappointment at the surprise defeat of Australia's bid to win a temporary seat on the United Nations Security Council yesterday. Howard has asked for a Department of Foreign Affairs review to uncover why more than 30 countries reversed pledges of support. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard admitted to a business lunch in Adelaide yesterday his sweeping industrial relations legislation - self-described as his single most important reform - would not be passed without substantial amendments. Howard's comments came after he signalled a pragmatic approach to negotiations on the legislation in the Senate. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following intense pressure from his own Labor caucus, New South Wales Premier Bob Carr has extended investigations into paedophilia by the New South Wales Police Royal Commission by announcing four new terms of reference covering the adequacy of current laws against paedophilia, penalties, and whether Government agencies and the police had done enough to protect children from sexual abuse. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to the Australian Medical Association, the Federal Government's A$10 million Budget cut, which will see Medicare rebates cut for surgical assistants in 150 common operations from November 1, will compromise patient care. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>In what amounted to a revolt, more than 20 MPs from all factions signed a petition last night demanding a special Caucus meeting to discuss the New South Wales Government's widening of the Police Royal Commission into paedophilia, which was announced yesterday by State Premier Bob Carr. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a ground-breaking compromise deal set to go before the New South Wales Government, the State's hotels will be allowed to operate 15 poker machines and clubs given access to multi-million dollar jackpots. The deal is intended to help smaller operator, such as the hotel industry which have been fighting for the right to operate poker machines for more than a decade. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The final master plan for Sydney's new A$384 million Showground at Homebush Bay was unveiled yesterday by New South Wales Premier Bob Carr. The site will contain an exhibition and sporting complex to be built on 30 hectares of land. The massive site is du to be completed in two years - in time to host five Olympic sports for 2000. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government has ordered an urgent review into Australia's failure to obtain a seat in the United Nations Security Council. In the lead up to the vote, Australia's Ambassador to the UN, Richard Butler had expressed strong optimism, however Austrlia underestimated its support by at least 30 per cent and was defeated by Portugal. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The ongoing controversy surrounding Government ministers owning shares continued yesterday when it was revealed Victorian Conservation Minister Marie Tehan bought 3750 shares in ERG, which is part of the OneLink consortium which has a lucrative Government contract, after payments had been guaranteed by the State. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following outrage over the death of Dillion Palfrey, who died from brain damage after he was shaken by his intellectually disabled mother, Victorian Youth and Community Services Minister Denis Napthine has rejected calls for a royal commission on child protection, and has accused Justice John Fogarty of making ill-informed remarks on the issue. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The immediate future of Sunset Boulevard, which was scheduled to premiere in Melbourne on the weekend, is cloudy after the female lead, Debra Byrne, fell heavily on stage during a preview performance of the musical on Monday night. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A study, conducted by the Australian Association of Surgeons' Victorian branch in August and September, of 95 visiting medical officers has shown two-thirds of the State's public hospital visiting specialists have considered resigning - with one-third conidering it frequently. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
