<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133482" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong hopeful unveils glowing vision of future.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong hopeful unveils glowing vision of future.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A billionaire businessman vying to lead Hong Kong when the British depart next year mapped out a vision on Tuesday of a glowing future for a community proud to be Chinese.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we should be proud of being Chinese,&quot; shipping magnate Tung Chee-hwa told a Hong Kong Management Association dinner.</p>
<p>But Tung steered clear of many of the issues preoccupying the British colony with just 252 days to go before the territory returns to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>Long considered a frontrunner to be the territory's first Chief Executive, Tung formally declared his leadership intentions last Friday.</p>
<p>Tung stressed the need for strength to resist political pressure and also the need to be flexible.</p>
<p>&quot;What is the thing the Chief Executive needs to do? Protecting Hong Kong interests. Protecting Hong Kong interests,&quot; Tung said.</p>
<p>&quot;Compromise is not a weakness,&quot; he added in a message apparently aimed at both the Hong Kong democratic lobby and Beijing. &quot;The best way to resolve differences in the long-run is through compromise.&quot;</p>
<p>Tung also promised to work with the controversial provisional legislature China plans to establish to replace Hong Kong's elected chamber.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's vocal pro-democracy lobby and outgoing British administration are united in their opposition to China's plan to quash the existing legislature.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to China at midnight on June 30 next year under the terms of a 1984 Sino-British treaty in which the tiny territory of just six million people was promised it could maintain its freedoms and capitalist way of life intact.</p>
<p>Tung sidestepped the thorny issue of Chinese dissidents. &quot;You place too much emphasis on this question,&quot; he told reporters after the dinner address.</p>
<p>Hours before Tung stood up to deliver his policy platform, what had been a three-way race intensified when a former Appeal Court judge threw his hat into the ring.</p>
<p>Simon Li's entry into the leadership race broadens what had been a contest between two business titans and a top judge.</p>
<p>Tung heads one of Hong Kong's most prominent shipping empires, while businessman Peter Woo is the son-in-law of late shipping tsar Sir Y.K. Pao.</p>
<p>The Pao and Tung families have long been rivals in Hong Kong business circles.</p>
<p>The third candidate, outgoing Chief Justice Sir Ti Liang Yang, had, until Li joined the fray, been regarded as the compromise candidate free of business ties and alliances.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's first post-colonial leader will be selected by a 400-strong electoral college chosen in turn by a China-appointed committee and not returned by universal suffrage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
