<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133431" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Oct 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>The arts and entertainment industry has emerged as one of Australia's biggest sectors, with spending on the industry estimated at A$8.8 billion a year. Surpassing the sale of beer, household appliances and cosmetics, the arts industry has attracted a 29 percent increase in spending over the past five years. The results were released by the Australia Council. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>WMC Ltd has revealed it may reverse its decision to employ mining contractors at its Kambalda nickel mine, choosing instead to rehire a company-employed workforce. WMC nickel operations manager Mark Cutifani said the company's decision to take on contractlabour was necessary to ensure a 10 percent improvement in operating costs, and until this was achieved the employment arrangement would remain. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Hospital Care Ltd has bought the Allamanda private hospital on the Gold Coast as part of its expansion plans. The licensed 214-bed medical surgical hospital with an adjacent medical centre, cost the AHC A$57.2 million. AHC is hopeful the purchase will boost net profit and earnings per share during the first year of ownership. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Pasminco Ltd's A$40.8 million net profit for last financial year is under threat by a 5 cent surge in the value of the $A against the $US, with every 1 US cent rise in the $A/$US exchange rate cutting the profit by A$7.5 million. The company revealed that unless metal prices improve, the exchange rate movement could slash A$37.5 million from the bottom line. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Goodman Fielder Ltd finance director Les Cullen shocked the market on Tuesday by resigning, just seven months after joining the company. Page 19</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following years of lobbying by Australian Government agencies and mining houses, the Indian Government will now allow mining exploration over a maximum 5,000 sq km - an increase on the 25 sq km previously granted under old legislation. Page 21</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>MIM Holdings is reviewing long-term profitability plans at its McArthur River zinc-lead-silver mine in the Northern Territory following the prediction of a loss unless operational improvements occurred. A task force has been established to work on a plan to boost productivity at the A$250 million plant, which could fall even further if metal prices remain low. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Australian Securities Commission confirmed yesterday the Australian Stock Exchange had formally referred its concerns over delays to BHP's announcement of its exciting Buffalo 1 oil discovery in the Timor Sea to the ASC's enforcement section to assess whether BHP has breached the Corporations Law. Page 39.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an interview with The Australian yesterday, the chairman of the Wallis inquiry into the financial system, Stan Wallis, indicated he was willing to unleash major change on Australian financial services and criticised conservative forces within the industry, which he said must keep pace with a revolution in the international marketplace. Page 39.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to a substantial shareholder notice lodged by deposed Australian National Industries director Ross Palmer's Tube Securities yesterday, Palmer temporarily topped up his voting power in an unsuccessful attempt to drum up support ahead of the shareholder vote that removed him from the board yesterday. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>On the eve of preliminary price talks between coal producers and their Japanese customers, Nippon Steel Corp, and other leading Japanese coal buyers, yesterday delivered a stern warning to Australian producers to fix their industrial relations problems orrisk losing contracts. Page 39.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the surprise resignation of respected Goodman Fielder finance director Les Cullen, which was announced early yesterday, and amid rumours of resulting boardroom tensions, the international food group's shares slumped almost six percent yesterday closing at A$1.44. Page 41.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Amid widespread rumours the National Australia Bank is planning a takeover of Westpac Banking Corp Ltd once the Wallis inquiry concludes its report into the financial services system next March, Westpac shares shot up almost three per cent yesterday, with more than four million Westpac preference shares traded. Page 41.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Australian Gas Light managing director Len Bleasel told the annual general meeting yesterday the group is poised for further major expansion after signalling its interest in the A$300 million-plus of Australian gas assets owned by US energy group Tenneco Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the shock resignation of Les Cullen from Goodman Fielder after working for the giant food group for only seven months, coupled with comments from chief executive David Hearn that the group was no longer a takeover target, Goodman shares fell six percent yesterday. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The National Australia Bank has been ruled out as the mystery raider who outlayed almost A$130 million purchasing millions of Westpac Banking Corp's converting preference shares over the past two days through broker Bankers Trust - making the buyer's total ownership of converting preference shares 19 per cent. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Treasury's latest assessment of the economy, presented to a Senate estimates committee hearing on Monday evening, says the outlook for Australia's struggling manufacturing sector will remain bleak, with the prospects for growth characterised as 'subdued' and investment plans as 'modest'. Page 29</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an effort to ensure the public can only invest in the Ten Group through one listed vehicle, Telecasters North Queensland TNQ.AX is preparing a new proposal for a sharemarket listing of Ten, and it is believed the new vehicle will look at buying all Ten shares as they are offered for sale. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian National Industries dissident director Ross Palmer yesterday advised that companies under his control bought about 40 million ANI shares last week, spending A$50 million to lift his stake in the engineering group ahead of Monday's annual meeing which saw him ousted from the board. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>An unidentified buyer, who bought A$130 million worth of Westpac Banking Corp converting preference shares over the past two days was not the National Australia Bank, it has been revealed. After sparking intense speculation within the market, the buyer yeterday purchased another 4.1 million shares in a move which has the market believing Westpac may be a takeover target. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As part of an expansion drive which will see an injection of A$600 million over the next three years, Glorious Sun Enterprises of Hong Kong will treble the number of its JeansWest stores to 1000 in China and Australasia by the year 2000. With the bulk of he new stores being established in China, Glorious Sun will open 30 new stores in New Zealand and 21 in Australia. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>An Internet system designed exclusively for the business market will be in operation within six months with designers IBM, AT&amp;T, the Bell group and national telecom providers confident it will solve the problem of slowness with the existing system. Called 'Internet II', the new system will incorporate point-to-point encryption which would ease users about the risk of making financial transactions over the Internet. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New 'CD rewritable' technology, which will enable users to store 450 times as much data as a 3.5 inch floppy diskette, is due to bring recordable CD devices to the market early in 1996. The new technology, developed by five hi-tech giants including Phillis Electronics and Sony Corp, will also be compatible with CD-ROM readers and upcoming DVD-ROM drives. At a cost of below A$1260, the devices may eventually pressure other companies to produce similar equipment. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a submission to the Productivity Commission inquiry into the motor industry, Toyota Australia has requested the introduction of a goods and services tax. Toyota said the tax reform was necessary to boost the industry and would help avoid local markets losing out to cheaper imports. The company said the current sales tax system and the lack of mechanism to rebate taxes on business inputs led exports to be taxed much more severely than they would with a broad-based consumption tax. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian economy was moving towards another recession by the year 2002, according to BIS chief economist Frank Gelber. Gelber said the solution to the current account deficit was not to boost national savings, as the Federal Government believed. He said Australia's manufacturing sector needed to be expanded in order to match growing consumer needs with insufficient production. Gelber said the economy was becoming weak but may gain momentum by the end of the decade. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
