<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13343" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Single Euro govt bond mkt could boost role - BIS.</title>
<headline>Single Euro govt bond mkt could boost role - BIS.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The successful creation of an integrated European government bond market based on a single currency could make it rival that of the U.S. and Japan, the Bank for International Settlements (BIS) said.</p>
<p>A single European currency would change Europe's bond markets profoundly, but this could bring advantages to both borrowers and investors and possibly boost the stature of the European bond market, BIS said in its latest quarterly report on banking and financial markets.</p>
<p>&quot;In an integrated Euroepean government bond market, investors might be more willing to buy large quantities of bonds if they could sell them without encountering reduced liquidity and any associated increase in volatility,&quot; BIS said.</p>
<p>Prospective interest savings through higher liquidity could encourage cooperative debt management and governments could auction issues jointly with identical coupons and maturities.</p>
<p>Governments could also match each others' coupons and maturities, in effect reopening each others' issues.</p>
<p>&quot;Were the similarities to prove sufficiently strong that the bonds were covered by a single set of exchange-traded futures contracts, then Europe's main bond market would join those of the United States and Japan in terms of size and liquidity,&quot; BIS said.</p>
<p>While the exchange and inflation risks would not distinguish between government bonds within a single currency Europe, markets would still distinguish between the creditworthiness of various governments, much like markets price provincial or state debt in federal systems, BIS said.</p>
<p>Another possibility is that the bonds of some or all of the governments participating in Europe's monetary union could trade interchangeably.</p>
<p>Markets are already allocating very slight differences to the credit ratings, single market bond yield spreads and swap spreads between the countries that are seen as likely candidates for early entry to EMU in 1999, according to a poll of market participants taken in January 1996, BIS said.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
