<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133421" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- SOME FACTORS COMPLICATE SCENARIOS FOR 1997</p>
<p>Two months before the end of the year, as economists begin to lay out scenarios for the new year, two factors have complicated the outlook for 1997: a deteriorating trade balance and the government's continued inability to straighten out the fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>-- COMMODITIES BREAK NEW RECORD ON THE BM&amp;F</p>
<p>The number of farm contracts negotiated in the Sao Paulo Futures and Commodities Exchange (BM&amp;F) have jumped to 240,000 or $2.4 billion this year against 120,000 or $1.6 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>-- WALLENBERG: SAO PAULO IS EXPENSIVE</p>
<p>On a brief visit to Brazil Peter Wallenberg, the head of Swedish holding Investor AB, said he was shocked with prices in the Sao Paulo metropolitan area. Wallenberg, who met with President Fernando Henrique Cardoso on Monday, said Sao Paulo was losing competitiveness compared to the North and South of the country. He also complained about the traffic in the city, which he said consumed enormous amounts of time and effort.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- MORTGAGE PAYMENTS WILL NOT EXCEED 40 PERCENT OF INCOME</p>
<p>State bank Caixa Economica Federal will renegotiate mortgage contracts with middle class families and guarantee they do not exceed 40 percent of income.</p>
<p>-- BEGGARS LAND IN COURT IN BRASILIA</p>
<p>A man and wife, who forced their four children to ask for money on the streets of Brasilia, are being charged with child abuse by a Brasilia court.</p>
<p>- - - FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- CARDOSO SEEKS SPECIAL PRIVILEGES FOR LAWMAKERS</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso is seeking to negotiate special terms that will allow lawmakers to earn over and above a 10.800 reais income ceiling set for all state employees.</p>
<p>-- HUMAN RIGHTS ACTIVIST IS MURDERED</p>
<p>Francisco Gilson Nogueira de Carvalho, a 32 year-old lawyer who was investigating a group of policemen suspected of being involved in a massacre in northern Brazil, was shot dead by unidentified gunmen on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Adrian Dickson, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
