<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133458" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-ConsFoods in issue to ABR.</title>
<headline>RTRS-ConsFoods in issue to ABR.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consolidated Foods Australia Ltd (CFA) said it will issue 20 million shares at A$0.40 each to Singapore-listed food group ABR Holdings Ltd to raise A$8 million.</p>
<p>The placement shares represent 35.7 percent of CFA's existing shares and 26.3 percent of its expanded capital of 76.07 million shares after completion of the placement, it said.</p>
<p>Funds from the proposed placement will be used to reduce CFA's borrowings and strengthen its working capital base, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The board of CFA believes the proposed placement to ABR will assist the company in its endeavours to expand its business into Asia and accordingly, has the full support of the CFA board,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The placement is subject to CFA shareholder approval, Australian Foreign Investment Review Board approval and the necessary approvals required by ABR, it said.</p>
<p>In addition to the placement, the existing major shareholder of CFA, Greater Pacific Foods Pty Ltd and its associates, have agreed to sell 5.0 million shares in CFA on market to ABR at a price of $0.40 each, CFA said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The combination of the purchase of shares from Greater Pacific Foods and the proposed placement will allow ABR to have a substantial and meaningful role in the expansion of CFA's products and brands in Asia and should be viewed as a very positive step for all CFA shareholders,&quot; CFA said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
