<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133457" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Talks continue as final NZ vote count awaited.</title>
<headline>Talks continue as final NZ vote count awaited.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The second phase of coalition negotiations was due to begin later on Wednesday morning, as MPs on small majorities anxiously awaited the outcome of special vote counting which could overturn close election night results.</p>
<p>Labour's team meets New Zealand First for the first time, for preliminary talks expected to focus on procedure for substantive negotiations and the confidentiality agreement that NZ First leader Winston Peters is seeking.</p>
<p>National and NZ First, who first met on Monday, are due to hold their second session on Wednesday afternoon.  </p>
<p>The New Zealand Press Association reported that National MPs were told on Tuesday they would not be given regular briefings on the progress of the talks because they were too secret.</p>
<p>NZPA sources said the MPs were told at a caucus meeting confidentiality had to be maintained so that the true picture was not distorted and the talks were not jeopardised by unauthorised comments.</p>
<p>NZ First also held a caucus meeting, but its MPs were given only a cursory briefing on the talks.</p>
<p>Special vote counting began just after 7pm on Tuesday but by midnight only seven electorate results had been announced.  </p>
<p>There were no surprises, and cabinet minister John Banks kept his seat with a majority increased from 196 on election night to 383 on the final result.</p>
<p>More final results were expected to be announced from about 10am on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The closest election night majority was in Waipareira where National's Brian Neeson held a 141 majority over Labour's Chris Carter.</p>
<p>National is hoping for a boost in its party vote total which could give it an extra seat in Parliament, taking it from 44 to 45.  </p>
<p>The party is closer than others to improving its percentage to the point where the actual numbers change. If it gets enough extra party votes to gain one more seat, Labour is likely to lose one when the percentages are redistributed.</p>
<p>That would change the balance in Parliament, giving National, Act and United a total of 54 seats against a Labour-NZ First total of 53.</p>
<p>Should that situation occur, a Labour-NZ First coalition would depend even more on the Alliance to hold a majority.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
