<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133410" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil '99 oil output seen at 1.3 mln bpd.</title>
<headline>Brazil '99 oil output seen at 1.3 mln bpd.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government is aiming for domestic oil output of 1.3 million barrels per day (bpd) by the year 1999 and natural gas production of 42.9 million cubic metres a day, a senior official said.</p>
<p>Giovanni Toniatti, secretary of mines and minerals at the Mines and Energy Ministry, told a seminar the government was also seeking $4.0 billion in research investment and $31 billion in production investment to raise mineral production.  </p>
<p>Toniatti said the aim was to raise Brazil's annual minerals output to $17.6 billion from $6.9 billion now.</p>
<p>&quot;In Brazil we are living through profound changes in the minerals sector, aiming to make its activities more dynamic and increase its contribution to the economic and social development of the country,&quot; he told the seminar in Brasilia.</p>
<p>Toniatti also said the government aimed to attract private capital into refining to lift domestic refinery capacity to 2.0 million bpd by 1999.  </p>
<p>He added in an interview with Reuters that the ministry's intention was to increase Brazil's self-sufficiency in oil to 70 percent by the year 2000 from 56 percent currently.</p>
<p>Toniatti was speaking at a seminar on the international oil and minerals sectors, attended by executives and academics from Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>He said Brazil had identified 29 sedimentary basins coverin an area of 5.7 million square km, of which 4.0 million square km were on land and the rest offshore.  </p>
<p>He said that oil and gas had been discovered in only eight of the basins and that 80 percent of money invested in exploration was concentrated in those areas.</p>
<p>&quot;The rudimentary stage of exploration in the rest is an indication of how necessary it is to intensify geological surveys, which could result in the discovery of new petroleum sources&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brazil has opened up the petroleum and mining sectors to private capital but legislation for the oil industry regulation remain unformulated, still awaiting a parliamentary vote.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
