<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133460" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-MIM sees new mine copper cost 55c/lb.</title>
<headline>RTRS-MIM sees new mine copper cost 55c/lb.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>MIM Holdings Ltd chief executive Nick Stump said he estimated cash costs at its planned new copper mine, the Enterprise Mine, in Queensland would be around US$0.55 per pound of copper.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident of the Enterprise Mine being 55 (U.S.) cents copper cash cost and at around 75 (U.S.) cents exchange rate (to one Australian dolar),&quot; Stump said at a briefing held by the Securities Insitute of Australia (SIA).</p>
<p>In June, MIM unveiled plans to spend A$500 million building the Enterprise mine and expanding its copper smelter at its Mount Isa Mines operation in northwest Queensland.  </p>
<p>&quot;Other parts of the underground ore body (at Mount Isa) would be higher then that, so we are really setting ourselves a target,&quot; Stump said.</p>
<p>Stump said he expected the copper to trade over 90 U.S. cents per pound over the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;While we can see that the granting of puts (options) will keep the price in excess of 90 cents in the short term, there is going to pricing pressure as we come out of that short term in the next six months,&quot; Stump said.</p>
<p>He said copper consumption was still strong, but new production coming on stream would put prices under pressure.  </p>
<p>&quot;The way that East Asia and Latin America is developing, people are improving their standard of living. We are seeing a huge consumption push ... we would expect (copper) consumption to have strong growth for the rest of the century and beyond,&quot; Stump said.</p>
<p>&quot;But against that there is new production coming on.&quot;</p>
<p>MIM plans to open copper/gold mines in Australia in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>Stump this scenario meant a tough outlook for the mining and smelting group. &quot;We accept that things are going to be tougher, so we will have to push harder,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In terms of turning around the company, I can't think of a better time to have that pressure on us, as it means we will have to run faster,&quot; said Stump, who took over the helm in April 1995.</p>
<p>MIM has raised about A$1.4 billion from the sale of non-core assets over the past few years.</p>
<p>MIM reported a net profit after abnormals of A$170.6 million in the 53 weeks to June 30, 1996, compared with a loss of A$216.10 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>MIM shares closed three cents lower at A$1.69.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
