<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133432" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES - Today in History - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES - Today in History - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>--BIRTHDAYS--</p>
<p>French encyclopaedist PIERRE LAROUSSE was born in 1817.</p>
<p>English poet, playwright and prose writer, ROBERT BRIDGES, was born in 1844. He was a physician in London for 13 years before becoming Poet Laureate in 1913.</p>
<p>American entertainer and leading chat show host, JOHNNY CARSON, was born in 1925.</p>
<p>British actress and post-war sex-symbol, DIANA DORS, was born in 1931. Her films include &quot;Yield to the Night&quot; and &quot;There's a Girl in my Soup&quot;.</p>
<p>Brazilian football player PELE was born in 1940. He began playing soccer internatioanlly at the age of 16 and scored more than one thousand goals during his long professional career.</p>
<p>British guitarist with 'Motorhead' WURZEL (MICHAEL BURSTON) was born in 1949.</p>
<p>United States country singer and songwriter DWIGHT YOAKAM was born in 1956. In 1985 he made his first record and has been in the country charts since 1986. His hits include &quot;Streets of Bakersfield&quot; (1988) and &quot;I Sang Dixie&quot; (1988).</p>
<p>			     --EVENTS--</p>
<p>    42 BC :    MARCUS JUNIUS BRUTUS, a leader in the plot to</p>
<p>assassinate JULIUS CAESAR, committed suicide when his republican cause was lost and he was heavily defeated in the battle of Philippi by ANTONY and OCTAVIAN.</p>
<p>    1366 :    A meteor shower passed over Europe raining small</p>
<p>pieces of meteorites over a wide area.</p>
<p>    1874 :    A severe cyclone in the Bay of Bengal took 2000</p>
<p>lives at Midnapore.</p>
<p>    1915 :    The great English cricketer W.G. GRACE died.</p>
<p>    1921 :    Scottish veterinary surgeon JOHN BOYD DUNLOP, who</p>
<p>invented the pneumatic bicycle tyre, died.</p>
<p>    1926 :    LEON TROTSKY was expelled from the Communist</p>
<p>Party.</p>
<p>    1942 :    British and Commonwealth forces led by General</p>
<p>BERNARD MONTGOMERY launched a huge offensive against German and Italian forces under ROMMEL at El Alamein, Egypt.</p>
<p>    1954 :    Britain, the United States, France and the Soviet</p>
<p>Union agreed to end the occupation of Germany and allow West Germany to enter NATO.</p>
<p>    1956 :    The Hungarian national uprising against Soviet</p>
<p>occupation began with students and workers demonstrating in Budapest.</p>
<p>    1970 :    American dare-devil GARY GAVELICH broke the world</p>
<p>land speed record in his rocket-propelled car &quot;Blue Flame&quot; on the Utah Salt Flats. He was clocked at approximately 1010 kilometres an hour.</p>
<p>    1974 :    Moscow was selected as the site for the 1980</p>
<p>Olympics.</p>
<p>    1976 :    South-eastern Australia experienced a total</p>
<p>eclipse of the sun.</p>
<p>    1987 :    Former champion jockey LESTER PIGGOTT was jailed</p>
<p>for three years after being found guilty of tax evasion. The British champion was one of the few jockeys to make a successful transition to race horse training. After more than 4000 wins as a jockey and winning the jockeys' championship 11 times he reportedly he had amassed a fortune of almost 40 million dollars. He was found guilty of evading almost 6 million dollars in tax.</p>
<p>    1989 :    The Lebanese parliament agreed to distribute power</p>
<p>equally between Muslims and Christians.</p>
<p>    1991 :    Legalised &quot;sexual slavery&quot; ended for wives in</p>
<p>Britain. A husband's immunity from being charged with rape was removed from British law. The decision upheld a Court of Appeal ruling that the marital exemption from prosecution was an &quot;anachronistic and offensive fiction&quot;.   &quot;Women Against Rape&quot;,</p>
<p>the pressure group that campaigned for law reform, welcomed the decision saying it overturned 250 years of sexual servitude by British wives.</p>
<p>    1994 :    The New South Wales Government offered a reward of</p>
<p>A$250,000 for information leading to the conviction of those responsible for the murder of Cabramatta MP JOHN NEWMAN.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS.)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
