<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133464" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Oriental Land Co, the operator of Tokyo Disneyland, plans to list its shares on the second section of the Tokyo Stock Exchange in early December. It hopes to issue around 15 million to 18 million new shares and sell around six to eight million existing shares. Oriental may see a capital infusion surpassing the record 172.3 billion yen raised by Japan Telecom Co Ltd when it listed on the second section in September 1994.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Shin-Etsu Chemical Co Ltd plans to build a vinyl chloride resin plant in the United States. It hopes to start plant construction later this month through its U.S. subsidiary Shintech Inc. It is expected to invest about $700 million and hopes to start operations in mid-1998.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Machine tool manufacturers are taking steps to shrink the gap between suggested and actual selling prices by introducing an open price system. Medium-sized machine tool maker Enshu Ltd plans to cut prices by about 20 percent on some models except new products from late October. Citizen Watch Co Ltd also plans to increase the number of machine tools on which it offers no discount.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Star Micronics Co Ltd, a leading electronic printer maker, plans to transfer production of about 30 percent of its machine tools, such as some automatic lathes, to its subsidiary in China. It hopes to start production from autumn 1997 and to export about 300 units annually to Japan.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Oil Co Ltd hopes to cut about 100 management staff by December under its early retirement programme, due to a sharp decline in the oil and gas prices.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Oji Paper Co plans to invest 3.2 billion yen to boost production of adhesive papers as part of its plan to gain a larger share of the growing market. It hopes to start operations in 1997.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Daiei Inc plans to launch Japan's largest supermarket in Osaka, with a size of about 30,000 sq meters. It hopes to start operations in April 1999.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Nippon Steel Semiconductor Corp a semiconductor maker and group company of Nippon Steel Corp, plans to boost production of 64-megabit dynamic random-access memory chips in late 1998. The Nippon Steel unit plans initial investment of 10 billion to 15 billion yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
