<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133497" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China envoy tells HK don't agitate for dissidents.</title>
<headline>China envoy tells HK don't agitate for dissidents.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Beijing envoy warned Hong Kong activists on Tuesday against campaigning for the release of Chinese dissidents on the grounds they were interfering in China's internal legal affairs.</p>
<p>The warning came as Hong Kong television broadcast a tearful telephone conversation between a Chinese dissident who escaped through the British colony to the United States, and his wife left behind in China.</p>
<p>Zhang Junsheng, a deputy director of the Xinhua news agency which serves as Beijing's unofficial diplomatic mission in Hong Kong, delivered the warning two days after hundreds took to Hong Kong's streets demanding China release dissident Wang Dan.</p>
<p>Wang Dan was one of the student leaders of the pro-democracy movement which was crushed by Beijing's military in June, 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;If you keep on using public opinion or organising protest demonstrations, this is interfering in China's judicial process and is not permitted,&quot; Zhang told Hong Kong reporters.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is due to revert to Chinese sovereignty on July 1, 1997.</p>
<p>Wang, 26, was accused of the capital charge of plotting to overthrow the government.</p>
<p>His trial is expected soon and his family members have said they are bracing themselves for a heavy sentence.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's ATV television station broadcast a brief and emotional telephone conversation between dissident Wang Xizhe, who fled to the United States, and his wife Su Jiang, from her home in the southern Chinese city of Guangzhou.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very sad,&quot; Su said through her tears after reciting her husband's favourite poem.</p>
<p>She told him his ageing parents missed him terribly and she had been too overcome with grief even to touch his personal belongings.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't cry. What had to be done has been done,&quot; Wang chided.</p>
<p>&quot;That's rather easy for you to say. You are on the outside. You can find some new things to do to pass the time. But for myself, I will have to wait, all alone, for maybe more than 10 years,&quot; his wife replied.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
