<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133463" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-INTERVIEW-Queensland Cotton goes transgenic.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INTERVIEW-Queensland Cotton goes transgenic.</headline>
<byline>Graeme James</byline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's biggest ginner and marketer of cotton, Queensland Cotton Holdings Ltd, expects to have up to 90 percent of its next season's planting comprising new pest-resistent transgenic cotton seed, the group's chief executive, Richard Haire said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;About 10 percent of our 1997 crop will be transgenic but next season up to 90 percent of our crop will comprise transgenic seed,&quot; Haire told Reuters in an interview.  </p>
<p>The new crop seed will go a long way towards solving the industry's long-standing problems of having to spray crops to combat cotton moth pest, a practice which has alienated many farmers who are adjacent to cotton fields.</p>
<p>&quot;The cotton industry in Australia has also been worried about the problem for many years as well as farmers,&quot; Haire said.</p>
<p>He said the 1997 season would see record Australian production of between 2.4 million and 2.5 million bales, compared with last year's national production of 1.9 million.  </p>
<p>The major increase was expected to come from New South Wales because of abundant water supply which would offset flat Queensland production where the water supply has been &quot;pretty volatile,&quot; Haire said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm pretty confident we have the marketing system which can successfully sell this season's record production,&quot; Haire said.</p>
<p>This was despite a world outlook for cotton which was currently looking a bit soft, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumption of cotton is not growing, mainly because of the high prices seen over the last two seasons. There is buyer resistance out there,&quot; Haire said.  </p>
<p>&quot;China production is down a bit and the United States market is mixed with exports down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>However global demand for cotton would remain strong because of the fibre's premier position in manufacturing, Haire said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Queensland Cotton was continuing to look for new markets, having already expanded in Asia, particularly Indonesia and Malaysia, Haire said.</p>
<p>The group was also on the lookout for acquisition opportunities despite this year's failed merger attempt by Queensland Cotton and Namoi Cotton Co-operative.  </p>
<p>There was still potential for rationalisation and expansion in the Australian cotton industry, Haire said.</p>
<p>Queensland Cotton was also looking at overseas acquisition opportunities, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are always interested. Overseas acquisitions are always an option for us in growing the business, but currently it's only an option,&quot; Haire said.</p>
<p>Queensland Cotton reported a net profit of A$8.03 million for the year to February 29, up from A$6.28 million a year earlier.  </p>
<p>For the six months to August 31, net profit was A$10.55 million on sales of A$268.31 million.</p>
<p>Sales for the full year to February were A$281.52 million.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100138">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
