<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133472" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crudes steady to weaker, Oman premium rises.</title>
<headline>Asian crudes steady to weaker, Oman premium rises.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia were steady to weaker on Tuesday, while premiums for Oman crude firmed.</p>
<p>Traders said Oman crude traded at MPM plus 10 cents per barrel -- but the trade could not immediately be confirmed.</p>
<p>One major, who was cited buying at MPM plus 10 cents, denied the deal.</p>
<p>However, traders involved in the Oman market said plus 10 was done amid a flurry of six or seven Oman deals.</p>
<p>One traditional seller of Oman was a noted buyer of the market.  </p>
<p>Most players expected Oman to remain firm, with two majors, a state oil company and the Bangchak refinery, which has tendered for December barrels, seen as buyers. Arbitrage into Europe and South Africa was still possible, one major said, valuing Oman at MPM plus 10 bid and plus 12 offered.</p>
<p>Late afternoon on Tuesday, futures prices were weakening.</p>
<p>December Brent fell as much as 22 cents to $24.42 per barrel from a day earlier.</p>
<p>Brokers cited the use of a Colonial Pipeline gasoline pipeline to run distillates, warmer weather in parts of Europe and the U.S. northeast, as taking the froth off the bull run.  </p>
<p>In the paper market, November Tapis fell to $25.05/$25.35 compared with a day-earlier bid of $25.35. That tempered the assessed rise in Tapis values -- which have been at five-year highs in recent weeks. Traders said the Tapis margin for middle distillates were not economical currently because products have failed to keep pace with the Malaysian crude.</p>
<p>Regional grades were quiet with Minas assessed at a premium of 25/35 cents and the last deals done at plus 29 cents and plus 30 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>--Singapore, N. Fullick (+65 870 3081), Tokyo, Miho Yoshikawa (+813-5473 3706)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
