<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13340" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Veba chief urges joint German telecoms network.</title>
<headline>Veba chief urges joint German telecoms network.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of private utilities group VEBA AG urged rivals in the German telecommunications industry to form a joint communications network to rival that of the monopoly holder Deutsche Telekom.</p>
<p>In an interview with Germany's Focus magazine, VEBA chairman Ulrich Hartmann said individual companies were placing too much emphasis on setting up their own networks and risked creating excess capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;Not even Telekom's network is used to capacity. Spending too much on networks now will create difficulties later...If competitors were smarter, they would build a joint, comprehensive alternative network,&quot; Hartmann said.</p>
<p>A copy of the interview was made avilable in advance of publication on Monday.</p>
<p>A host of firms are competing for a slice of the German telecoms market -- expected to be worth some 100 billion marks by the year 2000 --  as the state-owned Deutsche Telekom prepares to go public in November.</p>
<p>Hartmann said he planned to invest at least six billion marks in the long term in Vebacom, VEBA's own telecoms unit which is jointly held by Cable &amp; Wireless Plc.</p>
<p>He said Vebacom should eventually have annual sales of eight billion marks. In ten years, staff at the unit would increase to 10,000 from the current 1,600.</p>
<p>Vebacom remains a potential partner for the telecoms activities of engineering firm Mannesmann AG, which last month took a major stake in DBKom GmbH, the communications subsidiary of the German railway.</p>
<p>DBKom's 40,000 km communications network, while in need of some repair, is Germany's largest after Telekom.</p>
<p>&quot;We are open to all partners that can make a substantial contribution,&quot; Peter Mihatsch, Mannesmann board member and head of DBKom, said of Vebacom in a separate Focus interview.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
