<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133428" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: FEATURE - Venezuelan hunt for El Dorado blocked by bureaucracy.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Venezuelan hunt for El Dorado blocked by bureaucracy.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS, Venezuela 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>When 16th century European explorers came to Venezuela in search of the mythical golden city of El Dorado, they encountered impenetrable jungles, deadly diseases and hostile natives.</p>
<p>Four hundred years later, mining companies on a similar quest have to cope with complex legislation, land invasions and hostile government policies, mining executives say.</p>
<p>Even a recent decision by Canadian mining giant Placer Dome to develop a $576 million project to build one of the Western hemisphere's largest gold mines is seen as going ahead in spite of the government, not thanks to it.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good news-bad news,&quot; said one mining executive who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>While the Las Cristinas project -- of which Placer owns 70 percent and the state-owned Corporacion Venezolana de Guyana 30 percent -- is by far the biggest mining development in Venezuela in five years, many fear it could be taken as an endorsement of the government's mining policy.</p>
<p>RAPID DECLINE IN GOLD COMPANIES</p>
<p>The number of gold companies in Venezuela has plummeted from more than 70 three years ago to less than 20, said Courtney Neeb, head of the gold section at the Venezuelan Mining Chamber. Of those working now, only eight are actively exploring and just four have mines operating, all in southeasterly Bolivar state.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a war of attrition, but that can be reversed with the right policies,&quot; Neeb said.</p>
<p>Apart from Las Cristinas, which will not go into production until late 1998, Venezuela's other main mining projects are state bauxite mining company Bauxilum's Pijiguanos mine and state-owned Ferrominera de Orinoco's iron ore properties.</p>
<p>Minorco's AMSA unit is looking for financing for its $400 million Loma de Nickel nickel mine, which could produce 1.2 million dry tons of ore a year and Royal Dutch/Shell, Ruhrkohle AG and state-owned Carbozulia are in the early stages of a $1 billion project to convert the Paso del Diablo coal mine into an 18 million tons a year venture.</p>
<p>Venezuela will produce about nine tons of gold this year -- puny by world standards and unchanged for nearly a decade.</p>
<p>VENEZUELA COULD BECOME TOP GOLD PRODUCER WITHIN DECADE</p>
<p>Government officials have said the country could become a top 10 gold producer within the next decade, a target mining executives agree is well within Venezuela's grasp.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential in Venezuela's mining sector is phenomenal,&quot; said Brooke Macdonald, president of Placer Dome de Venezuela.</p>
<p>According to Neeb &quot;Venezuela could have about 20 world class gold mine projects.&quot; These mines would bring in about $4 billion in investment and produce about 120 tons per year in about 10 or 15 years, he said.</p>
<p>But in the two-and-a-half years since President Rafael Caldera came to power, &quot;the government has granted virtually no mining concessions,&quot; said Jorge Neher, CAMIVEN's legal adviser.</p>
<p>While approximately 40 percent of total mining investment (about $800 million) is coming to Latin America each year, &quot;we are lucky if we account for $25 million per year,&quot; said Neeb.</p>
<p>These figures stand in stark contrast to Venezuela's oil sector, which goes from strength to strength.</p>
<p>State oil company Petroleos de Venezuela in 20 years has export revenues of more than $16 billion a year. A recent push to open the oil sector to private investment is attracting billions of dollars of interest from the industry's top players.</p>
<p>SUCCESS WITH OIL HAS DISTORTED POLICY ON MINING</p>
<p>Such success with oil has distorted government policy toward the mining sector, mining executives say.</p>
<p>&quot;They have got totally confused in their minds the opening up of the oil sector and that of the mining sector,&quot; said Stephen Goss, head of Crystallex de Venezuela, which operates one small mine.</p>
<p>After 70 years of exploration, Venezuela's petroleum geology is well known and reliable, whereas &quot;with the mining sector, you are looking at a real green field,&quot; Goss said.</p>
<p>Even before the recent freeze on new concessions, applications were taking up to eight years to process.</p>
<p>&quot;At one point, we were talking about having to complete about 170 steps for a concession to be issued,&quot; said Neeb. This turnover is far too slow in an industry where less than one in every 10 exploration projects become mines, he added.</p>
<p>Such legislative battles, combined with foreign exchange controls and an obligation to sell 40 percent of gold produced to the Central Bank, raise serious doubts as to whether the flagship Las Cristinas project would go ahead.</p>
<p>Sheer force of numbers and the continual search for new sites have seen increasing clashes between small independent miners and the multinationals in recent years.</p>
<p>In July 1995, the area around the small mining town of El Dorado was militarized after looting by miners who had been evicted from a multinational gold company's concession.</p>
<p>One mining executive recounted how a mob stole company equipment even as the company tried to rescue workers believed to be buried under a mudslide after illegally entering the mine in the middle of the night.</p>
<p>Placer has found its own solution. It employs sociologists and consulting firms to develop a working relationship with the thousands of people forced off the Las Cristinas site when Placer and the CVG acquired it in 1991. Placer has spent $400,000 in building and improving services in the local area, Macdonald said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you keep them out simply by calling the National Guard, pretty soon it breaks down,&quot; he said. &quot;You have to work with them.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS, Venezuela"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
