<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133423" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Ortega casts cloud over Nicaragua, hints at fraud.</title>
<headline>Ortega casts cloud over Nicaragua, hints at fraud.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hinting at fraud, left-wing Sandinista leader Daniel Ortega has cast a cloud over Nicaragua's elections, demanding a review of results that showed right-winger Arnoldo Aleman headed for a strong victory.</p>
<p>In a challenge that reflected the bitter, antagonistic contest between the forces of Nicaragua's left and right, Ortega on Monday said &quot;fraudulent attitudes&quot; may have cost him a shot at returning to power, and he refused to accept the results of Sunday's vote.</p>
<p>&quot;We found serious irregularities,&quot; he told a news conference in which he had been expected to concede defeat.</p>
<p>As his supporters shouted &quot;Fraud! Fraud!,&quot; Ortega added: &quot;There were alterations in telegrams (of vote results) that were sent in from the departments that meant that many of those telegrams did not precisely reflect the number of votes that the (Sandinista) Front achieved.&quot;</p>
<p>He called on Nicaragua's electoral authorities to double-check the count, and authorities indicated they were willing to do so once the preliminary vote count, expected to end on Tuesday, was wrapped up.</p>
<p>With just over half the votes tallied, Aleman led Ortega by 48.54 percent to 38.96 percent -- well clear of the 45 percent hurdle the victor needs to avoid a second-round runoff.</p>
<p>Ortega's protests failed to visibly disrupt the victory party, however, at the Liberal Alliance headquarters of Aleman.</p>
<p>Like thousands of election observers, Aleman's supporters saw little wrong with the vote. Considering their victory a triumph of the populist right, Aleman's working class voters danced to brass bands until well into Monday night.</p>
<p>Aleman, in his first reaction to Ortega's charge, played it down, saying he hoped the Sandinistas would end up backing him. &quot;I hope that Commander Ortega has matured,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the Sandinistas have accused Aleman of being backed by supporters of Anastasio Somoza, the dictator they ousted in 1979. They are not likely to be easily wooed.</p>
<p>Ortega, a former revolutionary who admits he made mistakes as Nicaragua's Marxist president, says he is a different man now than he was back then, and noted that in 1990 when he lost power at the ballot box, he gave it up graciously.</p>
<p>His own supporters were angry, however, and demanded that the vote be annulled. Their leader's charge raised fears of a backlash by the Sandinista's still-mighty grassroots networks.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask that these elections be annulled because they are a mess,&quot; weeping Ortega supporter Ana Correa said on local television.</p>
<p>The first victim of the standoff was the hope for a quick national reconciliation, a key campaign pledge of both candidates that is considered crucial in stopping a slide back to the ideological conflicts of Nicaragua's past.</p>
<p>It was never given much chance of a long life, taking into account Nicaragua's long history of political violence and polarisation.</p>
<p>Each side demonised the other during the campaign, the Sandinistas playing up Aleman's links to the oppressive Somoza dynasty, and Aleman smearing Ortega as a closet Marxist thinly disguised as a social democrat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
