<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133434" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>JOBS COMMITTEE WELCOMED</p>
<p>The Australian Chamber of Manufactures says there's a desperate</p>
<p>need to stimulate economic activity and growth demands before any</p>
<p>turnaround in employment happens.</p>
<p>The latest Chamber survey has revealed a sixth consecutive</p>
<p>quarterly fall in employment, with a few slight signs of</p>
<p>improvement.</p>
<p>The Chamber's Alan Handberg, says without more robust activity,</p>
<p>there's no need for additional staff, and employers simply can't</p>
<p>afford to create positions.</p>
<p>However, both the business and manufacturing sectors have welcomed</p>
<p>the decision by Federal Cabinet to create a new Employment</p>
<p>Committee.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WATERHOUSE SUSPENSION OVERTURNED</p>
<p>Flamboyant trainer Gai Waterhouse can now concentrate all her</p>
<p>energy on this year's Spring Racing Carnival.</p>
<p>This follows today's ruling by the Australian Jockey Club to uphold</p>
<p>Mrs Waterhouse's appeal against a three month suspension.</p>
<p>The trainer and jockey Kevin Forrester were outed for three months</p>
<p>after an inquiry into the performance of Gossips in last month's</p>
<p>Shannon Quality.</p>
<p>The AJC today overturned the suspension against Mrs Waterhouse, and</p>
<p>reduced Forrester's suspension to two months.</p>
<p>Waterhouse will enter a strong contingent over the Spring Carnival,</p>
<p>including the short priced pre-post favourite for Saturday's Cox</p>
<p>Plate, Juggler.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BLACKHAWK INQUIRY HEARS MORE EVIDENCE</p>
<p>A Military board of inquiry into the Blackhawk collision in June</p>
<p>has heard a lack of flying frequency, due to maintenance problems</p>
<p>of one of the helicopters, contributed to the crash.</p>
<p>The collision between two helicopters near Townsville claimed the</p>
<p>lives of 18 soldiers.</p>
<p>Captain Scott Benbo, a co-pilot of the fifth blackhawk, told the</p>
<p>Inquiry he believed his aircraft was too far left of the target</p>
<p>during the counter-terrorism exercise.</p>
<p>Similar evidence has been given by the air crew of blackhawk three,</p>
<p>who also thought they were off track.</p>
<p>Captain Benbo said the lack of flying recently led to inexperienced</p>
<p>pilots.</p>
<p>He said experienced pilots were posted out, and there was a lack of</p>
<p>training.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>POSSIBLE APPEAL OVER SWEARING POLICEMAN RULING</p>
<p>New South Wales Police Commissioner Peter Ryan is considering a</p>
<p>High Court appeal over yesterday's decision to dismiss an offensive</p>
<p>language charge against a swearing policeman.</p>
<p>The Court of Appeal upheld the controversial Police Tribunal</p>
<p>decision, although it heard the officer habitually used the &quot;F&quot;</p>
<p>word in the workplace.</p>
<p>Police Minister, Paul Whelan, has told Parliament Commissioner Ryan</p>
<p>is very disappointed by the ruling, and is seeking legal advice on</p>
<p>a High Court appeal.</p>
<p>Mr Whelan says if the decision goes unchallenged, it will make</p>
<p>police stations unacceptable work places.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ENTRIES VYING FOR SOLAR CAR HONOURS</p>
<p>Mexican and British entries in Sunday's World Solar Challenge are</p>
<p>both feeling confident about their chances of completing the nine</p>
<p>day race.</p>
<p>Entrants in the 3-thousand kilometre race will travel from Darwin</p>
<p>to Adelaide under the steam of solar power.</p>
<p>Mexican team leader Daniel Amador says his team comprises 12 people</p>
<p>from seven universities in Mexico City and a quarter-million-dollar</p>
<p>car.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the owner of a private British entry has one of the more</p>
<p>unusually built cars.</p>
<p>Brian Hampton says the solar panel worth eight thousand dollars is</p>
<p>the most expensive item on his car...the rest of the vehicle is</p>
<p>made from scrap.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>INTERNATIONAL CUP HOPE ARRIVES</p>
<p>With only two weeks to the race that stops the nation, two of the</p>
<p>expected stars of the Melbourne Cup are due to in town tonight.</p>
<p>Two of the most important guests of this year's VRC Spring Racing</p>
<p>Carnival, Oscar Schindler and Court of Honour will arrive from the</p>
<p>United Kingdom to begin their mandatory quarantine period.</p>
<p>The VRC's Racing Manager, Les Benton, says all plans are in place</p>
<p>to ensure a smooth transition for both horses when they arrive at</p>
<p>Sandown.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOREA TO GIVE A$200,000 TO WAR MEMORIAL</p>
<p>The Korean Ambassador to Australia, Byong Hyong Kwan, has announced</p>
<p>the South Korean Government will give 200-thousand dollars to the</p>
<p>Korean War Memorial in Canberra.</p>
<p>Mr Kwan says the money is being budgetted for in the next South</p>
<p>Korean budget.</p>
<p>He says the money was pledged by South Korean President Kim, when</p>
<p>he made a State visit to Australia in 1994.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HOWARD DISAPPOINTED BY UN FAILURE</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard says while he's disappointed at</p>
<p>Australia's failure to gain a seat on the United Nations Security</p>
<p>Council, it's too early to try to extrapolate the reasons.</p>
<p>The two, non-permanent seats went to Sweden and Portugal.</p>
<p>Mr Howard says it won't alter the Government's commitment to the</p>
<p>U-N, and is confident that the Government couldn't have done more.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CALLS FOR GOVERNMENT RETHINK ON PUBLIC SECTOR</p>
<p>ACTU President Jennie George says the establishment of a Cabinet</p>
<p>Jobs Committee signals an admission of failure by the Federal</p>
<p>Government.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister yesterday announced the new employment committee</p>
<p>aimed at creating jobs and improving market confidence.</p>
<p>Ms George says the first task of the committee should be to reverse</p>
<p>budget cuts to the public service.</p>
<p>She says it's the government's treatment of the public sector</p>
<p>that's driving predictions that unemployment will reach nine per</p>
<p>cent or more.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ATTEMPTED ESCAPEES COMMITTED TO FACE TRIAL</p>
<p>A 29 year old man convicted of murdering Sydney nurse Anita Cobby</p>
<p>and another Goulburn inmate have been committed to face trial in</p>
<p>the District Court for attempting to escape from custody.</p>
<p>John Raymond Travers was one of three prisoners facing committal</p>
<p>proceedings in the Goulburn Local Court charged with attempting to</p>
<p>escape from a prison van on June 5th this year.</p>
<p>It's alleged Travers, Lauteau Fatafehi, 31, and 26-year-old Steven</p>
<p>Allen Fuller, tried to cut through an escape hatch in a prison van</p>
<p>while in transit on the M5 between Goulburn and Sydney.</p>
<p>Magistrate Mary Jerram dismissed the charges against Fuller saying</p>
<p>it was possible he was simply in the same van cell and had not been</p>
<p>part of the escape conspiracy.</p>
<p>Travers and Fatafehi will face trail on a date to be fixed. - - - -</p>
<p>RADIO AUSTRALAI MAY LOSE TWO PROGRAMS UNDER CUTS</p>
<p>The general manager of Radio Australia, Derek White, says budget</p>
<p>cuts could force the closure of two of the station's language</p>
<p>services next year.</p>
<p>Mr White told a meeting in Melbourne of the Australian Institute of</p>
<p>International Affairs that the services most likely to face closure</p>
<p>were Cantonese, and French.</p>
<p>He said other important Radio Australia services -- Bahasa</p>
<p>Indonesian and Mandarin -- could also have to shorten the number of</p>
<p>hours they broadcast because of staff cut-backs.</p>
<p>Mr White said such moves would be necessary if Radio Australia took</p>
<p>a proportional share of a proposed 10 per cent cut in government</p>
<p>funding for the ABC.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOREAN AMBASSADOR SEES AUSTRALIA AS OPEN SOCIETY</p>
<p>The Korean Ambassador to Australia, Byong Hyong Kwon, says he sees</p>
<p>Australia as an open liberal society where people from all over the</p>
<p>world live.</p>
<p>Mr Kwon says the concerns in Australia about increased racism will</p>
<p>have absolutely no impact at all on relations with South Korea,</p>
<p>saying it's a domestic issue.</p>
<p>He says he's tried to monitor the issue.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>INDEPENDENT AUDITOR FOR SECOND SYDNEY AIRPORT</p>
<p>The Federal Government will appoint an independent environmental</p>
<p>auditor for the proposed second Sydney airport.</p>
<p>Environment minister Robert Hill says the auditor will review</p>
<p>documentation relied on in preparing the Environmental Impact</p>
<p>Statement and report on its technical adequacy.</p>
<p>The minister says the auditor will review the Draft E-I-S, and the</p>
<p>report will be publicly released.</p>
<p>Senator Hill says the auditor will also report on the adequacy of</p>
<p>the final E-I-S.</p>
<p>The minister has written to seven environmental consultancy firms,</p>
<p>asking for expressions of interest, and expects to make an</p>
<p>appointment within three weeks.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney newsroom 61-2 93731800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
