<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133442" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Peters says NZ dollar rise gives urgency to talks.</title>
<headline>Peters says NZ dollar rise gives urgency to talks.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand First leader Winston Peters said on Wednesday the rise of the New Zealand dollar gave urgency to talks on forming a coalition government.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, of course they do, but overseas, talks take considerable time, up to six months. We are trying to do it in a much more rapid fashion and a much more responsible fashion, and we will,&quot; Peters said in reply to reporters' questions.</p>
<p>New Zealand First, which holds the balance of power, is negotiating with both the caretaker National Party government and main opposition Labour Party in the wake of an inconclusive general election 11 days ago.  </p>
<p>Peters said NZ First made very good progress in its first meeting with Labour on Wednesday and would hold another next Tuesday. He was due to meet National later on Wednesday and again on Tuesday afternoon, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think these talks are going along well. I don't want to compromise progress,&quot; he said, adding he would not make any comment that the parties had not agreed to.</p>
<p>The first session with Labour lasted over an hour and a half, about the same length of time as the initial meeting with National on Monday.  </p>
<p>Asked about the secrecy surrounding the talks, Peters said: &quot;If anything goes wrong by way of public statements that would affect the economy, you (the media) would seek to blame the parties for that. I think...the ultimate obligation of this party is to ensure that the economy and New Zealand's long-term social interests are looked after so we can bring the talks to finality.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;They are not in any way secret other than to ensure we can get the business done, and then the public will know the full and absolute detail of what has been resolved.&quot;  </p>
<p>Peters said NZ First was even-handed in its dealings with National and Labour.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to do these talks fairly and equally between all parties, so what we discussed with National, we discussed with Labour today. We have got agreement on process and procedures...and we don't intend to make any other statement.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if NZ First would get down to talk policy with National in the Wednesday afternoon session, he said &quot;Yes, obviously.&quot; -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
