<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133468" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan prosecutors arrest copper trader Hamanaka.</title>
<headline>Japan prosecutors arrest copper trader Hamanaka.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO</dateline>
<text>
<p>One-time copper trading king Yasuo Hamanaka was arrested Tuesday and his home was raided amid charges that he forged key documents as part of a massive scheme to engage in illegal trades.</p>
<p>The arrest came after giant trading house Sumitomo Corp. filed a formal legal complaint against Hamanaka, its former chief copper trader, whom it blamed for a huge $2.6 billion loss from unauthorised copper deals.</p>
<p>The company said, however, that there were no signs that Hamanaka had tried to control the world's copper markets.</p>
<p>In a statement on Hamanaka's arrest, the Tokyo District Prosecutor's Office said he was under suspicion of forging the signature of a Sumitomo board member on two letters in 1994.</p>
<p>The letters said he had the authority to enter into certain metals transactions and to designate recipients of funds deposited with firms in the Merrill Lynch group.</p>
<p>Hamanaka, once dubbed &quot;Mr. Five Percent&quot; due to his rumoured control of a huge 5 percent share of the global copper market, was fired in mid-June, when Sumitomo first announced it had discovered the trading losses.</p>
<p>At a news conference after Hamanaka's arrest, Sumitomo officials said they would also file a complaint against him for breach of trust against the company. They said they did not think Hamanaka was acting for personal gain or that he was manipulating the world copper market.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, we haven't found evidence that Hamanaka was manipulating the world copper market,&quot; Sakuo Nanba, general manager of Sumitomo's legal department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Metal traders had said that Hamanaka had successfully controlled the world's copper markets for years, and that they believed he had racked up huge gains in copper futures trading.</p>
<p>Hamanaka has repeatedly refused to comment on the affair.</p>
<p>Regulators in Britain, where the bulk of the trading took place, have been investigating whether there was an attempt to corner the world copper markets.</p>
<p>U.S. regulators also have been involved in the probe, but their Japanese counterparts have repeatedly said they are not involved as any trading would have taken place outside Japan.</p>
<p>Many copper traders speculated that high copper prices last year and early this year were due chiefly to Hamanaka's iron grip on a large portion of world copper stocks.</p>
<p>Copper prices plunged in May -- when Sumitomo assigned Hamanaka to another post -- and fell further after he was fired in June.</p>
<p>On Sept. 19, Sumitomo officials told a news conference that Hamanaka incurred an unreported loss of about $30 million in 1985, and that this snowballed to $2.6 billion as he tried to cover his losses with more off-the-books deals.</p>
<p>The company claimed he conducted as many as 2,000 unauthorised deals in a single year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
