<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133475" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- APPLE DAILY - Chinese dissident Wang Xizhe who escaped to the United States last week said he wanted to join the Kuomintang.</p>
<p>-- SING TAO DAILY - The family of jailed Chinese dissident Wang Dan had decided to hire the lawyer who defended the Gang Of Four to defend Wang.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO - A gang in Guangdong province was passing off Portugese escudas as Canadian dollars to local residents.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO - China's Central Committee had instructed provincial authorities to understand the policy of &quot;one country two systems&quot; that will apply to Hong Kong after the handover.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES - China's Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications said it was considering lowering rates for international long distance calls by at least 20 percent.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- Head hunters have proposed four candidates to take over as head of the Hong Kong Stock Exchange next year.</p>
<p>-- English-language SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST - The Kowloon and Canton Railway Corp was considering a plan to axe half the staff working on the Western Corridor Railway project. It expects to save at least $20 million a month as a result.</p>
<p>-- English-language HONGKONG STANDARD -- British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind urged China to explain Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen's comments concerning freedom of expression in post-handover Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
