<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133495" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Cambodian PM Ranariddh warns against poll violence.</title>
<headline>Cambodian PM Ranariddh warns against poll violence.</headline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cambodian First Prime Minister Prince Norodom Ranariddh on Tuesday said his party would win the next general elections in 1998 but warned against intimidation and violence ahead of the polls.</p>
<p>Analysts believed the words of the head of the royalist FUNCINPEC party were aimed at the former communist Cambodian People's Party (CPP) of Second Prime Minister Hun Sen, a battlefield foe turned coalition government partner.</p>
<p>The two parties formed a fragile alliance after FUNCINPEC narrowly edged out the incumbent CPP in landmark 1993 elections organised by the United Nations. Their partnership turned sour in March when the royalists demanded a greater share of power.</p>
<p>&quot;FUNCINPEC won the 1993 election and I am pretty sure that in 1998 FUNCINPEC is going to win the election again. It will not fail,&quot; the prince said when meeting members of the Islamic Cham community at his party headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;We must take the bitter lessons of the 1993 election and apply them for the 1998 election,&quot; he said, while claiming the run-up to the last polls was marred by intimidation, vote-buying and the unsolved killings of more than 50 FUNCINPEC members.</p>
<p>Ranariddh would not point the finger at any one party, but U.N. peacekeepers in Cambodia in the lead-up to the 1993 polls laid the blame for most of the scores of politically motivated killings on the CPP.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to say as president of FUNCINPEC that during the 1997 (local elections) and 1998 elections, we will not allow anyone to suppress FUNCINPEC as in 1993,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He reiterated, at a seminar on Monday to discuss the fifth anniversary of the October 23, 1991 Cambodian peace pact, that the next elections should end the current system of two premiers and introduce a single prime minister.</p>
<p>The coalition rift earlier this year saw Hun Sen at one stage warning he would use force to prevent any attempt to break up the government after Ranariddh had threatened to pull out.</p>
<p>The tension has abated in the past three months but the two leaders continue to snipe at each other, normally in closed doors meetings whose outcomes are often leaked.</p>
<p>Analysts see the bickering as early electioneering.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
