<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133466" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Kinkel says China, Germany set friendly course.</title>
<headline>Kinkel says China, Germany set friendly course.</headline>
<byline>Peter Ehrlich</byline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said on Tuesday that China and Germany had put their differences behind them and had set a new course for expanded economic ties.</p>
<p>Kinkel met Communist Party leader and State President Jiang Zemin and Premier Li Peng earlier in the day to cap a fence-mending trip long delayed by a diplomatic dispute over China's restive Himalayan region of Tibet.</p>
<p>China's leaders had made clear the dispute was now firmly in the past, Kinkel told a news conference after his meetings in the Zhongnanhai compound, central residence and workplace of China's communist leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides see the misunderstandings as resolved. President Jiang used the words: 'after the rain the sky cleared quickly',&quot; Kinkel said.</p>
<p>The prospects for Sino-German diplomatic ties and economic relations looked promising, he said.</p>
<p>Kinkel, who arrived on Monday for a five-day visit, said he had discussed human rights with Chinese leaders and had raised the cases of dissidents Wang Dan and Wei Jingsheng.</p>
<p>Kinkel said Wang's family had appealed for him to mention the former student leader, currently awaiting trial on the capital charge of plotting to overthrow the government.</p>
<p>Wei Jingsheng, a veteran dissident, was sentenced to 14 years in prison last December for plotting to subvert the government.</p>
<p>The dialogue with Chinese officials on human rights had been non-confrontational, Kinkel said without giving details.</p>
<p>Kinkel had originally planned to visit in July, but Beijing withdrew its invitation after the German lower house of parliament passed a resolution accusing China of trying to eradicate Tibet's cultural identity.</p>
<p>The dispute briefly threatened to affect China's economic ties with Germany, Beijing's largest European trade partner.</p>
<p>Kinkel said Tibet had been discussed. He said differences remained between Beijing and Bonn over the issue, but gave no details.</p>
<p>&quot;We have talked about this in our dialogue, and there are different opinions remaining,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China's Xinhua news agency said Kinkel had assured Jiang that Germany would not interfere in Beijing's internal affairs and would maintain its stance that Tibet was part of China.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang told a regular news briefing that foreign countries should not use differences over human rights to interfere in China's domestic concerns.</p>
<p>German opposition politicians have long criticised Kinkel's policies on China, accusing him of treading too softly on human rights to protect business opportunities for German industry.</p>
<p>About two dozen representatives of German companies, many of them specialising in environmental protection technology, have accompanied the foreign minister to China.</p>
<p>Asked about the case of Wang Dan, a leader of 1989 pro-democracy demonstrations in Beijing that were crushed by the army, Kinkel said he was doing what he could.</p>
<p>&quot;I raised a number of cases,&quot; he said. &quot;I do what I can and I am aware of responsibilities in that respect.&quot;</p>
<p>Kinkel's main task in China was to lay the ground for German President Roman Herzog's state visit from November 18 to 25, Xinhua quoted Jiang as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;President Roman Herzog's visit to China is an important event in bilateral relations,&quot; Jiang said.</p>
<p>Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen has accepted an invitation to visit Germany in early 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
