<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133483" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China says won't accept Taiwan's Lien at APEC.</title>
<headline>China says won't accept Taiwan's Lien at APEC.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>China said on Tuesday it would not accept any plans to upgrade the representation of rival Taiwan at next month's Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) summit.</p>
<p>A senior Philippine diplomat said in Manila on Monday that the Philippines would stick to the formula used at previous APEC summits, limiting APEC member Taiwan's representation to the level of economic minister.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese side will definitely not accept any practice that goes beyond this formula,&quot; Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman Shen Guofang told a news briefing.</p>
<p>Shen was asked to comment on a Taiwan newspaper report that the Philippines had promised to allow either Taiwan Vice President Lien Chan or Vice Premier Hsu Li-teh to attend the summit at the Subic free port north of Manila on November 25.</p>
<p>The Philippines had already denied the report.</p>
<p>Lien's presence, or that of his deputy, at the summit would likely provoke APEC member China, which has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since a civil war separated them in 1949.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
