<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13347" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa, slightly stronger, blesses nuns.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa, slightly stronger, blesses nuns.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa, fighting for her life on a hospital respirator, showed faint signs of renewed strength on Sunday and blessed a group of nuns who visited her in the intensive care unit.</p>
<p>&quot;She blessed some of the sisters of Missionaries of Charity who were allowed to see her in the evening,&quot; Dr S.K. Sen, medical director of Woodlands Nursing Home, told reporters. &quot;She blessed them by raising her hand gently.&quot;</p>
<p>Sen said the nuns were allowed to visit the renowned founder of their 47-year-old Roman Catholic order after doctors had noticed a slight improvement in her condition.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother Teresa had no further cardio-vascular problems during the day, though her heart rate is still irregular,&quot; said the smiling doctor.</p>
<p>The 85-year-old missionary was taken to hospital on Tuesday with a high fever and severe vomiting. Later she suffered heart failure and was diagnosed with malaria and a chest infection.</p>
<p>On Sunday, after several days of antibiotics, her fever abated. But Mother Teresa, who marks her 86th birthday on Tuesday, continued to need the respirator.</p>
<p>&quot;She is still seriously ill. We cannot say she is out of danger unless respiratory support is switched off,&quot; Sen said. &quot;We are very much encouraged by today's progress. By tomorrow we hope things will significantly improve.&quot;</p>
<p>The doctor, part of a six-member team of specialists treating Mother Teresa, said the respirator amounted to a life support system which they were trying gradually to withdraw.</p>
<p>Asked to what extent the respirator was breathing for Mother Teresa, Sen said: &quot;It's fifty-fifty. She is not yet able to breathe on her own but we hope she will be able to breathe completely on her own tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier thousands of people, including Moslems and Hindus, joined in prayer for the Albanian-born nun as she fought against a faltering heart in the hospital in Calcutta, one of the world's poorest and most overcrowded cities.</p>
<p>Thousands of people joined in Catholic Sunday services at churches across India in a spontaneous outpouring of concern.</p>
<p>Special prayers were held at the Mother House, the sprawling headquarters of the Missionaries of Charity, the order Mother Teresa founded in 1949 to help the poor and destitute.</p>
<p>More than 100 nuns and volunteers gathered at mass to pray for Mother Teresa, also known as the Saint of the Gutters for devoting her life to the poor.</p>
<p>&quot;Even a maulvi (Moslem cleric) came and knelt in the chapel,&quot; said Sister Priscilla, a senior nun at the order.</p>
<p>She said several Hindus and Moslems had also visited Mother House to inquire about Mother Teresa, adding: &quot;She is a living saint for everybody here.&quot;</p>
<p>Since 1989 when she was fitted with a heart pacemaker, Mother Teresa has been periodically admitted to hospital.</p>
<p>In 1991, she was treated at a California hospital for heart disease and bacterial pneumonia. In 1993, she fell in Rome and broke three ribs. In August the same year, she developed malaria, complicated by her heart and lung problems. Last April she fractured her left collar bone.</p>
<p>&quot;She is greater than any mother in this world. I would have died of cold if I hadn't come here,&quot; said Nada, one of about 100 destitutes at Mother Teresa's Calcutta shelter for the homeless.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
