<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133494" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Former Filipino rebel named development chief.</title>
<headline>Former Filipino rebel named development chief.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine President Fidel Ramos on Tuesday appointed former Moslem rebel chief Nur Misuari as head of a controversial body to supervise development in 14 provinces in the southern Philippines.</p>
<p>As chairman of the Southern Philippine Council for Peace and Development (SPCPD), Misuari will have a major say in drawing up economic programmes in an area dominated by Christians.</p>
<p>The creation of the SPCPD with Misuari as head is part of a peace deal signed last month between Manila and the Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) ending a 24-year revolt for Moslem self-rule in the southern Mindanao region.</p>
<p>Misuari, the head of the MNLF, is also serving concurrently as governor of a semi-autonomous region comprising four Moslem provinces after being elected to the post in recent polls.</p>
<p>Under the deal, the SPCPD will serve as forerunner of a wider autonomy area composed of the four Moslem provinces and others voting to join it in a plebiscite to be held in three years.</p>
<p>Nine Christian politicians have asked the Supreme Court to declare the SPCPD unconstitutional, saying it would lead to Moslem minority rule in largely Christian provinces and cities.</p>
<p>Ramos said the court had not issued any order declaring the SPCPD illegal, thus clearing the way for Misuari's appointment as its chairman.</p>
<p>The country's five million Moslem minority regard Mindanao as their ancestral homeland although they are now outnumbered 3-to-1 in the area by Christians.</p>
<p>Manila is holding exploratory talks with another Moslem insurgent group, the Moro Islamic Liberation Front (MILF), to try to reach a separate peace deal.</p>
<p>The MILF, although smaller than the mainstream MNLF, is considered by the military to be more dangerous because it wants to set up an Islamic state in the southern islands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
