<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133574" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Yemen sets deadline for captors of French diplomat.</title>
<headline>Yemen sets deadline for captors of French diplomat.</headline>
<byline>Mohammad Sudam</byline>
<dateline>SANAA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yemen on Tuesday told members of a tribe who seized a French diplomat to free him by Wednesday night or else be attacked by security forces, a senior government official said.</p>
<p>The deadline, announced by Marib governor Abdul-Wali al-Shumairi, ends on Wednesday midnight (2100 GMT). The diplomat is being held in the Marib area by several members of the Toaiman tribe who seized him in the capital Sanaa on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;If he is not released by then, the security forces will launch a crackdown on the homes occupied by kidnappers,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There should be no fear for the life of the diplomat as they cannot do anything to him since we have arrested tens of the tribe members and further arrests are continuing&quot;.</p>
<p>The diplomat has not been named.</p>
<p>Shumairi said the tribe wanted government compensation for losses inflicted on homes, farms, water pumps and wells by floods in June, more job opportunities and the settlement of a land dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will look into these demands, but only after the release of the hostage, the return of his car and the surrender of the captors,&quot; he added. &quot;No prior conditions will be accepted&quot;.</p>
<p>More than 65 people were believed killed, dozens went missing and hundreds were made homeless in the floods that caused damage estimated at more than $1.2 billion.</p>
<p>Security officials said earlier they arrested 18 tribe members to put pressure on the abductors.</p>
<p>They said police and army forces, using light and heavy weapons, were keeping a tight lid on the tribe's al-Mahjaza village.</p>
<p>Security officials said on Monday the diplomat was abducted while he was driving his car in Sanaa and taken to the province of Marib, 170 km (100 miles) east of the capital.</p>
<p>Officials said the diplomat's car had been spotted in Marib by local police before they were informed of his abduction.</p>
<p>The Toaiman tribe earlier this month hijacked the car of Yemen's minister of agriculture and kidnapped his driver in Sanaa. The minister was not in the car at the time. The driver was beaten up and later set free.</p>
<p>The tribe demanded then that the government provide it with water pumps and drilling equipment for wells in Marib.</p>
<p>In recent years, tribes in Yemen with grievances against the government or foreign oil firms have kidnapped tourists or foreigners for use as bargaining chips.</p>
<p>At least two diplomats, an American and a Saudi ambassador, have been among the kidnap victims.</p>
<p>The tribes' demands have usually involved land or water issues, and have rarely been political. There have been no reported casualties from the abductions.</p>
<p>In January, members of a tribe kidnapped 17 elderly French tourists in Marib who were later released.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
