<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133566" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan government may be on hold for two weeks.</title>
<headline>Japan government may be on hold for two weeks.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's party said on Tuesday Japan's government is likely to be on hold for at least two weeks until a coalition is stitched together and parliament reconvened after general elections.</p>
<p>Top government spokesman Seiroku Kajiyama told reporters that parliament would probably convene on November 7 to formally re-elect Hashimoto as prime minister, the signal for the government to stop acting on autopilot.</p>
<p>The prime minister's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) secured 239 seats in Sunday's voting, 12 short of the 251 it needed to govern alone in the 500-seat Lower House.</p>
<p>Hashimoto's first contacts with his old coalition partners, the Social Democrats and the Sakigake Party, have not brought any immediate breakthrough. A third possible ally, the Democratic Party, was also playing hard to get.</p>
<p>LDP officials have said the party needs about 280 seats to govern effectively.</p>
<p>Sakigake has just two seats, the Social Democrats 15 and the Democrats 52.</p>
<p>&quot;It will take two more days before we can formally start (coalition) policy negotiations because of technical reasons such as confirming elected seats,&quot; Kajiyama said.</p>
<p>The LDP's three possible coalition allies were holding their own separate meetings of parliament members to consider whether to join with the LDP.</p>
<p>Social Democrat leader Takako Doi said her party needed &quot;time to heal our wounds&quot; before jumping into a new LDP-led coalition.</p>
<p>Sakigake leader Shoichi Ide said his party was ready to consider an alliance if the LDP was serious about carrying out administrative reform.</p>
<p>Naoto Kan, co-leader of the Democrats, said in a television interview: &quot;We have not said no to forming a coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;But we must be assured somehow that the LDP would honestly strive towards the goal of streamlining the bureaucracy when the vested interests of LDP legislators themselves are at risk.&quot;</p>
<p>Behind the scenes, Hashimoto aides negotiated with up to 10 possible defectors from the main opposition Shinshinto (New Frontier Party) to try to persuade them to switch allegiance to the LDP. Shinshinto ended up with 156 seats, four fewer than before.</p>
<p>After a series of funding scandals, the LDP was toppled from power in 1993 after 38 years of single-party government. It returned to power in a coalition a year later and Hashimoto took over as prime minister in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The past 2 1/2 years of coalition government have taught us that maybe we have been complacent in the past about not carrying out reforms when we came under persuasion by bureaucrats,&quot; LDP secretary-general Koichi Kato said.</p>
<p>The LDP's need for more than a simple majority of 251 seats is dictated by Japan's parliamentary system, where most key deliberations take place in committees.</p>
<p>With 265 seats, a ruling bloc would have the power to name the chairmen of key, but not all, standing committees, such as the budget, security and cabinet committees.</p>
<p>With 280 seats, the ruling bloc would not only have the power to name chairmen to all standing committees, but would hold a majority in all committees.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
