<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133533" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Sampoerna prepared to sell Astra stake.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Sampoerna prepared to sell Astra stake.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian cigarette company PT Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna said on Tuesday the firm was prepared to sell its stake in the country's largest vehicle manufacturer Astra International.</p>
<p>PT Sampoerna bought a 2.85 percent stake in Astra last month at the height of a wave of buying into the firm. President director Putera Sampoerna bought an additional 9.81 percent, giving him effectively the single largest shareholding in Astra.</p>
<p>But the market did not approve of the company's move, sending Sampoerna shares tumbling as ratings agencies Moody's and Standard &amp; Poor's downgraded the company's debt on the grounds that it was moving out of its core business.</p>
<p>PT Sampoerna spokesman Jonathan Zax said the firm was prepared to sell its stake in Astra but declined to comment on speculation that the buyer could be Putera Sampoerna himself.</p>
<p>&quot;We are prepared to sell our stake. Not that we have identified a party to whom to sell our stake,&quot; Zax told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;What I'm suggesting is that if an offer comes or an individual on the market gives us an appropriate return on our investment then we would be prepared to sell our stake.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampoerna shares surged on Tuesday following a news report that it would sell the stake in Astra International, brokers said. They closed up 475 rupiah at 20,725.</p>
<p>Sampoerna shares surged 1,350 rupiah on Monday after the company announced the cancellation of a shareholders meeting, which sources in the firm said was to have considered acquiring an additional stake in Astra.</p>
<p>Zax also said PT Sampoerna would also disclose its investment plans, including the purpose of a recently obtained $400 million loan and its recent purchase of Astra shares, by end-October.</p>
<p>Sampoerna's finance director Eka Dharmajanto Kasih was quoted by Bisnis Indonesia daily on Tuesday as saying that Putera Sampoerna was likely to hold on to his stake but did not give details.</p>
<p>Separately, the Nusamaba group, with which President Suharto is connected, has announced that it is interested in acquiring a stake in Astra.</p>
<p>The group has said it has concluded an agreement with government banks and pension funds to buy out their stakes, estimated at about 10 percent in total, and is willing to consider offers from other large shareholders.</p>
<p>Nusamba is 80 percent owned by three foundations headed by Suharto. Timber tycoon Muhamad &quot;Bob&quot; Hasan, a close associate of Suharto, and the president's eldest son Sigit Harjojudanto own 10 percent each.  </p>
<p>Astra rose 250 rupiah to close at 4,250 rupiah on a turnover of 5.1 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
