<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133570" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: GCC chief arrives in Kuwait to prepare for summit.</title>
<headline>GCC chief arrives in Kuwait to prepare for summit.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) arrived in Kuwait on Tuesday, the last leg of a regional tour to prepare for the next Gulf Arab summit, set to be held in Qatar on December 7.</p>
<p>GCC Secretary-General Jameel Hujilan, in a statement to the official news agency KUNA after flying in from the United Arab Emirates, hinted that all leaders in the six-nation GCC might attend the summit.</p>
<p>Bahrain, locked in a territorial dispute with Qatar over a cluster of barren reefs and islands which are potentially rich in oil and gas, has threatened to boycott the summit.</p>
<p>There are also political differences among the GCC, which also groups Oman and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;The convening of the summit with all members is a matter that all GCC leaders are keen on&quot;, Hujilan told KUNA.</p>
<p>&quot;This will help meet the huge hopes of GCC nationals towards the summit as they expect it to come out with achievements that will bring more development and prosperity to their Gulf home&quot;.</p>
<p>Bahrain said it might not attend the Qatar meeting to protest against Doha's failure to withdraw the case it has taken to the International Court of Justice over the islands, which include Hawar islands -- controlled by Bahrain since the 1930s.</p>
<p>Qatar said it would only withdraw the case from the world court in the Hague if Saudi Arabia's mediation succeeded in settling the long-standing border row.</p>
<p>Qatar asked the court in 1991 to settle the problem. The court decided in January it had jurisdiction and is expected to produce a verdict by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Hujilan is trying to find a compromise to convince Bahrain's ruler to attend the summit, diplomats said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
