<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133506" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - KEB steps up with sub FRN.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - KEB steps up with sub FRN.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets were slow on Tuesday after a long holiday weekend in Hong Kong, with a subordinated bond for Korea Exchange Bank the major issue.</p>
<p>But there are some interesting deals in prospect.</p>
<p>Korea Exchange Bank offered some excitement with a US$200 million callable, subordinated step-up bond launched via joint bookrunners Chase Manhattan Asia and Merrill Lynch Far East.</p>
<p>The 10-year subordinated notes were launched at par and re-offered at 99.95. They can be called after five years.</p>
<p>The notes pay a quarterly coupon of 64 basis points over the three-month London Interbank Offered Rate for years one through five and LIBOR plus 200 basis points thereafter.</p>
<p>The re-offer yield is LIBOR plus 65 basis points payable quarterly for years one through five and LIBOR plus 132.5 basis points for years one through 10.</p>
<p>The syndicate group was small, with only six other banks joining the bookrunners, and the leads kept a large share of the issue on the view that it would trade in the secondary market, bankers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Subordinated issues are the ones in Asia that are most likely to be syndicated like true Eurobonds,&quot; remarked one syndicate manager.</p>
<p>That's because investors in subordinated debt tend to look at it as a trading instrument rather than as something to hold on their books, he said.</p>
<p>KEB International participated in the deal as co-lead manager. ABN AMRO Securities (Far East), ANZ, PaineWebber International, SBC Warburg and Tokyo-Mitsubishi International were co-managers.</p>
<p>Syndicate managers in London today said Korea Development Bank is expected to launch a US$500 million bond by the end of November, probably a global with a tenor of five to 10 years.</p>
<p>From the Philippines, Palawan's governor announced that the province will issue US$100 million worth of bonds to finance infrastructure and development projects.</p>
<p>The province's share of revenues from Shell Philippines Exploration, operator of the Camago-Malampaya field, the country's biggest gas find, will be used to guarantee the bond, Palawan governor Salvador Socrates said.</p>
<p>In the nearer-term, Merrill Lynch is expected to launch a perpetual subordinated bond guaranteed by Hong Kong's Swire Pacific this week. The deal is thought to be the first perpetual issue for an Asian borrower.</p>
<p>Blue-chip Swire is a rare issuer and bankers expect the bond to attract interest for that reason.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
