<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133515" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asian traders say China soyoil buying unconfirmed.</title>
<headline>Asian traders say China soyoil buying unconfirmed.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Traders in Hong Kong and China said on Tuesday they saw no concrete signs that China was in the market for soyoil.</p>
<p>Market reports that China was looking to buy soyoil helped push Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) soyoil October futures higher on Monday.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) said on October 18 private exporters had reported sales of 20,000 tonnes of soyoil for delivery to China during the 1996/97 marketing year which began on October 1.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been a lot of rumours about soyoil buying, but I have not been able to confirm anything,&quot; one trade source said.</p>
<p>Traders said a lack of available import quotas, low domestic demand, and international and local price differentials were deterring China from buying soyoil.</p>
<p>But one China-based vegetable oil trader said he had talked to people at shipping companies who indicated about 200,000 tonnes of soyoil and rapeseed oil were on the way to China for delivery before the end of 1996.</p>
<p>These cargoes were presumably bought on quotas issued earlier, he said. This could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>A trader in Shanghai said last week China's total quota issued for soybean oil imports was just over 100,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Some traders said China had been in the market for soybeans late last week but others said no deals had yet been concluded.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally think a lot of business has been done in the past couple of days,&quot; said a seasoned trader.</p>
<p>China was buying soybeans at $295-298 per tonne, c and f to China ports, he said, but no details on specific deals were immediately available.</p>
<p>Other traders said they were negotiating bean sales with China but the deals had not yet been concluded due to continued concerns over buyers defaulting on payment after price falls.</p>
<p>Some Chinese buyers demanded discounts and threatened to default on letters of credit if prices dropped following a purchase, traders said.</p>
<p>With new domestic Chinese soybean crop already arriving at market and the bulk due by the end of November, China's buyers were in no hurry to import beans, some grain traders said.</p>
<p>Other traders worried about increasing port congestion and demurrage charges towards the end of the year when much of the soybean and soymeal purchased earlier was due to arrive.</p>
<p>End-users wanted to avoid the risk of placing orders for delivery into China in January in case of any changes to agricultural trade or domestic policy, which could possibly be announced on January 1, one senior trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything is to be delivered after January 1, the risk is much greater,&quot; one senior trader said.</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran (852) 2843 6358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
