<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133519" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia youth group seeks to stop Jackson concert.</title>
<headline>Malaysia youth group seeks to stop Jackson concert.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Malaysian youth group is seeking to halt a concert by U.S. pop star Michael Jackson in Kuala Lumpur this weekend, the national news agency Bernama said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The news agency quoted Malaysian Youth Council President Suhaimi Ibrahim as saying the pro-Islamic group would submit a petition for an injunction to the High Court &quot;in a day or two&quot;.</p>
<p>It was the latest flap in the flamboyant entertainer's Asian tour, which also sparked controversy elsewhere in Malaysia and in South Korea.</p>
<p>Jackson had been scheduled to put on a show in Malaysia's central Selangor state, but local authorities abruptly banned the concert two weeks ago, saying it would have undesirable effects on youth.</p>
<p>The Malaysian cabinet later cleared Jackson to stage concerts, and the capital of Kuala Lumpur offered its stadium.</p>
<p>In South Korea civic and religious groups tried unsuccesfully to keep Jackson out earlier this month. The Ministry of Culture let him perform but said he had to refrain from making &quot;obscene or vulgar gestures or remarks&quot;.</p>
<p>The Malaysian youth group, citing a technicality, said the contract for the concert was no longer valid as it was two years old.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
