<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133544" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end up one pct after directionless day.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end up one pct after directionless day.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks rose for the fifth day on Tuesday as some investors bought shares of companies who have yet to release third quarter results and others sold finance shares following sluggish results, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index, which moved in directionless trade almost throughout the session, rose near the end to close 9.53 points higher to 958.05 on 3.5 billion baht turnover. The SET-50 index rose 0.95 point higher to 72.57.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors thought that most of the earning results of finance companies during the third quarter weren't good,&quot; said Busaba Kunasirin of Chao Phya Finance and Securities.  </p>
<p>Brokers said investors were not happy with third quarter financial results of some of the major financial companies including Phatra Thanakit and Finance One.</p>
<p>Phatra Thanakit's net profit in the third quarter dropped to 302.50 million baht versus 519.20 million baht the same period last year.</p>
<p>Finance One said its unreviewed net profit in the quarter fell to 457.93 million baht from 458.08 million baht the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Late bargain hunting was seen before the market closed when investors bought some stocks, mainly communication issues.  </p>
<p>Communication stocks which gained ground included Advanced Info Service, which rose 10 baht to 358 and Shinawatra Computer and Communications, which advanced four to 420.</p>
<p>Krung Thai Bank topped the active list, rising 0.50 baht to 73.50.</p>
<p>The market will be closed on Wednesday for Chulalongkorn Day holiday.</p>
<p>-- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
