<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133530" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Vietnam completes study on first oil refinery.</title>
<headline>Vietnam completes study on first oil refinery.</headline>
<byline>Ramthan Hussain</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned PetroVietnam and its foreign partners have completed a feasibility study to build Vietnam's first oil refinery and will submit the report to the government next month, a PetroVietnam official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The consortium expects the government to make a decision on the proposals by the end of the year to enable it to start construction early in 1997, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working on a tight schedule as we are trying to put the refinery into operation by the year 2000,&quot; the official told Reuters by telephone from Hanoi.</p>
<p>The partners are seeking government permission to form a joint venture company for the project in central Vietnam.</p>
<p>The official said other proposals from the study included the preferred way to source finance. The financial consultant for the refinery project was BZW Corporate and Project Finance, the investment banking division of Britain's Barclays Bank Plc, he said.</p>
<p>The cost of the 130,000-barrel-per-day capacity refinery, to be built on the coast, would be in the range of $1.2-$1.4 billion, the official said. This includes the development of a breakwater or dike to stave off high waves.</p>
<p>Under the feasibility study which was agreed in March, PetroVietnam and a consortium led by South Korea's LG Group hold 30-percent each. The LG-led stake includes three percent held by U.S. firm Stone and Webster.</p>
<p>Malaysia's state-owned Petroliam Nasional Berhad (Petronas) splits 30 percent with U.S. refiner Conoco Inc, a unit of DuPont Co. Two Taiwanese firms, state-owned Chinese Petroleum Corp and Chinese Investment Development Corp, share 10 percent.</p>
<p>But officials in the joint venture said in March that the split of shares in the study was not necessarily the split that would apply to an eventual joint venture agreement.</p>
<p>The project has long been considered controversial because the site chosen, Dung Quat Bay in central Quang Ngai province, is an undeveloped area 1,000 km (600 miles) north of the country's oilfield and main consumption base. French oil firm Total SA withdrew from the project last year, branding it economically unviable.</p>
<p>Refinery experts estimate that up to $400 million would need to be spent on a sheltered harbour and infrastructure at Dung Quat.</p>
<p>The official said another joint venture group would be given the task of developing infrastructure around the refinery and this has already attracted the interest of U.S., South Korean and Thai companies.</p>
<p>He said the Vietnamese government had already formed the Dung Quat Management Board to administer the infrastructural development of the Dung Quat Industrial Zone.</p>
<p>Vietnam is a net oil products importer and is expected to import 2.5 million tonnes of diesel this year, with an annual demand growth of 12-15 percent. The country is planning a second refinery but the location has not been decidied.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870 3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
