<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133599" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Formation of brokerages by Turk banks seen positive.</title>
<headline>Formation of brokerages by Turk banks seen positive.</headline>
<byline>Guzin Ovunc</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish brokers say the formation of separate brokerage houses by banks to carry out all capital market activities under a new regulation by the Capital Market Board (SPK), is necessary for stock market development.</p>
<p>Senior bank and brokerage officials told Reuters that separating capital market activities from banking activities might have positive outcomes such as establishing a &quot;qualified&quot; intermediary sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard for small brokerage houses which do not have many customers and a research and development departments, to survive from now on. The market needs more powerful, big brokerage houses,&quot; said Atilla Koksal, assistant general manager in Interbank.</p>
<p>SPK obliged the Istanbul Stock Exchange's (ISE) 62 member banks to set up new or acquire existing brokerage houses with a minimum 125 billion lira capital till January 2, 1997 to carry on their capital markets activities separately.</p>
<p>&quot;The capital markets department will be able to express itself better after being separated from the bank. It is hard to perform investment banking adeguately together with (regular) banking,&quot; said Cengiz Bicer, assistant general manager in Sumerbank.</p>
<p>So far, eight banks have officially disclosed their intention to form new brokerage houses.</p>
<p>SPK recommended banks to apply until November 11 for approval to set up a new brokerage, but said futures applications by banks that are not currently interested in setting up or buying a brokerage, would also be considered after January 2.</p>
<p>The intermediary licenses of a bank which does not set up or buy a brokerage house will be cancelled, except the ones to make T-bill repurchase and reverse repurchase deals in the Exchange's bond market and broker share trade outside the Exchange.</p>
<p>Separation from banks will enable brokerage performances to be measured adequately, said Erol Goker, general manager of Turkey's leading Global securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone will see that (brokerage) business is very profitable indeed. Thus, banks will invest more (in the capital markets) and this will affect the development of the capital markets positively,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A bank's brokerage will not be able to carry the word &quot;bank&quot; in its title. Its ownership may be divided between the bank and other financial firms within the group controlling the bank.</p>
<p>Goker said the setting up of brokerages by banks would also help to build trust in the stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;The inequality between brokerage houses and banks, arising from banks being under the guarantee of the state, will be omitted,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Stock market tansactions of the banks totalled 1,190 trillion lira while those of the brokerage houses were 2,570 trillion lira in January-September this year.</p>
<p>The brokerage houses made a total of 1,950 trillion lira volume in the bond market while banks made 55,600 trillion lira in the same period.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
