<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133512" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends down on sluggish trade, Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends down on sluggish trade, Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices retained midday losses and ended lower after the market trudged through another sluggish day, unaided by weak futures in Tokyo.</p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board (MRELB) quoted market indicator price for November RSS 1 buyer at 309.50 cents ($1.24) a kg, one cent down from Monday. November SMR 20 buyer was unchanged at 306.</p>
<p>Traders offered the SMR 20 at 305-306 cents, SMR10 at 307, SMR 5 at 317, SMR L at 343, SMR CV at 363 and drum latex at 235.</p>
<p>&quot;The sky's still wet....buyers and sellers are still cautious, nothing has changed,&quot; said a dealer.  </p>
<p>Traders said the market was seeing yet another extended bearish period when buyers seemed adequately stocked after active short-covering in recent months.</p>
<p>Rains since early October have somehat reduced output from rubber plantations but sentiment and demand remained weak, said traders.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day average rose to 238.72 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Oct 21 from 238.69 on Oct 18. The daily indicator was unchanged at 238.98.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7510) ($1=2.5050 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
