<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133557" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan party extends welcome to Chinese dissident.</title>
<headline>Taiwan party extends welcome to Chinese dissident.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's ruling Nationalist Party (Kuomintang) said on Tuesday that it would welcome Chinese dissident Wang Xizhe into the party if he voices support for Taiwan's Republic of China government.</p>
<p>&quot;The position of the Nationalist Party is that we welcome those who identify themselves with the ideas of the Republic of China and the Nationalist Party,&quot; party deputy secretary-general Hansen Chien said on state-funded television.</p>
<p>Wang, speaking in public for the first time since fleeing to the United States, said on Monday in Oakland, California, that he would apply to join the Kuomintang, or KMT.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the KMT leadership will consider my membership application seriously,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wang said he hoped someday to join a KMT delegation in negotiations with Beijing on the reunification of China and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Wang could apply to the KMT's department of overseas affairs to join the party, Chien said.</p>
<p>Taiwan and China have been diplomatic rivals since the Chinese civil war ended in 1949 with Mao Zedong's Communists driving Chiang Kai-shek and his Nationalists to Taiwan.</p>
<p>Beijing now regards Taiwan as a renegade province while Taipei, though maintaining an official policy of reunification, claims to be an independent political entity.</p>
<p>Wang fled his home in China's Guangdong province earlier this month, just days after Chinese authorities arrested pro-democracy activist Liu Xiaobo and ordered him to serve three years in a labour camp.</p>
<p>Wang went first to Hong Kong and then flew via Europe to the San Francisco area last week.</p>
<p>Wang, 46, one of China's leading dissidents, said through an interpreter in Oakland that he would not apply for political asylum in the United States until authorities in Taiwan give him a definite answer on his party application.</p>
<p>Taiwan's top authority on policies toward mainland China, the Mainland Affairs Council, said Wang was also eligible to immigrate to Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;According to current regulations, he can apply to come and stay in Taiwan,&quot; Liu Teh-hsun, director of the council's legal affairs department, said on state-owned radio, citing a Taiwan policy allowing mainland Chinese who contribute to democracy to apply to immigrate.</p>
<p>Wang's activism dates from 1974 when he co-authored an attack in Guangdong on the radical 1966-76 Cultural Revolution. He took part in the 1979 Democracy Wall movement in Beijing and produced his own dissident newsletters.</p>
<p>He was twice imprisoned, spending a total of 17 years in jail and labour camps. He was released on parole in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
