<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133535" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares end lower, focus on Astra, Sampoerna.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares end lower, focus on Astra, Sampoerna.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices ended lower in moderate trading on Tuesday, with the focus remaining on car manufacturer Astra International and cigarette company HM Sampoerna, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said, however, falls in other big capitalised stocks and profit-taking in second- and third-liners caused the index to edge down, despite sharp rises in Sampoerna and Astra.</p>
<p>The Jakarta composite index closed 0.12 percent, or 0.66 points lower at 571.81 points after rising in the past three consecutive trading days.</p>
<p>Losers beat gainers by 78 to 31, with 53 issues unchanged.  </p>
<p>Sampoerna and Astra were among the top gainers and active counters on continued speculation over who would actually control the giant automobile company.</p>
<p>One foreign broker said players were seen waiting for the outcome of a news conference by Astra later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said speculation over the outcome of the conference seemed to have sparked off another wave of buying, pushing Astra shares to 4,250 rupiah from 4,000 rupiah at the opening.</p>
<p>He said the wave was set off after local players saw brokerage SBC Warburg buying Astra local shares.  </p>
<p>&quot;The purchase by Warburg seemed to be the trigger because it was the same broker who had bought Astra shares for Putera Sampoerna earlier,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>Sampoerna shares also rose 2.35 percent at close to 20,725 rupiah in active trading on reports the firm would sell its 2.85 stake in Astra, coupled with news the firm had increased the retail price of its cigarettes.</p>
<p>Sampoerna president director Putera Sampoerna bought an additional 9.81 percent in Astra on his own account.</p>
<p>Another top gainer on Tuesday was Panin Bank, which soared to 2,225 rupiah from 2,000 rupiah in active trading.  </p>
<p>The top loser was third-liner Rimba Niaga Idola which tumbled almost 30 percent to 1,300 rupiah after rising sharply on Monday on talk of a possible rights issue later this month.</p>
<p>Brokers said some local investors were also seen trying to cash out from the market to accumulate funds for the Bank Negara Indonesia initial public offering next month.</p>
<p>Brokers attributed the rise to market talk over the bank's plan for a possible reorganisation similar to that undertaken by the Lippo Group.</p>
<p>But confirmation was not immediately available.</p>
<p>However, those rises failed to help lift the index for the fourth day following some unloading in big capitalised stocks such as Gudang Garam, Indosat, Indofood and Semen Gresik.</p>
<p>The foreign broker said declines in cigarette firm Gudang Garam could be due to portfolio-switching following the gain in Sampoerna.</p>
<p>Gudang Garam declined 0.81 percent to 9,175 rupiah.  </p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
