<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133572" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: U.S. envoy stays for Mideast talks, cites progress.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy stays for Mideast talks, cites progress.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton's peace envoy dropped his plans to leave the Middle East, citing progress in Israeli-PLO peace talks on Tuesday that made missing his plane worthwhile.</p>
<p>&quot;We delayed our departure last night because we were in the midst of the most promising discussions to date on the issue of civil affairs,&quot; veteran mediator Dennis Ross said in a statement.</p>
<p>But violence erupted. Witnesses said Israeli soldiers shot dead a Palestinian teenager during a stone-throwing protest in a West Bank village. The army said troops fired in the air and it was investigating.</p>
<p>The shooting near Ramallah followed the killing earlier of a Palestinian motorist near a Jewish settlement. Witnesses said his car was rocketed; Israeli security sources said it had been hit with a stone.</p>
<p>Israel and the PLO have been trying to hammer out a deal on a long-promised Israeli troop pullback from Hebron, the last and most sensitive of seven West Bank towns due to be handed over to Palestinian rule under a 1995 accord.</p>
<p>&quot;It's close to an end, it's not yet finished. I hope it will end quickly,&quot; Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu told a joint news conference with French President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>Ross was heading for the airport late on Monday when he got a call telling him progress had been made on civilian issues and asking him to postpone his flight, a U.S. official said.</p>
<p>The progress on civilian subjects contrasted sharply with a flareup in separate talks on security issues. Palestinians walked out during the night, describing Israeli delegates' attitudes as that of &quot;occupiers toward the occupied.&quot;</p>
<p>The security talks resumed on Tuesday night in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Israel had charged Palestinians were trying to put off a deal until after U.S. elections on November 5, thinking Clinton would have more leverage to pressure Israel into concessions.</p>
<p>But on Tuesday evening, Netanyahu said he hoped to tie up the loose ends at a meeting with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and announce a deal soon. He gave no specific date.</p>
<p>Clinton sent Ross to the region 15 days ago following an outburst of violence that claimed the lives of 60 Palestinians and 15 Israelis. On Monday, Ross said he was leaving, ready to return when the time was ripe. But then he got the call.</p>
<p>Clinton had made Middle East peace talks a centrepiece of his foreign policy, and administration officials had hoped for a breakthrough with U.S. elections only two weeks away.</p>
<p>The Hebron pullout has been frozen since March by Islamic suicide bombings and Israeli fears for the safety of 400 Jews living among the city's 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said Chirac had delivered a positive report from Israel's arch-foe Syria and the Israeli leader hoped to revive stalled peace talks with Damascus. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Chirac dismissed media reports that he had heard threats of war in Damascus, saying they were &quot;baseless disinformation&quot;.</p>
<p>Netanyahu apologised to Chirac after overzealous security men jostled the visiting French president and manhandled journalists as he toured the Old City of Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The confrontation in the streets of the walled Old City dramatised Franco-Israeli differences over the terms for Middle East peace, the role of Europe and the status of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Netanyahu explained that VIP security had become an obsession since the assassination of former prime minister Yitzhak Rabin nearly a year ago by an extreme-right Jew.</p>
<p>The French leader said that in the light of the apology, he regarded the incident as closed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
