<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13350" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian troops battle to rescue stranded pilgrims.</title>
<headline>Indian troops battle to rescue stranded pilgrims.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian troops with helicopters and relief supplies battled on Sunday to rescue thousands of Hindu pilgrims stranded along a rugged Himalayan trail after at least 116 died from cold, officials said.</p>
<p>Up to 70,000 pilgrims were stranded for a fourth day at heights of up to 3,700 metres (12,136 ft) in Jammu and Kashmir state, the officials said. They were all reported to be safe.</p>
<p>For the first time in four days the weather improved on Sunday, allowing stepped up efforts to rescue pilgrims who included naked &quot;sadhus&quot;, or Hindu holy men smeared only in ash.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather is improving. That is a silver lining,&quot; state government spokesman K.B. Jandial told Reuters in Srinagar, Jammu and Kashmir's summer capital.</p>
<p>&quot;At least 116 yatris (pilgrims) have died so far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United News of India put the death toll, resulting from high monsoon rains, snow and sub-zero temperatures, at 133.</p>
<p>Officials said some 112,000 Hindus had arrived in Kashmir this year to visit the holy Amarnath cave, where devotees worship an ice stalagmite believed to be a manifestation of the &quot;lingam&quot;, or phallus, of the Hindu God Shiva.</p>
<p>Two army helicopters flew about 60 pilgrims suffering from breathing trouble and other cold-related ailments to a Srinagar hospital on Sunday, officials said.</p>
<p>The helicopters also dropped food, medicine and blankets to help some 3,000 people on a thickly-forested part of the route near the frozen Sheshnag lake, 60 km (38 miles) from Srinagar.</p>
<p>&quot;The priority was to bring back ailing pilgrims,&quot; added Jandial, who said helicopters also took oxygen cylinders to pilgrims near the lake.</p>
<p>The lake is about 15 km (nine miles) south of Amarnath and is normally the third stage of a five-day trek to the cave in some of the world's most scenic but rugged areas.</p>
<p>Jandial said between 300 and 400 soldiers were detailed to escort pilgrims trekking down the sides of the Kashmir valley. Paramilitary troops also joined the rescue operations.</p>
<p>He said there were no pilgrims left at the cave.</p>
<p>Those stranded included 15,000 devotees strung along the 50-km (30-mile) route to the Amarnath cave, officials said. The cave is at 3,880 metres (12,725 ft).</p>
<p>The officials said about 55,000 people were stranded at the trek's starting point, Pahalgam. All roads leading to the town were impassable because of flooding.</p>
<p>Pahalgam is about 40 km (25 miles) east of Srinagar by air but more than double that by road.</p>
<p>The Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party demanded an inquiry into the deaths, the Press Trust of India said.</p>
<p>A doctor at a makeshift pilgrim camp said: &quot;The main reason for the deaths is that the pilgrims had no warm clothing. Many were were old people. The holy men were trekking naked.&quot;</p>
<p>The taxing trek across India's only Moslem majority state had to be halted soon after the unexpected weather. It had been scheduled to end this Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have moved almost 30,000 people out of the vicinity of the cave, removing them from the highest sector of the trek since yesterday,&quot; a spokesman told Reuters in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Last year the pilgrimage was threatened by Moslem separatist guerrillas who staged two bomb attacks on the heavily guarded pilgrims. A civil servant was killed in one of the blasts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
