<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133514" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore gas oil come under selling pressure.</title>
<headline>Singapore gas oil come under selling pressure.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products prices were steady to weaker on Tuesday along with softer crudes with gas oil under selling pressure from one trader and pressured by falling IPE gas oil, traders said.</p>
<p>The Singapore trader has been trying to push down gas oil prices since Monday when it offered at $30.40. It lowered its offer Tuesday to as low as $30 for Nov 16-20 lifting fob, with no bids seen. Other offers for mid-November were seen as high as $30.80 but traders said prices might have peaked around $30.50 for now. Swaps gas oil also dipped to trade for November between $30.08 and $30.20, compared with Monday's $30.40.  </p>
<p>Traders said India's December gas oil imports would be limited to 300,000-400,000 tonnes as its ports are still facing congestions. The Kandla port on the west coast now has 18 tankers waiting to discharge. Traders also said India is also facing difficulties financing its imports especially at current record prices. The tender for December closes on October 24.</p>
<p>Traders said jet fuel was offered down to $30.20 for mid-November lifting fob, with a bid for early November at $30. They said a US trader has about one million barrels of jet fuel stored in eastern China. The trader also has jet fuel in storage in Guam. This signalled abundant regional supplies.  </p>
<p>Gasoline remained steady although high prices in the past two months dampened buying interest and supplies are piling up, traders said. The price of a barrel of 95-octane unleaded rose by over $3 from below $22 end August. But this has closed the arbitage to Africa and supplies from China were ample. A trader said the naphtha-gasoline spread would narrow from its current $2.40 a barrel to under $2 by the end of fourth quarter. Traders were concerned about processing cargoes from Chinese refineries and potential supplies from the new 100,000-bpd Dalian refinery which started early Oct. Refinery sources said there would  be no exports in the short term.--Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
