<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133547" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine exchange faces crucial vote on reforms.</title>
<headline>Philippine exchange faces crucial vote on reforms.</headline>
<byline>Uday Khandeparkar</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine stockbrokers were in turmoil on Tuesday as they prepared to vote on reforms seen as crucial if they want to avoid a showdown with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).</p>
<p>&quot;We are calling all members ... we are asking each and every one of them to attend,&quot; Wilson Sy, chairman of the Philippine Stock Exchange, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The bourse has called a special meeting on Wednesday at 3 p.m. (0700 GMT) to approve three resolutions, the most contentious of which will allow the audit department to check brokers' books without approval from the governing board.</p>
<p>Under existing rules, the audit department has to get board approval before checking a broker's books, a provision the SEC says defeats the purpose as the audit is no longer a surprise.</p>
<p>The other resolutions are to make room for two non-broker members on the bourse's governing board and to agree to an annual audit of each member.</p>
<p>&quot;I can tell you tomorrow's meeting will be bloody,&quot; Roman Azanza, director of brokerage Crosby Capital Markets, said.</p>
<p>Azanza is also chairman of the Capital Markets Development Council, a body funded by the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and is a strong supporter of the reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;But the trouble is that voting rights are on the basis of one vote per broker seat ... and the small boys don't really want the reforms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Azanza said big brokers supported the changes because they see them as beneficial in the long run. But the larger brokers were a minority in the industry, with about 20 of them accounting for nearly 80 percent of trading volumes.</p>
<p>The Philippine Stock Exchange has 185 brokers, many of whom had acquired seats cheaply when the exchange was small.</p>
<p>The SEC struck at one of the earning sources of small brokers on Monday night when it repealed a rule which forced companies making initial public offerings (IPO) to allocate up to 40 percent of the issue to brokers.</p>
<p>The rule was based on the assumption brokers would distribute the issue to small investors, but SEC officials say many made money out of it by sitting on it and buying on their own account if it became a hot stock. If the stock failed, they would simply return it to the underwriter.</p>
<p>When asked if he thought the resolutions would be approved by the required two-thirds majority, Sy, who is elected by brokers, said: &quot;We don't have an idea. It will be decided on the floor.&quot;</p>
<p>He said most brokers supported the SEC's views on the need for reforms but disliked the way it was portrayed that brokers were making money out of the IPO allocations.</p>
<p>On the need for surprise audits, Sy said brokers were worried about being victimised by the bourse management.</p>
<p>Molly Bayley, who advises the SEC on behalf of USAID's Capital Markets Development Project, said the SEC had been pressing for the reforms for a long time and that a meeting called by the bourse in March failed to produce results as brokers said they needed more time.</p>
<p>If the brokers refuse to act again on Wednesday, the SEC believes it can simply force the new rules on the bourse. In response to the threat of SEC action, Sy said: &quot;Well, that's a legal question.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
