<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133571" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurd chief Talabani backs U.S. peace bid.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurd chief Talabani backs U.S. peace bid.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Kurdish militia leader said on Tuesday he supported a U.S.-proposed ceasefire to end Kurdish infighting that has hit Washington's efforts to keep President Saddam Hussein out of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;I told Mr Pelletreau we are for an immediate ceasefire. I hope we are close,&quot; Kurdish faction leader Jalal Talabani told reporters after meeting U.S. envoy Robert Pelletreau in Turkey.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no conditions about a ceasefire,&quot; Talabani said. But he stopped short of announcing an end to clashes with the Kurdistan Democratric Party (KDP) of Massoud Barzani.</p>
<p>Pelletreau, who also called on Barzani to halt the feud at talks on Monday, cautioned there was more work to be done even if the guns fell silent.</p>
<p>&quot;We also discussed the need for that ceasefire to be followed by reconciliation talks under the auspices of the United States,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S.-sponsored peace talks during a lull in fighting last year failed to find a full settlement. Washington fears that Iran or Saddam might fill a power vacuum caused by the chaos.</p>
<p>&quot;Armed intervention by either Tehran or Baghdad is a very negative factor and should cease,&quot; Pelletreau said.</p>
<p>Barzani joined with Iraqi armoured troops to capture the key city of Arbil from Talabani's forces in August, prompting U.S. missile strikes on south Iraq in reprisal.</p>
<p>The KDP accuses Iran of sending men and munitions to Talabani's Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK). Tehran and Talabani deny the charges.</p>
<p>There has been no obvious sign of Iraqi or Iranian forces in the mountainous region in the last 10 days.</p>
<p>Barzani's alliance with Baghdad in August forced Washington to ditch aid, military and intelligence programmes in the north.</p>
<p>Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz on Tuesday attempted to head off the U.S. peace bid.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing at this time is to end fighting and prevent foreign intervention whether from the Iranian side or American and then proceed toward dialogue in Baghdad between the two (Kurdish) sides,&quot; the official Iraqi News Agency INA quoted Aziz as saying.</p>
<p>He blamed the United States for the Kurdish clashes.</p>
<p>&quot;America is fully responsible for the destruction and explosions in the Kurdish autonomous region because it is only serving its own interests,&quot; Aziz said.</p>
<p>The West encouraged the Kurds to break from Baghdad in 1991 but has been powerless to resolve the Kurdish power struggle, which broke out in fighting in December, 1994.</p>
<p>KDP forces prepared defensive positions on a hill in northern Iraq on Tuesday in readiness for a counter attack towards Arbil by Talabani's PUK.</p>
<p>KDP fighters set up mortar and machinegun posts on the 500-metre-high Heibet Sultan hill.</p>
<p>The PUK beat off a KDP attack on the strategic Dukan Dam on Monday. Some of Barzani's fighters, looking weary, were walking the 35 km (20 miles) back to the hill from Dukan.</p>
<p>&quot;There were a lot of deaths at Dukan, including civilians,&quot; local KDP commander Hassan Balamarani told Reuters. He did not say how many people had been killed.</p>
<p>Kurdish officials in Arbil said U.N. representatives in the region had spoken to both factions and arranged for a temporary truce along the road between the PUK-held city of Sulaimaniya and Koi Sanjak, south of Arbil, to allow an aid convoy to travel there on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
