<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13354" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa shows signs of strength, blesses nuns.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa shows signs of strength, blesses nuns.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Doctors battling to save the life of Mother Teresa, the Roman Catholic nun known as the Saint of the Gutters, said her condition showed signs of improvement but she remained on a respirator to assist her faltering heart.</p>
<p>&quot;She is improving,&quot; said an official at Calcutta's Woodlands Nursing Home where six doctors are keeping a round-the-clock vigil on Mother Teresa, 85, winner of the 1979 Nobel peace prize.</p>
<p>Doctors said her heartbeats were less irregular and she was breathing easier than before. She even managed to raise her hand to bless a group of nuns from the missionary order which she founded to care for the destitute and dying in Calcutta.</p>
<p>&quot;She blessed some of the sisters of Missionaries of Charity who were allowed to see her in the evening,&quot; Dr S.K. Sen, the nursing home's medical director, told reporters late on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother Teresa had no further cardio-vascular problems during the day, though her heart rate is still irregular,&quot; Sen said. &quot;We are very much enouraged by today's progress. By tomorrow we hope things will significantly improve.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked to what extent the respirator was breathing for Mother Teresa, who will be 86 on Tuesday, he said: &quot;It's 50-50. She is not yet able to breathe on her own but we hope she will be able to breathe completely on her own tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>She was admitted to the hospital last Tuesday with a high temperature and severe vomiting. Doctors said later she was suffering from irregular cardiac beats and a nagging fever caused by malaria.</p>
<p>Roman Catholics churches held special prayers for her recovery and thousands of people in Calcutta, including Moslems and Hindus, joined in prayers for the Albanian-born nun.</p>
<p>Special prayers were also held at Mother House, the sprawling headquarters of the Missionaries of Charity, the order which she founded in 1949 to relieve suffering among Calcutta's teeming millions.</p>
<p>The order now has nearly 3,000 people working in the slums of 200 cities worldwide to minister to the needs of the homeless, AIDS patients, the mentally depressed and orphans.</p>
<p>&quot;She is a living saint for everybody,&quot; said Sister Priscilla, a senior nun of the order.</p>
<p>&quot;She is greater than any mother in this world. I would have died of cold if i hadn't come here,&quot; said Nada, one of about 100 destitutes who found a haven at her Calcutta shelter for the homeless.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
