<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13358" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: North Afghan highway opening put off, radio says.</title>
<headline>North Afghan highway opening put off, radio says.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The planned reopening of Afghanistan's main northern Salang highway as a result of peace talks with an opposition alliance has been put off until Wednesday, official Kabul Radio said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The embattled Afghan government said last week that the Kabul-Salang highway would be opened on Monday or Tuesday following talks with the Supreme Coordination Council alliance led by Jumbish-i-Milli movement of powerful opposition warlord General Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>The radio said on Sunday the postponement of the opening had been made due to &quot;precautions&quot;. It did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The Salang highway, Afghanistan's main route to Central Asia, has been controlled by Dostum since he began fighting President Burhanuddin Rabbani's government in Kabul in January 1994 in alliance with Hezb-i-Islami party leader Gulbuddin Hekmatyar, then prime minister but rival to the president.</p>
<p>Hekmatyar rejoined the government as prime minister last June under a peace pact with Rabbani and has since been trying to persuade other opposition factions to follow suit.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Jumbish denied a Kabul government statement that the two sides had agreed to a ceasefire in the north.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
