<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133526" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Minor Metals--Asia traders see magnesium steadying.</title>
<headline>Minor Metals--Asia traders see magnesium steadying.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Magnesium prices appear to be steadying after a protracted slump and may even firm somewhat going into Japan's next round of quarterly price negotiations in December, Japanese traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said spot activity in Japan was very light, with most needs met through long-term contracts, although Chinese metal was quoted at about $2,400 a tonne on a CIF basis at major Japanese ports.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, Chinese metal is in the process of rising slightly,&quot; said a trader for a major Japanese trade house. He said prices may rise to $2,500 by December.  </p>
<p>&quot;We seem to have found a floor,&quot; added another trader, although he said a continued slide in the yen could make it difficult for producers to secure higher prices at the mid-December negotiations on January-March 1997 prices.</p>
<p>Prices for Russian metal were $100 to $150 a tonne above Chinese product, while Western metal, at $3,500 to $3,600 a tonne, retained its substantial premium.</p>
<p>Magnesium prices have fallen sharply in the past year, traders said, forcing out of business many small Chinese producers who jumped into the market when prices spiked higher in 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;Many of the smaller plants that opened when the price was high have closed down,&quot; said a European dealer in Hong Kong. &quot;Nobody is buying from them because of the bad quality material they produce.&quot;</p>
<p>China's biggest plants are located in the far north of the country, in the regions of Ninxia and Qinghai. They have an annual output of 10,000 to 15,000 tonnes each, much less than major European and North American producers, trade sources said. Chinese production costs have been estimated at around $2,700 a tonne.  </p>
<p>Traders estimated China's magnesium production capacity at 50,000 to 60,000 tonnes a year. One source said less than 10 percent of this is consumed domestically, while most of the remainder is exported to Japan.</p>
<p>According to the latest figures from the Japan Magnesium Association, Japanese magnesium demand fell 2.4 percent to 29,824 tonnes in the year through March 1996. Traders expected demand to be largely flat during the current year.</p>
<p>-- Edmund Klamann, Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-6179</p>
<p>-- Lynne O'Donnell, Hong Kong News Desk +85-2-2843-6470</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
