<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133553" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Malaysian LPG term talks deadlocked -- traders.</title>
<headline>Malaysian LPG term talks deadlocked -- traders.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Term talks for Malaysian liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) are stalled, with the exporter seeking a premium of about $34.00 and Japanese buyers suggesting a premium of about $25.00, traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Prices for the current annual term ending this month are set at $38.00 per tonne over Saudi Aramco's contract prices for the first cargo each importer procures, $37.00 for the second lot and $36.00 for the third, they said. Some traders said current prices for Malaysian term cargoes were too high, compared with the term price for Kuwaiti cargoes of $30.00 per tonne above Saudi contract prices.  </p>
<p>But they also said that as Malaysia was one of the few Asian crude suppliers to Japan, negotiators wanted to avoid hurting ties with the country by aggressively pushing for a price cut or by walking out of the negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;The buyers need to be very careful in the price talks because they cannot afford to run the risk of losing a precious non-Middle Eastern crude supplier,&quot; one LPG trader said. About 80 percent of Japan's crude comes from the Middle East.</p>
<p>The new prices are expected to set by early 1997 at the latest, traders added.</p>
<p>Saudi Aramco's contract prices are loosely based on the results of three-monthly spot LPG tenders and the company's own assessment of spot market trends.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
