<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133503" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS-Possible Lotus deal seen boosting Proton.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Possible Lotus deal seen boosting Proton.</headline>
<byline>Azhar Sukri</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Perusahaan Otomobil Nasional Bhd's (Proton) reported deal to buy British sports car maker Lotus Group would give the Malaysian maker the advanced engine technology it had long sought, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Proton's Vice President of Strategy and Operations Tengku Mahaleel Tengku Ariff declined to comment when asked about an Asian Wall Street Journal report on Tuesday that Proton was acquiring an 80 per cent stake in Lotus.</p>
<p>Proton chairman Yahaya Ahmad could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Proton was acquiring the stake for 210 million ringgit ($84 million) in cash and would also assume debt of 51 million ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;Lotus is not a very profitable company. Its market (for its cars) is not that big, but it does have the ability to produce fast engines,&quot; said Choo Swee Kee, automotive analyst at equities research house Vickers Ballas in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>&quot;Proton does not have the technology to build its own engine, but through this deal it could secure the technology to do so,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Other auto analysts agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The only market Proton has not tapped into is the luxury end. The Proton Perdana (luxury sedan) has not been selling very well,&quot; said an HG Asia analyst who did not want to be named. &quot;This would be a way for Proton to enter the 2000 cc-and-above luxury car market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An HLG Securities analyst said: &quot;The deal should not impact Proton's bottom line too much if it is only going to cost 261 million ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;Proton is obviously buying Lotus for the technology. If it is for (Lotus') profits, they cannot be that much.</p>
<p>&quot;Lotus may have developed technology which may not be suitable for Lotus cars, but which may be used by other manufacturers, like Proton,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>The reported deal appears to be a sign that Proton has outbid Daewoo Motor Co of South Korea for the stake.</p>
<p>Lotus chairman Romano Artioli had said on September 19 that Lotus would announce a new partner for the company &quot;within days&quot;. Lotus is owned by Artioli-controlled, Luxembourg-based Bugatti International SA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
