<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13353" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - August 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - August 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Sunday's Pakistani newspapers:</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- At least 23 people were killed in floods after rains in Lahore in central Pakistan.</p>
<p>- Banks, leasing companies and mutual funds have some seven billion rupees ($197 million) stuck up in the stock market on account of shares they under-wrote in the past three years.</p>
<p>- The government may not cut import duty on tea despite the growing demand from the Pakistan Tea Association.</p>
<p>- Sugar-cane growers and sugar mills urged the government to restrict import of sugar after assessing the actual shortage.</p>
<p>- Authorities in Khyber Agency burnt an abductor's houser in Bara sub-division and exacted a fine of 100,000 rupees.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- Weekend rains caused losses of 400 million rupees in five major markets in Lahore.</p>
<p>- Several letters of credit for basmati rice exports to the Middle East expired for lack of shipping service between Karachi and the Gulf.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL POST</p>
<p>- Mobile phone companies are seriously considering suing the government for breach of contract due to the continuing ban on cellular services in their most lucrative market in Karachi.</p>
<p>- A three-member World Bank Private Sector Assessment mission is in Islamabad for wide-ranging talks with government officials for revamping Pakistan's dormant private sector.</p>
<p>- PTCL is likely to pay a 1.78 percent cash dividend for the year ended in June.</p>
<p>THE NEWS</p>
<p>- Pakistan will send a team of senior economic officials to Washington next month to negotiate with the International Monetary Fund and World Bank at their annual meetings.</p>
<p>- Afghan Islamic Taleban militia overran Spina Shega, an important military base of Prime Minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar's Hezb-i-Islami party in the eastern province of Paktiya.</p>
<p>- Ex-finance minister Sartaj Aziz, secretary general of the main opposition Pakistan Muslim League, called the government's energy policy disastrous, saying privatisation of the Jamshoro power plant should be suspended and no more private sector thermal power project be approved for the next five years.</p>
<p>- The vessel Malakand is due to arrive in Karachi in the first week of September with previously embargoed U.S. arms for the Pakistani army and navy.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
