<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133525" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX to cut noon break for Euroyen, JGB futures.</title>
<headline>SIMEX to cut noon break for Euroyen, JGB futures.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's futures exchange said on Tuesday it plans to eliminate the midday break for floor trading of Euroyen and Japanese government bond futures and options contracts from October 28.</p>
<p>The Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX) said in a circular to its members that the one-hour break at 0315 GMT would be discontinued, bringing it in line with the practice for Eurodollar futures and options contracts.</p>
<p>Some futures traders, already chafing under a move by SIMEX to extend the Euroyen pit session by one hour earlier this month, were less than enthusiastic about the change.</p>
<p>&quot;They're taking everything away from us now. With Tokyo closed (for lunch), that is the time we'll be more quiet,&quot; said a trader with an Asian institution.</p>
<p>&quot;Tokyo dealers will be out for lunch. I don't see the locals giving up their lunch break and it's way too early for Europe to be trading. I don't see any extra business coming out of it,&quot; said a dealer with a European institution.</p>
<p>He said SIMEX was probably seeing an additional 1,000 lots traded in the Euroyen pit since it moved to extend the closing time to 1205 GMT on October 15.  </p>
<p>&quot;But it's not clear whether they've stolen additional market share or whether people are just taking their own time because they know they have longer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some traders saw the move as a competitive measure by SIMEX in the light of a decision by the Tokyo International Financial and Futures Exchange (TIFFE) to reduce its morning break by 30 minutes to one hour from November 5.</p>
<p>&quot;The attitude is, they shave half-an-hour -- we'll stay open all the time,&quot; said the trader with the European house.</p>
<p>But a spokesman for SIMEX said the extended hours were not being introduced for competitive reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;Our basis is that we're streamlining the floor trading hours. That's the only reason,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
