<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133573" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel apologises for Chirac security clashes.</title>
<headline>Israel apologises for Chirac security clashes.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu apologised on Tuesday after overzealous security men jostled visiting French President Jacques Chirac and manhandled journalists as he toured the Old City of Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The confrontation in the streets of the walled Old City dramatised Franco-Israeli differences over the terms for Middle East peace, the role of Europe and the status of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>A red-faced Chirac, teeth clenched and elbows flailing, forced his way through a forest of Israeli bodyguards and police to demand that they leave him in peace to greet Palestinians and visit Christian, Moslem and Jewish holy sites.</p>
<p>&quot;This is provocation. Stop this now. Do you want me to go back to my plane and go home to France?&quot; Chirac protested in English to the head of security.</p>
<p>The Israelis ignored his requests. Armed police forced Palestinian tradesmen to stay in their shops, kept Arab wellwishers well away from the French leader and repeatedly wrestled reporters and furious aides away from his cortege.</p>
<p>Netanyahu apologised privately and at a joint news conference with Chirac for what he called &quot;perhaps excessive zeal in trying to protect a friend&quot;.</p>
<p>He explained that VIP security had become an obsession since the assassination of former prime minister Yitzhak Rabin nearly a year ago by an extreme-right Jew.</p>
<p>The French leader said that in the light of the apology, he regarded the incident as closed.</p>
<p>Keen to repair the damage to Franco-Israeli ties from pictures of a furious Chirac shouting at intransigent Israeli security men, Netanyahu heaped praise on the French leader and said he could help improve relations with Israel's neighbours.</p>
<p>He said Chirac, who had lengthy private talks at the weekend with Syrian President Hafez al-Assad, had delivered a positive message that could help to revive peace talks with Damascus.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we very much value the readiness of France to try to help us in the effort we are making in order to reach a discussion obviously -- obviously in the end to renew the bilateral negotiations between us and Syria,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Netanyahu did not flatly rule out Chirac's call for a Palestinian state and stressed his commitment to respect signed agreements and negotiate peace with all of Israel's neighbours.</p>
<p>However Israeli resentment, and perhaps a determination to show the French leader who is boss in Jerusalem, flared again when he visited the Israeli parliament on Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Two far-right members walked out, one shouting &quot;anti-Semite&quot;.</p>
<p>Knesset speaker Dan Tichon said in a barbed welcome speech: &quot;We have disagreements with you, Mr President. The things you say are not always music to the ears of all the citizens of Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>He regretted that Chirac, keen to avoid imitating his Socialist predecessor, the late Francois Mitterrand, chose not to address the Knesset, which Israelis regard as the only truly democratic parliament in the Middle East.</p>
<p>PLO Paris representative Leila Shahid, who accompanied Chirac on his Old City tour, said the French leader had seen first-hand the treatment inflicted daily on 170,000 Palestinians under Israeli occupation in East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Chirac's spokeswoman Catherine Colonna said he had specially requested light security. Israeli officials replied the French had courted trouble by insisting dozens of cameramen and journalists follow the president in the narrow streets.</p>
<p>A French protest note said: &quot;The manifestly excessive number of security agents, the brutality and harassment they inflicted on Palestinians in the Old City and on journalists marred the friendly and relaxed spirit in which the visit was intended.&quot;</p>
<p>At St Anne's Church, granted to Napoleon III in 1856 by the Ottoman empire, Chirac refused to enter until Israeli police left what is officially French territory. After a 10-minute standoff, the police left through a side door.</p>
<p>Chirac appealed to Palestinian Christians to stay in Jerusalem and not despair. &quot;This city must remain open -- open to the Christians of Palestine and to the Christians of the world. Open to all religions,&quot; he said. He also visited the Wailing Wall, Judaism's holiest site.</p>
<p>Chirac had turned down a tour with the Israeli mayor of Jerusalem, Ehud Olmert, since the international community does not recognise Israeli sovereignty over Arab East Jerusalem, including the Old City, annexed after the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
