<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133585" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iran, Turkey working together on opposition groups.</title>
<headline>Iran, Turkey working together on opposition groups.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati said on Tuesday that Iran and Turkey had reached agreement halting cross-border activities by opposition groups of the two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed with Turkey not to help the opposition groups of the other country and we have started to cooperate together practically,&quot; Velayati told a development conference attended by seven developing Moslem countries held in Istanbul.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in common and mutual understanding with Turkey,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said both countries had mounted simultaneous operations against opposition groups on their own sides of the border. He did not disclose the nature of the operations.</p>
<p>Ankara has accused neighbouring Iran of allowing the Turkey-based separatist Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) to conduct operations in Turkey from Iran. The PKK are fighting for self-rule in Turkey's mainly Kurdish southeast.</p>
<p>Iran says the Mujahideen Khalq armed opposition group is allowed to operate in Turkey.</p>
<p>Turkey and Iran were involved in a diplomatic dispute earlier this month following the Iranian capture of an alleged Turkish spy.</p>
<p>Earlier this year a row erupted in which Ankara was accused of operating spy rings in Iran and Ankara alleged Iranian involvement in the killing of Iranian exiles in Turkey. The dispute led to the mutual expulsion of diplomatic staff from each country.</p>
<p>Iran accused Turkey in June of conducting air raids on the Iranian border and was angered by Ankara's military accord with Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
