<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133594" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Leftist Israeli lawmaker attacked by Jew in Hebron.</title>
<headline>Leftist Israeli lawmaker attacked by Jew in Hebron.</headline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A religious Jew threw hot tea in the face of Yael Dayan, a leftist member of the Israeli parliament, while she toured the West Bank town of Hebron on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;A Jew with a kippa (skullcap)...came up to me and asked if I wanted a cup of tea. And I said sure, and I have on my face scalding tea and on my chest,&quot; she told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Dayan, daughter of the late Israeli general Moshe Dayan, was treated in an ambulance in Hebron for burns to her face and chest and did not require hospitalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;Arrest him. Arrest him,&quot; a stunned Dayan said as steam rose from her face on a main Hebron street.</p>
<p>Israel Television, which carried footage of the incident, said her attacker, apparently a Jewish settler, fled the scene.</p>
<p>About 400 settlers live among 100,000 Palestinians in Hebron, the focus of Israeli-PLO talks on implementing a long overdue army redeployment in the town.</p>
<p>Dayan is a member of the main opposition Labour party which signed a 1995 deal with the PLO providing for Israeli handover of most of Hebron to Palestinian self-rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
