<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133517" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Megawati meets jailed supporters.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Megawati meets jailed supporters.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ousted Indonesian minority party leader Megawati Sukarnoputri on Tuesday met some of her 124 supporters jailed in connection with riots in Jakarta in July and said they were unlikely to be freed soon.</p>
<p>Judges in five separate trials in the Central Jakarta State Court are due to deliver decisions on Wednesday on whether the trial of the first group of 64 supporters, charged with assault and disobeying police orders, should continue or be dismissed as requested by defence lawyers.</p>
<p>The remaining 60 accused will have a similar decision handed down next Monday as part of the normal criminal trial process.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a big possibility the trials will proceed to the evidence-taking stage,&quot; Megawati said after visiting more than 100 of the accused interned at the Dutch colonial Salemba prison in central Jakarta.</p>
<p>Lawyers have said evidence-taking itself could last for about two months.</p>
<p>&quot;I came to pay them a friendly visit and boost their spirits,&quot; Megawati told reporters before leaving for the Pondok Bambu prison in east Jakarta, where the remaining accused are detained.</p>
<p>Lawyers said it was Megawati's first visit to her supporters in prison since they were detained on July 27.</p>
<p>The 124 supporters, including four women, were taken into custody after police raided the headquarters of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) on July 27.</p>
<p>Megawati, daughter of late founding president Sukarno, was ousted from the PDI leadership by a government-backed faction in June.</p>
<p>The eviction of her followers from the PDI headquarters by police and supporters of the rival faction sparked off the worst rioting in more than 20 years in the capital in which at least five people died.</p>
<p>Almost all of those arrested were her supporters, most of whom were in the headquarters.</p>
<p>Political analysts have said the government sought to sideline Megawati as it feared she could cut into the ruling Golkar party's vote in the 1998 general elections.'</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
