<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133561" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore Dec gas oil/jet spread slumps to $1.50.</title>
<headline>Singapore Dec gas oil/jet spread slumps to $1.50.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The December gas oil/jet fuel swap spread (regrade) was quoted on Tuesday at a low of $1.30/$1.55 on a huge stock build in China, Guam, Singapore and the Middle East, industry sources said.</p>
<p>About two months ago, the December regrade traded at $4.25 but now it has plummetted to around $1.50 on ample stocks and record price of gas oil, one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Is the low regrade because of the weakness of jet or the strength of gas oil?&quot; asked one trader.</p>
<p>The answer most traders say is due to both.  </p>
<p>Physical gas oil in Singapore, currently trading around the five-year high mark of $30.55 a barrel due to low distillate stocks in the U.S. and Europe has caused the regrade to narrow.</p>
<p>Asian gas oil prices were dragged up on the back of record Western prices which attracted Middle East cargoes. These cargoes were traditionally sold to Asia.</p>
<p>Jet fuel did not keep pace with the increases seen on gas oil as jet demand was relatively weaker and as a result the regrade crunched, one trader said.  </p>
<p>Sources estimated that oil trading firms and refiners have stored about five million barrels of jet fuel at independent terminals in Asia on expectations of strong winter demand.</p>
<p>But winter demand has yet to materialise and as a result there's strong downward pressure on prices, traders said.</p>
<p>The regrade is traditional at its widest in December and January due to peak winter demand for jet-kerosene fuel as a burning fuel in North Asia.</p>
<p>Last winter, the December regrade traded at a peak of nearly $5.00, a broker said.  </p>
<p>Jet fuel prices skyrocketted last December after unexpected refinery shutdowns in Indonesia and India, and Japanese refiners cutting operating rates by between five and 10 percent, one trader said.</p>
<p>But this year there are no such news and supplies have improved substantially as a result of the start up of new refineries in Thailand and South Korea, he said.</p>
<p>Although the regrade has crunched, the price of prompt physical jet fuel is still relatively high at above $30.00 per barrel free-on-board (fob) Singapore due to high crude prices, traders said.  </p>
<p>At this time last year, prompt physical jet fuel was trading between $22.50 and $23.00 per barrel fob Singapore.</p>
<p>Most traders said that because jet fuel prices are already quiet high and gas oil is expected to remain firm, it is not likely that the regrade will change substantially.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
