<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133582" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan bourse ends session nearly unchanged.</title>
<headline>Moroccan bourse ends session nearly unchanged.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca stock market on Tuesday remained stagnant compared with the previous session, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 435.31 points, up 0.01 percent over Monday's session.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders concentrated on privatisation bonds because it was the last day of subscription for the privatised Fertima fertiliser firm,&quot; said Reda Mellakh, a stockbroker at Casablanca Finance Intermediation (CFI). Morocco offered 30 percent of Fertima's stock on the bourse, equivalent to 690,000 shares, at 174 dirhams per share.  </p>
<p>Subscription was valid from 15 to 22 October 1996.</p>
<p>Investors rushed to privatisation bonds  BDP2.CS in order to buy Fertima's shares, which led to a value drop of BDP1.CS, Mellakh said.</p>
<p>BDP1 and BDP 2 were launched earlier this year by the privatisation ministry to attract investors to the bourse and boost the privatisation programme.</p>
<p>BDP2 rose 10 dirhams to close at 1,070, while BDP1 lost 17 dirhams to close at 1,145.</p>
<p>ONA Group, Morocco's largest private conglomerate, rose two dirhams to close at 477 dirhams.</p>
<p>Credit Eqdom was traded at 1.085, up five dirahms on the previous session.</p>
<p>The traded volume on the official market rose to 30.8 million dirhams of which 16.2 million were privatisation bonds. This compared with a traded volume of 27.2 million dirhams on Monday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.7 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
