<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133545" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan 1996 M2 growth may not hit 9-14 pct target.</title>
<headline>Taiwan 1996 M2 growth may not hit 9-14 pct target.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's M2 money supply growth may not fall within the official target of 9-14 percent in 1996, vice central bank governor Hsu Chia-tung said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that the growth may not fall within the target, but we will not aggressively seek to meet the target of nine percent,&quot; Hsu told reporters. Taiwan's M2 -- the broadest measure of the island's money supply -- grew 8.44 percent from a year earlier in August after rising 8.47 percent in July. The September figure will be announced on October 25.  </p>
<p>Hsu said liquidity in the banking system was loose at present.</p>
<p>&quot;It may affect the stability of consumer prices, so it is not appropriate to further loosen monetary policy,&quot; Hsu said, adding that the central bank would conduct open market operations when necessary to mop up excess funds.</p>
<p>The central bank said on Saturday after a board meeting that it would leave Taiwan's monetary policy unchanged.</p>
<p>Central bank officals have noted in recent days that current interbank money rates were low and foreign exchange rates stable, implying Taiwan's monetary policy needed no adjustment.</p>
<p>Bank governor Sheu Yuan-dong said on October 7 that liquidity had become &quot;slightly too loose&quot; but that the bank would maintain an &quot;appropriately loose&quot; monetary policy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
