<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133580" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraqi Kurds edge towards U.S.-mediated peace deal.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurds edge towards U.S.-mediated peace deal.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Iraq's warring Kurdish factions looked close to agreeing a U.S.-brokered ceasefire after two months of fighting that has hurt Washington's anti-Baghdad policy.</p>
<p>&quot;I told Mr Pelletreau we are for an immediate ceasefire. I hope we are close,&quot; Kurdish militia leader Jalal Talabani told reporters after meeting U.S. peace envoy Robert Pelletreau in Ankara on Tuesday. &quot;We have no conditions about a ceasefire.&quot;</p>
<p>Pelletreau had proposed a ceasefire plan to rival militia leader Massoud Barzani on Monday to end the recent clashes, which worsened on August 31 when Barzani asked Baghdad to intervene against his rival.</p>
<p>A Western diplomat close to the talks described Barzani as &quot;very positive&quot; about an end to the fighting.</p>
<p>But Talabani and Pelletreau stopped short of announcing a ceasefire and it was still not immediately clear how and when a truce might be enforced between Barzani's Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) and Talabani's Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>Numerous ceasefires between the two groups have been announced and broken over the past two years as the problems of distributing toll money from the Habur border crossing with Turkey -- in KDP-held territory -- and sharing the Kurdish capital of Arbil remained unsolved.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein helped Barzani's forces take Arbil after nearly two years of PUK rule in the city. Arbil had housed the autonomous Kurdish administration until the PUK captured it in January 1995.</p>
<p>The United States responded to Baghdad's involvement with cruise missile attacks last month, but despite an apparent respite brokered then by Pelletreau, the fighting continued.</p>
<p>Washington was forced to cancel aid, military and intelligence operations in the region it had encouraged the Kurds to rule -- only to see the factions fall out and split the mountainous region between the two warlords.</p>
<p>The United States got the warring parties round the table at two separate meetings in Ireland last year, but no concrete results were produced.</p>
<p>Before the Talabani-Pelletreau talks, PUK fighters were pessimistic about a ceasefire and its durability.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not hopeful for a ceasefire,&quot; said Kosrat Rasoul -- PUK commander and former prime minister of the joint Kurdish administration. His weary fighters on Monday beat off a KDP attack on the strategic Dukan Dam, a major source of power.</p>
<p>But signs were for a quiet day in the region on Wednesday after the U.N managed to arrange for a temporary truce along the road between the key PUK city of Sulaimaniya and Koi Sanjak, south of Arbil, to allow an aid convoy to travel there.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Iraqi Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz called on the Kurds to settle their differences under Baghdad's auspices and blamed Washington for what he said were its self-serving policies in the region that caused the fighting.</p>
<p>The U.S., by leading a Western strike force patrolling the region to protect the Kurds from Baghdad, has kept President Saddam Hussein out of the region for the past five years. But it has failed to come up with any long-term policy for Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
