<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133541" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Khmer Rouge, army troops bond in jungle town.</title>
<headline>Khmer Rouge, army troops bond in jungle town.</headline>
<dateline>PAILIN, Cambodia 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 3,000 villagers and Khmer Rouge dissidents descended on a temple in this remote jungle town on Tuesday to welcome Cambodian co-Premier Hun Sen and cheer moves to end years of war.</p>
<p>Hundreds of schoolchildren with rouged faces and villagers in their finest clothes gathered in the grounds of the Rattana Sophoan temple in the shadow of Yat mountain, about 12 kilometres (eight miles) from the northwest border with Thailand.</p>
<p>They enthusiastically clapped Hun Sen as he accompanied dissident Khmer Rouge leader Ieng Sary, the former bitter foe he was meeting for the first time.</p>
<p>In August, Ieng Sary split with Khmer Rouge hardliners loyal to Pol Pot and forged a ceasefire pact with the government.</p>
<p>Banners reading &quot;Peace and National Reconciliation&quot; and the national motto, &quot;Nation, Religion, King&quot; hovered above the crowd who clapped and sang as a band heralded Hun Sen's arrival.</p>
<p>&quot;I am so very happy that there is peace now,&quot; said Kohan, 61.</p>
<p>He has lived in and around Pailin since 1979 when the Khmer Rouge were ousted by Vietnamese forces after almost four years of the &quot;killing fields&quot; regime during which more than one million Cambodians died.</p>
<p>Ieng Sary, foreign minister under Pol Pot from 1975-79, was last month given a royal amnesty from a death sentence for his role in the genocide.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to stop the war, I want to have peace,&quot; said Mahry, 39, a Khmer Rouge soldier based at the dissidents' Phnom Malai base since 1979. &quot;We have been fighting for so long.&quot;</p>
<p>Since the weekend Khmer Rouge soldiers and government forces have been mingling in Pailing, the gem-mining and logging centre that fuelled the Khmer Rouge war machine, often reminiscing about former battles.</p>
<p>Bonding prevailed on Monday night when soldiers from both sides drank beer, took group photos and listened to a band flown in for the occasion.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Khmer Rouge and government soldiers worked together to provide tight security, frisking all who entered the temple and confiscating weapons.</p>
<p>As Hun Sen spoke, government bodyguards and Khmer Rouge soldiers stood side-by-side guarding the stage, decked out with Cambodian government flags and a portrait of the king and queen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PAILIN, Cambodia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
