<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133550" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia late palm olein stable in slow trade.</title>
<headline>Indonesia late palm olein stable in slow trade.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian palm olein prices were generally stable in late trading on Tuesday, ignoring news that Pakistan had devalued its currency, traders said.</p>
<p>They said olein stayed at 1,360-65 rupiah/kg in Jakarta, but quotes were also heard at 1,350-55 rupiah for small offtakes.</p>
<p>Crude palm oil was done at an equivalent of 1,145 rupiah/kg at a 500-tonne tender in Medan, where it fetched 1,165 rupiah at a tender last week.</p>
<p>Traders said that while Pakistan's 7.86 percent-devaluation of its rupee against the dollar was considered bearish news, it did not have any impact on the local market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan has to buy what it has to consume. It will not stop buying oil just because it has become more expensive for it,&quot; one trader said. &quot;But there is the possibility that the amounts purchased by Pakistan might be reduced.&quot;</p>
<p>Another trader said the devaluation move could trigger a move to step up Pakistan's production of oilseeds, but added that that process could take time.</p>
<p>Traders, meanwhile, said local buying interest remained thin on expectations of a continued weakening in prices.</p>
<p>-- K.T. Arasu, Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
