<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133568" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B shares dip in sluggish trading.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B shares dip in sluggish trading.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai B shares dipped in sluggish trading on Tuesday with overseas investors returning to the market to sell their shares following yesterday's holiday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index slipped 0.250 points or 0.51 percent to 48.476 points on volume of 5.0 million shares worth $2.1 million. Of 41 B shares, 37 traded with 15 down, 15 flat and seven up.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index moved down with weak support while overseas investors came back to the market to unwind their positions.  </p>
<p>&quot;Obviously overseas investors have lost confidence in the market and their attitude dominated the direction in which the market moved,&quot; one broker said. &quot;They are expected to unwind their positions further in the short term.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is still the possibility of breaching the key 48-point support level although there is unlikely to be any drastic movements, either up or down,&quot; a second broker said.</p>
<p>Shanghai Steel Tube was the biggest loser on a correction following yesterday's big gains, falling $0.006 or 4.61 percent to $0.124 on volume of 5,500 shares.  </p>
<p>Eastern Communications followed on overseas liquidation, falling $0.022 or 3.04 percent to $0.700 on volume of 366,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai Yaohua Pilkington Glass traded the most on inter-institutional trading, ending unchanged at $0.490 on volume of 643,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai A shares closed up on bullish market sentiment, and third tier stocks became the market buying focus, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A index rose 13.097 points or 1.29 percent to 1027.560 points on volume of 972.4 million shares worth 7.3 billion yuan.  </p>
<p>The SSE 30 blue-chip index put on 27.709 points or 1.07 percent to 2615.986 points.</p>
<p>Shanghai Erfangji was the star on bargain-hunting, jumping 0.52 yuan or 10.83 percent to 5.32 yuan on volume of 14.5 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
