<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133508" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen hit new contract highs on JGB rally.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen hit new contract highs on JGB rally.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen and Japanese government bond (JGB) futures shot to new highs on Tuesday on a positive 10-year JGB auction and a sharp drop in Japan's leading and coincident indicators for August.</p>
<p>&quot;The coincident and leading indicators tumbled hard. And the important thing is, they were both below the key 50 mark, suggesting a slowing economy,&quot; said a trader with a European institution.</p>
<p>&quot;The curve continues to flatten as people move their timing for a rate hike further out. They were not just buying but also selling the spread,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>The benchmark June Euroyen was quoted at a new high of 99.25 in late trade against its CME close at 99.20. March was at 99.37 against 99.34.</p>
<p>December JGBs rose above their previous high of 123.72 on SIMEX on swap-related buying early in the day, and continued to march upwards after the indicators and auction results.</p>
<p>They settled at 123.96 against their opening 123.60 after touching the psychological resistance level of 124.00.  </p>
<p>&quot;The big level everyone is looking for is 125.05, which is the all-time benchmark low yield,&quot; said the trader, adding that a break above the resistance area of 124.30 would take the contract into new territory.</p>
<p>But he said the market had already absorbed all Tuesday's positive factors and would need a burst of fresh good news to maintain its upward momentum.</p>
<p>Eurodollar futures finished steady in thin trade amid a lack of fresh leads ahead of the U.S. Treasury's two-year note auction. March ended at 94.30 against its CME close at 94.31.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the market failed to react to comments by New York Federal Reserve Bank President William McDonough, who said the Fed needed to continue keeping a close watch on inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;These were just the usual Fed mantras. There was nothing you could construe from them,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
