<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133647" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Health costs and insurance still U.S. problems.</title>
<headline>Health costs and insurance still U.S. problems.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although health reform may be off the political radar screen, insurance coverage remained a pressing problem and many poor and sick Americans reported having trouble getting medical care, according to a study released Tuesday.</p>
<p>A third of the 3,993 adults surveyed reported at least one &quot;core&quot; access problem last year -- being uninsured for at least part of the year, having trouble paying medical bills or being unable to get the medical care they thought they needed, even when going without meant living with pain or disability.</p>
<p>&quot;Is there a crisis in our health care system? The voices of the people that we surveyed give life to the statistics and tell us a story of millions of individual crises in getting and in paying for health care each year,&quot; wrote Karen Donelan and Robert Blendon, both at Harvard School of Public Health.</p>
<p>The researchers, whose findings appears in this week's Journal of the American Medical Association, told a news briefing that their study contradicts the conventional wisdom that people can get health care when they really need it.</p>
<p>&quot;That's untrue,&quot; said Donelan, adding that sick people were more likely to be sent to a bill collection agency than they were to get free or reduced fees from a doctor.</p>
<p>Getting care was a problem for 45 percent of the uninsured and 11 percent of the insured.</p>
<p>Other studies found that the uninsured often put off getting care, seeking help only when their conditions deteriorated.</p>
<p>Often that meant that costs were higher and the prognosis for recovery far more grim, said Drew Altman, president of the nonprofit Kaiser Family Foundation which supported the research.</p>
<p>Blendon said care might have been available somewhere in the state for these people, but was either not easily reached or the individuals had problems seeking out charity.</p>
<p>Health insurance was one of the hottest issues in the 1992 presidential race and the failed universal coverage initiative dominated President Clinton's first two years in office.</p>
<p>But in the 1996 race, while the number of uninsured passed 40 million according to the U.S. Census bureau, the topic has scarcely been mentioned although the anecdotes in this study -- people skimping on medicine because they could not afford it,  or paying off their bills on instalments -- were reminiscent of the stories told during the debate over the Clinton initiative.</p>
<p>Donelan and Blendon noted that &quot;very few Americans are uninsured by choice&quot; and that most who lacked insurance cited cost as a reason.</p>
<p>Forty percent of those who lacked insurance had gone without coverage at other times in the past five years. About 60 percent were without insurance for the first time in five years. Seventy percent of the uninsured had no coverage for at least six months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
