<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133646" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New England storm damage said &quot;in tens of millions&quot;.</title>
<headline>New England storm damage said &quot;in tens of millions&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Allan Dowd</byline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Maine 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A storm that poured more than a foot-and-a-half (0.5 metre) of rain on parts of the New England region caused damages estimated &quot;in the tens of millions&quot; of dollars emergency management officials said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The storm damaged roads and bridges, flooded homes and caused havoc to the area's transportation systems.</p>
<p>The head of the Massachusetts Emergency Management Agency, Peter LaPorte, in a telephone interview said the storm caused &quot;tens of millions (of dollars) in damages&quot; to the eastern part of the state.</p>
<p>New Hampshire Gov. Stephen Merrill, said through a spokesman that more than 40 communities in eight of the state's 10 counties had reported some loss. &quot;We have a rough preliminary estimate of $5-to-$7 million in damages,&quot; said Merrill's spokesman Jim Rivers.</p>
<p>In Maine, &quot;we're estimating damages of at least $10 million,&quot; said a spokesman for Gov. Angus King.</p>
<p>King said a request would be made for federal emergency assistance.</p>
<p>Rainwater runoff broke the primary supply pipe of the Portland Water District, leaving 140,000 residents of the state's largest city and surrounding communities without drinking water Tuesday.</p>
<p>Police said at least one person had been reported missing.</p>
<p>Authorities in New Hampshire kept a close eye on the Saco and Lamprey rivers that were both above flood stage. Rivers in Massachusetts were slowly dropping from rainfall received over the weekend.</p>
<p>Dams also remained a concern in Northern New England. Residents near Highland Lake in Westbrook, Maine, were urged to evacuate Tuesday after water began flowing around the lake's dam.</p>
<p>&quot;A Deluge of Misery&quot; read a banner headline in the Portland Press Herald. Portland received 12.27 inches (29.7 cm) of rain from the storm that began late (on) Sunday -- three times what it normally gets in the entire month of October.</p>
<p>Travel remained tricky throughout the region. A 100-foot section of the Maine Turnpike was washed out.</p>
<p>In Boston, portions of the subway system remained closed because of flood damage on Monday to Kenmore Square, an important junction, which remained under water, a day after the storm left the city.</p>
<p>But Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority officials, who operate Boston's subway system were actually pleased Tuesday afternoon. Pumps had been able lower the water covering the tracks to six-and-a-half feet from 20-feet on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Maine"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
