<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13363" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Students burn Hasina effigy, battle police.</title>
<headline>Students burn Hasina effigy, battle police.</headline>
<byline>Anis Ahmed</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Students backed by opposition parties battled police and burned an effigy of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina during a strike in the north Bangladeshi town of Bogra on Sunday.</p>
<p>The strikers barricaded streets, attacked the local office of the ruling Awami League, fought running battles with police and set alight hundreds of copies of the popular &quot;Janakantha&quot; newspaper, alleging it was pro-government.</p>
<p>Police used batons and teargas to try to disperse students who were throwing stones and home-made bombs, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The strike, called by the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP), to denounce the deaths of four students killed by police over the last few days, coincided with a visit to the area by Hasina.</p>
<p>Local officials said one policeman was killed by gunshots during clashes with pro-opposition students on Thursday.</p>
<p>Hasina told a cross section of people at the Bogra police headquarters on Sunday that the government had already suspended three police officers and ordered a judicial probe into the violent incidents.</p>
<p>The prime minister offered financial grants to the families of those killed, ordered the best possible medical care for the injured and urged Bogra residents to call off the strike.</p>
<p>Opposition legislators walked out of parliament in Dhaka on Sunday denouncing &quot;unprecedented police barbarity&quot; against opposition students and supporters.</p>
<p>They renewed their call for the resignation of Home (Interior) Minister Rafiqul Islam.</p>
<p>Hundreds of police raided the Dhaka university on Sunday, arresting nearly 30 outsiders who had been living in student dormitories and seizing weapons, university officials said.</p>
<p>Police stormed ten residence halls on the campus, flushed out people at gunpoint and searched their baggage. They seized revolvers, sawn-off rifles, shotguns and knives. The students were later allowed to return.</p>
<p>The swoop followed the resignation of the university's Vice-Chancellor Dr. Emajuddin Ahmed on Saturday over the deteriorating law and order situation on the campus.</p>
<p>Authorities closed down the 28,000-student university on Wednedsay following gunbattles between students and police.</p>
<p>Police said they fought armed activists from the BNP, headed by former prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia.</p>
<p>Hasina told police the home ministry had already given a &quot;blanket order&quot; to arrest terrorists and possessors of illegal firearms irrespective of their political identities.</p>
<p>Nearly 100 students have been injured in the clashes in Dhaka and Bogra, police told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
