<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133606" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli dollar-linked bonds fall in mixed trading.</title>
<headline>Israeli dollar-linked bonds fall in mixed trading.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli bond prices closed mixed on Tuesday, with the dollar-linked issues off sharply in response to the U.S.currency's drop in the local foreign currency market, traders said.</p>
<p>Indices:</p>
<p>* Government bonds general: unchanged at 168.16</p>
<p>* CPI-linked government bonds: +0.1 pct at 168.80</p>
<p>* Dollar-linked government bonds: -0.5 pct to 167.47</p>
<p>* Unlinked government bonds (Gilon - issued for four years): -0.1 pct to 167.01</p>
<p>* Bank of Israel short-term Makam bills: unchanged at 158.46</p>
<p>Inflation-index bonds were higher across the board by as much as 0.2 percent, said Haim Baron, head of mutual funds at Nesuah Trading and Investment. &quot;The index-linked market can be termed both interesting and positive,&quot; he said</p>
<p>Turnover was a relatively heavy 180 million shekels.</p>
<p>Unlinked bonds were lower, while dollar-linked bonds fell as much as 0.5 percent after the Israeli shekel rose sharply against the dollar and the basket of foreign currencies in nervous trading. The dollar representative rate was fixed at 3.246 shekels on Tuesday, down from 3.2693 yesterday.</p>
<p>Baron said he was not disturbed by the dollar's strength. &quot;Here and there, there will be changes (in the trend), but as long as interest rates go down, the shekel will continue to depreciate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Israel is expected to announce a reduction in the base short-term rate on October 28 by as much as 0.5 percentage point from the current 15.5 percent.</p>
<p>Eliezer Carmel, an independent financial consultant, said in his weekly survey of the market that the downward trend in index-linked yields could be coming to an end. &quot;There are rumours that the structure of new issues in November and December will include a bigger index-linked component,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This change...is likely to make it difficult for the yield in linked bonds to maintain their downward trend,&quot; he concluded.</p>
<p>But Baron said he was less certain that the government would emphasize inflation-linked bonds. He noted that in recent weeks, new issues have tended toward unlinked bonds.</p>
<p>In its monthly economic survey released on Tuesday, Israel Discount Bank estimated that the government would issue a net 5.8 billion shekels in September-December. But Baron said fundraising would have less of an impact on the market than the extent of redemptions by the public in the provident funds, which are the mainstay of the market.</p>
<p>($1= 3.246 shekels)</p>
<p>- David Rosenberg, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
