<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133609" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Next Egyptian privatisation at P/E of about eight. [CORRECTED 23/10 01:10 GMT]</title>
<headline>Next Egyptian privatisation at P/E of about eight. [CORRECTED 23/10 01:10 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Egyptian state company General Silos and Storage will go on sale for two days from October 28 at a price/earnings ratio of about eight compared to a market average of nearly nine, according to details made available on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The privatisation will be the first for about a month and mark the start of an accelerated programme in which the state expects to sell 91 companies by the middle of 1998.</p>
<p>The state's Holding Company for Rice and Flour Mills, which owns General Silos and Storage, will offer four million of the 10 million shares in the company at 37 pounds ($10.90) a share.</p>
<p>Two million shares are available to individuals, one million to financial institutions and mutual funds and one million to the Employee Shareholder Association, which buys on behalf of workers, a holding company official said.</p>
<p>The state does not intend to sell more than 40 percent, regardless of demand, because General Silos works in what the state considers a strategic sector -- the storage and transport of wheat for subsidised bread.</p>
<p>The official, financial department head Kamel el-Qumus Mikhail, told Reuters the company made net profits of 48.3 million pounds ($14.2 million) (corrects dollar conversion from &quot;$142,000&quot;) in the financial year 1995/6, compared with 40.489 million in 1994/5 and 32.992 million in 1993/4. The years end on June 30.</p>
<p>The company is forecasting net profits of 53.485 million pounds (corrects from 43.485 million pounds) in the current year and 61 million in 1997/8. For last year it will pay a dividend of at least 3.35 pounds, he said.</p>
<p>The company owns five grain silos with a total capacity of 529,000 tonnes and a fleet of 121 trucks. The state has valued its assets at more than 325 million pounds.</p>
<p>($1=340 Egyptian pounds)</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
