<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133607" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk Atas refinery urges new pricing mechanism.</title>
<headline>Turk Atas refinery urges new pricing mechanism.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's private Atas oil refinery, which will stop production from Wednesday in a pricing dispute, urged the government to introduce a new pricing mechanism.</p>
<p>&quot;The partners regretfully announce that the 50 percent reduction in output that was put in place to minimise the current losses has not helped the situation, and from tomorrow the refinery will cease production until a workable system for fuel pricing is introduced,&quot; Atas partners said in a statement.</p>
<p>Atas, owned by Mobil Corp, Shell, British Petroleum Co Plc and Turkish Marmara Petrol, has a maximum output capacity of 3.5 million tonnes a year (roughly 70,000 barrels per day) and a 14 percent share in Turkish production of petroleum products.</p>
<p>The partners blamed increasing losses -- $55 million so far this year after $43 million in 1995 -- for the work stoppage. An Atas official said the output has been halved gradually since end-September to minimise losses.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the last few months the international price of crude oil has risen significantly and the Turkish lira has continued to depreciate steadily against the dollar,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Industry sources say Atas will continue to meet its outstanding supply obligations from its stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;It can manage it for about two to three weeks,&quot; said an industry source, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Turkey's state-run Tupras refinery has the authority for crude imports to meet domestic demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Tupras should either increase its imports or use its stocks to meet domestic demand after Atas halts production,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Mobil's Turkey-based general manager Ertugrul Tuncer told reporters in Istanbul that a 40 percent price increase could end the refinery's losses. However, Tupras raised prices by seven percent on Monday.</p>
<p>The Atas partners offer the government to switch &quot;a robust Automatic Pricing Mechanism which would ensure that the price of refined products would take account of the costs of the raw materials involved and the cost of production.&quot;</p>
<p>Tuncer said the production stoppage might cause shortage in southern Turkey where the refinery is based.</p>
<p>Turkish economy officials fear any sharp oil price hike may fuel Turkey's chronic inflation, now running at around 80 percent.</p>
<p>Tupras officials were not immediatly available for comment.</p>
<p>Atas refinery in the southern port town of Mersin is owned 51 percent by Mobil, 27 percent by Shell, 17 percent by BP and five percent by Marmara.</p>
<p>-- Ankara Newsroom, 90-312-446 2940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
