<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133669" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New guide advises adults on child TV use.</title>
<headline>New guide advises adults on child TV use.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The television is a magical teller of tales, but a child's eyes can glaze over after watching hour after hour. For parents, the challenge is to decide how much is too much, as well as what and when your kids can watch.</p>
<p>TV Tactics, a new publication from TVSM Inc., publishers of The Cable Guide monthly and weekly Total TV, offers some suggestions to the decades-old problem of too much TV, and too much of the wrong type.</p>
<p>TV Tactics helps parents &quot;take control of their environment for themselves,&quot; said Editor Cree McCree.</p>
<p>The publication, which will be updated yearly, does not rate television or cable programmes, or make value judgments on &quot;moral&quot; or &quot;immoral&quot; viewing. Rather, it offers &quot;timeless good information&quot; to allow adults to make their own decisions on the viewing of television and cable programmes.</p>
<p>Currently, the average American child watches two to three hours of television a day, almost double the one to two hours recommended by the American Academy of Pediatrics.</p>
<p>Too much television has a &quot;numbing and deadening&quot; effect on children, McCree said.</p>
<p>In addition, the amount of violence that a child might observe -- as many as 200,000 acts of TV violence by the age of 18, according to TV Tactics -- leads children to believe &quot;life is one unending series of violent confrontations,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Crime and violence engage more (television) characters than all other occupations combined,&quot; says Dr. George Gerbner, founder and chair of the Cultural Environment Movement, a coalition of media-literacy groups.</p>
<p>&quot;Children are subjected to an accelerated impact of the adult environment before they read,&quot; says Gerbner.</p>
<p>One of the major problems with uncensored television viewing is children watching programmes that are inappropriate for their age group. TV Tactics suggests using the &quot;P-Chip,&quot; a variation on the controversial censoring device, the V-Chip.</p>
<p>In this case, the P-Chip stands for nothing more than &quot;parental control.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The solution to this problem isn't as simple as switching the channel to kiddie shows ... you must actively seek them out,&quot; TV Tactics says.</p>
<p>McCree says finding quality programming for children is not easy.</p>
<p>&quot;On one hand there is a lot more available, especially for preschoolers -- much of it due to cable -- on a fairly high calibre, such as The Learning Channel,&quot; McCree said. &quot;It's what PBS has been doing for years.&quot;</p>
<p>However, there has been less of an increase in quality programming for older children. &quot;Not much of an effort has been made in that area,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Content of cartoons, still the mainstay of many children's television diet, &quot;is still very violent,&quot; McCree said. She is also concerned about &quot;the blatant commercial tie-ins.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there has been a great deal of improvement on commercial tv,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>TV Tactics offers the following suggestions for making television viewing a positive experience:</p>
<p>- Establish quality control.</p>
<p>- Make television viewing a distinct event.</p>
<p>- Do not keep the television on as background noise.</p>
<p>- Try to place the television in an area or room other than one where much family activity takes place.</p>
<p>- Last but not least, keep a library of quality videos for children to watch.</p>
<p>Nothing, McCree said, is often more violent and disturbing to children than the local news. The best way to help children understand violence, as well as anything else they might not understand on television, is to discuss it with them.</p>
<p>&quot;Keeping silent about objectionable behaviour leads kids to believe that you endorse it,&quot; TV Tactics says.</p>
<p>&quot;Air your feeling about violence. Ask your kids if some other, more creative solution couldn't have been applied on a programme you've been watching.&quot;</p>
<p>To order a copy of TV Tactics, send $1 to TVSM Inc., P.O. Box, 989, Horsham, Pa. 19044-9826. Or call 1-800-440-TVSM (8876).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
