<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13366" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa's condition improves, many pray.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa's condition improves, many pray.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA, India 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The condition of 85-year-old Mother Teresa, the Nobel peace laureate whose devotion to the poor has inspired the world, improved slightly on Sunday, a spokeswoman for her Missionaries of Charity order said.</p>
<p>&quot;The doctors say her general condition has improved slightly although she is not out of danger,&quot; Sister Priscilla, a senior nun, told Reuters. She gave no further details.</p>
<p>Thousands of people, including Moslems and Hindus, earlier joined in prayer for the Albanian-born nun as she fought against a weakening heart in a nursing home in Calcutta, one of the world's poorest and most overcrowded cities.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa was admitted to the Woodlands Nursing Home on Tuesday with malarial fever and severe vomiting.</p>
<p>A hospital official said earlier on Sunday she was conscious but in grave condition because her heart remained vulnerable.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa, who marks her 86th birthday on Tuesday, remained on a respirator in intensive care and was still being fed intravenously.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother Teresa's condition shows no appreciable change,&quot; Dr S.K. Sen, medical director of the Woodlands Nursing Home, told reporters on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Her cardiac irregularity is under control but she still needs respiratory support. She still has a low-grade fever.&quot;</p>
<p>Thousands of people joined in Catholic Sunday services at churches across India in a spontaneous outpouring of concern.</p>
<p>Special prayers were held at the Mother House, the sprawling headquarters of the Missionaries of Charity, the order Mother Teresa founded 47 years ago to help the poor and destitute.</p>
<p>&quot;Even a maulvi (Moslem cleric) came and knelt in the chapel,&quot; Sister Priscilla said.</p>
<p>She said several Hindus and Moslems had also visited Mother House to inquire about Mother Teresa, adding: &quot;She is a living saint for everybody here.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 100 nuns and volunteers gathered at Sunday mass to pray for Mother Teresa, also known as the Saint of the Gutters for devoting her life to the poor.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa was conscious but had not spoken to anyone, Sen, the doctor, had said. Anything could happen, given her age, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;It might take days. At this age, anything could happen,&quot; Sen said in reply to a question about how long Mother Teresa would be on the respirator. Her doctors have forbidden visitors.</p>
<p>A panel of six specialists have kept a round-the-clock vigil over Mother Teresa, whose heart was fitted with a pacemaker in 1989 -- 10 years after she won the Nobel Peace Prize.</p>
<p>On Saturday, Mother Teresa's fever fell slightly and Sen had said she was showing surprising strength, though her weak heart complicated the picture.</p>
<p>&quot;She is showing enormous strength, given her age, which has surprised all of us,&quot; Sen said.</p>
<p>&quot;She is greater than any mother in this world. I would have died of cold if I hadn't come here,&quot; said Nada, one of about 100 destitutes at Mother Teresa's Calcutta shelter for the homeless.</p>
<p>Nada spent a year rummaging through rubbish heaps and begging for food in Calcutta's streets before he came to Mother Teresa's home. Now he, like others in the shelter, is praying for Mother Teresa to recover and resume her daily rounds.</p>
<p>&quot;All of them are praying to God for Mother's recovery,&quot; said Sister Dolores, one of six nuns who work in the home.</p>
<p>&quot;None of them has ever seen a bible, but they are praying because they know it could save Mother.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
