<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133608" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan's Zara to raise capital by 15 mln dinars.</title>
<headline>Jordan's Zara to raise capital by 15 mln dinars.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zara Investments, Jordan's leading holding company for tourism investments, announced on Tuesday a private placement to raise its capital to 40 million dinars ($56 million) from 25 million within a month, company officials said.</p>
<p>The private placement will be offered to its 147 existing shareholders, with a closing date of November 16.</p>
<p>&quot;The capital increase will finance some of the capital costs of our estimated $180 million worth of projects that are due for completion by 1999,&quot; Saleh al-Rifai, general manager of Zara Investments Holdings Company, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Zara, listed on the primary market of the Amman exchange, was set up in 1994 by investors and institutions, with a key 16 percent stake held by Cairo-Amman Bank and similar stakes by two leading Jordanian investors, Khalil Talhouni and Sabih al-Masri.</p>
<p>The company, which is pinning its hopes on a tourism boom after Jordan's peace treaty with Israel, acquired a 27.7 percent stake in the five-star Amman InterContinental.</p>
<p>A $20 million expansion programme is under way to add an extra 150 rooms, a mall and a health club by 1998.</p>
<p>Rifai said Zara had already received a commitment from the IFC, the World Bank's private investment arm, to take a $3 million stake in its equity capital.</p>
<p>Arab Bank was also negotiating to enter as a shareholder but no final agreement has been reached yet, Rifai added.</p>
<p>Rifai said the IFC had agreed to provide a $15 million loan to the company's three main projects currently under construction.</p>
<p>The projects include a 313-room five star hotel in Amman to be managed by U.S chain Hyatt Regency. The hotel is expected to be ready by end 1998 at a cost of around $42 million. An adjoining $30 million trade centre is under construction.</p>
<p>A $35 million 231-room Dead Sea village resort, to be managed by Switzerland's Moevenpick, will be opened in the first quarter of 1999.</p>
<p>Zara recently opened a 179-room hotel, also managed by Moevenpick, in the Nabatean city of Petra at a cost of around 14 million dinars ($20 million).</p>
<p>$1 = 0.7080 dinar</p>
<p>-- Suleiman al-Khalidi Amman Newsroom +9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
