<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133620" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mexican opposition seeks more open PEMEX selloff.</title>
<headline>Mexican opposition seeks more open PEMEX selloff.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's main opposition party supports a greater private sector role in the state-run petrochemical industry -- as long as the government makes privatization more transparent, a party leader said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Felipe Calderon, president of the National Action Party (PAN), said his party stood by its 1994 electoral platform advocating a wider private participation in Petroleos Mexicanos (PEMEX).  </p>
<p>&quot;PAN favors greater (private) participation and competition in the production and distribution in the petrochemical sector, with the exception that our platform makes reference to the generation and exploitation of hydrocarbons,&quot; Calderon said at the Americas Society here.</p>
<p>Amid intense poltical presure, the Mexican government of the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI) last week abandoned plans to totally sell its secondary petrochemical plants and instead offered joint state-private ventures.  </p>
<p>Calderon said that moves to privatize the petrochemical sector would need greater transparency and the inclusion of wider groups of shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico needs to revisit carefully in advance methods of participation and competition to avoid mistakes made with other privatizations,&quot; Calderon said.</p>
<p>He said the privatization would need to have a broad dispersal of shares.</p>
<p>Calderon said his party advocated increased federalism and a broader distribution of resources now controlled by Mexico City. &quot;We have to take a regional approach.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Mexican government would need to provide for the wellbeing of citizens through improved public services, such as drinking water, roads and electricity, but this strategy would not necessarily mean increased state spending.</p>
<p>&quot;One doesn't have to make a quantitative change in expenditure but a qualititative change,&quot; Calderon said.</p>
<p>Mexico needs political reform and greater transparency in governance to free the country from recurrent economic crises, Caldera said.</p>
<p>&quot;Either we change the political system to be more democratic or face recurrent economic crises,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
