<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133640" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Four drugmakers have higher profits.</title>
<headline>Four drugmakers have higher profits.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four major pharmaceutical companies reported third quarter earnings Tuesday in line with or above Wall Street expectations, benefitting from strong demand for profitable new drugs.</p>
<p>Drug maker Eli Lilly &amp; Co. said earnings per share jumped 34 percent in the third quarter, including a one-time gain, and Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. posted a 9 percent profit gain as strong worldwide sales outweighed the loss of a key U.S. patent on a heart drug.</p>
<p>American Home Products Corp., the maker of the pain relievers Advil and Anacin, said earnings rose 25 percent percent, excluding a year-ago restructuring charge. Warner-Lambert Co. reported an earnings rise of 16 percent, excluding a gain in the 1995 quarter.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said the companies, and others in the group, benefitted in the quarter from the launching of new drugs with generally higher prices and profit margins.</p>
<p>Last week companies including Merck and Co. Inc., Pfizer Inc. and Schering-Plough Corp. beat Wall Street expectations with their third quarter results.</p>
<p>Managed health care has also helped boost drug unit sales growth by increasing patient compliance with drug regimes and opting for preventive drug therapies in an effort to avoid expensive surgeries and hospital stays, the analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The dominant underlying theme is strong demand for products,&quot; said Gruntal and Co. analyst David Saks.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said profits rose 9 percent to $753 million, or $1.50 a share, in the third quarter on revenues of $3.74 billion. The results compared with year-ago earnings of $689 million, or $1.36 a share, on revenues of $3.41 billion.</p>
<p>Wall Street had expected earnings of $1.48 a share, according to First Call, which tracks analysts' forecasts.</p>
<p>The New York-based company said strong worldwide sales of its newer drugs including the cholesterol-lowering Pravachol and the anti-cancer agent Taxol more than offset a large drop in U.S. sales of its Capoten heart drug following the expiration of its U.S. patent.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said domestic Capoten sales plunged 72 percent in the quarter as a result of the patent's loss in February and competition from lower-priced generic versions.</p>
<p>It did not provide a dollar figure for Capoten sales, but noted that worldwide Capoten sales were still expected to exceed $1 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>Eli Lilly said profits rose to $415.6 million, or 76 cents a share, compared with year-ago profits of $310.5 million, or 54 cents a share. Sales rose 11 percent to $1.80 billion from $1.63 billion.</p>
<p>The Indianapolis-based company said results were boosted by the sale of domestic marketing rights for its Ceclor CD and Keftab antibiotic drugs to Dura Pharmaceuticals Inc. for $100 million, which increased earnings by 12 cents a share. Without the one-time gain, the results matched forecasts for 64 cents a share.</p>
<p>Eli Lilly said sales of its anti-depressant drug Prozac grew 10 percent despite competition from generic forms of Prozac in Canada and competition in France. Prozac's sales reached $1.75 billion for the first nine months of the year.</p>
<p>American Home, based in Madison N.J., met forecasts with profits of $491.1 million, or 77 cents a share, up from $276.5 million, or 45 cents a share. The year-ago numbers included a restructuring charge of $117 million, or 19 cents a share. Excluding the charge, earnings rose 25 percent from 1995.</p>
<p>Revenues rose to $3.47 billion from $3.26 billion.</p>
<p>The company cited the anti-obesity drug Redux, approved in the United States in April, among products driving its earnings.</p>
<p>Morris Plains, N.J.-based Warner-Lambert reported third quarter net income of $153 million, or 56 cents a share, compared with $132 million, or 48 cents a share, a year ago.</p>
<p>The 1995 number excludes a one-time gain of $82 million, or 31 cents a share, from the sale of the company's PRO toothbrush business last year to Gillett Co. Analysts had expected the company to earn 54 cents a share.</p>
<p>Revenues edged down to $1.76 billion from $1.77 billion. The company said the strong dollar cut its foreign sales by 3 percent in dollar terms.</p>
<p>Warner-Lambert's stock ended down 87.5 cents at $65.25 on New York Stock Exchange. Eli Lilly rose 50 cents to $69.25, Bristol-Myers gained $2.75 at $106.875, and American Home lost 50 cents to $65.875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
