<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133635" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: California wildfires destroy more than 80 homes.</title>
<headline>California wildfires destroy more than 80 homes.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>MALIBU, Calif 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An army of weary firefighters on Tuesday battled wildfires that burned more than 80 homes across southern California, consumed more than 20,000 acres (8,000 hectares) and threatened the celebrity enclave of Malibu.</p>
<p>Firefighters backed by water-dropping tanker planes and helicopters and aided by lighter winds struggled to control the fires, but authorities said most of the major blazes remained out of control.</p>
<p>A wildfire that raced across the Santa Monica Mountains to the sea on Monday charred more than 13,000 acres (5,000 hectares) and forced several thousand people out of their homes. Flames on Tuesday continued to pose a serious danger to Malibu and other coastal communities.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors declared a local emergency on Tuesday and said it would ask Gov. Pete Wilson to issue an emergency decree to free up state funds.</p>
<p>The latest rash of wildfires struck almost three years to the day after a firestorm swept southern California from the Mexican border north to Malibu, destroying nearly 1,000 homes and causing hundreds of millions of dollars in damage.</p>
<p>In San Diego County, authorities said a firestorm gutted at least 70 homes overnight in Carlsbad and San Marcos. Carlsbad police Lt. Greg Fried said the damage estimate was &quot;extremely conservative&quot; and more than 80 homes may actually have been lost in the 6,000-acre (2,400-hectare) blaze.</p>
<p>The fire broke out in the Elfin Forest on Monday afternoon and quickly spread to nearby canyons lined with homes about 15 miles (25 km) north of San Diego.</p>
<p>Hundreds of Carlsbad residents were evacuated and one firefighter suffered smoke inhalation. One man was listed in critical condition with burns over 45 percent of his body and was being treated at a local burn center.</p>
<p>Marines from nearby Camp Pendleton joined the fire lines as volunteers and civilian fire crews from the base were dispatched to help battle the blaze.</p>
<p>Don Kruger returned to his home in San Marcos on Tuesday morning to find it a smoldering shell. A house next door was left unscathed. &quot;It seems the roofs have been the difference,&quot; he said. Fire officials said most of the burned homes had wood-shingle roofs, popular in the late 1970s.</p>
<p>Authorities said it was the most destructive fire in San Diego County in more than a decade.</p>
<p>Another fire that sprang up overnight in the Otay Mountains southeast of San Digeo had consumed 5,000 acres (2,000 hectares) and had forced the closure of the Otay Mesa border crossing with Mexico.</p>
<p>Malibu was the focal point of a massive firefighting effort on Tuesday after a two-mile (3 km)-wide wall of smoke and flame roared across the Santa Monica Mountains to the edge of the Pacific Ocean, threatening seaside mansions and beachfront bungalows.</p>
<p>Fire Capt. Steve Valenzuela said the blaze was about 10 percent contained on Tuesday morning. At least two homes were destroyed along with several sheds and mobile homes.</p>
<p>About 2,500 firefighters backed by tanker planes and helicopters were battling to control the blaze, helped by some of the city's most famous homeowners who stayed behind to defend their properties, ignoring appeals to evacuate.</p>
<p>Actress Shirley MacLaine watered down the roof of her home to protect it from flames that licked dangerously close by.</p>
<p>The fire started on Monday near the suburb of Calabasas, 35 miles (55 kms) northwest of downtown Los Angeles. Fueled by fierce, dry Santa Ana winds, flames raced to the coast in less than six hours.</p>
<p>Five people were injured including a firefighter whose truck collided with another fire engine on a winding mountain road. Authorities said they had no clues on the fire's cause.</p>
<p>In the exclusive Orange County community of Lemon Heights southeast of Los Angeles a wind-whipped blaze destroyed 10 homes and damaged 19 others on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MALIBU, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
