<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133639" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends off, LME stock puzzle continues.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends off, LME stock puzzle continues.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper ended weaker despite a further sharp drop in LME stocks Tuesday and news of the arrest of Yasuo Hamanaka, the disgraced former head trader at the heart of the Sumitomo Corp copper scandal.</p>
<p>LME stocks tumbled 13,075 tonnes, in line with trade expectations. The drop was already factored into the market, a broker said.</p>
<p>Stocks at Long Beach, Calif. fell 3,000 tonnes to 40,125 tonnes. LME stocks have fallen by about 100,000 tonnes in recent weeks while prices have failed to rally convincingly.</p>
<p>COMEX warehouse stocks rose 1,469 short tons to 22,314 short tons Tuesday.</p>
<p>December COMEX settled 0.55 cent weaker at 92.45 cents per pound, traded narrowly between 93.00 and 92.00 cents.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 9,000 lots compared to Monday's official 9,120 lots.</p>
<p>News that Hamanaka has been arrested on suspicion of forging documents used in metal trades with U.S. broker Merrill Lynch failed to move a market which traders believed the Japanese trader dominated for so long.</p>
<p>Unions at Kennecott Copper tentatively agreed a new deal.</p>
<p>The Utah producer was hit by a two-day strike last week.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Bloomsbury Minerals Economic Limited said world refined copper surplus is likely to reach 100,000 tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Much of the large amount of metal drawn from LME stocks in recent weeks was sent to Chinese state stockpiles and has not been consumed, Bloomsbury said.</p>
<p>An LME and COMEX broker said there were going to be further drawdowns in LME stocks over the coming weeks, but there is no agreement where all the metal is going.</p>
<p>Attractive arbitrage rates have made it profitable to take metal out of Hamburg or Long Beach for shipment to COMEX warehouses in San Manuel or to U.S. consumers, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the fact that there is no metal going into LME warehouses means to me that there is still a relative tightness,&quot; the broker said. &quot;All this new production talked about has not filtered through the system yet.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
