<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133633" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Swiss revelation on Jewish assets stirs protest.</title>
<headline>Swiss revelation on Jewish assets stirs protest.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jewish leaders and a U.S. senator accused Switzerland on Tuesday of conspiring with Communist Poland to confiscate the unclaimed assets of Holocaust victims and said the Swiss may have entered into similar deals with other East European countries.</p>
<p>The accusations came after the Swiss published a secret 1949 protocol between Switzerland and Poland in which they agreed to use the assets of heirless Poles in Swiss banks to help compensate Swiss citizens for property nationalised in the communist country.</p>
<p>Jewish groups say that most of the heirless assets were from Jews who died in the Holocaust and who had used Swiss banks as a safehaven from the Nazis.</p>
<p>World Jewish Congress Vice President Kalman Sultanik called on Switzerland to provide immediate restitution for the funds it confiscated and said the deal meant that &quot;first people were murdered in the Holocaust and then robbed in Switzerland.&quot;</p>
<p>Senate Banking Committee chairman Alfonse D'Amato said the protocol was a &quot;shocking&quot; admission by Switzerland that it had confiscated the unclaimed assets of Polish Holocaust victims to benefit Swiss citizens.</p>
<p>The Swiss Foreign Ministry declined comment on what exactly the protocol meant but insisted it did not mean that Swiss citizens were compensated with Jewish funds.</p>
<p>In a scathing three-page letter to Swiss Confederation President Jean-Pascal Delamuraz, D'Amato said the agreement showed &quot;that the Swiss government was actually part of a conspiracy with the Communist government of Poland&quot; to confiscate the assets.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;This dishonesty and deception by any government would be offensive against the background of one of the saddest chapters in human history. It is especially disturbing given Switzerland's reputation for neutrality and compassion.&quot;</p>
<p>He called on Switzerland to now provide all information regarding the protocol, to describe the assets it took, name the people it took them from and the methods it used.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, D'Amato, a New York Republican, wondered how it was possible to declare assets &quot;heirless&quot; only four years after the war.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the heirs could have been teenagers trying to rebuild their lives without knowing that they had to go to Switzerland and file claims,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that since Switzerland returned heirless property to other communist nations at about the same time, it was possible that these funds were also used to pay compensation to Swiss citizens and businesses as well.</p>
<p>The Senate Banking Committee is investigating activities of Swiss banks during and after the Second World War.</p>
<p>The protocol, discovered in Swiss archives, called for creating a bank account &quot;N&quot;, that used dormant Polish accounts and proceeds from Polish coal sales for the compensation payments.</p>
<p>The controversial protocol said: &quot;At the start of each month, beginning Jan. 1, 1951, the balance of account N will be credited to the Swiss government, which will use it as a partial payment toward the global compensation fixed in the first and third articles of the treaty.&quot;</p>
<p>It referred to a treaty under which Poland agreed to pay Switzerland 52.5 million Swiss francs ($41.5 million) for property the then-communist government in Warsaw seized from Swiss citizens after the war.</p>
<p>The Swiss Foreign Ministry declined to comment on the contents of the protocols. It denied that a spokesman had earlier confirmed, as reported by Reuters and other news media, that the documents showed Swiss citizens were compensated with Jewish funds.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps there was some confusion today, this cannot be excluded. It is possible we said there is a connection between the treaty and the dormant assets, but not that Jewish funds were used to compensate Swiss citizens,&quot; said foreign ministry spokesman Hans-Ruedi Bortis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
