<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13361" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa, slightly better, blesses nuns.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa, slightly better, blesses nuns.</headline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa, battling for her life on a hospital respirator, had no further heart problems on Sunday and blessed a group of nuns who visited her in the intensive care unit, a doctor said.</p>
<p>&quot;She blessed some of the sisters of Missionaries of Charity who were allowed to see her in the evening,&quot; Dr S.K. Sen, medical director of Woodlands Nursing Home, told reporters. &quot;She blessed them by raising her hand gently.&quot;  </p>
<p>Sen said the nuns were allowed to visit the renowned Roman Catholic missionary after doctors had noticed a slight improvement in her condition.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother Teresa had no further cardio-vascular problems during the day, though her heart rate is still irregular,&quot; Sen said.</p>
<p>The 85-year-old missionary, who was taken to hospital on Tuesday with a high fever and severe vomiting, no longer had a temperature but continued to need the respirator, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;She is still seriously ill. We cannot say she is out of danger unless respiratory support is switched off,&quot; he said. &quot;We are very much encouraged by today's progress. By tomorrow we hope things will significantly improve.&quot;</p>
<p>Sen was asked to what extent the respirator was breathing for Mother Teresa. &quot;It's fifty-fifty,&quot; he said. &quot;She is not yet able to breathe on her own but we hope she will be able to breathe completely on her own tomorrow.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
