<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133636" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole promises Truman-like election upset.</title>
<headline>Dole promises Truman-like election upset.</headline>
<byline>Sue Kirchhoff</byline>
<dateline>TROY, Mich. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole on Tuesday told voters to ignore polls and pundits who say the election is all but over, vowing a come-from-behind victory.</p>
<p>Stepping up the pace of his campaigning, Dole scurried through Michigan and Ohio charging President Bill Clinton had never made a promise he meant to keep and touting his own plan for a 15 percent tax cut.</p>
<p>With only two weeks remaining until the election, new national polls showed Dole trailing Clinton by more than 20 points. The Reuters-Zogby daily tracking poll showed Clinton at 46 percent compared to 34.7 percent for Dole.</p>
<p>But Dole recalled a stunning Democratic victory as he predicted voters would defy the conventional wisdom and send him to the White House.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm like Harry Truman. I'm from the Midwest and I'm plain-spoken and I'm going to win whether you like it or not,&quot; Dole told a cheering rally in Troy.</p>
<p>Dole was referring to Democratic President Harry Truman's 1948 upset of New York governor Thomas Dewey. A famous photograph shows the triumphant Truman holding up the front page of the Chicago Tribune, which erroneously announced &quot;Dewey Wins&quot;.</p>
<p>Claiming Clinton would promise anything in coming days in his drive to get re-elected, an almost giddy Dole told the crowd, &quot;anything you ever wanted in your life, the next two weeks is the time to write the president.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You can just give me a note, I'll take it to him. I may want something myself,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>Dole's performance ranged from disconnected to delighted as he finished a bus tour through Michigan and moved on to a boisterous rally at Otterbein College in Westerville, Ohio -- one of the biggest crowds the campaign pulled in during a two- day Midwest swing.</p>
<p>Obviously buoyed by the big crowd, Dole grinned like a Cheshire cat as he shook hands with supporters after his speech. Earlier in the day in Grand Blanc, Michigan, Dole, battling a cold, stumbled over syntax.</p>
<p>Despite the stepped-up schedule, there was a sense the campaign was running out of steam. Dole spent most of his time in conservative areas of Michigan that should be firmly in his column by now. State polls, however, show Dole trailing Clinton by double digits.</p>
<p>At every stop he called for tightening federal laws to bar noncitizens from contributing to political campaigns.</p>
<p>But the Clinton campaign has begun fighting back, running an ad that accused Dole of desperation tactics.</p>
<p>Asked whether his character attacks on Clinton were backfiring Dole said,&quot;I don't think so.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
