<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133672" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Digital posts $66 million loss.</title>
<headline>Digital posts $66 million loss.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Digital Equipment Corp. said Tuesday it posted a deeper-than-expected loss of $66 million in its fiscal first quarter after a difficult worldwide realignment of its sales force hurt its business.</p>
<p>The Maynard, Mass.-based computer manufacturer said it lost $65.9 million, or 48 cents a share, for the three months ended Sept. 30, compared with a profit of $48.2 million, or 26 cents a share, in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The per-share loss was more than three times the 14 cents that Wall Street was expecting, according to First Call, which tracks analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>Digital's stock plunged $5.75 to $28.625 in afternoon trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The sales force changes took longer, and were more difficult to implement and more distracting to the sales force then were planned,&quot; Chairman Robert Palmer told reporters during a conference call.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result, our selling ability was temporarily reduced, and product revenues were significantly affected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The sales realignment resulted in new management and sales representatives taking new accounts, but the changes began to show positive results toward the end of the quarter, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect as a result that we will return to profitability in the December (second) quarter as the sales pick up and we get this thing behind us,&quot; Palmer said.</p>
<p>The second consecutive quarterly loss, following six quarters of profits, was a clear blow to Digital's turnaround hopes and called into question Palmer's future.</p>
<p>Analysts said that, if Digitial failed to turn a profit for the fiscal second quarter, Palmer, who is also president and chief executive officer, may be out.</p>
<p>&quot;If that (profit) does not happen, I think the level of support that Mr. Palmer currenly enjoys from the board of directors is going to evaporate,&quot; said Terry Shannon, editor of the Ashland, Mass.-based newsletter &quot;Shannon Knows DEC.&quot;</p>
<p>Palmer said he has the continued support of the board and the company has a capable management team.</p>
<p>Since Palmer restructured the company into business units, Digital's profitability excluding restructuring charges has improved by more than $1 billion and the balance sheet has strengthened, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a difficult turnaround,&quot; he said. &quot;We've been working through a lot of previous problems, but we remain committed.&quot;</p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer Vincent Mullarkey said fluctuations in the dollar resulted in a loss of more than $70 million for the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Had the currency impact year-over-year not occurred, we would essentially have been break even for the quarter,&quot; Mullarkey said.</p>
<p>During the fiscal first quarter sales of Digital's fast-performing Alpha computer systems grew at only 4 percent as a direct result of the changes and realignments in its sales organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm pretty confident that as we get stable with the sales force, we'll see the Alpha revenues continue to grow again,&quot; Palmer said.</p>
<p>Mullarkey said the company made solid progress in the management of gross margins and operating expenses, despite its revenue shortfall. Total operating expenses were essentially unchanged at $900 million in the quarter.</p>
<p>Digital said the performance of its personal computer business continued to improve and the unit made good progress toward breaking even or turning a profit by the end of the second quarter.</p>
<p>Industry-wide price cuts in personal computers earlier this year and an inventory build-up hurt Digital's personal computer unit in its fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Enrico Pesatori, head of the personal computer unit and heir apparent to Palmer, resigned suddenly in early July, citing distribution problems.</p>
<p>The company said it ended the quarter with about 57,000 employees, a reduction of 2,100 from the end of fiscal 1996. Personnel levels are expected to fall further to 53,000 at the end of the fiscal year, Palmer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
