<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133626" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries narrowly lower at midday.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries narrowly lower at midday.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury prices remained narrrowly lower at midday on Tuesday as dealers positioned themselves for new supply.</p>
<p>The Treasury will sell $18.25 billion in two-year notes shortly. The deadline for bids is 1300 EDT/1700 GMT. Auction results are due around 1340 EDT.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the Treasury will sell $12.5 billion in five-year notes on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The market opened lower, at much the same levels that it was trading at in the early afternoon.  </p>
<p>The market treaded down to its session lows on news that the BTM/Schroders U.S. adjusted chain store sales index rose 0.8 percent in the October 19 week versus the prior week.</p>
<p>The Redbook chain store sales report is due at 1455 EDT/1855 GMT.</p>
<p>The other data on tap for later this afternoon is not expected to move the market.</p>
<p>September federal budget figures, due at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT, are expected to show a monthly budget surplus of $29.4 billion after a deficit of $41.83 billion in August.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the market is focusing on supply. Two-year Treasury notes were last auctioned on September 25. At that time the notes were sold at an average yield of 6.08 percent. A six percent coupon was awarded to the $18.26 billion in two-year notes sold. The bid-to-cover ratio was 2.64 and the auction attracted non-competitive bids totaling $1.45 billion.</p>
<p>In when-issued trade shortly before this two-year note auction, the notes were yielding 5.94 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts at MMS International said technical indicators have &quot;eased off from their overbought position, pointing to additional gains once supply is cleared.&quot;</p>
<p>In when-issued trade, the five-year Treasury notes to be auctioned on Wednesday were yielding 6.28 percent.</p>
<p>Three-month bill rates were down one basis point to 4.99 percent. Six-month bill rates were up one basis point to 5.13 percent.</p>
<p>Year bill rates were up two basis points to 5.26 percent.</p>
<p>The 6-1/2 percent ten-year note was down 5/32 to 99-23/32 to yield 6.54 percent.</p>
<p>Dipping in early afternoon trade again, the 6-3/4 percent 30-year bond was down 7/32 to 99-2/32, yielding 6.82 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
