<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133604" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Frankfurt/Schiphol seek Euro-rail standards for air cargo.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt/Schiphol seek Euro-rail standards for air cargo.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frankfurt airport (FAG) and its Dutch counterpart, Amsterdam-Schiphol have set up a joint working group to study the development of rail services for the air cargo industry, Frankfurt airport said in a statement released here.</p>
<p>The main issues are the need for rapid progress, for co-ordination and standardisation -- so that there is a common European approach -- and ensuring the support of the Dutch and German governments, the statement added.</p>
<p>The first results of the working group's studies are expected to be presented at next September's International Frankfurt Air Days, it added.</p>
<p>However the scheme is not exclusive to the two airports and they welcomed any other interested parties, FAG's head of freight logistics marketing, Bernhard Lessman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to be a co-ordinator or moderator and provide an interface for dealing with the rail industry,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The first step will be to launch a conventional service for the air cargo industry, as both airports expect the demand for faster and more frequent services to increase, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;This train could be based on the recently launched German &quot;Cargosprinter&quot; service which is able to carry large containers,&quot; added Lessmann.</p>
<p>&quot;But to make sure it is a success, we must get the cost of air cargo carried by rail down to the same level as that now carried by road,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The working group's joint action programme has three primary issues, FAG said. These are the co-ordination of efforts towards a conventional air cargo shuttle train, the sharing of market information and establishing a joint view on future project developments.</p>
<p>Such projects include high speed freight trains, combi-trains and radically new transport systems, such as the underground cargo pipeline to move flowers between Schiphol, Dutch flower auctions and a future rail terminal near the airport.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
