<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133629" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT -  Monsanto Q4 EPS view cut.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT -  Monsanto Q4 EPS view cut.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- NatWest Securities Corp said it reduced its fourth quarter earnings estimate to $0.13 a share from $0.17 a share, but is maintaining its full year 1996 estimate at $1.46.</p>
<p>-- Earlier, Monsanto reported third quarter earnings of $0.28 a share, above the consensus of of $0.24 a share.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Earnings surpassed expectations due to the early timing of bulk aspartame shipments and due to a lower tax liability,&quot; NatWest wrote in a report. &quot;As these factors are likely to mean a slightly reduced outlook for the next quarter, we are adjusting our (fourth quarter) estimate downward.&quot;  </p>
<p>-- Monsanto shares were up 3/4 at 42-1/2.</p>
<p>-- NatWest said it believes Monsanto will announce a spinoff of its chemical business in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>-- Monsanto previously announced it is weighing options for its chemical business, including spinning it off as a separate company or merging it with another firm.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Monsanto announced in its conference call that restructuring charges relating to chemicals are likely to occur in (the fourth quarter), indicating to us that a spin out/sale announcement is imminent,&quot; NatWest said.  &quot;As the chemical group has a lower projected growth rate than the rest of Monsanto's businesses, we believe the separation of this business will provide a boost to Monsanto's core growth rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
