<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133641" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks down at midday, high techs soft.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks down at midday, high techs soft.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Profit-taking in high-tech issues kept Wall Street stocks lower at midday.</p>
<p>The selling was encouraged by a worse than expected fiscal first quarter loss by Digital Equipment Corp and a better than forecast but far from spectacular Microsoft Corp earnings report, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Dow Industrials were down 23 points, or 0.39 percent, at 6067. The Nasdaq Composite Index, a barometer of high-tech issues, was off 11 points, or 0.88 percent, at 1225.</p>
<p>The long bond was down 5/32 to yield 6.82 percent.  </p>
<p>Big Board declines led advancing issues by better than three to two on volume of about 193 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The high techs are getting a much needed near-term correction,&quot; said Roy Blumberg, chief investment strategist at Josephthal Lyon &amp; Ross. &quot;They have been the leaders of the move higher over the last couple of months. They've had a tremendous run and, as long as the market holds up well, they will have a correction of some five percent.&quot;</p>
<p>However, if the market embarks on a significant downward move, the techs would be vulnerable in the ensuing sell-off, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Not that there is anything wrong with their fundamentals, but when people like stocks they take them too high,&quot; Blumberg said. &quot;The techs were taken to levels at which too much is discounted.&quot;</p>
<p>Digital Equipment posted a loss of $65.9 million, or $0.48 a share, for the three months ended September 30. Wall Street had expected a loss of just $0.14 a share, according to First Call. In the year-earlier quarter the company had a profit of $48.2 million, or $0.26 a share.</p>
<p>Digital shares were down five at 29-3/8.  </p>
<p>It was a different story for Microsoft -- but one familiar in the high-tech sector.</p>
<p>The company reported fiscal first quarter earnings of $0.95 a share, $0.05 above the First Call estimate. But because the stock had a run-up last week when Intel Corp reported a blowout quarter, $0.05 was not good enough for many investors.</p>
<p>Microsoft shares were down two at 132.</p>
<p>Other high techs followed suit, with Intel down 2-1/2 at 105-1/4, Iomega Corp down 1-1/2 at 21-3/4, and Micron Technology Inc down 1-1/8 at 29-1/2.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market continues to consolidate last week's gains, and the Nasdaq and the tech sector could continue to see considerable profit-taking,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow needs to get back below 6000 as a consolidation-type move,&quot; he said. Markets must hammer out the lower and upper boundaries of a new trading range now that the Dow has topped 6000 and the Nasdaq has made a new high, he said.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq will find downside support in the mid-1200 level, Bleier said.  </p>
<p>In other earnings-related news, Bristol-Myers Squibb Co was up 1-3/8 at 105-1/2 after the company reported third quarter earnings of $1.50 a share, above the First Call estimate of $1.48.</p>
<p>Eli Lilly &amp; Co reported third quarter operating net per share of $0.76, up from $0.54 a year earlier. The stock was up 1-1/4 at 70.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street Desk 212-859-1737</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
