<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133660" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. notifying 20,000 troops in chemical incident.</title>
<headline>U.S. notifying 20,000 troops in chemical incident.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Pentagon said on Tuesday it was notifying 20,000 U.S. Gulf War veterans that they may have been exposed to chemical weapons in the destruction of an Iraqi ammunition dump.</p>
<p>The announcement by Defence Department spokesman Ken Bacon greatly expanded the search for possible victims of at least two incidents at the Kamisiyah arms depot in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>The Pentagon, which has repeatedly denied a coverup, said in June it was notifying 150 U.S. troops that they might have been exposed. Last month it expanded that to 5,000 who could have been affected by fallout from blast clouds believed to contain Sarin nerve gas in March 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;We have decided after looking at the facts that it would be best to go out and aggressively reach out to these 20,000 people, the number of people we think were in a 50-kilometre (30-mile) radius of Kamisiyah,&quot; Bacon told reporters.</p>
<p>He said troops from the 82nd Airborne Division and 24th Mechanized Infantry Division would be notified by letter but stressed the Pentagon had no evidence U.S. troops had been affected by gas from rockets destroyed on March 4 and 10.</p>
<p>&quot;We may decide we will have to notify more people,&quot; Bacon said, referring to a computer model being prepared by the Central Intelligence Agency using weather and other factors at the time to estimate the drift of the chemical clouds.</p>
<p>Recently published reports have suggested that more than 100,000 U.S. troops from several divisions might have been exposed to fallout from the chemical agents at Kamisiyah.</p>
<p>Another Pentagon official, who asked not to be identified, told reporters on Tuesday there may have been a third incident on March 12 in which Iraqi rockets, possibly filled with nerve gas, were destroyed at Kamisiyah.</p>
<p>The Pentagon has repeatedly denied that it ignored medical complaints from Gulf War veterans or that it has attempted to cover up possible exposure of U.S. troops to chemical agents in the war. It has also said there there is no evidence Iraq ever used chemical weapons against U.S.-led coalition forces.</p>
<p>On orders from President Bill Clinton, the government last year mounted a major effort to resolve medical complaints from as many as 60,000 veterans ranging from numbness to memory loss. No common cause or &quot;Gulf War syndrome&quot; has been found.</p>
<p>&quot;I know there has been a lot of suspicion about our policy,&quot; Bacon said on Tuesday, adding that pressure had risen in recent months after it became clear that chemical weapons were located at Kamisiyah and that U.S. troops were nearby.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make sure we have the best possible information from troops there at the time about where they were and what they did. We have had frankly a hard time gathering that information,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
