<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133730" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast power flat despite Fla. nuke outage.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast power flat despite Fla. nuke outage.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity values in the southeastern U.S. finished flat on Tuesday against Monday's level despite outage at another nuclear generating station in Florida, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Mild autumn weather in Florida offset concerns over further reduction in production capacity in the Southeastern Electric Reliability Council (SERC), marketers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather is more than compensating for a reduction in generation,&quot; a Florida utility trader said.</p>
<p>Temperatures in Florida for Wednesay were forecast to peak in the low- to high-80s Fahrenheit, while the rest of the Southeast were predicted to hit highs in the low-70s to low-80s.</p>
<p>Florida Power &amp; Light Co said it aimed to restart the 666 megawatt (MW) Turkey Point 4 nuclear unit late Wednesday. The Florida City, Fla., plant was shut on Monday to repair a feedwater heater.</p>
<p>Florida Power Corp said it still did not have a restart date of its 860 MW Crystal River nuclear power plant in Red Level, Fla.</p>
<p>In addition to those Florida nuclear stations, four other facilities, with combined capacity of 5,275 MW, in the SERC district remained shut for repairs or refueling: 1,148 MW Sequoyah 2 nuclear plant in Soddy-Daisy, Tenn.; 822 MW Farley 2 in Dothan, Ala.; 767 MW Brunswick 1 in Southport, N.C. and the 2,538 MW Oconee complex in Seneca, S.C.</p>
<p>Virginia Power Co's 909 MW North Anna 2 nuclear plant in Mineral, Va., was shut on Monday for repairs, and expected to return some time on Thursday.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, firm, peak electricity for Tuesday was again quoted at $21.00-$23.50 a megawatt hour.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity for next-day delivery was still valued at $15.00-$16.00.</p>
<p>Hourly economic dispatch on Tuesday available to Florida utilities was heard near $17.00.</p>
<p>Up in the northern portion of Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) system, firm, peak electricity was assessed at $17.00-$18.00, flat from Monday.</p>
<p>Off-peak, firm power in northern TVA for Tuesday delivery was mostly pegged near $12.00, unchanged from Monday's quote.</p>
<p>For a second day, the TVA did not offer its own generation for next-day sale, according to market sources.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
