<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133756" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midwest direct hogs seen $1-$2 lower - dealers.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midwest direct hogs seen $1-$2 lower - dealers.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Midwest direct cash hog prices Wednesday were seen $1.00 to $2.00 per cwt lower, pressured by continued large hog supplies and mostly lower pork prices which reduced packer margins, livestock dealers said.</p>
<p>Top prices for hogs delivered to the plant in Iowa and southern Minnesota could range from $52.00 to $53.00. Illinois top hog prices at the plant could range from $50.00 to $51.00.</p>
<p>Ohio and Indiana top prices at plants also were seen ranging from $50.00 to $51.00.</p>
<p>Widespread rainfall in the western Corn Belt contributed to increased hog marketings as farmers halted fieldwork.  </p>
<p>Interior Iowa/southern Minnesota hog marketings Monday totaled 108,000 head, above the earlier estimate of 105,000, USDA said. Tuesday's estimate was 105,000 head, but actual marketings were expected to be higher, livestock dealers said. Many buyers said they had enough hogs by midday to fill Wednesday's slaughter needs. There also was talk that several packers could be trimming operating hours the next two days, the dealers said.</p>
<p>Carlot pork prices at midday were mostly lower, with hams mostly steady to $2.00 per cwt higher, bellies $1.00 to $2.00 lower and lean trimmings $2.00 lower, USDA said.</p>
<p>There were 47.5 pork cut loads and 19.5 loads of trimmings reported sold, according to USDA.</p>
<p>--Bob Janis 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
