<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133754" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida officials confident Miami can end deficit.</title>
<headline>Florida officials confident Miami can end deficit.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida officials have no plans to take over Miami's finances and are confident the city can work out its budget problems, Gail Sittig, assistant director of the Governor's Office of Plannnig and Budget, said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sittig said the city's $68 million budget deficit would force it to make tough decisions.</p>
<p>But, she said, &quot;They are, as far as I know, taking every measure that is appropriate. We feel, based on some preliminary deficit ellimination plans, that they are capapble of making those kinds of decisions.&quot;</p>
<p>Sittig and other members of Gov. Lawton Chiles' staff have been working closely with Miami. Last week, the state advanced the city $22.4 million in shared tax revenues it would otherwise have received in monthly payments, in order to help Miami bridge the cash flow gap until property tax revenues come in in December.</p>
<p>Under Florida statute, the governor could appoint an emergency board to take over city finances if Miami missed a payroll, skipped a debt service payment or failed to transfer employee withholding taxes.</p>
<p>But no emergency board has ever taken over a Florida municipality, and that is not expected to be done in this case, Sittig said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is not the way we really want this handled. We think the best people to make these kinds of decisons are the locals. They know best, in terms of service delivery and what they're willing to pay for,&quot; Sittig said.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Miami officials) have a very tight spending freeze that is in place right now. We're watching it. We feel comfortable that they've already identified 75-plus measures they could take to bring the budget back into balance,&quot; Sittig said.</p>
<p>Additioanlly, she said, &quot;They've got the whole fiscal year to basically spread the cut over.&quot;</p>
<p>Acting City Manager Merrit Stierheim has proposed a package of hiring freezes, fee increases, service cuts and worker concessions to help close the gap in the budget year that began Oct 1.</p>
<p>Sittig said $38 million of the shortfall was &quot;of a non-recurring nature&quot; that could be covered with one-time fixes, while the other $30 million represents recurring problems that must be covered with permanent revenue increases or service cuts.</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
