<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13379" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India sidesteps politics to woo foreign investors.</title>
<headline>India sidesteps politics to woo foreign investors.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The diverse interests in India's new centre-left coalition government have closed ranks in support of Finance Minister Palaniappan Chidambaram, allowing him a free hand to attract foreign investment, analysts said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's 13-party United Front -- a textbook example of rainbow coalition politics -- includes diehard communists and socialists, but they have hardly disturbed Chidambaram's zeal for free-market policies.</p>
<p>Chidambaram, who was commerce minister in the government of former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao which lost general elections ended in May, is pressing ahead with the economic reforms agenda Rao started in 1991.</p>
<p>Amal Ganguli, a partner with consultants Price Waterhouse, said the Foreign Investment Promotion Board (FIPB), which screens all major foreign investments, had opened its arms to overseas firms since Deve Gowda took office on June 1.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems it (the FIPB) is anxious to welcome investments,&quot; Ganguli said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are approving foreign investment proposals faster,&quot; N. Mohanty, the Industry Ministry's civil servant in charge of promoting foreign investment, told Reuters last week.</p>
<p>Among the numerous proposals the two-month-old government has approved is one by Coca-Cola Co for $700 million. That came despite the coalition's professed goal, pushed by the left wing, of discouraging foreign investment in the consumer goods sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry Minister Murasoli Maran deserves full support for his creative interpretation of the ruling in the United Front's common minimum programme,&quot; the Economic Times daily said in an editorial last week, referring to the coalition's platform.</p>
<p>Last week the Power Ministry said some 145 private power projects languishing in the bureaucracy would get &quot;fast-track&quot; treatment.</p>
<p>The government has already rolled out a red carpet for investors in key infrastructure areas like roads, telecommunications and ports.</p>
<p>Chidambaram is looking for $10 billion every year in foreign direct investment, up from $1.98 billion in the 1995/96 fiscal year ended last March 31. It wants to increase India's share of world trade to one percent in 2000 from 0.64 percent last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Their (foreign investment) real surge is yet to come,&quot; central bank governor C. Rangarajan said last week, adding that India should aim for sustained 15 percent growth in inflows from exports and tourism.</p>
<p>Some holy cows remain on the road to liberalisation. They include insurance, a sector in which trade unions are well organised, and the media, where a powerful domestic lobby and politicians fearing cultural invasion are blocking foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately the government is a bit confused. If insurance had been opened up, it would have been something good,&quot; Ganguli said.</p>
<p>The government is reluctant to slash fertiliser subsidies, which peasant leader Deve Gowda believes helps poor farmers.</p>
<p>Ganguli said corruption cases linked to the privatisation of telephone services and prolonged re-negotiations for a concluded power project deal involving Enron Corp of the United States could dissuade some foreign investors.</p>
<p>But the government has already shown its liberal stripes, analysts say. &quot;The fact this is a coalition and yet pro-business is very welcome,&quot; Ganguli said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
