<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133735" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Six firefighters injured battling California blaze.</title>
<headline>Six firefighters injured battling California blaze.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>MALIBU, Calif 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six firemen were injured on Tuesday battling wildfires that burned more than 80 homes and consumed over 20,000 acres (8,000 hectares) across southern California.</p>
<p>The largest of a half-dozen major blazes continued to threaten the celebrity enclave of Malibu, where firemen were trapped in their truck by a sudden flare-up in a steep canyon.</p>
<p>Deputy Fire Chief Dave Parsons said at least one of the six men was seriously burned, and they were airlifted to a Los Angeles hospital.</p>
<p>They were trying to reach a burning house when &quot;the fire just boiled up on them,&quot; Parsons said. &quot;They were unable to continue ... because of a car blocking the road.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked why the men did not abandon their vehicle and run, Parsons said, &quot;You can't run away from a freight train.&quot;</p>
<p>The large, expensive house the firemen were trying to save was destroyed, bringing the total number of homes burned in the Malibu wildfire to four. Eleven people, most of them firefighters, have been injured so far in the blaze.</p>
<p>Firefighters backed by water-dropping tanker planes and helicopters and aided by lighter winds struggled to control the Malibu fire and others burning in southern California, but with varying degrees of success.</p>
<p>The Malibu fire raced across the Santa Monica Mountains to the sea on Monday. By Tuesday it had charred more than 13,000 acres (5,000 hectares) and forced several thousand people out of their homes. Flames on Tuesday continued to pose a serious danger to Malibu and other coastal communities.</p>
<p>Authorities said the fire was only 10 percent contained and the Los Angeles County Board of Supervisors declared a local emergency.</p>
<p>The latest rash of wildfires struck almost three years to the day after a firestorm swept southern California from the Mexican border north to Malibu, destroying nearly 1,000 homes.</p>
<p>In San Diego County, authorities said a firestorm gutted at least 70 homes overnight in Carlsbad and San Marcos. Carlsbad police Lt. Greg Fried said the damage estimate was &quot;extremely conservative&quot; and more than 80 homes may actually have been lost in the 6,000-acre (2,400-hectare) blaze.</p>
<p>Gov. Pete Wilson on Tuesday declared a state of emergency for San Diego County, freeing up state emergency funds.</p>
<p>Authorities said the Carlsbad fire, which broke out in the Elfin Forest on Monday and quickly spread to canyons lined with homes about 15 miles (25 km) north of San Diego, was the most destructive fire in San Diego County in over a decade.</p>
<p>Hundreds of Carlsbad residents were evacuated and four firefighters suffered smoke-related eye injuries.</p>
<p>Officials said the fire was 50 percent contained with full containment hoped for by Wednesday night.</p>
<p>Another fire that sprang up overnight in the Otay Mountains southeast of San Digeo had consumed 9,000 acres (2,000 hectares) and had forced the closure of the Otay Mesa border crossing with Mexico.</p>
<p>A blaze on the Rincon Indian Reservation north of San Diego which started on Monday night consumed 1,200 acres (500 hectares) and destroyed six structures.</p>
<p>Malibu was the focal point of a massive firefighting effort on Tuesday after a two-mile (3 km)-wide wall of smoke and flame roared across the Santa Monica Mountains from Calabasas, 35 miles (55 km) northwest of downtown Los Angeles. Fuelled by fierce, dry Santa Ana winds, flames raced to the coast in less than six hours, threatening seaside mansions and beachfront bungalows.</p>
<p>The blaze was being fought by about 2,500 firefighters. Authorities said they had no clues on the fire's cause.</p>
<p>In the exclusive Orange County community of Lemon Heights southeast of Los Angeles a wind-whipped blaze destroyed 10 homes and damaged 19 others on Monday. It was caused by a downed powerline.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MALIBU, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
