<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133748" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US LBO funds grow amid questions of credit quality.</title>
<headline>US LBO funds grow amid questions of credit quality.</headline>
<byline>Al Yoon</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>At a time of rapid growth for corporate financing, some money managers Tuesday said the lure of easy cash has sparked concerns over credit quality.</p>
<p>Daniel O'Connell, chief executive officer and founder of Vestar Capital Partners, said more high-yield deals have entered the market backed with more questionable credit stories. He said the markets may end up with some rude reminders of the overextended companies of the late 1980s.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the next six to eight months you'll see companies getting into trouble with debt,&quot; O'Connell said, adding that the resurgence of bridge loans is one ominous indicator.</p>
<p>But despite warning signs, O'Connell also said the players will likely participate in more cautious practices, thereby avoiding a late 1980s scenario.</p>
<p>O'Connell and two other leveraged finance fund managers spoke to about 200 corporate finance professionals on a panel at the Nationsbanc Capital Markets Inc Corporate Bond Conference at New York's Plaza Hotel on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Panelists said the amount of cash dedicated to the leveraged buyout industry has almost doubled in the past two years, making it an extremely favorable environment for dedicated funds. But at least one of the managers sees better buyout opportunities further down the road.</p>
<p>Roger Altman, co-founder of leveraged finance firm Evercore Partners, noted the financial markets are at all-time highs and he expects markets may be more favorable after 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's an interesting question as to whether private equity investors want to be aggressive in offering funds at this moment,&quot; he said. &quot;On one hand they could be very selective or on the other (hand they could be) waiting for prices to correct themselves.</p>
<p>Altman added, &quot;the economy is strong, monetary policy is very accommodative and inflation is beginning to rear its ugly head - particularly wage inflation.&quot;</p>
<p>The heady flow of cash to leveraged funds has its upside, however. The number of funds has increased along with the cash flow and competition for deals has made the markets more efficient, said Donald Gogel, co-president of Clayton, Dubilier &amp; Rice Inc.</p>
<p>--U.S. corporate bond unit, 212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
