<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133798" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYS state may fight ruling 'gutting' welfare curb.</title>
<headline>NYS state may fight ruling 'gutting' welfare curb.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State seems likely to appeal a court decision that knocked out one of the first new limits on welfare that Gov. George Pataki last year got the legislature to approve, a state official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The new regulations, which did not go into effect in August 1996, prevented anyone who had not lived in the state for six months from collecting Home Relief, which gives needy individuals grants and helps pay for shelter and heat.</p>
<p>The state, which fears its bigger benefit package will attract residents of other states to move to New York, shares the cost of the program with counties.</p>
<p>Judge Andrew Siracuse, a state supreme court judge in Monroe County, late last week approved a class-action suit against the state, saying the six-month residency requirement violated the federal and state unconstitutions.</p>
<p>The far-reaching implications of the judge's decision were swiftly seized upon by the state attorney general's office.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like this ruling would gut any meaningful welfare reform in New York State,&quot; said Marc Carey, who is a spokesman for the state attorney general, Dennis Vacco.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point it looks like Dennis Vacco is very, very strongly leaning towards any appeal,&quot; Carey added.</p>
<p>The class-action suit was filed on behalf of two individuals, both in their mid-50s, who moved to western counties in New York from Florida and Puerto Rico. Their suit, which seeks retroactive benefits, could be expanded to about 5,000 people who also have moved to the state.</p>
<p>The Pataki Administration, like many state governments, is drafting a new welfare program to comply with the dramatic changes to the federal program that became law in August.</p>
<p>A preliminary outline of New York's program has been sent to Washington. While it gave few hints about the plan's direction, there has been speculation Pataki would seek to impose stiffer curbs on Home Relief, including a 90-day limit.</p>
<p>Should the state appeal the court decision, it would get an automatic stay, but one of the attorneys who brought the suit, Susan Ann Silverstein of the Public Interest Law Office in Rochester, said that she would ask a stay to be set aside. &quot;An appeal can take a long time. We need to protect the people in the meantime,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>New York State is particularly vulnerable to the harsh new federal restrictions, partly because the state constitution's Article 17 obliges it to care for the needy.</p>
<p>Citing this article, Judge Siracuse ruled that there was a compelling history of court decisions prohibiting the state from creating different clases of individuals on welfare. &quot;The Court of Appeals has consistently interpreted this provision as one that forbids any classification of welfare recipients by standards other than need itself,&quot; he wrote in his opinion.</p>
<p>This interpretation of the state constituion was disputed by the spokesman for the state attorney general, who said that Article 17 allows the legislature to determine the care of the needy.</p>
<p>However, the judge held that the new residency requirement also violated the federal constitution because it impeded the plantiffs' right to travel.</p>
<p>This finding also was attacked by the attorney general's spokesman, who noted that neither Florida nor Puerto Rico have Home Relief programs.</p>
<p>Under New York state's program, single individuals in New York City can collect about $352, more than in New Jersey, where the amount is $210, Pennsylvania, which pays $215, or Vemont, which provides $277, he added.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
