<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133743" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US WCoast lt. crudes rise with WTI, run cut seen.</title>
<headline>US WCoast lt. crudes rise with WTI, run cut seen.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices for U.S. West Coast light crude gained ground with West Texas Intermediate (WTI), forcing at least one regional refiner to cut runs 18 percent overnight as crude prices stayed relatively high.</p>
<p>Buyers said they refused to buy Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude while West Coast margins weakened and differentials stayed tight with WTI.</p>
<p>ANS sellers kept offers $2.10 below November WTI, compared to bids of minus $2.50.</p>
<p>Official discounts remained unchanged since September 24, when a cargo of ANS sold for $2.30 under.  </p>
<p>&quot;It doesn't make sense for me to run it at that,&quot; one refinery trader said, claiming ANS discounts would have fallen to minus $3.00 or more if a major producer could not export to the Far East.</p>
<p>Cash WTI rose 15 cents to $25.95/26.05 a barrel, lifting outright ANS prices to $23.55/23.85 a barrel.</p>
<p>In addition to confirmed cuts by the Northwest refiner, buyers such as Ultramar, Unocal, and Tosco, considered throttling back production.</p>
<p>Traders forecast more space would open on California's Line 63 for November crude shipments.</p>
<p>Arco, which runs Line 63, will set space limits late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said increased exports of California crudes and weak profits cut back shippers' requests for line space.</p>
<p>The line has been crowded since a 1994 earthquake damaged a companion line.</p>
<p>Discounts for Line 63 crude stagnated at $3.20 to 3.00 off November WTI.</p>
<p>Heavy California crudes remained unchanged.</p>
<p>--David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles energy +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
