<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133742" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. CREDIT OUTLOOK - Grumpy ahead of fresh supply.</title>
<headline>U.S. CREDIT OUTLOOK - Grumpy ahead of fresh supply.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. credit markets are likely to stay trapped in a range on Wednesday as fresh supply and a dearth of fresh economic data will probably keep moods grumpy for another trading session, analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Treasury will offer $12.5 billion in five-year notes on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Demand for the notes is likely to be moderate. Analysts predicted the Treasury will probably face no major snags in placing the securities, which are expected to yield between 6.30 and 6.32 percent at the sale.  </p>
<p>&quot;You set up okay for the five-year auction ... I don't see any reason why we will not absorb the five year auction very well,&quot; said Cary Leahey, senior financial market economist at Lehman Government Securities.</p>
<p>But pundits did not rule out the possibility of a mild pre-auction sell-off followed by a post-supply rally. The sale's bidding deadline is set for 1300 EDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;Once you get the five years underwritten ... then the dealers will put on their rose-colored glasses and try to talk up the market for a distribution rally,&quot; said Josh Stiles, senior bond strategist at consulting firm I.D.E.A. Inc.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the market has a decent support between 6.86 and 6.87 percent on the 30-year Treasury bond yield. If prices are to rally, analysts said the benchmark yield could slip to 6.75 percent and then to 6.70 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If you were to analyze the 50 percent retracement of the entire bear market this year, in futures that would come in at 112-23 which is something around 6.70 percent on the bond yield. So that's as far as I think you can get,&quot; Stiles said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the two-year note auction on Tuesday was relatively smooth. The Treasury sold $18.28 billion in notes at 5.930 percent. The bid-to-cover ratio was 2.62 times.  </p>
<p>Some international buying was detected and players did not discount the possibility of fresh foreign money being pumped into Wednesday's auction as well. &quot;I believe we might see some foreigners,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. investment bank.</p>
<p>Some analysts expressed concerns about the weakness of the U.S. dollar against other major currencies seen over the last few days, saying it could weigh on Treasury prices.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a little concern about the weakness of the dollar that we've seen in the last couple of sessions,&quot; said Gary Thayer, senior economist at A.G. Edwards and Sons Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;We had a gold rally in the last couple of days and commodity prices doing a little better today (on Tuesday), crude oil at a 5-year high. These are things people might be watching in the lack of other economic news,&quot; Thayer added.</p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was quoted down 18/32 at 98-23/32 in late trading on Tuesday to yield 6.85 percent.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve injected reserves to the banking system on Tuesday through two-day fixed system repurchase agreements when the federal funds were trading at 5-3/16 percent, below the central bank's 5-1/4 percent target.  </p>
<p>The fed funds rate is expected to open at 5.31 percent on Wednesday. Analysts said funds might come under pressure as players square off their positions in the last day of the current maintenance period, which ends on October 23.</p>
<p>Analysts are also on the watch for a possible bill pass by the Fed late in the month or early in November to meet higher demand for cash ahead of the year-end holidays.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking for a bill pass. I think the most likely dates are either October 30th or November 6th,&quot; said Dana Saporta, economist at Stone and McCarthy Research Associates.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
