<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133766" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon reports lower profit, surprising Wall Street.</title>
<headline>Salomon reports lower profit, surprising Wall Street.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Inc. said Tuesday its earnings tumbled 57 percent in the third quarter, snapping a string of strong earnings reports from Wall Street investment houses.</p>
<p>Until Salomon's report, major brokerage houses had reported strong results for the quarter, above the comparable 1995 quarter though short of the record profits posted in the second quarter. The gains came from the stock market rally earlier this year.</p>
<p>But Salomon said net income fell to $112 million, or 88 cents a share, in the quarter, from $268 million, or $2.36 a share, in the 1995 period. Analysts had expected Salomon to earn $1.19 a share, according to First Call, which tracks estimates.</p>
<p>Net revenues fell to $816 million from $1.18 billion.</p>
<p>Salomon stock took a drubbing after the report, falling $3.25 to $45.375 on the New York Stock Exchange. Industry analysts said a recent run-up in the shares ahead of the report likely accounted for the sharpness of the sell-off.</p>
<p>Analysts also noted that Salomon's earnings, more so than at other brokers, are linked heavily to its trading for its own account and are therefore volatile.</p>
<p>But the weak showing at the firm's Phibro unit commodities trading and refinery unit did raise eyebrows on Wall Street. The unit posted a $7 million profit in the third quarter, down from $68 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm never shocked when Salomon shows either a sharp increase or decline,&quot; said Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette analyst Joan Solotar. &quot;But one surprise was that ... profits at Phibro were down.&quot;</p>
<p>During a conference call with analysts, Salomon declined to spell out the reasons for the profit decline, but the firm did announce its exit from coal, coke and fertiliser trading.</p>
<p>The good news for Salomon was that underlying businesses such as investment banking showed improvement.</p>
<p>&quot;(Salomon's) long-term arbitrage portfolio and Phibro's trading results will continue to report widely varying results from quarter to quarter,&quot; Brown Brothers analyst Raphael Soifer said in a research note, &quot;but the firm's underlying performance continues to improve.&quot;</p>
<p>Salomon's third quarter investment banking revenues rose to $187 million in the quarter from $128 million last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
