<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133750" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Biogen looking at product gap in 1998-2000.</title>
<headline>Biogen looking at product gap in 1998-2000.</headline>
<dateline>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street analysts greeted news of Biogen Inc two-for one stock split as part of the ongoing celebration from the company's successful launch of the multiple sclerosis drug Avonex.</p>
<p>But analysts also cautioned that the market for Avonex is not infinite. There are an estimated 250,000 to 300,000 MS suffers in the United States, and while the product will experience continued growth for the next few years, there &quot;is a potential gap around 1998 to 2000&quot; in the product line, said Cowen &amp; Co. analyst David Stone.  </p>
<p>&quot;Ideally, they need a Phase II or Phase III clinical trial product&quot; to acquire for licensing, he said. &quot;It's a challenge that they've set for themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>The company's own development of Gilsolon, an agent that could be used in treating respiratory illnesses, has entered Phase I clinical trials in the United Kingdom, but Stone notes &quot;that means if its successful, it still won't be on the market for five years.&quot;</p>
<p>Biogen spokeswoman Kathryn Bloom said the Cambridge-based biotech firm &quot;has been aggressively looking for technology and new product candidates to lease in.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bloom noted the company's recent licensing agreement with Ontogeny, another Cambridge-based biotech firm and Genovo, a Philadelphia gene therapy design company.</p>
<p>She said the company was concentrating on &quot;moving Avonex toward market approval,&quot; which was granted by the U.S. Federal Drug Administration last spring, and now was &quot;actively moving to get product to fill the pipeline.&quot;</p>
<p>--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBRIDGE, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
