<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133722" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, scenting victory, challenges Dole in Florida.</title>
<headline>Clinton, scenting victory, challenges Dole in Florida.</headline>
<byline>Gene Gibbons</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Tuesday brought his soaring re-election campaign to sunny Florida, a state normally hostile to Democrats in presidential races, as signs mounted that he was poised for a big victory on Nov. 5.</p>
<p>Speaking to a wildly enthusiastic audience of some 1,500 at Miami-Dade Community College, Clinton trumpeted &quot;more evidence that America's economy is on the right track&quot; -- new home ownership data released in Washington earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have four-and-a-half million new homeowners in the last four years, and lower interest rates have helped 10 million more Americans to refinance their home mortgages at lower rates, saving huge amounts of money for those families,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clinton, who later was the star attraction at a pair of Democratic Party fundraising galas, said home ownership was &quot;an idea that ought to be available to every working American.&quot; And he promised that if he wins a second term, &quot;by the year 2000 more than two-thirds of the American people will be living in their own homes.&quot;</p>
<p>About 65 percent of the U.S. population -- 66.3 million households -- are already classified as homeowners.</p>
<p>Clinton flew to Miami after an overnight visit to Michigan, where he delivered a major foreign policy speech that set 1999 as the target year for admitting new members to NATO.</p>
<p>Outside the Biltmore Hotel, where Clinton was due to speak, Cuban exile groups staged noisy demonstrations against and in support of the U.S. trade embargo on Cuba. Lines of police kept the two sides apart.</p>
<p>On one side protesters held placards saying &quot;Clinton Yes, Helms-Burton, No&quot; and &quot;The Embargo is Genocide.&quot; Their opponents waved Cuban flags and bellowed through megaphones &quot;Castro is genocide.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton's foray into Florida, which has voted Republican in nine of the last 11 presidential races, reflected a growing sense of confidence within the Clinton camp that victory is all but certain. Spending precious time in a state that last went Democratic in 1976 showed that Clinton and his aides believe he is in good shape elsewhere in the country.</p>
<p>A recent Tampa Tribune poll showed Clinton with a narrow lead over Republican Bob Dole for the state's 25 electoral votes -- just under 10 percent of the 270 electoral votes needed to win the presidency.</p>
<p>Dole planned to campaign on Wednesday in the conservative northwestern Florida panhandle, while the president was scheduled to visit Daytona.</p>
<p>Another sign of Clinton's strength was Republican National Committee chairman Haley Barbour's use of the &quot;blank check&quot; argument to try to convince voters to keep Congress in Republican hands.</p>
<p>&quot;If Clinton is re-elected, heaven forbid, the last thing the American people would want would be for him to have a blank check in the form of a liberal, Democrat Congress,&quot; Barbour said.</p>
<p>Another sign of Clinton's growing aura of invincibility was his lead in public opinion polls. A daily tracking poll sponsored by Reuters which has consistently been more conservative than other polls on Tuesday showed Clinton edging a little further ahead of Dole.</p>
<p>Two weeks before Election Day, Clinton led with 46 percent over Dole's 34.7 percent. Reform Party candidate Ross Perot's support climbed a little to 5.4 percent, and 11.5 percent said they were still undecided.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted by John Zogby Group International, tracks about 900 likely voters over a three-day period. The latest result, with a 3.3 percentage point margin of error, reflects polling from Saturday through Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
