<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133758" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Second quarter key to Digital prospects.</title>
<headline>Second quarter key to Digital prospects.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a disappointing first quarter, Digital Equipment Corp's second quarter will show whether its sales and marketing difficulties are really short-term problems as management asserts.</p>
<p>&quot;They have all the tools they need, but marketing remains the biggest monkey on DEC's back,&quot; said Terry Shannon, editor of the Ashlan, Mass.-based newsletter, &quot;Shannon Knows DEC.&quot;</p>
<p>Digital Chief Executive Robert Palmer said Tuesday a worldwide sales realignment had unexpected consequences, resulting in the $66 milllion loss for the first quarter.  </p>
<p>Palmer said the realignment showed some positive results toward the end of the first quarter and predicted Digital would return to profitability in the second quarter, ending in December.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, have been stung by disappointments at Digital before and remained cautious.  Another weak quarter could usher Palmer out the door, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;If that (profit) does not happen, I think the level of support that Mr. Palmer currently enjoys from the board of directors is going to evaporate,&quot; Shannon said.  </p>
<p>William Milton, an analyst with Brown Brothers Harriman, said he has heard from Digital's competitors that its sales force appears &quot;unfocused, disorganized and demoralized.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Reorganization alone is not going to solve the problem here.  I don't know how one goes about motivating a sales force and focusing that sales force and directing its efforts productively,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Analysts questioned if the slowdown to just four percent growth in sales of Digital's Alpha systems was due entirely to the sales realignment or to increasing competition from Sun Microsystems Inc, International Business Machines Corp and others.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a black eye for the entire Alpha strategy, but it certainly is not a death knell for Alpha,&quot; Shannon said.</p>
<p>Digital's sales team which sells to the U.S. government did not go through a realignment and recorded better results.  </p>
<p>That could validate Palmer's assertion that the slow sales across most of Digital's business were a result of the sales changes, analysts said.</p>
<p>Despite the difficulties, Milton said it was not time to give up on Digital yet.</p>
<p>Shannon said Palmer has the reputation as a &quot;comeback kid,&quot; as Digital has rebounded from seemingly insurmountable losses before.</p>
<p>Steve Milunovich, an analyst with Morgan Stanley, cut his earnings estimates for Digital but still believes the second half of the year could look better.</p>
<p>Currency fluctuations which also contributed to the first quarter loss could show better comparisons during the second quarter, he said.</p>
<p>Digital's troubled personal computer division, hit by excessive investories in its direct sales channel, has also worked out its problems, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Boston bureau (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
