<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133726" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Union report chides Bridgestone U.S. unit.</title>
<headline>Union report chides Bridgestone U.S. unit.</headline>
<byline>Peter Szekely</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The union representing striking workers at Bridgestone/Firestone Inc. Tuesday issued a report of the company's alleged misdeeds that it hopes will help widen the boycott against the company's tires.</p>
<p>The report by the United Steeworkers of America (USWA) lists environmental, safety and other claims against the company, the American arm of Japanese tire maker Bridgestone Corp., many of which already have been reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The Steelworkers union believes Bridgestone's irresponsible behaviour must not go unnoticed,&quot; USWA Executive Vice President John Sellers told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We are calling on individual and institutional customers, retail merchants and original equipment manufacturers to join our union's 'Don't Buy' campaign against Bridgestone/Firestone products and services,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In January, 1995, the company replaced more than 2,000 workers who went on strike in July 1994. The union offered an unconditional return to work in May 1995 and by last month fewer than 100 of the replaced strikers had not been recalled.</p>
<p>But with its members working under company-imposed terms and conditions, without a contract and no talks scheduled, the union is seeking to step up its Bridgestone/Firestone boycott.</p>
<p>&quot;We've still got to get at the very serious business of negotiating a fair and equitable contract,&quot; said USWA President George Becker, whose union merged with the United Rubber Workers in July 1995.</p>
<p>Bridgestone/Firestone spokesman Trevor Hoskins called the report part of a &quot;smear campaign&quot; against the company, which, if successful, could jeopardise union jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;While we have not yet seen the complete report, it is very difficult to understand the union's logic of continuing to try to falsely harm the reputation of Bridgestone/Firestone and its 45,000 employees....&quot; Hoskins said in a statement.</p>
<p>The 42-page glossy report accused the company of lax enforcement of safety standards, cited fatal accidents and injuries at some plants and fines proposed by regulators.</p>
<p>It said the company paid $3.45 million to settle three of six federal and state suits in 1991 for improper waste disposal and admitted dumping polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) and other chemicals at 16 other locations.</p>
<p>At the Noblesville, Ind., plant, the company agreed in 1990 with regulators to clean up soil and water contamination there, but took until December 1995 to formulate a cleanup plan, which is now awaiting approval, the report said.</p>
<p>The report also said the company sought to recruit other rubber companies in an all-out effort to break the union and claims the replacement of 2,300 workers last year was illegal.</p>
<p>A regional office of the National Labour Relations Board has agreed that the replacement was illegal. A hearing scheduled to begin next month will determine whether the charges hold up.</p>
<p>The USWA has sought to enlist unions around the world, especially those that represent other Bridgestone workers, in its boycott and has gotten the Saturn division of General Motors Corp. to give some support to the boycott.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
