<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133776" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cash poor funds will want yield on N.J. Trans deal.</title>
<headline>Cash poor funds will want yield on N.J. Trans deal.</headline>
<byline>Kathie O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>With little but dust in mutual fund coffers, Wednesday's $713 million New Jersey Transportation Fund Authority offering will have to flash some attractive yields to attract buyers, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;I've chatted with a couple of our accounts, and to be honest with you, none of our accounts have that much interest in it,&quot; one trader said of deal, set for competitive bidding at 1100 EDT.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure there's going to be interest in it, no doubt about it, but I don't see it right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While insurance companies appear to have some money, &quot;the funds don't have anything,&quot; the trader said. The market needs to adjust a bit in order to entice institutional buyers, he added.</p>
<p>Tom Moles, a managing director at J&amp;W Seligman, agreed. Municipal yields are at &quot;nose bleed&quot; levels these days, he said. Lacking additional cash, Moles would have to swap out of some of his current holdings in order to participate, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the stuff I'd have to swap out of is better coupon, better yield right now,&quot; Moles said. &quot;I don't have trouble with the credit, it's just that the price is a little shocky to me.&quot;</p>
<p>Bob MacIntosh, a vice president and portfolio manager at Eaton Vance Management, also cited scarce cash at mutual funds, and, like Moles, said buying bonds would require him to swap out of something else. Limited cash flow is &quot;clearly the situation across the board,&quot; among muni funds, MacIntosh said.</p>
<p>As for the New Jersey deal, &quot;the price needs to make sense, but as far as the credit is concerned, there is no problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Joe Deane, a managing director at Greenwich Street Advisors, also described the N.J. Transportation credit as &quot;fine.&quot; But while he remains &quot;pretty constructive&quot; on the market, Deane said any purchase he would make right now would hinge not only on price, but on structure.</p>
<p>Constructive on the market for the past three or four months, Deane remains positive for the balance of the year, and is looking for discount bonds, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Any deal that we take a look at right now is going to be a combination of some potential upside in the bond, and an attractive price,&quot; he said. &quot;If you have an attractive price and a par bond right now you are not going to get us interested.&quot;</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
