<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133783" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Biogen announces 2-for-1 stock split.</title>
<headline>Biogen announces 2-for-1 stock split.</headline>
<dateline>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Biogen, Inc on Tuesday announced a two-for-one stock split effective November 15 to shareholders of record at the close of business on Nov. 4.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts who follow the biotech company, which has had a solid runup since the U.S. Federal Drug Administration approved of its multiple sclerosis drug, Avonex, in May said the split would increase liquidity and give the Cambridge-based company more options to acquire licensing agreements.  </p>
<p>Jim Vincent, Biogen's chairman and chief executive officer said, &quot;The stock split is in keeping with the company's long-term strategy of broadening our stockholder base and increasing the liquidity of the company's shares.&quot;</p>
<p>David Stone of Cowen &amp; Co said, &quot;It won't mean much to institutional holders, but it will mean something to the individual holders and will make the shares easier to trade. It shouldn't affect the fundamentals.&quot;</p>
<p>Biogen said institutional investors make up 65 percent of its shareholders.</p>
<p>Bear Stearns David Molowa said he was not surprised at the split. &quot;It seems very normal in this industry when stocks get up in the 80s and 90s that they split. They're trying to keep their investor audience.&quot;</p>
<p>In late afternoon trading, Biogen was hovering at 80-1/4, down 1/4 from the Monday close.</p>
<p>Asked if he thought the split would result in possible acquisitions by Biogen, Molowa replied, &quot;Well, that's part of liquidity, isn't it.&quot;</p>
<p>--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAMBRIDGE, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
