<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133728" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RTRS-News and MCI seek partners in TV centre.</title>
<headline>RTRS-News and MCI seek partners in TV centre.</headline>
<dateline>GILBERT, Ariz. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global communications giant News Corp Ltd and long-distance provider MCI Communications Corp are looking at possible new investors in their $129 million satellite broadcast center to be built in Arizona, company executives said Tuesday.</p>
<p>At a ground-breaking ceremony, the top executives of both companies said the issue of attracting other investors to the project is actively being considered</p>
<p>&quot;We've been approached by many people who would like to join us and we'll certainly give them consideration,&quot; said Rupert Murdoch, News Corp chairman and cheief executive.</p>
<p>Murdoch did not identify the possible investors to reporters, adding that that no decision had been made.</p>
<p>Bert Roberts, MCI chairman and chief executive, said he would encourage others to join the venture.</p>
<p>&quot;From MCI's point of view, I hope we do take other partners,&quot; Roberts said. &quot;I think that we're going into a business which has tremendous revenue opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>Currently, the two companies are partners in the American Sky Broadcast facility, which is expected to open in a small town east of Phoenix in November 1997.</p>
<p>The 100,000-square-foot facility will act as the nerve center for satellite feeds from around the world, providing subscribers with 300 channels of entertainment news and information. Officials also have said that it could be the future home of a 24-hour news network.</p>
<p>Additionally, the 100-employee center will offer a range of multi-media services to businesses and consumers.</p>
<p>Murdoch said he plans to go head-to-head with the cable industry and other satellite operations with the help of the new Arizona facility.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that we have a very solid business plan to give the consumer the highest quality, to offer the most choice and keeping it all around simple and at the right price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Later, he told reporters that his battles with Time Warner Inc continue and that there have been no settlement discussions.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought we had everything settled, but it didn't turn out that way,&quot; said Murdoch, in an impromptu news conference following the ceremonies. &quot;So now we're in dispute. I certainly hope that it will be settled in an amicable way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked about any settlement talks, he said: &quot;We're awaiting their call.&quot;</p>
<p>Time Warner and News Corp have been at odds over Time Warner's decision to carry MSNBC, an all news venture between Microsoft Corp and General Electric Co, instead of News Corp's new Fox news network.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GILBERT, Ariz."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
