<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133841" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reich, religious leaders turn up heat on sweatshops.</title>
<headline>Reich, religious leaders turn up heat on sweatshops.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As the holiday shopping season approaches, Americans should be aware of products manufactured in sweatshops, the top U.S. labour official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;As over the next few months Americans begin to celebrate many different religious holidays through purchases of gifts, often through purchases of garments, there is an appropriate focus on where these garments were made ... were they produced in an ethical way?&quot; Labour Secretary Robert Reich said.</p>
<p>He was joined at a media briefing by various religious leaders who pledged to turn up the heat on companies dealing with sweatshops by raising awareness in their congregations.</p>
<p>The Labour Department releases names of firms that deal with sweathshops every three months. It also planned to release on Nov. 27 an annual &quot;Trendsetter&quot; list of companies that have taken extra steps to ensure their goods are not made in sweatshop conditions.</p>
<p>While the religious leaders did not call for a boycott of any one firm, a Baptist representative said one way to increase pressure could be through &quot;selective buying.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For us it's not a question of human rights but the right to be human,&quot; the Rev. Archie LeMone of the Progressive National Baptist Convention said. &quot;It's uncomfortable&quot; to wear clothing made by exploited workers, he added.</p>
<p>Reich said the Labour Department was not pushing any particular method of increasing pressure. &quot;We are not advocating any particular technique,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Progress on the issue has been made by retailers and manufacturers, but Reich said the United States is a long way from having eradicated the thousands of sweatshops that exist.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
