<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133816" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GATX General American unit Q3 profit up.</title>
<headline>GATX General American unit Q3 profit up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>GATX Corp said its General American Transportation Corp unit had third quarter earnings of $17.8 million, up from $15.6 million a year ago, reflecting both new car additions and fleet acquisitions.</p>
<p>Domestic fleet utilization was 95 percent at the end of the quarter, the same level as a year ago, but one percent higher than the previous quarter.</p>
<p>The number of U.S. railcars on lease was 63,400 versus 60,900 at the end of last year's third quarter.</p>
<p>GATX Terminals earned $2.0 million in the current quarter, down from $8.2 million for the third quarter of 1995.  </p>
<p>This reflects the continuing weak market for the storage of petroleum products in the United States and expenses related to rationalization initiatives and market and organization evaluation studies.</p>
<p>Utilization at the end of the quarter was 84 percent compared to 87 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>GATX Capital reported earnings of $19.1 million for the third quarter, up from earnings of $7.6 million a year ago.</p>
<p>American Steamship Co earned $2.6 million for the 1996 third quarter compared to earnings of $2.9 million a year ago. Although tonnage demand remains strong on the Great Lakes, earnings were reduced because two vessels were temporarily out of service during the quarter.</p>
<p>GATX Logistics reported earnings of $100,000 for this year's third quarter compared to earnings of $200,000 million for the third quarter of last year. The company said empty space, elimination of short-term contracts and customer attrition reduced earnings for the quarter.</p>
<p>Earlier, GATX reported third quarter earnings of $1.47 a primary share, up from $1.13 a year ago.</p>
<p>Cash flow from operations and portfolio proceeds were $260 million in the third quarter, up from $95 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I84804">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8480401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
