<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133854" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends firm on soybean rally, hedges noted.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends firm on soybean rally, hedges noted.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures ended firm on a late surge in soybeans but commercial hedge selling limited the advances, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a little hedge selling today,&quot; a trader said. &quot;Everytime corn pops its head up the phones ring and elevators call with some sell orders, not heavy, but enough to take it back down.&quot;</p>
<p>Continental Grain sold two million bushels of December, Cargill Inc sold one million December and SAK Futures sold one million December, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn also remained technically weak.</p>
<p>Technicians cited the continued bearish slant given off by key moving averages such as the four and 20 day and reported the first support for the December at $2.77-1/2 with the next support level at $2.74-1/4. The session low for December was $2.76-1/4.</p>
<p>Corn was underpinned by forecasts for wet weather which would slow corn harvesting. USDA Monday said 30 percent of the U.S. corn crop had been harvested as of Sunday, which was below trade expectations that ranged from 30 to 45 percent.</p>
<p>Corn closed unchanged to one cent per bushel higher, with December up 1/2 at $2.79-1/2.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 50,000 contracts, down from 51,048 Monday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In corn options, FIMAT Futures bought 400 March $2.60 puts at three cents and Cargill Investor Services sold 500 March $2.60 puts at three cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 24,000 contracts, up from 22,015 Monday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
