<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13388" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Bratsk Aluminium sees output rising by 1999. [CORRECTED 17:00 GMT 30/8]</title>
<headline>Bratsk Aluminium sees output rising by 1999. [CORRECTED 17:00 GMT 30/8]</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bratsk Aluminium, Russia's biggest aluminium smelter, expects its output this year to be 770,000-780,000 tonnes after 772,500 tonnes in 1995, chief executive Boris Gromov said on Monday.</p>
<p>Output will rise to 800,000 tonnes in 1997 and 857,000 tonnes by 1999, he told a news conference. </p>
<p>&quot;We want to return to our peak production,&quot; Gromov said.</p>
<p>He said peak production was 857,000 tonnes, without naming the year that was achieved, and said the company would reach that level in 1998 or 1999.</p>
<p>Gromov said the expansion in output would cost about 50 billion roubles (corrects from 500 billion roubles) over three years and that expansion had already begun, funded from the company's cash-flow.</p>
<p>He said he did not rule out using bank credits or share issues to fund the project.</p>
<p>Most of the expanded output would be channelled into domestic sales as the Russian economy picked up, and the overall share of exports at Bratsk could fall, Gromov said.</p>
<p>Gromov said the company plans to increase the proportion of A7 aluminium (99.7 percent pure aluminium) in its production to 90 percent by 1997.</p>
<p>But Eduard Lasenko, head of Bratsk's production department, said he believed the company would increase production of A7 higher-quality aluminium to 70 or 80 percent of output within two years from approximately 60 percent at present.</p>
<p>&quot;Quality depends on the experience of the workers and condition of the equipment,&quot; Lasenko said. Bratsk, which is 30 years old, is a relatively labour-intensive smelter. </p>
<p>Gromov said the expansion was not related to the recently created Siberian Aluminium financial-industrial group, which Bratsk Aluminium has joined.</p>
<p>Other members of the group are Sayansk Aluminium, Kazakhstan's Pavlodar smelter and London-based Trans-World Group, which has invested in the non-ferrous metals industry in the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>AOOT Bratsky Alyuminiyevy Zavod (BrAZ) had pre-tax profits in 1995 of 1.19 trillion roubles after 401 billion in 1994, a company statement said. BrAZ had already announced net profits for 1995 of 765 billion roubles.</p>
<p>Sales in 1995 were 3.7 trillion roubles, according to a financial statement in local specialist publication Bratsky Metallurg.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
