<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133823" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. may speed troop withdrawal from Bosnia.</title>
<headline>U.S. may speed troop withdrawal from Bosnia.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said on Tuesday it might speed withdrawal of 15,000 U.S. peacekeeping troops from Bosnia because of a delay in holding municipal elections there until next year.</p>
<p>It also said Bosnian Serbs were &quot;on probation&quot; and could lose international aid or face new sanctions if they did not cooperate with the Organisation for European Security and Cooperation (OSCE) on the polls, expected by June.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that there could be some acceleration in the redeployment&quot; in the American troops in Bosnia, Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon told reporters.</p>
<p>But he stressed that current plans to have most of those troops out early next year remained in effect.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton promised to have U.S. troops out of Bosnia by Dec. 20, but that deadline has already slipped.</p>
<p>Talk of extending their stay -- or deploying a new force -- drew fire from critics who feared an open-ended American commitment in the Balkans. This has been an issue in the U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p>U.S. Gen. George Joulwan, NATO's supreme allied commander, had said most of the 50,000-member NATO-led peace implementation force (IFOR) in Bosnia, including 15,000 Americans, needed to remain to ensure security for the municipal elections when they were planned for November.</p>
<p>With the polls postponed, a speedier withdrawal was possible. But this also could mean a follow-on force would be even more necessary to provide security when the elections do take place.</p>
<p>Bacon spoke shortly after the head of the international mission organising Bosnia's postwar elections, American Robert Frowick, announced that municipal voting set for November would be postponed because of &quot;continuing political problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Bacon said he did not know exactly how the move would affect IFOR. The delay was a factor in whether the United States and its allies send a &quot;follow-on&quot; peacekeeping force to Bosnia next year, but no decision had been made, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm saying that as of right now ... our plans are unchanged and the IFOR forces are coming out. I anticipate they will come out on schedule, possibly ahead of schedule,&quot; Bacon said.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department backed the OSCE postponement decision but said elections must ultimately be held under OSCE auspices and Bosnia Serbs must cooperate or face consequences.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no question ... that one of the great problems encountered in arranging the elections in November was the unwillingness of the Bosnian Serbs to cooperate with the OSCE,&quot; spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bosnian Serb leadership should understand that the ability and the willingness of the international community to be helpful to them economically and otherwise is a direct function of their cooperation on this issue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Serbs are &quot;on probation&quot; and could face re-imposition of sanctions, he added.</p>
<p>The United States had insisted Bosnia's national elections be held in September despite deep concerns in many quarters that conditions in Bosnia -- including little freedom of movement -- would not permit free and fair polls.</p>
<p>Burns insisted the municipal elections were different. The 1995 Bosnia peace accord mandated national elections but said municipal polls should be held &quot;if feasible.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
