<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133853" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans rally late on various factors.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans rally late on various factors.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed mixed but nearby November staged an impressive turnaround late on a variety of fundamental and technical factors, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone has been trying to find a bottom. This may be the post-harvest rally but I say that with utmost caution,&quot; said Mark Cermak of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Rain-delayed harvesting of the U.S. soybean crop, slow farmer selling, firm basis markets and persistent talk that China continues to buy U.S. soybeans and soy products led the advances, they said.</p>
<p>USDA early Monday said U.S. exporters had reported a sale of 100,000 tonnes of U.S. soybeans to China and talk continues that even more has been sold.</p>
<p>Support came from forecasts for wet weather in the U.S. Midwest which will slow soybean harvesting plus news that soybean yields were dropping as the later-maturing soybean crop was being combined.</p>
<p>Technical indicators, including the four and 20 day moving averages were bearish early but Nov was short-term oversold.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed 8-1/2 cents per bushel higher to 4-1/2 lower, with November up 8-1/2 at $6.89.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is it (Nov) tried to fall below $6.80 on spot futures and they couldn't take it out. That's a strong area and at the $6.75 area there were a few interested in owning November beans,&quot; Cermak said.</p>
<p>The session low for November was $6.78 and the high was $6.90.</p>
<p>&quot;There were buy-stops at $6.85 in November and that brought in aggressive short covering,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rosenthal Collins triggered a late rally with two to three million bushels purchased in the November, the traders said. Rosenthal also was buying the January, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an outside day turnaround and it looked good for the November,&quot; a technical trader said. &quot;It (November) traded lower than yesterday's low and higher than yesterday's high and that usually precedes a change in direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated by the CBOT at 65,000, down from 66,451 Monday.</p>
<p>In soybean options, Term Commodities, the marketing arm of Louis Dreyfus Corp, bought 1,200 March $6.75 puts at 15 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated at 18,000, up from 14,605 Monday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
