<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133858" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. farmers holding out for $3.50 corn, $7.50 soy.</title>
<headline>U.S. farmers holding out for $3.50 corn, $7.50 soy.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slow farmer corn and soybean selling in the U.S. Midwest have held cash basis levels firm and farmers are not likely to sell unless prices rebound at least $0.80 per bushel, grain analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think farmers are going to be looking for $3.50 on corn and closer to $7.50 or $8.00 on beans,&quot; said Joe Miller, market analyst with the Indiana Farm Bureau.</p>
<p>&quot;We may not get to those prices but I think that's what they're going to be waiting for,&quot; Miller added.  </p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade corn and soybean futures prices have fallen more than $1.00 per bushel since July, prompting many farmers to store their crops in hopes of a recovery.</p>
<p>And country elevators have responded by holding cash basis bids at historically high levels.</p>
<p>While flat prices are lower than they were a year ago when concerns of a small crop drove prices sharply higher, basis bids at several country locations were sharply higher.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the basis level is a fair measurement of the farmer's perception of the price,&quot; said Dave Armstrong, grain analyst with The Chicago Corporation.  </p>
<p>&quot;This year, farmers believe this is too low a price,&quot; Armstrong said.</p>
<p>Bids for delivery at Clinton, Iowa, were at 15 cents over CBOT December futures on Monday. December futures closed at $2.80-1/4 per bushel on Friday.</p>
<p>That same location was quoting bids at 11 cents under the December on Oct. 23, 1995 while December futures stood at $3.35 per bushel.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a very large difference in basis levels for corn,&quot; Armstrong added. &quot;Five cents is noticeable and 10 cents is large.&quot;</p>
<p>One central Illinois river elevator noted basis levels at this time of year typically range from five to 10 cents a bushel under CBOT December. On Monday, bids stood at 10-1/2 cents over the December.</p>
<p>A merchandiser there said farmers would likely sell at least a portion of their corn crops if prices rallied 20 cents per bushel.</p>
<p>&quot;I've got offers here that are less than ($3.50 per bushel),&quot; said the grain dealer who declined to be named. &quot;Farmers would move some grain at the $3.00 level.&quot;</p>
<p>Soybeans would likely move at $7.00 per bushel, he added.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
