<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133847" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT wheat ends lower on Australian crop forecast.</title>
<headline>CBOT wheat ends lower on Australian crop forecast.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT wheat futures closed lower and new contract lows were set on a hike in an estimate for Australia's 1996-97 wheat production, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wheat fell below $4.00 (December). Everybody's talking about the Australian estimate,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>The Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) said the 1996-97 Australian wheat crop would total 20.9 million tonnes, up from ABARE's previous estimate for 18.8 million tonnes.</p>
<p>A late surge in soy gave wheat underpinning at the close.</p>
<p>December ended below $4.00 per bushel, the lowest level for a nearby contract since June 1995 and an important psychological benchmark support area. Technicians cite support now at $3.98 and $3.92 per bushel for the December contract.</p>
<p>A new contract low of $3.87-1/2 a bushel was set in the March, down from the previous low of $3.92 set Monday.</p>
<p>Wheat already was struggling with slack exports and building competition from the European Union, Argentina, Canada and Australia, the traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat closed one to three cents per bushel lower, with December down one at $3.99-1/2.</p>
<p>Traders said the key moving averages indicate the market remains bearish but the short term indicators indicate an oversold scenario.</p>
<p>December's nine day relative strength index (RSI) closed at 22.333 points. The market generally considers an RSI of 20 or less as indicative of a very oversold market.</p>
<p>Key sellers included Prudential Securities and Refco Inc each with two million bushels sold in the December, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 16,000 contracts, up from 15,488 Monday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 10,000 contracts, up from 4,154 Monday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
