<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133845" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar closes lower in U.S. on late profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Dollar closes lower in U.S. on late profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended lower against major currencies Tuesday as a late afternoon nosedive wiped out modest early gains.</p>
<p>Investors sold dollar/mark and sterling/mark to lock in profits after several days of rallying, while a wire service report triggered sales of dollar/yen, currency dealers said.</p>
<p>Market News Service reported an unnamed White House official predicted the persistent U.S.-Japan trade gap would soon begin to widen after months of shrinkage.</p>
<p>The U.S. propensity to import leaves foreigners with a steady supply of dollars to be sold in the currency market.  </p>
<p>&quot;That story is probably what got the ball rolling,&quot; said James Phoenix, director of foreign exchange sales at Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce in New York.</p>
<p>For most of the day the dollar sat just below Tuesday's 33-month high at 112.91 yen. But the late selloff sank the dollar to 112.27/32 yen, down from 112.80/90 at the open.</p>
<p>Against the mark, the dollar fell nearly a pfennig and closed at 1.5252/57 from 1.5332/35 at the open. The dollar also fell to 1.2535/45 Swiss francs from 1.2628/33. The British pound ended higher at $1.5988/95 from $1.5960/70.  </p>
<p>Investors sold sterling when it failed to top key technical hurdles at 2.45 marks, a 22-month high, and $1.60.</p>
<p>The mark and Swiss franc powered higher against the dollar as a result, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some pretty aggressive dollar selling by investment banks. Some people had gotten long the dollar in the morning, but when there was no follow-through buying, they got nervous,&quot; said Stephen Jury, chief dealer at Union Bank of Switzerland in New York.  </p>
<p>The dollar climbed against the yen in early trade after Japan reported its index of leading economic indicators plunged to 33.3 in August from 77.8 in July--well below the 50.0 level deemed the boundary between boom and bust.</p>
<p>That suggests the Bank of Japan will keep interest rates low in coming months, which would bolster the dollar by enhancing the relative value of assets priced in dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese economy is still struggling. The dollar should continue to move gradually higher against the yen over the next month or so,&quot; said Tadatoshi Taso, chief dealer at Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi in New York.  </p>
<p>The mark also got an early boost as Germany began the road show of its planned privatization of the state-owned telephone company, Deutsche Telekom.</p>
<p>The sale would raise about 18 billion marks and some investors bet the mark would rise as would-be Telekom buyers sell other currencies for marks in preparation, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's move was very much a move of the mark against sterling and the yen. That also touched off some sales of dollars for marks,&quot; said Chris Adair, currency trader at Mellon Bank in Pittsburgh.  </p>
<p>In other trade, the dollar fell to Canadian $1.3452/57 from C$1.3469/74. The Australian dollar fell to $0.7942/47 from, $0.7960/65.</p>
<p>--Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
