<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133818" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Treasuries end lower after two-year note sale.</title>
<headline>Treasuries end lower after two-year note sale.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices of U.S. Treasury securities ended substantially lower on Tuesday as concern over fresh supply weighed on the market for a second session.</p>
<p>The Treasury's sale of $18.28 billion in two-year notes produced encouraging results, but dealers said there was little buying in the auction's aftermath.</p>
<p>Weakness in the dollar during the afternoon also took a toll on Treasuries, which are expected to remain vulnerable until Wednesday's five-year note auction is out of the way.</p>
<p>&quot;The market traded briefly better after the auction but when there was no follow-through it came down once again,&quot; said James Kenney, head of government trading at Prudential Securities. &quot;It appears there was strong bidding for the issue but then people tried to sell everything else around it.&quot;</p>
<p>The benchmark 6.75 percent 30-year bond was off 19/32 at 98-25/32 to yield 6.85 percent in late Tuesday trading vs. 6.81 percent on Monday. The new 5.875 two-year note was yielding 5.95 percent in late dealing.</p>
<p>The Treasury's two-year note sale produced a high yield of 5.93 percent and 56 percent of bids were awarded at the high rate. This was down from the 6.08 percent registered at the last auction of two-year notes on Sept. 25.</p>
<p>A total of $47.89 billion in bids was received, $1.01 billion of which were non-competitive bids. The bid-to-cover ratio, a measure of auction demand, came in at a firm 2.62.</p>
<p>After the auction results were released, Treasuries extended their early losses, ultimately sinking to session lows as the dollar deteriorated in late trading.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of what has been propelling the markets is the sense that the dollar is getting stronger,&quot; said David Horner, senior financial strategist at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>When the dollar showed signs of faltering, Horner said, the bond and stock markets followed suit.</p>
<p>The dollar ended nearly one pfennig lower against the German mark and retreated against the Japanese yen as well. The Dow Jones industrial average shed about 29 points.</p>
<p>Ample gains in weekly retail sales reports also lent Treasuries a negative bias, analysts said. Both the BTM/Schroders and Redbook Research Service showed sizable 0.8 percent gains for the period ending Oct. 19, suggesting that consumers may be bouncing back from an extremely weak third quarter.</p>
<p>Economists predicted further price erosion ahead as dealers set up for the Treasury's sale Wednesday of $12.5 billion in five-year notes. But once this supply is digested, they said, the market should perk up.</p>
<p>&quot;Once we chip through the five-year and get the supply out of the way we have a chance to do marginally better into the end of the week,&quot; said Lee Youngdahl, money market economist at Aubrey G. Lanston &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>In a report that had little tangible impact on prices, the Labour Department said import prices rose 0.8 percent in September while export prices fell by 0.8 percent. CORPORATE BONDS</p>
<p>In the corporate market, trade was plagued for a second consecutive session by negative sentiments surrounding the credit status of TCI Communications, dealers said.</p>
<p>TCI debt widened from 10 to 20 basis points in active trade, doubling losses sustained in Monday's trade.</p>
<p>The downward spiral commenced after rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's said late Friday that it might lower TCI's debt ratings to junk bond status. In its comment, S&amp;P said the negative outlook reflected its concern that &quot;debt relative to cash generation may remain at the outer edge of S&amp;P's parameters for a marginal investment grade rating.&quot;</p>
<p>High-grades traders said the move has the entire market scared and has given them reason to reevaluate the entire sector. Traders were unwilling to forecast further widening in TCI debt, but most did expect the negative trend to continue.</p>
<p>Other cable and media debt was also quoted lower in sympathy with TCI, but only marginally by comparison. Time Warner's 7-3/4 percent notes due 2005 widened 5 basis points to 120 basis point spread, one trader said. MUNICIPAL BONDS</p>
<p>In the municipals market, a deluge of new offerings totalling about $2.2 billion drew mixed results, helping cut the prices of municipal bonds in the secondary market by one-quarter to three-eights of a point.</p>
<p>While some of the issuers who raised capital saw their balances decline sharply, partly due to demand by casualty insurers and bond funds, this did not necessarily mean that the issues had left the dealers' shelves.</p>
<p>&quot;The bonds are in some of the dealers' hands. No one's getting rich off them, people are selling them where they own them or slightly better,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Among the large primary offerings, California sold $500 million of general obligation bonds at a true interest cost of 5.509 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
