<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133838" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas prices rally with cold weather.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas prices rally with cold weather.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natgas prices rallied Tuesday as cold temperatures blanketed the central U.S., thereby putting additional strain on already tight supplies, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Gulf Coast prices jumped more than 10 cents into the low-$2.50s as the first touch of winter brought additional Midwest and Texas Panhandle buyers to the market.</p>
<p>At the Henry Hub, La., most deals were confirmed done in the low-to-mid $2.50s, while in south Texas prices climbed into the $2.42-2.47 range.  </p>
<p>Prices were equally higher in the Midcontinent where deals were reported done mostly in the low-$2.40s.</p>
<p>The Chicago city-gate market was quoted in the high-$2.80s to low-$2.90s, soaring more than 10 cents over Monday's level. Similarly at Demarcation prices gained an additional 10 cents to the high-$2.40s.</p>
<p>In west Texas, there was buying interest from both the East and the West, pushing Permian prices into the mid-$2.30s, up at least 10 cents from Monday.</p>
<p>At Waha, gas sold mostly in the low-$2.40s, still holding the approximately five-cent premium to Permian basin prices.</p>
<p>Oasis Pipe Line Co reported earlier Tuesday it will curtail about 200 million cubic feet per day of gas in the first three weeks of November due to scheduled maintenance at the Prairie Lea Compressor Station in Caldwell County, Texas.</p>
<p>The outage is expected to end by November 21.</p>
<p>At the southern California border, cold weather in the Northwest and the tight Permian supplies resulted in prices in the high-$2.40s, up more than 10 cents.</p>
<p>On the opposite coast, New York city-gate prices surged into the mid-$2.90s, up an average of 10 cents on the day, despite forecasts for above-normal temperatures later this week in the region.</p>
<p>Although temperatures are below-normal now in the Midwest, the weather is expected to moderate by the latter part of the week.</p>
<p>As the time before the onset of the traditional winter withdrawal season dwindles, some buyers may take advantage of the milder weather before the weekend to replenish storage inventories, trade sources said.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
