<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133830" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT-Mark/yen to lead once dlr/yen tests 113.58.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Mark/yen to lead once dlr/yen tests 113.58.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Once the dollar chips through resistance at 112.90 yen, it should make a break for 113.58 but the mark may soon take over driving the yen down, technicians said.</p>
<p>The dollar/yen prognosis still calls for a test of the January 1994 high at 113.58. But while the dollar's rally starts to look overextended, mark/yen seems poised to break free from a long-standing consolidation pattern.</p>
<p>&quot;I think now that we're breaking out of this triangle, we're going to go above 74.00 yen,&quot; said Pete Grant, senior foreign exchange analyst at MMS International.  </p>
<p>Mark/yen has been trapped in a narrowing trading pattern since July. But trendline resistance at 73.65 came under assault on Tuesday, leading analysts to forecast the cross may soon punch through the July 15 high of 73.78.</p>
<p>&quot;Pennants or contracting triangles are, first of all, continuation patterns,&quot; said David Solin, partner at Foreign Exchange Analytics. &quot;Usually when you break out of them you break very sharply.&quot;</p>
<p>The expected move up in mark/yen may play out over several weeks and there is an outside chance the cross could return to the triangle base near 72.45 first, analysts said.  </p>
<p>The initial upside target is mark/yen 74.40, followed by 75 and possibly 77, chartists said.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen may find it tough going above 113.58, with the relative strength index (RSI) on the daily charts registering an almost overbought 69.</p>
<p>The outlook for dollar/mark, meanwhile, is less sanguine after it broke the base of a rising wedge near 1.5360 Monday.</p>
<p>Its subsquent rise from Tuesday's 1.5285 marks low may run counter to an emerging down trend after the decline from last week's high at 1.5454 marks unfolded in a classic five step Elliot Wave pattern, analysts said.  </p>
<p>Tuesday's dollar/mark low nearly coincides with trendline support; a break would target 1.5235 then 1.5200, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think how it will wash out is there is going to be a much higher mark/yen because ... dollar/mark over the next week or two comes off pretty good and dollar/yen probably stays stable or ... works its way a little higher,&quot; Solin said.</p>
<p>At 1430 EDT on Tuesday, mark/yen was near 73.57, up from 73.40 late Monday. Dollar/mark was trading at 1.5307/12, off from 1.5342/45 and dollar/yen was at 112.62/67, off from 112.71/76.   -- Alden Bentley 212 859 1667</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
