<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133879" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS - FX volatilities firmer, eyes on sterling.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS - FX volatilities firmer, eyes on sterling.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for dollar-pair options were generally firmer, particularly cable options as sterling rose to a 14-month high, within a whisker of $1.6000, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks pretty one-way,&quot; said Ted Voorhees, a senior trader at Deutsche Bank in New York. &quot;I don't see any reason why that should change in the near term. It's one of the few nice runs in this market right now.&quot;</p>
<p>Sterling has been on a steep uptrend since breaking out above the $1.57-level at the start of the month after a period of range-trading.  </p>
<p>Earlier in the day, the pound was boosted by a comment from a major British employers' group that the currency's strength had yet to harm British exporters.</p>
<p>Cable implied volatilities were well bid across the maturity curve, with one-month quoted at 5.6/5.9 percent, up a quarter point from late Monday levels.</p>
<p>Risk reversals, which reflect pricing differential between puts and calls, were skewed towards sterling calls, with one-month 25-delta assessed at 0.2/0.5 percent.</p>
<p>A U.S. bank trader said volatilities for sterling crosses were also firm.  </p>
<p>One-month sterling/mark volatility was up a few tenths of a point to 6.3/6.6 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sterling seems to be the flavor of the week,&quot; the U.S. bank trader said. He added that profit-taking would inevitably emerge soon but he expected sterling calls to stay bid over puts.</p>
<p>Implied volatilities were little changed in other major currency pairs as the spot dollar stayed within recent ranges.</p>
<p>Still, dollar/yen volatilities remained edgy as the dollar hovered just below its Monday high of 112.91 yen.  </p>
<p>One-month dollar/yen volatility stood at 6.8/6.9 percent, unchanged from late Monday levels but up from lows earlier in the day.</p>
<p>One-month 25-delta risk reversal was around par, while shorter-dated risk reversals slanted somewhat toward yen puts and longer-dated ones toward yen calls.</p>
<p>Traders said dollar/yen volatilities, during a dollar uptrend, tended to be vulnerable to a pause in the dollar's advance. But they noted that if the dollar kept rising, a huge amount of low-delta yen puts traded recently would start becoming more influential, forcing short-covering in options.  </p>
<p>One-month dollar/mark volatility stood at 6.75/6.95 percent, off early lows and marginally above late Monday levels. One-month risk reversal flipped slightly toward mark calls as concerns grew about a correction to the dollar's recent gains.</p>
<p>Voorhees said dollar/mark has recently been dictated by mark crosses and lacked energy. He expected the volatility curve to steepen as traders were likely to sell the front end to offset time-decay of their portfolios.</p>
<p>-- Shin Kishima/Chicago Derivatives Desk (312) 408-8750 E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
