<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133850" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soy products end mostly higher on demand.</title>
<headline>CBOT soy products end mostly higher on demand.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talk of strong demand for soyoil and soymeal, especially by China, plus a late rally in soybeans boosted CBOT soy product futures to a mostly higher close, traders said.</p>
<p>The market continued to hear rumblings of Chinese demand for soybeans, soyoil and soymeal and commercial bull spreading helped magnify the talk, they said.</p>
<p>The October oil and meal contract expired quietly at 1201 CDT. October soymeal closed at $231.00 per ton,  up $1.30 per ton and October soyoil went off the board at 22.75 cent per lb, down 0.16 per lb.</p>
<p>Traders said the soy complex was boosted late by rain-delayed harvesting of the U.S. soybean crop, slow farmer selling, firm cash basis markets and the China talk.</p>
<p>Soyoil futures volume was estimated at 14,000, down from 14,921 Monday, according to the CBOT. Soymeal futures volume was estimated at 24,000, down from 26,173 Monday.</p>
<p>Soyoil closed 0.05 to 0.17 cent per lb higher, with December up 0.10 at 23.31. Soymeal was $3.40 per ton higher to $1.20 lower, with December up $3.40 at $225.20.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
