<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133842" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Community Psych sells psychiatric centers.</title>
<headline>Community Psych sells psychiatric centers.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Community Psychiatric Centers said it agreed to sell its psychiatric operations in the U.S. and Puerto Rico to Behavioral Healthcare Corp for a combination of cash and BHC stock valued at $130-$165 million.</p>
<p>The deal consisted of $60 million in cash and BHC stock and stock equivalents valued from $70 million to $105 million.</p>
<p>In addition, CPC will realize a tax benefit from this transaction by substantially offsetting the gain attributable to the sale of its United Kingdom operations, it said.  </p>
<p>Community Psychiatric recently sold its U.K. psychiatric operations for $136 million in an effort to focus on being a provider of long-term acute care hospital services.</p>
<p>The new psychiatric company will retain the Behavioral Healthcare Corp name and will be based out of Nashville.</p>
<p>The combined entity will have 38 hospitals and four residential treatment centers. For the trailing 12 months as of July 31, 1996, pro forma annualized net revenues were about $309 million. Pro forma net earnings and EBITDA for the combined entity were about $13.0 million and $39.1 million, respectively.  </p>
<p>Based on the proposed ownership structure, CPC's share of the pro forma earnings would have been about $5.7 million (or $0.13 per share of CPC stock).</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close by November 30.</p>
<p>Richard Conte, CPC's chairman and chief executive officer, will serve as BHC's chairman. Edward Stack, BHC's founder and current president and CEO, will be CEO of the new BHC.</p>
<p>CPC plans to change its name to Transitional Hospitals Corp. THC operates 14 hospitals, two satellite facilities, has two facilities in development and is evaluating other projects and potential acquisitions across the country.  </p>
<p>THC's net revenues and net earnings through the first nine months of fiscal 1996 totaled $179.7 million and $7.8 million, or $0.18 per share, respectively.</p>
<p>It said the sale will further enhance its balance sheet.</p>
<p>After the close of the BHC transaction and receipt of an expected tax refund, there will be about $150 million in cash and just $25 million in debt on CPC's balance sheet.</p>
<p>It said it will use cash to accelerate THC's expansion and buy back stock. Its board voted to approve a $50 million stock repurchase, a program that is incremental to a $25 million buyback program authorized in August 1996.  </p>
<p>It said it has spent about $17 million to repurchase more than $2 million of its shares at an average price of $8.12.</p>
<p>BHC plans to take the new combined psychiatric company public as soon as market conditions and BHC's strategy permit.</p>
<p>It said CPC plans to retain about 20 percent of the shares outstanding in the new public company, while releasing the remaining 42 percent into the stock market in a manner most advantageous to the company and its shareholders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PURI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
