<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133828" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - new issues get mixed results.</title>
<headline>U.S MUNICIPAL FOCUS - new issues get mixed results.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A deluge of new offerings totaling about $2.2 billion, which drew mixed results, helped depress prices of municipal bonds in the secondary market by 1/4 to 3/8 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>While some of the issuers saw their balances decline sharply, partly due to demand by casualty insurers and bond funds, this did not necessarily mean that the issues had left the dealers' shelves.</p>
<p>&quot;It definitely seems like some of the bonds still are around at some of the dealers,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Similarly, another trader said likely buyers might be holding off to see how Wednesday's competitive sale of nearly $713 million revenue bonds by New Jersey Transit fares.</p>
<p>And potential buyers have another reason for taking their time: the U.S. Treasury on Wednesday sells of $12.5 billion of five-year notes.</p>
<p>While results from the Treasury's auction of $18.25 billion of two-year notes this afternoon were considered decent, traders said there was no follow-through buying.  </p>
<p>New offerings in the municipal bond market were expected total as much as $4.8 billion this week, with the bulk of the sales coming today.</p>
<p>This has given institutional investors lots of issues to pick and choose from, and some seemed to be pressing for higher yields.</p>
<p>&quot;It (demand) is not broad-based yet,&quot; a trader said. &quot;There's a little bit of congestion right now. The market is pretty tight, but people want to buy bonds a little cheaper,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bonds are in some of the dealers' hands. No one's getting rich off them, people are selling them where they own them or slightly better,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Among the large primary offerings, California sold $500 million of general obligation bonds at a true interest cost of 5.509 percent. Its syndicate, led by Lehman Brothers, said the unsold issues or balance totaled just over $80 million. Traders said some of the state's term bonds still seemed to be in need of homes.  </p>
<p>Minnesota sold $170 million of GO at a true interest cost of 5.16 percent, and its syndicate, led by J.P. Morgan Securities, reported a $48 million balance.</p>
<p>And Massachusetts Water Resources sold $150 million of bonds at a true interest cost of 5.7204 percent. The balance for these issues was $14.5 million, said its syndicate, which was managed by Goldman, Sachs &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Although December municipal bond futures traded on the Chicago Board of Trade have underperformed December U.S. Treasury bond futures, this pattern reversed late Tuesday.</p>
<p>While December municipal bond futures shed seven ticks to 113-31/32, the Treasury bond futures fell 14 ticks to 110-20/32. The MOB spread fattened slightly from levels seen on Monday to 107 ticks.</p>
<p>Actively traded issues in the secondary market included Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority of March 2020, which pay a 5-1/4 percent coupon, and were bid at 5.76 percent NET. This was up three basis points from Monday's levels.</p>
<p>Yet Matagorda County Texas Navigation District Number 1 Pollution Control revenues of May 2030, which have a 6-1/8 percent coupon, were bid at 101-1/2, up 1/2.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
