<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133824" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TALKING POINT/Wall St earnings season trickier.</title>
<headline>TALKING POINT/Wall St earnings season trickier.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street has made the earnings reporting season this fall more tricky for some major U.S. companies.</p>
<p>No longer is the marker for performance as simple a figure as the Wall Street consensus estimate -- the average of forecasts by industry analysts.</p>
<p>Now the target is often the &quot;whisper&quot; number -- an unpublished, phantom estimate that flies from trading room to trading room.  </p>
<p>To be sure, analysts said unpublished underground estimates a few cents higher or lower than the official consensus have been around for years.</p>
<p>But they noted such information has become vital in a market dominated by institutions that quickly shift stakes on a company's ability to produce. At a time when stocks are at or near record highs, valuation worries have become magnified.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is such a sensitivity to earnings, probably this quarter more so than others. Investors are more on edge since people know profit growth is slowing. There will be more shortfalls. Whisper numbers make the situation worse,&quot; said Marshall Acuff, portfolio strategist at Smith Barney.</p>
<p>He said some of the whisper numbers &quot;floating around the Street are probably unrealistically high, and the (earnings) numbers are needed to support stock prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael LaTronica, director of research at Gruntal &amp; Co, does not encourage whisper numbers among his analysts, though he has seen such underground guidance's impact on the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is more institution-, more mutual fund-driven so (whisper numbers) are more an issue. Analysts don't want to be surprised on the negative side. So the whisper circuit does tell some institutions what the real number will be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said some whisper numbers have resulted from companies being very conservative in guidance. &quot;They keep the official guidance lower and make the whisper number (which is higher, so the stock could rise on an upside &quot;surprise.&quot;) It turns into quite a game,&quot; LaTronica said.  </p>
<p>One industry analyst, who requested anonymity, said whisper numbers are generated in a variety of ways. &quot;There's no cookie-cutter answer. It's very company specific.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Any big, liquid market-cap company has numbers every quarter that are a whisper number. Sometimes it's the same&quot; as the official consensus, the analyst said.  </p>
<p>Philip Orlando, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management, said: &quot;The whisper numbers may come from trading desks, the sales force or analysts -- all on the sell-side and generated to the buy side to attempt to provide the appearance that any individual sell-side broker's research is superior to that of his competitor's.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The whisper may sound like this: 'The official consensus is $0.45, but I spoke with my contacts at the company and confidentially it looks like it'll be closer to $0.50.'&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I tend to ignore it from a statistical valuation standpoint. But I keep it in the back of my mind,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Whisper numbers tend to come with more volatile, higher-beta stocks, which by definition tends to be technology,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Among recent examples, International Business Machines Corp briefly dipped Monday morning after it reported third-quarter earnings rose to $2.45 a share, two cents above the First Call consensus. But the number was shy of the whisper numbers of $2.50 and $2.53 quoted by some traders.  </p>
<p>On October 16, Sun Microsystems Inc tumbled 6-7/8 to 63-1/8 after reporting a jump in fiscal first-quarter profit to $0.63 a share, two cents above the First Call consensus. But some were looking for an even better number.</p>
<p>Sun Micro declined to comment on whisper numbers.</p>
<p>Also on October 16, Compaq Computer Corp reported quarterly earnings jumped to $1.26 a share, above the First Call consensus of $1.07. Still, the stock lost 1-1/8 to 73-5/8 on a day when the Dow set a record high.</p>
<p>&quot;The whisper the day before was $1.32, and that was a stupid number,&quot; a tech trader said.  </p>
<p>A spokesman for the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, when asked to comment on the impact of underground guidance, would only say the SEC could not confirm or deny any investigation into whisper numbers.</p>
<p>As for how the current earnings season is proceeding, some analysts said the period was going well as companies hurdle Wall Street's generally low expectations.</p>
<p>Gail Dudack, chief investment strategist at UBS Securities, said earnings were expected to rise five to six percent from a year ago, above trendline but slower than in recent quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;It depends on what you look at,&quot; said Acuff. &quot;Some better companies are coming through with good numbers like Intel, Chrysler, Caterpillar, Pfizer and Compaq. But the average or lesser companies seem to be having more shortfalls.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212 859-1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
