<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133832" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt fund managers remain bullish -- MCM.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt fund managers remain bullish -- MCM.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. fixed-income managers maintained a bullish exposure in their debt portfolios over the past week, according to an MCM MoneyWatch Inc survey.</p>
<p>&quot;This group is bullish ... and not intending to bail until inflation surfaces or the economy shows more signs of life,&quot; said MCM money market analyst Peter McTeague, who conducts the asset allocation survey.</p>
<p>The weekly survey showed durations as a percentage of benchmark rose to 106.3 percent in the week ended October 21 from 105.8 percent in the prior week.  </p>
<p>A duration reading above 100 percent indicates the group of investors polled is mostly long on the market.</p>
<p>A portfolio's duration represents its average maturity and is used by portfolio managers to calculate exposure to risk.</p>
<p>In the &quot;next likely move&quot; category, portfolio managers representing 12 percent of total assets in the survey said they would &quot;buy,&quot; down from 14 percent the prior week.</p>
<p>Strategists leaning toward &quot;sell&quot; also fell, to 26 percent, down from 34 percent in the week ended October 15.</p>
<p>Sixty-two percent of managers said they were &quot;neutral&quot; on the market, up from 52 percent a week ago.  </p>
<p>Cash as a percentage of assets fell to 2.49 percent, against 2.68 percent registered the previous week.</p>
<p>The survey showed 20 percent of investors polled overweighted the 10-plus years duration sector, down from 21 percent in the previous week, while 28 percent underweighted it. The remaining 52 percent were &quot;neutral.&quot;</p>
<p>In the five- to 10-year duration sector, 49 percent of investors polled said they overweighted the securities and 16 percent underweighted them.  </p>
<p>The survey included 40 domestic participants, who manage about $100 billion in fixed-income assets. The poll is conducted weekly by MCM and usually is released on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Results of the survey follow:</p>
<p>   Category*					   Oct 21, 1996</p>
<p>   Duration percentage of benchmark		 106.3 pct</p>
<p>   Next Likely Move-Buy(B)/Sell(S)	12 pct B-26 pct S</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) Weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   Governments				  20 pct O-55 pct U</p>
<p>   Corporates				   52 pct O-25 pct U</p>
<p>   Mortgages				    49 pct O-12 pct U</p>
<p>   Cash as a percentage of assets		    2.49 pct</p>
<p>Percentage experiencing cash</p>
<p>	In (I) - Out (O)			35 pct I-22 pct O</p>
<p>Over(O)-Under(U) weight Benchmark</p>
<p>   1- to 5-year duration sector	   24 pct O-47 pct U</p>
<p>   5- to 10-year duration sector	  49 pct O-16 pct U</p>
<p>   10+     year duration sector	   20 pct O-28 pct U</p>
<p>* Table provided by MCM MoneyWatch Inc consultants.</p>
<p>Results are dollar-weighted.</p>
<p>-- Jeff Coelho, (212) 859-1562</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
