<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133829" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures rally further on late short cover.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures rally further on late short cover.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures continued to score gains late Tuesday in moderate trade, with more short covering driving the soon-to-expire November contract through key resistance, industry sources said.</p>
<p>At 1405 EDT, November was up by 14.3 cents at $2.625 per million British thermal units, while December was 12.7 cents higher at $2.73. Others were up by 1.6 to 10.5 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little cold in the Midwest, but (longer-term), I don't see that much bullish in the weather. This is not new buying and I think it's blowing out too early (in the season),&quot; said one East Coast trader.  </p>
<p>Traders said colder Midwest weather helped firm the cash and fuel buying last night on ACCESS that pushed the spot contract through minor resistance in the $2.51 area.</p>
<p>They said shorts, spooked after recent gains and facing increased spot margins later today, opted to bail ahead of November's expiration this Friday.</p>
<p>But some were skeptical, expecting mostly above-normal Eastern temperatures later this week and next to cap the rally.</p>
<p>Technically, with November off the board Friday, traders said a December settle above the recent $2.725 recent high could lead to a move to the $2.80 area and possibly a test of the $2.865 contract high.</p>
<p>Cash sources said Gulf Coast prices firmed about 10 cents Tuesday to near the $2.50 level. Midcon pipes were up 10 cents or more to about $2.40. New York city gate gas also gained about 10 cents to the low-$2.90s. November city gate quotes were in the NYMEX plus 65-cent area.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 34,700 Hub contracts traded at 1335 EDT.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Alberta natgas was still up by 3.5 cents at $1.11, while deferreds remained untraded at 1410 EDT. NYMEX said 28 Alberta contracts traded by 1335 EDT.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Alberta natgas expires Tuesday, October 29.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Permian natgas jumped 16.5 cents to $2.38, while deferred months were untraded.</p>
<p>NYMEX November Permian natgas expires Tuesday, October 29.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, November was 13 cents higher at $2.42, while deferreds were up by 7.5 to eight cents. The East/West spread widened by 1.3 cents to 20.5 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>KCBT November natgas expires Monday, October 28.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
