<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133878" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DC bond documents say SEC muni probe unwarranted.</title>
<headline>DC bond documents say SEC muni probe unwarranted.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The District of Columbia told investors in a recent general obligation bond offering that an SEC probe launched in February 1995 of city bonds continues despite being groundless.</p>
<p>&quot;The District does not believe that it violated the federal securities laws in connection with such offerings,&quot; the city said in the preliminary Official Statement for the $168.87 million of GO bonds sold October 3.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the investigation launched February 9, 1995 &quot;is ongoing,&quot; the District said in the document.</p>
<p>&quot;The District cannot, at this time, predict what action, if any, the SEC will take as a result of the investigation or what impact, if any, the investigation may have on the District or its securities,&quot; the POS says.</p>
<p>Daniel Rezneck, general counsel for District's five-member control board told D.C. lawyers October 9 that the SEC's probe continues and probably has been expanded to cover city financial statements for fiscal year 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The District sold a large amount of bonds in&quot; late 1994, Rezneck said. &quot;The result was an SEC investigation of the District which is still ongoing.&quot;</p>
<p>Rezneck added that D.C. auditor KPMG Peat Marwick in January highlighted deficiencies in D.C.'s financial statements for FY 1995. Thos recent findings are &quot;undoubtedly part of SEC's investigation,&quot; Rezneck said.</p>
<p>D.C.'s lawyer Gerald Laporte, an attorney with the lawfirm Patton Boggs, said he had no comment on the investigation.</p>
<p>Washington sources say SEC is examining the quality of D.C.'s disclosure in the December 1994 notes sale, among other matters.</p>
<p>When the 1994 notes were sold through a syndicate led by Prudential Securities Inc. bond documents put D.C.'s budget deficit at $492 million. Six weeks later, however, city officials estimated it at roughly $722 million.</p>
<p>Rezneck told lawyers at the October 9 D.C. bar meeting that SEC probably would not be investigating the city as enthusiastically if D.C. were not at its doorstep.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
