<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133871" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Date set for senior level U.S.-China arms talks.</title>
<headline>Date set for senior level U.S.-China arms talks.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The State Department's top arms control expert will meet Chinese officials in Beijing on Nov. 4-5 to discuss alleged nuclear sales and other non-proliferation issues, the State Department said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Undersecretary of State Lynn Davis' talks, agreed to in principle by U.S. and Chinese officials some months ago, are designed to pave the way for a trip to China on Nov. 21-22 by Secretary of State Warren Christopher, spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>He added that Davis' discussions would involve &quot;the full-range of non-proliferation and security issues.&quot;</p>
<p>Her visit is part of a newly-resumed dialogue between the United States and China on arms-related matters.</p>
<p>John Holum, head of the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, held talks in Beijing recently and Deputy Assistant Secretary of State Robert Einhorn, one of the administration's leading technical experts on non-proliferation, will be in the Chinese capital ahead of Davis.</p>
<p>Also, the State Department's top Asia expert, Assistant Secretary of State Winston Lord, was in Beijing last week.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said relations with China have generally improved in recent months, but there have been frictions in the last three weeks over its treatment of dissidents and over fresh reports of Chinese nuclear sales to Pakistan.</p>
<p>Washington has continued to maintain that China had not violated past pledges with the sale, which the Washington Times said last week consisted of a special industrial furnace and high-tech diagnostic equipment, a point Burns reiterated on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
