<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133851" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N. Korean envoy to meet U.S. officials in New York.</title>
<headline>N. Korean envoy to meet U.S. officials in New York.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea's top American affairs specialist will meet U.S. officials in New York this week for talks on a possible North Korean missile test and Pyongyang's nuclear programme, administration officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Yi Hyong-chol, chief of the North Korean foreign ministry's American Affairs Bureau, is officially visiting New York on United Nations business.</p>
<p>But Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon said: &quot;We will carry on conversations with him about the test, about the framework agreement (on nuclear cooperation) and other topics.&quot;</p>
<p>The State Department said it was likely Yi would join a periodic meeting between U.S. and North Korean diplomats at the United Nations -- the principal channel of communication between the two countries which have no direct relations.</p>
<p>Yi's visit comes amid high tension on the Korean peninsula following an intrusion by a North Korean submarine into South Korean waters last month and the landing of 26 North Koreans, all but three of whom have since been killed or captured.</p>
<p>Last week, U.S. and Japanese military officials said North Korea had made apparent preparations to test-fire a medium-range missile into the sea off Japan. The State Department said it has several times warned Pyongyang not to conduct the test, most recently last Friday.</p>
<p>Because of the submarine incident, South Korea has said it may delay implementing a 1994 deal to supply the communist North with modern nuclear reactors in return for Pyongyang's abandonment of its existing nuclear programme.</p>
<p>U.S. Assistant Secretary of State Winston Lord also spoke during a visit to Seoul last week of a &quot;pause in the pace of our activities&quot;, prompting Pyongyang to threaten that the entire nuclear agreement could be jeopardised.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Lord would not meet Yi. South Korea's Yonhap news agency reported on Monday that Yi was likely to seek meetings with Lord's deputy in the State Department's East Asia bureau, Charles Kartman.</p>
<p>Burns said Yi's visit came at &quot;a time of great tension between the United States, the Republic of (South) Korea on one hand, and North Korea&quot;.</p>
<p>Apart from the submarine incident and missile test, North Korea is holding an American, Carl Hunziker, on spy charges. And Washington is still awaiting a reply from Pyongyang to a proposal in April for four-party talks on the future of Korea.</p>
<p>Burns defended the administration's policy of continuing a dialogue with Pyongyang, which has been criticised by some U.S. commentators and is viewed with suspicion in Seoul.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made a decision that we're going to keep talking to the North Koreans, despite all the problems in the relationship, because we believe that by continuing to meet them we might be able to make progress in some of these issues,&quot; he told a news briefing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
