<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133802" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kiwi Int'l gets $5 mln backing from Wasatch.</title>
<headline>Kiwi Int'l gets $5 mln backing from Wasatch.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kiwi International Air Lines secured $5 million in debtor-in-possession financing, which will sustain the bankrupt airline until additional financing is obtained, a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>The $5 million financing commitment from Wasatch Group will &quot;likely to be converted into equity in the final reorganization,&quot; Kiwi spokesman Rob Kulat told Reuters following a bankruptcy hearing in Newark.</p>
<p>Bankrutpcy Judge Rosemary Gambardella asked both Wasatch and Kiwi to return Thursday, October 31, to present a more definitive transition plan.  </p>
<p>Kiwi said it was too early to determine when it will recall its furloughed employees. Kiwi now has 85 people on payroll, but at its peak, the airline employeed 1,200.</p>
<p>Kiwi filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy reorganization on September 30 under a $40 million debt load and suspended flights on October 15 after failing to secure financing. The carrier's 15-jet fleet remains inactive.</p>
<p>Kiwi's bankruptcy followed its partial shutdown earlier in the year and a general slowing in air passenger traffic after the crash of a ValuJet airliner in May.</p>
<p>The link with Wasatch, which owns Palm Beach Cruise Lines, may provide Kiwi with &quot;some synergies&quot; in the future, Kulat said.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have our charter license and we could service the cruise line,&quot; Kulat said.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
