<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133819" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. foreign crudes pressure domestic sour grades.</title>
<headline>U.S. foreign crudes pressure domestic sour grades.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. foreign crudes from the region are pressuring domestic sour barrels at a time when some refineries have lowered operating capacities.</p>
<p>Traders said problems at several Midwest refineries and autumn maintenance, coupled with Canadian and Latin American heavy crudes flowing into the U.S., added to the surplus.</p>
<p>News Venezuela's Amuay refinery shut down a 108,000 barrel per day catcracker for at least a week of repairs today was also expected to add to short-term availability.</p>
<p>Sour supplies included 360,000 barrels of Oriente offered by a trader for later November.</p>
<p>Oriente will now be priced against West Texas Sour rather than West Texas Intermediate, according to Petroecuador's latest sales formula.</p>
<p>The grade was recently heard sold at WTI minus $2.60 cif.</p>
<p>A cargo of heavy, sweet Argentine Mendanitos moved earlier this week at WTI minus $1.35 a barrel fob, for late Nov.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf imports ballooned to 8.1 million barrels per day for the week ended Oct 18, in spite of a tight arbitrage but traders said North Sea and West African cargoes were scarce.</p>
<p>A major was seen exploring potential outlets for Brent in late Nov/early Dec, but no delivered numbers were heard.</p>
<p>In the U.S. after market, Brent intermonth Nov/Dec traded at 38 cents, and Dec/Jan at 68 cents, confirming the market's downtrend from the London session.</p>
<p>Dec Brent partials traded at $24.68 a barrel and $24.66, up from the London IPE close of $24.63.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
