<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133843" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arkansas ponders sending invitation to Lady Luck.</title>
<headline>Arkansas ponders sending invitation to Lady Luck.</headline>
<byline>Kathie O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lady Luck could get a firmer foothold in Arkansas if voters approve a lottery and casinos referendum this November. But while some bet she'll boost the state's economy, others see a jackpot of misery.</p>
<p>The Arkansas ballot contains four proposed amendments that call for a variety of reforms to the state constitution, including permiting a state lottery, bingo and raffles, video terminals and casino gambling.</p>
<p>Craig Douglass, campaign coordinator for one of the amendments, Amendment 4, said under his plan, net revenue from the lottery could mean $70 million in the first year. This money would be split evenly between Arkansas schools and law enforcement projects.</p>
<p>In addition, a limited number of casinos, confined to a tourist area, would keep Arkansas money from going to neighboring states and create jobs at home, he said.</p>
<p>But the lure of big and fast revenues also has a downside, according to some opponents of the measures.</p>
<p>Larry Page, executive director of Christian Civic Action Committee, said that while gambling generates revenue and creates jobs, the revenue and jobs never reach the level proponents say they will.</p>
<p>&quot;Gambling is not a cost-free, care-free form of recreation,&quot; Page said. &quot;The costs are significant.&quot;</p>
<p>Gaming requires oversight, attracts crime, can be addictive and diverts money that might have been spent elsewhere, Page said. Lotteries are an inefficient way to gather revenue that prey upon the poor who tend to gamble more than they can afford.</p>
<p>Arkansans can now travel across the stateline to gamble.</p>
<p>Douglass said Arkansas is &quot;virtually surrounded&quot; by lotteries and casino gaming.  Missouri has casino gambling to the north, Mississippi has it to the east and Louisiana has it to the south. Missouri, Louisiana and Texas also have lotteries.</p>
<p>&quot;So what we've found in Arkansas is that Arkansans are playing lottery games and casino games, sending Arkansas money and creating jobs in other states around our borders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tourists that used to come to Arkansas are now by-passing Arkansas (and) going to the Casinos in Mississippi, Louisiana and Missouri, so Amendment Four would address all of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Arkansas Department of Finance and Administration has projected that the first year of the lottery could create gross sales of roughly $207 million and net revenues of about $70 million, Douglass said.</p>
<p>&quot;That means the school districts would split up $35 million, and tht's new money without raising taxes,&quot; he said. The remaining $35 million would be used to go to law enforcement programs.</p>
<p>If approved in November, the lottery would probably be up and running by January 1998.</p>
<p>But Christian Civic's Page said casinos would not increase tourism substantially because virtually every state tourists have to cross to come to Arkansas has gambling.</p>
<p>While ARkansas casinos might attract some tourists, the effect would be &quot;nothing like they are talking about.&quot;</p>
<p>As for the lottery, Christian Civic Action Committee views is as another tax on the poor, who tend to gamble disproportionately, Pafge said.</p>
<p>--212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
