<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133812" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Coffee prices rise sharply on supply shortage fears.</title>
<headline>Coffee prices rise sharply on supply shortage fears.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee prices rose sharply Tuesday on growing concern about tight supplies, contributing to an overall advance in commodity prices with gasoline and soybeans among the day's other strong performers.</p>
<p>Prices rose from the outset on the New York Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange , fuelled by a 24,000-bag drop in exchange-deliverable coffee.</p>
<p>The drawdown, which caught many traders by surprise, reduced CSCE certified stocks to just 5,583 60-kg bags as of October 18.</p>
<p>&quot;People are nervous that there is not much coffee available,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Steve Platt. &quot;The certified stock report put stocks at an extremely low level.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said mounting concerns about Colombian supplies as a trucking strike there reached its ninth day also contributed to the market's bullish mood.</p>
<p>The head of Colombia's National Coffee Growers Federation, Jorge Cardenas, said Tuesday the work stoppage had paralysed the nation's coffee industry and forced delays in the shipment of about 250,000 60-kilo bags of coffee for October delivery.</p>
<p>December coffee closed at 117.60 cents a lb, up 4.60 cents on the day.</p>
<p>The Commodity Research Bureau's index of 17 commodities rose by 1.12 points to 244.95.</p>
<p>Gasoline prices in New York Tuesday surged on news Petroleos de Venezuela's Amuay refinery, a major gasoline maker, suffered a partial outage, while heating oil prices declined on prospects of increasing supplies, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The refinery supplies about 70,000 barrels per day of gasoline, so the effect of this problem (on supply) could be significant depending how long this lasts,&quot; said a New York trader.</p>
<p>Gasoline for November delivery on the New York Mercantile Exchange settled up 1.20 cents at 69.12 cents a gallon while November heating oil ended off 0.18 cent at 73.45 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>The rise in gasoline prices took November crude to a contract high of $26.10 a barrel at a time when crude is already at five-year highs.</p>
<p>But, November crude closed off 17 cents a barrel at $25.75.</p>
<p>Heating oil prices fell on news Colonial Pipeline Co. will use its gasoline pipeline to accommodate a surge in requests to ship distillates, especially heating oil, on its pipeline.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is reacting to Colonial's maximizing distillate deliveries by using its gasoline line,&quot; said John Bradberry, vice president of risk and inventory management at Continental Ozark Inc.</p>
<p>The Colonial Pipeline extends from Houston to Linden, N.J., on the edge of New York Harbour, and includes a distillate line that can ship 960,000 barrels a day.</p>
<p>Colonial said requests to ship more distillates on its pipeline increased following a meeting between U.S. Energy Department officials and oil company executives to discuss a spike in heating oil prices related to record low inventories.</p>
<p>Soybean futures on the Chicago Board of Trade, also closed higher, reversing direction after recent weakness.</p>
<p>Prices rose as rain further delayed the harvest, which, according to USDA figures, was only 63 percent complete as of Sunday, down from a five-year average of 70 percent.</p>
<p>The market has fallen steadily during the last month as the first phase of the harvest saw better-than-expected yields. The early promise has not been maintained and later maturing crops have performed much less impressively.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone has been trying to find a bottom. This may be the post harvest rally but I say that with utmost caution,&quot; said Mark Cermak of Chicago-based grain house O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>November soybeans ended 8-1/2 cents up at $6.89 a bushel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
