<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133938" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Christian group seeks probe temple fund raiser.</title>
<headline>Christian group seeks probe temple fund raiser.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Christian Coalition, a conservative political activist organisation, has asked the Federal Election Commission to investigate a Democratic Party fundraiser at a Buddhist Temple, executive director Ralph Reed said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reed said in a prepared excerpts of a speech at the National Press Club that coalition lawyers filed a formal complaint against the Democratic National Committee (DNC), the party's administrative and fundraising arm.</p>
<p>He was referring to the political row over a fundraiser held last June by Democrats at a Buddhist temple where members take vows of poverty but where $140,000 was raised at the event attended by Vice President Al Gore.</p>
<p>The man who organised the temple fundraiser, Democratic National Committee official John Huang, has come under fire for soliciting funds from Asian Americans, including a couple associated with the Lippo Group, a far-flung Indonesia-based banking combine.</p>
<p>&quot;Now all Americans can see the double standard that has been imposed upon conservative people of faith,&quot; said Reed.</p>
<p>&quot;The DNC has complained about our nonpartisan voter guides while turning a Buddhist temple of worship into a den of thieves,&quot; he said. &quot;We condemn as unethical and irresponsible the actions of a party and an administration that have polluted a sanctuary of sacred vows with the corruption of special interests.&quot;</p>
<p>The Democratic Party has asked the FEC to investigate the fund raising but the agency said there was no way an investigation could be completed by the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>The Christian Coalition, which is a tax exempt nonpartisan organisation, is being sued by the FEC in federal court for allegedly making illegal contributions to former President George Bush and other Repubublicans through the voter guides it distributes before elections and for conducting get-out-the- vote drives for certain candidates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
