<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133961" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: VW Chairman to remain defendant in GM lawsuit.</title>
<headline>VW Chairman to remain defendant in GM lawsuit.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volkswagen AG Chairman Ferdinand Piech and another top executive must continue to defend themselves in General Motors Corp.'s industrial espionage lawsuit against the German automaker, a federal judge ruled Monday.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Nancy Edmunds in Detroit has not yet issued a written opinion, but told lawyers in the case that she has decided to deny VW's motion to exclude Piech and VW management board member Jens Neumann from the suit, a court clerk said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Edmunds also ruled that Volkswagen AG, in addition to its Volkswagen of America Inc. subsidiary, must continue to defend itself against GM's charges.</p>
<p>GM alleges that Volkswagen's production chief, Jose Ignacio Lopez de Arriortua, conspired with Piech, Neumann and others to steal GM corporate secrets when he left GM to join VW in March 1993.</p>
<p>GM claims Lopez and seven executives who followed him to VW took vital parts pricing data, future product plans and proprietary manufacturing techniques, among other information. The lawsuit seeks unspecified damages.</p>
<p>Edmunds last week denied VW's motion to dismiss the case, a decision that allows GM to pursue justice on its home turf in the heart of the U.S. auto industry instead of having to rely on German courts. Criminal investigations on the matter are still underway in both Germany and the United States, and a civil suit is still active in Braunschweig, Germany.</p>
<p>In a hearing last week, lawyers for GM argued that Piech and Neumann should remain defendants in the lawsuit based on claims that they conspired with Lopez to steal the documents when they hired him away from GM.</p>
<p>Lawyers for VW argued that the two executives should be dismissed from the case because they rarely visted the United States and that GM lacked proof of direct involvement in the alleged theft of documents.</p>
<p>But Edmunds last week said that GM's complaint contained a lot of detail and merited further consideration in regard to Piech's and Neumann's roles.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a bare-bones complaint. It names names, it cites dates of lunch meetings and phone conversations,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A GM spokesman said the Detroit-based automaker was pleased that Edmunds extended the court's jurisdiction over Piech, Neuman and the VW parent company.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's ruling reinforces our confidence that the substantial damages we suffered in connection with Lopez' departure for VW will be remedied,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A spokesman at Volkswagen of America's headquarters in Auburn Hills, Mich., was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>On Oct. 28, Edmunds will hear oral arguments on VW's motions to dismiss other GM claims in the case, including those accusing VW of copyright and trademark infringement, that VW engaged in unfair trade practices and that it conspired in violation of the federal Racketeer-Influenced and Corrupt Organisations (RICO) Act.</p>
<p>The RICO act gives prosecutors and civil litigators broad powers to pursue activity that shows a pattern of racketeering and conspiracy. It has been widely used to prosecute organised crime in the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
