<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133958" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Group says Swiss should return millions to Jews.</title>
<headline>Group says Swiss should return millions to Jews.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Jewish group demanded on Tuesday that Switzerland pay immediate restitution to Jews after the Swiss were reported to have admitted they used assets of Holocaust victims to compensate Swiss citizens for property nationalised by Poland.</p>
<p>But the Swiss Foreign Ministry withdrew comments made by spokesmen to two news organisations, including Reuters, saying it had discovered a protocol linking the transfer of heirless assets to Poland in 1949 to the compensation agreement for nationalised property that same year.</p>
<p>A Foreign Ministry spokesman said he could no longer comment on what the protocol contained and would neither confirm nor deny the earlier comment about a link.</p>
<p>By the time he spoke, the first comment had unleashed a flood of criticism and the World Jewish Congress demanded the Swiss pay immediate restitution to a Jewish group that aids families of Holocaust victims and survivors.</p>
<p>Sen. Alfonse D'Amato, who raised the heirless assets issue last week, fired off an angry letter to the Swiss president asking him to conduct a full inquiry including an accounting of whose assets were taken and under what Swiss laws.</p>
<p>In 1949, the U.S., British and French governments protested the turning over of heirless assets by the Swiss to Poland because it violated an agreement with the Allies three years earlier that all such assets would aid refugees.</p>
<p>An aide to D'Amato said the New York Republican, who is chairman of the Senate Banking Committee, &quot;wanted the Swiss to come clean on everything&quot; including whether similar deals were struck with other East European countries whose then-communist governments had also nationalised property belonging to Swiss citizens and companies.</p>
<p>WJC President Edgar Bronfman was expected to brief the Jewish community on Wednesday on negotiations with the Swiss and on recent discoveries related to looted Nazi gold. Sources said he was expected to release U.S. documents saying that the Allies found bags of gold tooth fillings in a cache of Nazi gold in a salt mine at Merkers in western Germany in 1945.</p>
<p>WJC Vice President Kalman Sultanik said the first Swiss comment &quot;demands that immediate steps be taken to compensate the World Jewish Restitution Organisation to put an end to this ugly chapter.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement to Reuters, Sultanik called the first Swiss admission &quot;a major breakthrough&quot; in the controversy over what happened to hundreds of millions of dollars deposited by Jews in Swiss banks to protect their savings from the Nazis.</p>
<p>He called on the Swiss to examine now whether their citizens also received money from the unclaimed assets of Hungarian, Romanian, Yugoslav, Bulgarian and Czechoslovak Holocaust victims.</p>
<p>After its deal with Poland to return the heirless assets of Polish citizens that were deposited in Switzerland, the Swiss reached similar deals with those countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
