<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133968" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Aide plans for day after Dole come-from-behind win.</title>
<headline>Aide plans for day after Dole come-from-behind win.</headline>
<byline>Susan Cornwell</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the elegant surroundings of his lobbying firm, long-time Republican insider William Timmons has spent many hours quietly planning for the morning after a Bob Dole election victory that may never come.</p>
<p>Timmons is in charge of organising that peculiarly American interlude, the transition of power from one president to the next, between the election on Nov. 5 and Inauguration on Jan. 20.</p>
<p>If there is such a transition, Timmons has everything ready: the offices, the computers, the telephones, the schedule. He's even close to deciding on the airplane a President-elect Dole would use during those 11 weeks.</p>
<p>All he needs is for Dole to score a stupendous upset by coming from much farther behind than any winning presidential candidate has ever been at this late stage of a campaign.</p>
<p>Timmons is a veteran political operative who worked in the White House under Presidents Richard Nixon and Gerald Ford and was the deputy director of Ronald Reagan's transition office.</p>
<p>He is well aware that sceptics liken his current job to planning the welcoming party for the Titanic's first crossing.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the press kind of gives a snicker about this. I understand. They are looking at the headlines that say it's all over,&quot; Timmons told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;So a lot of people in the Fourth Estate think it's a silly exercise, and that's fine. But if he's elected, they won't think it's a silly exercise the next morning.&quot;</p>
<p>Most polls give Clinton at least a double-digit lead and some put him more than 20 points ahead. Many Republicans have clearly concluded the White House race is lost and are focusing on the fight to hold their majorities in Congress.</p>
<p>But Timmons said he has stopped watching the polls.</p>
<p>Instead he has spent an hour or two each day since summer on his assignment. A president-elect usually uses the transition period to make Cabinet appointments and issue policy pronouncements, and Timmons has to make sure Dole would have the staff and surroundings in which to do these things.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a duty to try to design the best transition possible and let the campaign worry about winning the election,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>And his plans are becoming quite detailed: He has determined, for example, that the transition will need 223 full-time paid employees, 51 volunteers, and 100 part-timers to manage the handover of 20 departments and agencies.</p>
<p>He drew up a list of &quot;eight or nine&quot; key people to run the transition, approved by Dole last Sunday. But Timmons will not say who they are, partly because some could be expected to stay on in a Dole government.</p>
<p>Grasping a red folder that he said contained the names, Timmons said he hoped none are revealed publicly until the morning after the election, Nov. 6. Then he smiled. &quot;From my long association with Dole, (I know) he may name some of them beforehand.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of Timmons' work has been focused on logistics. He has located 110,000 square feet of office space in a downtown building he says is &quot;not far&quot; from the White House.</p>
<p>It is a government-leased building, but for security reasons Timmons says he cannot reveal the address.</p>
<p>Congress provides $3.9 million to fund presidential transitions, but Timmons said Dole would also set up a presidential transition foundation, as some other presidents-elect have done, to help raise more cash.</p>
<p>Timmons, 65, has been around Washington as long as his 73-year-old friend Dole. He managed or played a big role in every Republican national convention from 1968 to 1988.</p>
<p>Timmons met Dole on Capitol Hill in the 1960s, when Dole was a young Republican congressman from Kansas and Timmons was an aide to Tennessee Representative Bill Brock, who was later a senator and chairman of the Republican National Committee.</p>
<p>He worked for six years as a congressional liaison to then-Presidents Nixon and Ford, then opened what is said to be a lucrative lobbying and consulting practice, Timmons &amp; Co.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there will be a transition,&quot; he said. &quot;I think this will not be for naught.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
