<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133918" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ag trade opportunity in East, Central Europe-USDA.</title>
<headline>Ag trade opportunity in East, Central Europe-USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Central and Eastern Europe offer a trade opportunity for U.S. poultry meat, oilseeds and processed foods, an Agricutlure Department official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Deputy Agriculture Undersecretary James Schroeder said there also were opportunities for food processing equipment and joint ventures in food marketing and processing.</p>
<p>At a USDA-sponsored conference, Schroeder and a World Bank analyst said the region, through its desire to join the European Union, would put pressure on Europe to reform its farm support program. Otherwise, farm costs could soar.</p>
<p>Schroeder and World Bank analyst Michel Debatisse said Central and Eastern Europe already was a sizable agricultural force and output could expand with access to EU markets.</p>
<p>Four of the region's nations -- Romania, Hungary, Poland and Czech Republic -- produce one-third as much grain as the 15 members of the EU, Debatisse said.</p>
<p>In general, the region provides far less government support to farmers than the EU, so an influx of new EU members could quickly drive up farm subsidy costs without reform.</p>
<p>The EU has begun initial steps toward a new round of ag reform since the new world trade agreement took effect.</p>
<p>Schroeder said the United States wanted to see the EU move toward freer agricultural trade. He declined to be more specific.</p>
<p>At present, the EU holds the lion's share of ag trade with Central and Eastern Europe. The U.S. share is 5-10 percent.</p>
<p>Prospects for sales of U.S. bulk goods, he said, were affected by weather, ag reforms and preferences given to EU.</p>
<p>Ten of the region's nations have requested membership in EU. No timetable has been set. Some hope to join by 2005.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
