<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133972" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Philip Morris posts 15 percent profit rise.</title>
<headline>Philip Morris posts 15 percent profit rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc. said Tuesday that increased cigarette sales worldwide and improvements in its North American food businesses pushed its profits up by 15 percent in the third quarter.</p>
<p>The company, whose products include Marlboro cigarettes, Miller beer and Maxwell House coffee, said its net income for the three months ended Sept. 30 rose to $1.65 billion, or $2.01 a share, from $1.43 billion, or $1.71 a share.</p>
<p>It said revenues grew by 4.3 percent to $17.4 billion from $16.7 billion.</p>
<p>Philip Morris said its profit and revenue comparisons did not include North American food businesses sold since the start of last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Philip Morris hit another home run in the quarter,&quot; Chairman Geoffrey C. Bible said in a statement accompanying the results. &quot;Our three largest businesses are absolutely flying, with terrific momentum in both domestic and international tobacco, and growth in North American food that is clearly outstanding by industry standards.&quot;</p>
<p>The company, whose cigarette products include Merit, Benson &amp; Hedges, Parliament and Virginia Slims, said tobacco income grew 13 percent, primarily on increased sales of premium-priced cigarettes like Marlboro and Benson &amp; Hedges.</p>
<p>Worldwide tobacco revenues grew 12.6 percent to $9.5 billion as Philip Morris sold 238 billion cigarettes, an increase of 9.3 percent.</p>
<p>Marlboro continued to build on its position as the best-selling cigarette in the world, the company said.</p>
<p>Philip Morris, whose food brands include Kraft, Oscar Mayer, Del Monte, Kool-Aid and Jell-O, said its North American food revenues grew 4 percent, excluding divestitures.</p>
<p>It said a 9 percent increase in food income was fuelled by double-digit gains in beverages, pizza and desserts, along with solid increases in coffee, cereals, and processed meats.</p>
<p>However, Philip Morris said beer revenues fell 3.9 percent to $1.1 billion on lower volume.</p>
<p>Higher worldwide cigarette sales and North American food volume gains also drove up profits for the first nine months, the company said.</p>
<p>Net income for the period rose 16 percent to $4.83 billion, or $5.87 a share, from $4.18 billion, or $4.95 a share, as revenues expanded by 4 percent to $52.4 billion from $50.3 billion.</p>
<p>The company said tobacco revenues in the period grew by 13 percent to $27.8 billion from $24.7 billion while food revenues declined due to the sale of several subsidiaries.</p>
<p>Philip Morris stock slipped 87.5 cents to $92.625 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
