<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133978" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: France's Trichet sees EMU on target for January 1999.</title>
<headline>France's Trichet sees EMU on target for January 1999.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Governor of the Bank of France Jean-Claude Trichet said on Tuesday seven European countries are meeting the criteria to join the European Monetary Union (EMU) on target in January 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have the EMU on January 1, 1999,&quot; Trichet told Reuters Financial Television on a visit to New York. &quot;I say this based on the track record of those seven countries whose currencies have not been realigned in the past 10 years.&quot;</p>
<p>Austria, Belgium, Denmark, France, Germany, Luxembourg, and the Netherlands have maintained their currencies close to their central rate in the narrow bands of Europe's old Exchange Rate Mechanism.</p>
<p>He made no mention of Italy which insists it will be among the first wave of EMU members and has reacted angrily to previous French statements that doubted its ability to join.</p>
<p>Trichet, however, stressed that the current exchange rates of these currencies &quot;corresponds to the old band does not mean much in itself.&quot; But Trichet pointed out this mattered as far as the &quot;stability that is necessary for the list of countries that will be in Euro.&quot;</p>
<p>Trichet said European financial markets will be ready to trade instruments denominated in Euros as of January 1, 1999, while the physical currency will be circulated in 2001.</p>
<p>&quot;The big markets that will be moving to the Euro will have an appropriate way of dealing with the Euro zone and are actively preparing (toward that goal,)&quot; Trichet added.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a vision that is widely shared by our colleagues in the EMU of a constellation of marketplaces (trading in EMU products),&quot; Trichet noted. &quot;Of course, Paris will play its role, but also London and Frankfurt and others.&quot;</p>
<p>Turning to the French economy, Trichet said &quot;We are now observing a pick up in the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Indebtedness in the productive sector is low, indebtedness of the household sector is low, the current account is in surplus and the market interest rates are at quite a low level,&quot; Trichet added.</p>
<p>Trichet said France also enjoys a low-inflation environment, running at around 1.6 percent, as &quot;law requires us to ensure price stability.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are exactly within the mandate that was given to us by the legislation,&quot; Trichet added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
