<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133969" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton edges further ahead on Reuters poll.</title>
<headline>Clinton edges further ahead on Reuters poll.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton edged a little further ahead of Republican Bob Dole in the Reuters daily tracking poll released on Tuesday and his lead now stands at 11.3 percentage points.</p>
<p>Exactly two weeks before Election Day, Clinton led with 46 percent over Dole's 34.7 percent. Reform Party candidate Ross Perot's support climbed a little to 5.4 percent and 11.5 percent said they had still not made up their minds.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted by John Zogby Group International, tracks about 900 likely voters over a three-day period. The latest result, with a 3.3 percentage point margin of error, reflects polling from Saturday through Monday.</p>
<p>Other polls on Tuesday gave Clinton a much larger lead. A CNN/USA Today Gallup poll said Clinton led by 21 percentage points. A CBS/New York Times survey said the president was 22 points ahead.</p>
<p>Pollster John Zogby noted that the Reuters/Zogby poll had consistently shown Clinton's lead was narrower than some other major polling companies. A major reason is that Reuters/Zogby does not push voters who say they are undecided to come down for one candidate or another until the final days of the race.</p>
<p>Most other pollsters do what is known as a &quot;hard push,&quot; pressing undecided voters to make a candidate choice. This is why the level of undecided voters in the Reuters/Zogby tracking poll has stayed at between 11 and 13 percent of the sample for the last few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Many voters still have not focused on the campaign. Those unsure who they will vote for tend to be genuinely uncommitted. Pushing them to make a choice well ahead of the election does not tell us anything useful and may lead to inaccuracies,&quot; Zogby said.</p>
<p>In the latest poll, Clinton and Dole backers were asked how strong their support was for their preferred candidates and 73 percent of Clinton's backers said their support was &quot;very strong,&quot; compared to 70 percent of Dole's backers.</p>
<p>For each candidate, 23 percent said their support was &quot;somewhat strong&quot; while 7 percent of Dole's backers but only 2 percent of Clinton's said their support was &quot;not strong.&quot; That suggests there is little room for a last-minute Dole comeback.</p>
<p>The race is tight among older voters but Clinton has a commanding edge among voters under 50. He still leads by better than two to one among self-described moderates and almost two to one among independents.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the congressional vote remains close. Slightly more voters would vote for the Democratic candidate in their district (37.3%) than would vote for the Republican (34.9%).</p>
<p>A 10-point Clinton victory could turn into an overwhelming vote in the Electoral College. In the 1988 presidential election, Republican George Bush won by eight points and took 426 of the 538 electoral votes.</p>
<p>U.S. elections are really 51 separate contests in each of the states and the District of Columbia, with the winner in each state gaining delegates to the Electoral College, where a majority of 270 votes is needed to be elected.</p>
<p>				Table 1</p>
<p>If the election for president were held today, for whom would you vote, Clinton, Dole, or Perot?</p>
<p>				Reuters Tracking</p>
<p>	     Oc22 Oc21 Oc20 Oc19 Oc18 Oc17 Oc16 Oc15 Oc14</p>
<p> Clinton   46.0 46.6 44.9 44.6 43.6 45.0 45.8 47.4 47.7</p>
<p> Dole	34.7 35.8 36.6 36.8 34.6 33.1 33.0 32.3 32.9</p>
<p> Perot	5.4  4.9  5.0  5.1  5.8  6.3  5.1  5.3  4.6</p>
<p> Other	2.4  2.1  1.8  1.8  2.8  2.5  2.9  2.5  2.7</p>
<p> Undecid   11.5 10.6 11.8 11.7 13.3 13.1 13.1 12.4 12.1</p>
<p>Note: Columns may not add to 100 % due to rounding</p>
<p>			    Congress Table</p>
<p>Which party's candidate do you intend to vote</p>
<p>for in your congressional district?  Democrat   37.3 37.5 37.9 37.1 39.0 39.1 38.5 38.3 39.4</p>
<p> Rebublic   34.9 36.3 34.9 35.5 33.7 32.7 33.0 32.5 33.5</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
