<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133981" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Voters react against Dole's campaign attacks.</title>
<headline>Voters react against Dole's campaign attacks.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, Political Correspondent</p>
<p>Just as he feared, voters seem to be reacting badly to Republican Bob Dole's decision to denigrate President Bill Clinton's ethical standards, according to polling data and voter interviews.</p>
<p>Dole, who trails Clinton by a wide margin two weeks before the Nov. 5 election, hesitated for months before deciding to unleash the &quot;character issue&quot; because of concerns it might offend voters and reinforce his own image as a hatchet-man.</p>
<p>Since he went on the attack last week in a speech listing what he called a litany of Clinton's ethical transgressions, he has seen his position in the race erode even further. Two polls released on Tuesday put him more than 20 percentage points behind the Democratic president.</p>
<p>In a New York Times poll, 63 percent of respondents said Dole was spending more time attacking Clinton than explaining what he would do as president, a 13 point increase over those reporting the same unfavourable impression last week.</p>
<p>Only 19 percent thought Clinton was spending more time on attacks than policy explanations, even though his campaign has in fact run many negative advertisements about Dole.</p>
<p>Another survey by the Pew Research Centre earlier this month asked if Dole had been too personally critical of Clinton. Fifty three percent said he had, 40 percent said no.</p>
<p>Only 21 percent said Clinton had been too personally critical of Dole, while 70 percent disagreed.</p>
<p>Interviews with voters who took part in a Reuters survey showed even Republicans were turned off by Dole's tactics.</p>
<p>&quot;Dole's campaign has been absolutely horrible,&quot; said Michael Williams, a recently retired oil company manager from Amarillo, Texas, who said he would nevertheless vote for the Republican nominee.</p>
<p>&quot;He seems to be throwing mud, which is what the middle class is not looking for. They want specific answers to specific problems. I wouldn't be surprised if Dole loses by a landslide,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>Henry Engle, a dairy worker from Evart, Michigan, said much the same, although he too plans to vote for Dole.</p>
<p>&quot;Dole's campaign has been quite negative. He has been extremely personal. I don't like the advertising I'm seeing,&quot; Engle said.</p>
<p>Warren Wise, a teacher from North Canton, Ohio, and another Dole backer, said the decision to go negative near the end of the campaign made it look as if he was panicking.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm disappointed ... He's panicking and doing some mudslinging. If he was going to do that, he should have started six months ago. It looks like desperation,&quot; Wise said.</p>
<p>Dole was well aware of the danger of this kind of reaction. In interviews and speeches earlier this month, he noted that women voters were particularly turned off by harsh negative attacks -- and he is particularly weak among women.</p>
<p>Adding to Dole's problem was his already well-established public image, whether justified or not, as mean-spirited.</p>
<p>&quot;In an interview with the Chicago Tribune two weeks ago, he said he was walking 'a very fine line because there's a myth out there that Bob Dole is mean.'&quot;</p>
<p>Judging by voter reaction, he may have crossed that line.</p>
<p>Clinton seems to have better grasped the current public aversion to anything seen as mudslinging.</p>
<p>In last week's presidential debate, he declined to respond to most of Dole's attacks, saying, &quot;No attack ever created a job or educated a child or helped a family make ends meet.&quot;</p>
<p>But while Clinton has remained above the fray, his campaign has spent millions of dollars on a relentless series of television ads attacking Dole's record in harsh terms.</p>
<p>The message seems to be that voters are much more tolerant of indirect barbs than those from the mouth of the candidate.</p>
<p>The voter backlash against negative campaigning first emerged in the campaign for the Republican presidential nomination early this year, when millionaire publisher Steve Forbes was forced to abandon his attack ads -- although only after they had done some evident damage to Dole.</p>
<p>It is also evident in some prominent congressional races this year where negative campaigning seems not to be working.</p>
<p>All of which prompted columnist Suzanne Garment, in a Los Angeles Times article Sunday, to bemoan &quot;the lost art of mudslinging&quot; and yearn for days when politicians were not afraid to attack their opponents' character and voters were not repelled by such attacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
