<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133960" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republican chief Barbour sees House, Senate pickup.</title>
<headline>Republican chief Barbour sees House, Senate pickup.</headline>
<byline>Michael Posner</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican Party Chairman Haley Barbour, brushing aside worries that a big victory by President Bill Clinton could bring down the Republican Congress, predicted on Tuesday his party would gain both House and Senate seats.</p>
<p>Barbour conceded in a telephone conference call with reporters that Republican presidential challenger Bob Dole is an underdog with an uphill fight on his hands but said he can overcome Clinton with two weeks to go to Election Day.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got polling that shows Dole behind from 9 (percentage points) to 20-something,&quot; he said. &quot;I think Dole is behind (by) about 50 to 40.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Clinton had received all the support he was going to get &quot;and the question is can Dole pick up the undecideds and bring Clinton down three or four points. I think the answer is, yes he can.&quot;</p>
<p>As for the possibility of Clinton helping Democrats take back Congress, the Republican chairman said the president had been trying to &quot;masquerade as a moderate Republican -- that's not the formula for sweeping in Democrats.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1994, Republicans won control of both houses for the first time in four decades. Since then, Clinton has signed several bills pushed by the Republicans in Congress, such as immigration and welfare reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;If Clinton is re-elected, heaven forbid,&quot; Barbour said, &quot;the last thing the American people would want would be for him to have a blank check in the form of a liberal, Democrat Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>Barbour said if the election were held today Republicans would make gains in the House of Representatives  similar to 1990 or 1992. &quot;We gained five seats in '90 and 10 seats in '92 -- obviously we're not going to pick up 52 seats like we did in '94,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added a &quot;high single-digit gain is the most likely&quot; in the House and predicted a gain of one to three seats in the Senate plus one or two more state governors.</p>
<p>Republicans now have a 235 to 198 margin over Democrats in the House with one independent and one vacancy. Republicans control the Senate 53 to 47 and 32 of the 50 state houses.</p>
<p>Barbour denied the party has written off the presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;I have said for two years our first goal is to elect a Republican president, and since Dole won the nomination I have been saying our first goal is to elect Bob Dole as president -- but it is not our only priority,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said increasing Republican margins in Congress, state legislatures and governors' mansions also were priorities.</p>
<p>Barbour also denied that Dole's attacks on Clinton's ethics and character had backfired. He said that assessment &quot;is very inconsistent to what we see in the field,&quot; citing a growth in volunteers, crowds and small donor contributions.</p>
<p>&quot;Volunteers, energy, enthusiasm -- none of that jibes with polling that says Dole's hurt himself,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Barbour also joined in the current Republican assault on Clinton's Democratic Party for accepting money from people linked with an Indonesian banking combine, the Lippo Group, and raising money in a Los Angeles Buddhist temple.</p>
<p>He charged that there was a &quot;a pattern&quot; of misdeeds in the Clinton administration. &quot;Everybody screws up sometime, I screw up,&quot; he said, adding, &quot;But what we're talking about is over and over and over the same abuses, the same pattern, deny, and then when you're caught lying, blame it on someone else.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
