<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133906" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton ends firmer and above key resistance.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton ends firmer and above key resistance.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYCE cotton futures continued to rack up gains but closed a heavy session below resistance at 73.00 cents a lb for December delivery.</p>
<p>The contract ended up 0.96 at 72.88, having ranged from 73.50 to 72.40. The back months closed 1.22 higher to 0.35 lower.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 11,000 lots.</p>
<p>Market sources attributed gains to cold temperatures in West Texas and an anticipated technical correction. &quot;The impending freeze in West Texas scared the market, coupled with the the expected technical rally,&quot; said O.A. Cleveland, a cotton marketing specialist with Mississippi State University.</p>
<p>But prices are not likely to climb much higher in the face of high world output and slack demand, analysts said.</p>
<p>The December contract could fall into the 60.00 centper lb range over after the U.S. Department of Agriculture releases its next supply and demand report November 12.</p>
<p>Suport was pegged at 70.50, the contract low in December.</p>
<p>In Texas, cotton is progressing ahead of schedule with 87 percent of the bolls open compared with an average of 75 percent.</p>
<p>But &quot;the open bolls are vulnerable to moisture and with cold air, any kind of snowfall would burn the plants as well,&quot; said Smith Barney meteorologist Jon Davis. He said conditions should be monitored over the next two weeks.</p>
<p>In the Delta, continued rain is likely to dampen the quality of the crop.</p>
<p>--Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
