<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13399" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Dollar down sharply on uncertainty over Japan.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Dollar down sharply on uncertainty over Japan.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar was down sharply against the mark and yen on Monday with the markets nervous over Tokyo's monetary direction ahead of a key Japanese economic survey due this week.</p>
<p>The dollar slipped by a pfennig and a yen on Friday's European close in dealings that were subdued as British markets were shut for a seasonal holiday.</p>
<p>The weaker dollar had a depressing effect on the main European bourses, which were down in business that was quiet because of London's closure. A poor opening in Wall Street did nothing to help.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to 107.57 yen compared to Friday's closing figure of 108.50because of the growing uncertainty over the direction of Japan's monetary policy.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan's quarterly Tankan survey on companies' expectations of future business is out on Wednesday and is regarded as an important reference for formulating monetary policy.</p>
<p>Although few expect the survey to change Japan's steady monetary policy stance, markets become nervous because the lower the Tankan's index, the gloomier the outlook.</p>
<p>The dollar, which began sliding against the mark last week as euphoria over a German interest rate cut fizzled out, fell further on Monday to 1.4776 marks against Friday's late Europe figure of 1.4871.</p>
<p>The mark was stronger against most European currencies as well, gaining against the French franc and posted hefty gains on the lira because of renewed uncertainty about the single European currency proposed to begin in 1999.</p>
<p>Mark/lira was trading at 1022.45 from 1018.82 on Friday. Mark/French franc was at 3.4180 against 3.4137.</p>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said in La Repubblica newspaper that Italy did not want a revision of the Maastricht criteria.</p>
<p>Prodi's comments come after a weekend newspaper interview by his deputy, Walter Veltroni, who said that Italy and other European countries should consider the possibility of a Maastricht re-think.</p>
<p>But at the same time the Swiss franc strengthened to a four-month high against the mark despite the Swiss National Bank's moves to add liquidity to the money markets, which would tend to mean lower interest rates.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, German stocks ended almost unchanged from Friday's closing price after a listless session. The mood was depressed by the weaker dollar and the holiday in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It's like a morgue out there, everything's dead. Hopefully by the end of next week things will begin to fill up again,&quot; said one Frankfurt trader.</p>
<p>In after-hours business, trading on the computerised IBIS index was also down.</p>
<p>French shares lost their slender gains in thin afternoon trading and slipped into negative territory, weighed down by the fragile franc.</p>
<p>Last Thursday and Friday, the bourse rose after the Bank of France cut its intervention rate to 3.35 percent following a surprise Bundesbank repo rate cut.</p>
<p>But dealers said the rate cuts would have a limited effect on the French economy and therefore its longer term boost to the CAC-40 was doubtful.</p>
<p>&quot;While the rate cut is positive, it wasn't big enough to completely change the economic situation, which is quasi-recessionist when you look at price indices and consumer confidence,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4776 marks and 107.57 yen compared with 1.4871 marks and 108.50 yen at the London close on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The London stock market is closed for a public holiday. On Friday the FTSE 100 closed at 3,907.5 up 16.4 points.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 2.77 points to 2,018.05.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed down 2.80 points at 2,552.36.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was stronger at $388.45 versus $387.50 at Friday's London close. Silver was unchanged at $5.24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
