<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13395" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Japan's Hashimoto bears gifts for Brazil.</title>
<headline>Japan's Hashimoto bears gifts for Brazil.</headline>
<byline>Michael Christie</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA, Brazil 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto met Brazil's President Fernando Henrique Cardoso on Monday, bearing gifts in the form of $510 million for environmental projects, officials said.</p>
<p>On a 10-day Latin American tour intended to show Japanese firms the region was again ripe for investment after the &quot;Lost Decade&quot; of the debt crises and 1980s hyperinflation, Hashimoto had been expected to focus on bilateral issues with Cardoso.</p>
<p>Hashimoto's spokesman said on Sunday that multilateral issues, such as reform of the United Nations and progress on a Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty, might also be raised.</p>
<p>After their 1-1/2 hour talks on Monday, Cardoso and Hashimoto were to preside over the signing of $510 million in Japanese Overseas Economic Cooperation Fund (OECF) financing for four environmental projects in Brazil.</p>
<p>They included programmes in the states of Parana and Santa Catarina, a project to clean the Bay of All Saints in Salvador in Brazil's northeast and a wind-powered energy project in the northern state of Ceara.</p>
<p>Vera Machado, head of the Brazilian Foreign Ministry's Asia and Oceania Department, said Tokyo had also broached the possibility of financing small-scale community projects and the Brazilian government was considering its response.</p>
<p>After lunch in Brasilia's futuristic Foreign Ministry, Hashimoto was to meet representatives of Brazil's 1.3 million-strong Japanese community, the largest outside Japan. On Sunday, he mingled with Japanese immigrants in Brazil's sprawling industrial heartland of Sao Paulo.</p>
<p>For Brazilian officials, the first visit by a Japanese prime minister in almost 15 years reflected renewed confidence in Latin America's largest economy. Hashimoto's spokesman said it also reflected renewed faith in Brazil being able and willing to play an expanded role on the world stage.</p>
<p>Hashimoto was also expected to touch on relations between Tokyo and the four-nation Mercosur customs union, of which Brazil is the powerhouse. &quot;There is always the possibility that Mercosur could take steps that would be damaging to Japanese trade, though we think and hope not. But we believe it's worth reminding them that this should not be the case,&quot; his spokesman said.</p>
<p>Among other issues, Japan was hoping to convince Brazil to lift a ban on Japanese fishing vessels entering Brazilian ports. The ban dates back to 1992 when Japanese and Spanish fishing vessels were caught trawling in Brazilian waters.</p>
<p>Hashimoto's tour has already taken him to Mexico and Chile. He was to depart Brasilia for Lima on Monday afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
