<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133990" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: E. Midwest soy yields dip as late crops harvested.</title>
<headline>E. Midwest soy yields dip as late crops harvested.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Soybean yields in eastern Midwest states are falling as more farmers harvest crops that were planted late, agronomists said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the early soybeans that came in, we saw some real good yields,&quot; said Ellsworth Christmas, soybean extension agronomist at Purdue University. &quot;But now they're getting into the later-planted beans and things don't look as good.&quot;</p>
<p>Although early yield results have been highly variable, Indiana's overall soybean yield is likely to come in below the U.S. Agriculture Department's last yield estimate of 38 bushels per acre, Christmas said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of us who wonder whether that is going to be correct or not,&quot; Christmas said. &quot;Right now, I'm not hearing any real good yields.&quot;</p>
<p>Yields from Ohio's soybean crop were also expected to lag behind average, according to James Beuerlein, extension agronomist with Ohio State University in Columbus.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say overall it's going to be a mediocre to poor year for us,&quot; Beuerlein said.</p>
<p>He expects Ohio's final yield to fall within the range of 32 to 33 bushels per acre. That forecast compares with USDA's latest yield estimate for Ohio of 34 bushels per acre.  </p>
<p>Beuerlein said that early soybean yields were reported ranging from 40 to 50 bushels per acre, while later yields were falling in the 35 to 40 bushel-per-acre range.</p>
<p>But soybean yields in the western Corn Belt, where planting and growing weather was more favorable, were said to be better than expected, agronomists there said.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been pleasantly surprised,&quot; said Dale Farnham, Iowa State University extension agronomist. &quot;I've had numerous reports of yields in the 50s (bushels per acre) and a few in the low 60s.</p>
<p>Three days of nearly perfect harvesting weather over the weekend and Monday allowed Indiana producers to make good harvest progress, Christmas said. He estimated that the soybean harvest was now 65 to 70 percent complete, compared with USDA's latest estimate of 60 percent as of Sunday.</p>
<p>According to the latest crop progress report from the Ohio Agricultural Statistics Service, the crop was 45 percent harvested as of Sunday.</p>
<p>- Anna Driver and Emily Kaiser 1-312-983-7294</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
