<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133982" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hog and pork belly futures mostly limit down.</title>
<headline>CME hog and pork belly futures mostly limit down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Waves of fund selling flooded the CME live hog futures sending most contracts down the 1.50- and 2.00-cent-per-lb daily limits under fast market conditions, traders said.</p>
<p>The volume of selling was less in pork bellies but was sufficient to push most contracts down the 3.00-cent daily limit.</p>
<p>Hogs moved lower early in reaction to lower cash hog prices early Tuesday and to sharply lower cash pork prices late Monday. That selling triggered chart-based selling that launched the fund selling.</p>
<p>Leading sellers appeared to be LIT, Refco, and R.J. O'Brien, traders said. Near midsession, the order flow was so great, crowds of runners stood two and three rows deep at the December section of the live hog pit.  </p>
<p>Late Monday, USDA reported pork cutout values were down $1.17 to $1.01 per cwt, with the greatest break in cash loins which were down $5.00 to $132.00 for 14- to 22-lb product.</p>
<p>Traders said the sharp break in hog futures should prompt lower cash hog prices Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;After this type of action they (meat packers) will be bidding lower, because the product is still in trouble,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Pork bellies were pressured by a mix of commercial and fund selling, plus by the lower hog futures, traders said.</p>
<p>The monthly USDA Cold Storage Report to be released at 1400 CDT did not appear to be influencing trading. A Reuter survey of analysts show they expect the data will show October 1 stocks between 11.9 milliion and 13.7 million lbs versus September 1 stocks of 28.896 million and October 1, 1995, stocks of 6.255 million.</p>
<p>At 1127 CDT, hogs were off 1.50 to 2.00 cents with December down 1.50 at 52.100 cents per lb. The limit in February 1997 and forward lean hog contracts is 2.00 cents. Pork bellies were off 3.00 cent in all months with February at 65.300 cents per lb.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
