<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133936" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs end limit down, pork bellies sharply down.</title>
<headline>CME hogs end limit down, pork bellies sharply down.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live hog futures closed down in the first three contracts, pressured throughout the session by active fund selling, traders said.</p>
<p>Pork bellies closed sharply lower but late commercial buying pulled contracts off session lows.</p>
<p>Hogs moved lower early in reaction to lower cash hog prices early Tuesday and to sharply lower cash pork prices late Monday. That selling triggered chart-based selling that launched the fund selling.</p>
<p>At the close, traders estimated there was a pool of about 1,200 December contracts offered limit down, and about 25 contracts were offered limit down in the October hogs.  </p>
<p>Late Monday, USDA reported pork cutout values were down $1.17 to $1.01 per cwt, with the greatest break in cash loins which were down $5.00 to $132.00 for 14- to 22-lb supplies.</p>
<p>Traders said the sharp break in hog futures should prompt lower cash hog prices Wednesday.</p>
<p>Pork bellies were pressured by a mix of commercial and fund selling throughout the session, until late when commercial buying trimmed losses. Some traders said the late recovery may signal the market was poised for a technically-inspired uptrend.</p>
<p>However, they also said Wednesday's price action in pork bellies may be influenced by Tuesday's USDA Cold Storage Report to be released at 1400 CDT and by the weekly CME out-of-town storage report due out at 1330 CDT.</p>
<p>Hogs closed down 2.00 to 0.350 cent with December down the 1.50 limit at 52.100 cents per lb. The limit in February 1997 and forward lean hog contracts is 2.00 cents. Pork bellies were off 1.125 to 2.050 cent a lb with February off 1.625 at 66.675 cents per lb.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
