<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133996" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trichet says dollar may have room to appreciate.</title>
<headline>Trichet says dollar may have room to appreciate.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of France governor Jean-Claude Trichet said on Tuesday that the dollar might have room to rise against European currencies.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters Financial Television, he declined to say by how much it should rise.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say only that acccording to a number of indications we have, in particular of course PPI and so forth, there might be some room for appreciation of the U.S. dollar towards European currencies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is something that it seems to me the various monetary authorities the world over are sharing, the idea that a strong dollar is in the interests of all.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a G7 (Group of Seven) meeting here in the U.S., in Washington, some weeks ago and this idea that a strong dollar is in the interests of all has been more or less considered appropriate by the various monetary authorities and governments participating in this meeting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked however when it would be clear that the dollar had risen enough, he said: &quot;We will see exactly what is the -- I would say -- the market consensus, monetary authority consensus.</p>
<p>&quot;Today this idea that the strong dollar is in the interests of all is the kind of consensus we are observing. We will see when the consensus will be: &quot;well this is okay now',&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the dollar had already appreciated against European currencies and noted the G7 had to ensure the relationships between currencies were in line with fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;It was more obvious before than today. But when you come from Europe to the U.S. or from the U.S. to Europe, you can see, you can see yourself that there is some kind of maybe room for appreciation, as I said.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
