<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133941" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton calls for NATO expansion, has huge lead.</title>
<headline>Clinton calls for NATO expansion, has huge lead.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton, nurturing an enormous lead in the polls exactly two weeks before Election Day, on Tuesday took on the statesman role on the campaign trail by calling for an expansion of NATO.</p>
<p>Republican Bob Dole meanwhile wrapped up a two-day trip to Michigan, struggling to persuade voters to take a second look at his candidacy.</p>
<p>&quot;The election is about two weeks from now and a lot of people haven't focused,&quot; Dole said on Monday in Detroit. &quot;Maybe there's no interest in politics, maybe nobody cares or maybe they're just getting around to focus on it and they're making up their minds.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton visited Detroit on Tuesday, where he set 1999, the 50th anniversary of the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation, as the target date for admitting new members from among former Communist nations in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I want to state America's goal: By 1999 -- NATO's 50th anniversary and 10 years after the fall of the Berlin Wall -- the first group of countries we invite to join should be full-fledged members of NATO,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>The president, who has not mentioned his opponent by name for days, was in the enviable position of being able to use the foreign policy speech to underline his role as commander-in-chief as the Nov. 5 election approaches.</p>
<p>Dole issued a statemant accusing Clinton of dragging his heels on expanding NATO. &quot;The time to begin expansion for Hungary, Poland and the Czech Republic is now,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>Still, Clinton's initiative was likely to be popular among the many people of Eastern European descent in the politically crucial Midwest -- not that Clinton appeared to need much help.</p>
<p>The Reuters daily tracking poll gave Clinton an 11.3 percentage point advantage and other polls on Tuesday gave Clinton a much larger lead. A CNN/USA Today Gallup poll said Clinton led by 21 percentage points. A CBS/New York Times survey said the president was 22 points ahead.</p>
<p>A 10-point Clinton victory could turn into an overwhelming vote in the Electoral College. In the 1988 presidential election, Republican George Bush won by eight points and took 426 of the 538 electoral votes.</p>
<p>The presidential election is really 51 separate contests in each state and the District of Columbia, with the winner in each state getting votes in the Electoral College, where a majority of 270 votes is needed to be elected.</p>
<p>Many Republicans are now focusing on the battle to retain control of both houses of Congress, which they won only two years ago.</p>
<p>Party chairman Haley Barbour said the party would gain both House and Senate seats, although he acknowledged that Dole was an underdog with an uphill fight on his hands.</p>
<p>&quot;If Clinton is re-elected, heaven forbid,&quot; Barbour said. &quot;The last thing the American people would want would be for him to have a blank check in the form of a liberal, Democrat Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was scheduled later on Tuesday to fly to Florida for two days of campaigning in a state that has gone to the Republicans for the past two decades but where he now holds a narrow lead over Dole.</p>
<p>The Clinton campaign also rejected a request from former first lady Nancy Reagan to stop running a television advertisement showing the 1981 assassination attempt against her husband, which she said &quot;stretches even the minimum levels of civility on current political advertising.&quot;</p>
<p>James Brady, who was President Ronald Reagan's press spokesman at the time, was badly wounded in the assassination attempt. He endorses Clinton because of the president's stand on gun control and is shown in the ads extolling Clinton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
