<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13393" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French return to what could be a tough autumn.</title>
<headline>French return to what could be a tough autumn.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French are returning from their holidays in a depressed mood, disappointed by economic weakness and continued budget austerity which could lead to a difficult autumn for the government.</p>
<p>According to a poll published in the Le Parisien newspaper on Monday, 54 percent of the French are pessimistic about &quot;La Rentree&quot; - the big return to work, school and politics.</p>
<p>Strikes, poverty and job losses topped voters' worries, the CSA survey of 1,005 people showed. The poll also found that 78 percent of those polled expected troubles for the centre-right government when the summer holidays end.</p>
<p>Of the people surveyed, 52 percent feared strikes and social unrest the most.</p>
<p>Unions have vowed to challenge plans to cut spending by around 60 billion francs in real terms next year in a budget due to be unveiled in September.</p>
<p>Around 7,000 civil service jobs face the axe as part of government initiatives to close the gap between spending and revenues and qualify for a European single currency from 1999.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac on Sunday said he did not know whether there would be unrest after the summer break as threatened by unions, who say conditions are right to revive unrest to match a crippling 24-day wave of strikes in late 1995.</p>
<p>But financial markets are uncertain and the franc, bonds and shares remain fragile due to worries about the reaction to France's 1997 austerity budget, due to be unveiled in September.</p>
<p>Communist Party leader Robert Hue warned on Monday the spirit of last year's strikes, which brought France to a virtual standstill, was &quot;still alive in hearts and minds&quot;.</p>
<p>Economists are sceptical the budget -- marrying spending restraint with tax cuts -- will be enough to reach government's goal of a budget deficit of three percent of gross domestic product (GDP), needed to qualify for European monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;Deficit-busting has the highest government priority but still more needs to be done,&quot; Smith Barney economists Paul Horne and Steven Englander said in a note to investors on Monday.</p>
<p>A series of key dates starts on Tuesday with a meeting of the main teachers' unions. Some teachers' unions have already announced strikes over perceived government plans to cut 2,300 posts in education.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the government has its first cabinet meeting after the summer break and a ministerial seminar on the budget.</p>
<p>Louis Viannet, head of the Communist-led CGT union will hold a news conference the same day in which he is expected to warn the government against any attacks on the welfare system.</p>
<p>On Friday August 30, the July unemployment figures are due. Unemployment, at record levels, remains a major thorn in the side of the government. But the level is not expected to fall any time soon.</p>
<p>Juppe said on Sunday that around September 10 he would present both the 1997 budget and the social security financing plan as well as plans for a tax reform. As soon as September 11, the government could present the cabinet with the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>Activists have planned protest meetings and news conferences to follow hard on the heels of the budget presentation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
