<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133905" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alaska House race poses dilemma for indigenous voters.</title>
<headline>Alaska House race poses dilemma for indigenous voters.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alaska's Eskimo, Indian and Aleut voters must choose between re-electing a veteran congressman who has long enjoyed their support or sending the state's first indigenous woman to Congress.</p>
<p>State Sen. Georgianna Lincoln, an Athabaskan Indian from the village of Rampart, is seeking to oust Representative Don Young, a 23-year Republican incumbent and chairman of the House Resources Committee.</p>
<p>Urging Alaska's Eskimos, Indians and Aleuts to continue their support for him, Young brought his Athabaskan wife to a convention dais last week. &quot;You want a woman in Washington, D.C.? This is the woman you have in Washington, D.C. right now,&quot; Young told the Alaska Federation of Natives.</p>
<p>&quot;She's my buddy, she's my wife, she's my mistress and she's my lover,&quot; said Young, 63, of his wife Lu. &quot;And for those of you not that privileged, she is a great one.&quot;</p>
<p>But this year, Alaska Natives have the option to send another woman to Congress, and in a different role. Democrat Lincoln, 53, already represents a sprawling, Texas-sized district that comprises about half of Alaska's territory.</p>
<p>Her stances are more pro-environment than Young's but she also contrasts herself with him on style. &quot;You will never be embarrassed by any of my actions,&quot; Lincoln promised voters in one televised forum.</p>
<p>Young is well-known for gaffes, such as the time last year when he made an explicit reference to anal sex in a speech to Fairbanks high school students. He has also questioned the patriotism of environmentalists.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm proud to say that they are my enemy,&quot; he said in a radio interview this year. &quot;They are not Americans, never have been Americans, never will be Americans.&quot;</p>
<p>Last weekend, the native federation, which endorsed Young last year for his long advocacy of native issues, threw its support to Lincoln. No indigenous Alaskan has ever been elected to statewide office and only one woman, Lt. Gov. Fran Ulmer, has ever won a statewide election.</p>
<p>For many, the decision this year poses a dilemma, said State Representative Irene Nicolai, an Athabaskan from Tanana. Although they are proud of Lincoln, the first native woman elected to the state Senate, many fear Young's wrath, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people have told me she's put them in, what do you call it, a hard-rock situation,&quot; Nicolai said. &quot;They'd like to endorse her, but in case she loses they don't want to be in a bad spot with Don Young.&quot;</p>
<p>Outside of the indigenous community, which comprises 16 percent of Alaska's population, Young appears headed for an easy win. In the Aug. 27 open primary, he got 58 percent of the vote, compared to Lincoln's 32 percent. As of mid-October he had $519,000 in campaign funds, compared with Lincoln's $175,000, according to the Federal Election Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, maybe he is in a powerful position, but what good does that do us?&quot; asked Katherine McConkey, an Athabaskan from Copper Centre who was waving a Lincoln campaign sign at the native convention.</p>
<p>Nor was she impressed with his marital tribute. &quot;I didn't like that. I thought he was using his wife,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But many pro-development natives, especially on the oil-rich North Slope, remain loyal to Young. They embrace his plans to open the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge to oil drilling and repeal the Endangered Species Act.</p>
<p>&quot;I am still standing with Don Young,&quot; said Lucille Adams, an Inupiat Eskimo from Barrow. &quot;He's done a great job for the people of the North Slope.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
