<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133913" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rain seen further delaying U.S. corn harvest.</title>
<headline>Rain seen further delaying U.S. corn harvest.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Corn harvest in the U.S. Midwest was behind average pace as moisture levels remained high, and a series of storms was expected to further delay combining, agronomists said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're operating at extremely high moistures compared to average,&quot; said Bob Nielsen, extension agronomist with Purdue University in Indiana. &quot;Last year at this point we were down around 18 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>This year, corn moisture levels in Indiana were averaging near 25 percent, he said.</p>
<p>U.S. corn harvest was 30 percent complete as of Sunday, trailing average of 46 percent, the National Agricultural Statistics Service said. Indiana's crop was 23 percent combined, down from 48 percent average.</p>
<p>Forecasts called for rain this week across most of the U.S. Midwest which would further slow harvest pace and keep moisture levels high. Rainfall amounts of 0.50 to 2.00 inches were likely through Thursday.</p>
<p>On average, corn loses .25 percent moisture per day in late October but rain and cold temperatures slow the drying process, said Dale Farnham, Iowa State University agronomist.</p>
<p>&quot;The concern always is stalk rot,&quot; Farnham said, referring to problems with rains at this time of year. &quot;If they're in the mid 20s (percent moisture) we're telling farmers to go ahead and harvest.&quot;</p>
<p>Iowa's corn harvest was just getting underway with 17 percent combined as of Sunday. That compared with the five-year average of 39 percent.</p>
<p>In Illinois, corn borer and grey leaf spot were noted but damage appeared to be light, said Don White, University of Illinois plant pathologist.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like the stalks themselves are in good shape,&quot; he said. &quot;We're getting a little bit of ear droppage and stalk rot but it's not as bad as I thought it was going to be.&quot;</p>
<p>Illinois' corn harvest was 35 percent complete as of Sunday, trailing the five-year average of 56 percent.</p>
<p>White said it was too early to draw conclusions about overall yields but one Illinois cash merchandiser said farmers were harvesting fields with 150 to 170 bushels per acre.</p>
<p>&quot;The yields are there but (farmers) are losing money on the dry down costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
