<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133966" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FBI official charged in Ruby Ridge incident.</title>
<headline>FBI official charged in Ruby Ridge incident.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An FBI official was charged Tuesday with obstruction of justice in connection with the murder trial of white separatist Randy Weaver over the deadly 1992 shootout at Ruby Ridge, Idaho.</p>
<p>Justice Department sources said E. Michael Kahoe, chief of the violent crimes section at FBI headquarters during the incident, has agreed to plead guilty to the charges and cooperate with prosecutors in their long-running investigation into possible wrongdoing by FBI officials.  </p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Michael Stiles, who has been in charge of the investigation, said Kahoe allegedly participated in the concealment and destruction of an FBI headquarters document sought by prosecutors in preparing for Weaver's trial.</p>
<p>The sources declined to say who Kahoe may have implicated or how soon any other charges might be brought. The charges against him were the first arising from the investigation.</p>
<p>Obstruction of justice carries a maximum penalty of 10 years in prison and a $250,000 fine.</p>
<p>Weaver and his friend Kevin Harris were charged with the murder of Deputy U.S. Marshal William Degan, who was shot and killed in a confrontation on August 21, 1992. Weaver's son was also killed in the firefight. The two defendants were acquitted on the murder charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
