<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133959" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. warns Bosnian Serbs on elections.</title>
<headline>U.S. warns Bosnian Serbs on elections.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States warned Bosnian Serbs on Tuesday that the world's willingness to help them recover from civil war would depend on their cooperating in staging municipal elections.</p>
<p>The State Department backed a decision by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe to postpone the polls from November until an unspecified date in 1997 but said that the elections would ultimately be held under OSCE sponsorship.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's no question...that one of the great problems encountered in arranging the elections in November was the unwillingness of the Bosnian Serbs to cooperate with the OSCE,&quot; department spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bosnian Serb leadership should understand that the ability and the willingness of the international community to be helpful to them economically and otherwise is a direct function of their cooperation on this issue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States had refused to postpone the national elections in September despite deep concerns in many quarters that conditions in Bosnia -- including little freedom of movement -- would not permit free and fair polls.</p>
<p>But Burns insisted postponing the municipal elections was different. He said the postponement would be one factor in deciding whether NATO troops should remain in Bosnia beyond the December target for NATO-led peace implementation forces (IFOR) to depart. Robert Frowick, chief of the OSCE's Bosnia mission, confirmed earlier in Sarajevo that that the municipal elections would be delayed until next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
