<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133937" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: London business area seeks N.Y.C's turnaround tips.</title>
<headline>London business area seeks N.Y.C's turnaround tips.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City, whose potholed, fear-ridden streets only five years ago represented what can go wrong when a big city starts breaking down, now is showing part of London how to tap the business community for help.</p>
<p>Saying the two cities faced similar problems, from litter to a drop in public spending, Corporation of London officials at a news conference Monday said they hoped to get firms to organize and provide some services needed to renew areas.</p>
<p>The Corporation, which calls itself the financial and commercial heart of Britain, studied New York City's privately funded Business Improvement Districts (BID) and concluded they had helped turn around a variety of neighborhoods.  </p>
<p>New York City's businesses have created 35 such districts, which assess property owners to pay for a range of services, from street-cleaning and improving security to helping to care for the homeless.</p>
<p>The city collects the fees, which for the Times Square BID are about 0.3 percent of the assessed value of commercial buildings, and return the funds to the BIDS.</p>
<p>London Corporation mainly is funded by local property taxes, and if parts of London, and perhaps other areas in Britain, adapted New York City's BIDS to their own needs, they likely will use some sort of tax, said Bernard Harty, the Corporation's chamberlain and tax clerk.  </p>
<p>Harty all but ruled out having such entities issue debt for capital projects, as a few New York City BIDs have done, at least in the near-term.</p>
<p>&quot;We see BIDs as much more dealing with exactly the sort of things we're talking about, which is bringing back a pride to the central area and regalvinizing them,&quot; he told reporters, explaining the system instead would use annual expenditures.</p>
<p>Now the Corporation wants Parliament to take up a bill to let BIDs be set up in London, though Harty pointed out such entities would have to have a distinctly British character.</p>
<p>While he said he did not expect the bill to be approved the first time around, Harty predicted both political parties would be interested, partly as public spending is falling.  </p>
<p>The most important obstacle appears to be working out how to fund the BIDS with some form of taxes, a step the Treasury would have to approve, and convincing the local business community of the plan's merits.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, the biggest single problem for us...is that there would be quite a reaction to paying extra taxes,&quot; said Harty, adding the Association of Town Managers was planning to study the issues further.</p>
<p>Representatives of two New York City BIDs said their organizations had helped turn around Times Square and downtown Manhattan, partly by using tax incentives to attract developers, though they also outlined some of the pitfalls.  </p>
<p>Gretchen Dykstra, president of the Times Square BID, which has a $6 million annual budget, noted that unless the effort is led by the companies, attempts by local goverment to organize such districts and assess new taxes can backfire.</p>
<p>&quot;The private property owners get galvinzed to pay it (the tax) because they think they're not getting the services they deserve from government,&quot; she said. &quot;So if you have government leading the march, government is going to have to be in the position of saying we failed, and that's not a very comfortable position for anybody to be in.&quot;</p>
<p>L. Edward Bentall, chairman of Bentalls, who was a member of the Corporation's delegation, said he was very interested in BIDs as they might be helpful in revitalizing Bristol, where the retail chain recently bought a store.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
