<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133911" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end mixed, feeder cattle lower.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end mixed, feeder cattle lower.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle closed narrowly mixed and feeder cattle mostly lower after a lightly traded session.</p>
<p>In live cattle, traders said short covering appeared to have supported the October contract. Tight supplies of market-ready cattle and the narrow premium of October to cash prices prompted the shortcovering, they said.</p>
<p>eeders are current and traders said sellers may be in a position to force higher bids from meat packers. Also, with October live cattle expiring Thursday, traders said December is priced well under current cash prices.</p>
<p>December closed at the equivalent of $65.100 per cwt versus current $69.00 bids in High Plains feedlot markets.</p>
<p>Also news of snow Monday from Kansas to Texas raised concerns an early winter could slow weight gains and delay cattle marketings to beyond the December delivery period.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle closed mostly lower. Lower deferred live cattle futures likely prompted selling in the nearby feeder contracts, traders said.</p>
<p>Also, the late rebound in CBOT corn was bearish for feeder cattle. CBOT corn closed steady to 0.50 cent per bushel higher after trading about one cent lower early.</p>
<p>Further, some traders said cash feeder cattle prices seasonally trend lower now as cattle are moved from summer pastures in the fall and into feedlots.</p>
<p>Live cattle futures were up 0.600 cent a lb to down 0.175 cent with December up 0.200 at 65.100 cents per lb. Feeder cattle were off 0.200 to up 0.100 cent with November off 0.150 at 63.200.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
