<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="133916" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole promises come-from-behind win in two weeks.</title>
<headline>Dole promises come-from-behind win in two weeks.</headline>
<byline>Sue Kirchhoff</byline>
<dateline>TROY, Mich 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole told voters on Tuesday to ignore polls and pundits who say the presidential race is all but over and promised a come-from-behind victory on Nov. 5.</p>
<p>On the final day of a two-day bus tour through central Michigan, Dole charged that President Bill Clinton had built a record of broken promises and touted his own plan for a 15 precent tax cut.</p>
<p>With only two weeks remaining until the election, several new national polls showed Dole trailing Clinton by more than 20 points. The Reuters-Zogby daily tracking poll showed Clinton at 46 percent and Dole at 34.7 percent.</p>
<p>But Dole reached back to 1948, when President Harry Truman came from behind in the polls to win a stunning Democratic victory over Republican Thomas Dewey. &quot;I'm like Harry Truman. I'm from the Midwest and I'm plain-spoken and I'm going to win whether you like it or not. I'm going to win on Nov. 5,&quot; Dole told a rally in Troy.</p>
<p>Claiming Clinton would promise anything to get elected, Dole said &quot;anything you ever wanted in your life, the next two weeks is the time to write the president. You can just give me a note, I'll take it to him. I may want something myself.&quot;</p>
<p>At every stop he called for a change in the law to bar non-citizens from contributing to political campaigns. The Democratic National Committee has come under fire for accepting contributions from individuals with ties to the Lippo Group Indonesian banking and real estate conglomerate.</p>
<p>But the Clinton campaign has begun fighting back, running an ad accusing Dole of desperation tactics for bringing up the issue this late in the campaign and pointing out contributions to Dole's campaign from people who are not U.S. citizens.</p>
<p>Asked if his attacks on Clinton were backfiring as some polls indicated on Tuesday, Dole said, &quot;I don't think so.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole picked up the support of rock star Ted Nugent, who appeared on the stage at the Troy rally, along with local state officials and police officers.</p>
<p>Nugent said he had long backed Republican ideas. &quot;There's a lot of people that are represented by the Republican attitude that are seldom heard from. We call it the ponytail vote,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also said he supported Dole's anti-drug stance, claiming, &quot;I've probably busted more hippies' noses than all the narcs in North America.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, Mich"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
