<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134071" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Court dismisses Salt unions claims as inadmissible.</title>
<headline>Court dismisses Salt unions claims as inadmissible.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of First Instance dismissed as inadmissible on Tuesday two separate but related complaints from salt producers that state aid granted to Frima of the Netherlands was illegal.</p>
<p>A union of French salt producers (CFS) learned the aid was being granted through a newspaper in the Netherlands. CFS wrote to the Commission and requested a copy of the decision approving the grant of HFL 12.5 million by the Dutch government to Frima.</p>
<p>The court characterised the letter as a request for information, and not a decision producing binding legal effects affecting the complainant's interests.</p>
<p>&quot;The mere fact that a letter is sent by a Community institution to its adressee in response to a request made by the latter is not enough for it to be treated as a decision within the meaning of artice 173 of the Treaty,&quot; the court said.</p>
<p>Article 173 allows individuals to challenge Community decisions of direct and individual concern to the challenger.</p>
<p>In another case, the English based Salt Union argued the Commission's refusal to propose &quot;appropriate measures&quot; under treaty article 93(1) could be challenged by the union at the European court.</p>
<p>The court disagreed and said the union might have grounds to challenge a state aid decision at the European court only if the Commission had proposed measures which brought about a distinct change in the union's legal position.</p>
<p>The court noted the salt producers could challenge the grant of state aid in national courts, and in some cases those courts will refer to the European court questions of Community law.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>EXCERPTS FROM THE JUDGMENT</p>
<p>(Court translation into English. Original language of the case: French)</p>
<p>&quot;State aid - General regional aid scheme - Letter from the Commission concerning aid - Action for annulment - Inadmissible&quot;</p>
<p>22 October 1996</p>
<p>Case T-154/94</p>
<p>Comite des Salines de France,</p>
<p>and Compagnie des Salins du Midi et des Salines de L'Est SA, applicants</p>
<p>supported by</p>
<p>Salt Union, Ltd</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>Sudwestdeutsche Salzwerke AG</p>
<p>Verein Deutsche Salzindustrie eV, interveners</p>
<p>v</p>
<p>Commission of the European Communities, defendant</p>
<p>supported by</p>
<p>Frima BV, intervener</p>
<p>application for annulment of the decision allegedly contained in a letter addressed by the Commission on 7 February 1994 to Comite des Salines de France concerning aid granted to Frima BV by the Netherlands authorities</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE hereby</p>
<p>1. Dismisses the action as inadmissible;</p>
<p>2. Orders the applicants to pay the costs, including those incurred by Frima BV;</p>
<p>3. Orders Salt Union Ltd, Sudwestdeutsche Salzwerke AG, and Verein Deutsche Salzindustrie eV to bear their own costs.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>&quot;State aid - Refusal of the Commission to propose &quot;appropriate measures&quot; pursuant to article 93(1) of the Treaty - - Action for annulment - Inadmissible&quot;</p>
<p>22 October 1996</p>
<p>Case T-330/94</p>
<p>Salt Union, Ltd, applicant</p>
<p>supported by Verein Deutsche Salzindustrie eV, intervener</p>
<p>Commission of the European Communities, defendant</p>
<p>supported by</p>
<p>Frima BV, intervener</p>
<p>application for the annulment of the decision contained in a letter of 5 August 1994 in which the Commission stated that it had found no reason to propose &quot;appropriate measures&quot; pursuant to article 93(1) of the EC Treaty with regard to the Netherlands regional aid scheme &quot;Subsidieregeling regional investeringsprojecten 1991&quot;</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE hereby</p>
<p>1. Dismisses the application as inadmissible;</p>
<p>2. Orders Salt Union to pay the costs, including those incurred by Frima BV;</p>
<p>3. Orders Verein Deutsche Salzindustrie eV to bear its own costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
