<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134006" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Daimler puts off restructuring decision until 1997.</title>
<headline>Daimler puts off restructuring decision until 1997.</headline>
<dateline>STUTTGART 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German industrial giant Daimler-Benz AG, whose reorganisation plans have sparked an internal power struggle, on Tuesday said it would put off a decision about a corporate overhaul until early 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The board wants to consider the management structure more intensively over the next few weeks,&quot; it said in a statement after a meeting of the executive committee of its supervisory board.</p>
<p>Germany's largest industrial group has been considering a reorganisation for some months, as part of efforts to make individual operating units more profitable, and closer integration of its main car and truck making operation, Mercedes-Benz.</p>
<p>What would become of Mercedes and its chairman, Helmut Werner, has become the object of intense internal political manoeuvring.</p>
<p>The reorganisation has led to bad blood within the Daimler group, where speculation of a turf war between Mercedes-Benz chairman Werner and Daimler group chairman Juergen Schrempp has grown almost by the day.</p>
<p>According to local media, Werner has threatened to resign if his operation were integrated more closely.</p>
<p>Industry sources on Monday said Schrempp, desperate to prevent the loss of the highly-regarded Werner, has gone as far as to offer the Mercedes boss a top job in the restructured Daimler in order to keep him on board.</p>
<p>Werner's contract as management board member of Daimler, which expires at the end of 1997, is up for renewal at a supervisory board meeting on November 6. His contract at Mercedes runs until 1999.</p>
<p>But Daimler said on Tuesday that it would not decide any personnel moves at the November meeting.</p>
<p>Mercedes officials, who oversee the bulk of Daimler's profit and revenues, have reportedly baulked at closer integration and are resentful that their operation must help underwrite loss-making units such as Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG.</p>
<p>Mercedes, which now makes up around three-quarters of Daimler's group revenues, has predicted its 1996 profits will be clearly higher than last year's 2.275 billion marks ($1.49 billion).</p>
<p>According to company sources, six of seven board members at Daimler favour plans to integrate Mercedes into the parent with only Werner opposed to the move.</p>
<p>Despite the support of board members, analysts said Schrempp was in no position to force his wishes through.</p>
<p>Daimler has already suffered a series of public relations fiascos recently, including a record 5.3 billion mark loss last year.</p>
<p>($1=1.5323 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
