<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134037" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria issues draft constitution for reform vote.</title>
<headline>Algeria issues draft constitution for reform vote.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algeria on Tuesday issued a draft of a new constitution being put to a referendum on November 28, banning Islamic fundamentalists from seeking power and aiming to end nearly five years of violence.</p>
<p>The draft states that Islam is Algeria's state religion and that Arabic is the official language -- two articles aimed at preventing what officials have termed the &quot;hijacking&quot; of religion by fundamentalists, and of language by regional parties, to use as political weapons to seek power.</p>
<p>It also reiterates that Algeria is a democratic and popular republic -- a demand made by secular parties who criticised President Liamine Zeroual's earlier efforts to bring jailed fundamentalist leaders into dialogue.</p>
<p>&quot;Having always been militant for freedom and democracy, the people intend by this constitution to give themselves institutions founded upon the participation of citizens in the management of public affairs and achieving social justice, equality and the freedom of each individual and of all,&quot; says the draft preamble carried by the official news agency APS.</p>
<p>Zeroual's office sent copies of the draft to political parties, dozens of social organisations, the media and Algeria's embassies abroad to start a campaign of explaining the text to ordinary Algerians.</p>
<p>The size of the turnout will be carefully watched to weigh the extent of support for the authorities after a massive and only partly successful effort to gain political and popular support.</p>
<p>Algeria erupted into violence shortly after the authorities in January 1992 cancelled a general election in which the Islamic Salvation Front (FIS), later outlawed, had taken a huge lead. The FIS had also won control of more than 50 percent of townhalls in local elections in 1990.</p>
<p>Discussions over two years, headed by Zeroual who initially tried to include fundamentalists, culminated last month with a political conference which laid the basis for the proposed constitution.</p>
<p>Thirty-eight party, union and other leaders signed a pact at the conference from which the FIS was excluded and which was boycotted by two of the main secular parties.</p>
<p>The pact signalled the ban on the use of religion and language as political platforms, condemned violence and laid the framework for a multi-party democracy.</p>
<p>At the conference, Zeroual offered clemency to guerrillas who surrended and promised a general election would be held in the first half of 1997, followed by local elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
