<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134082" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian shares toppy, but no correction seen.</title>
<headline>Belgian shares toppy, but no correction seen.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares are seen consolidating at around current levels after solid gains in the past two weeks, dealers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite toppy at the moment and we'll see some profit-taking tomorrow. But everything depends on New York,&quot; said a trader. &quot;We won't get a correction, just some consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index  .BFX ended up 0.15 percent at 1,823.55 after losing five points in early trade. An average 2.3 billion francs of Belgian shares changed hands with Solvay, Kredietbank and Powerfin leading the way.</p>
<p>Oil group Petrofina, benefitting from recent buy recommendations, was the most active by value, climbing 0.3 percent to 9,880 francs on healthy oil prices.</p>
<p>Biggest gainer Quick hamburger chain jumped 2.1 percent to 2,195 francs, after surging 4.8 percent on Monday, as France scrapped plans to raise VAT on fast food.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been driven higher by UCB for the past couple of weeks&quot; said an analyst. &quot;It's recent 9,000 francs rise was worth about 20 index points but it's softer today.&quot;</p>
<p>Drugs firm UCB fell 0.3 percent to 70,000 francs after a recent rally on its Zyrtec drug sales success in the U.S.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
