<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134078" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian GSM operator Mobistar has 20,000 clients.</title>
<headline>Belgian GSM operator Mobistar has 20,000 clients.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian-French company Mobistar, which operates Belgium's second GSM mobile phone network, has signed up 20,000 clients six weeks after its launch, the group said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mobistar Managing Director Bernard Ghillebaert told a news conference that Mobistar hoped to have an 11 percent market share by the year 2000 and 25 percent by 2005.</p>
<p>Its first profits should come earlier. &quot;We hope to break even in three to four years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rival operator Belgacom Mobile, whose Proximus service was launched in January 1994, now has an estimated 400,000 clients.</p>
<p>Belgacom Mobile is a 75/25 venture between state telephone company Belgacom SA and AirTouch Communications Inc of the U.S..</p>
<p>Belgacom is 49.9 percent owned by a consortium including U.S. Ameritech, Singapore Telecom and Tele Danmark. The rest is owned by the Belgian state.</p>
<p>Mobistar is owned 62 percent by France Telecom. Belgian data communications firm Telinfo NV has 10 percent and a group of eight other Belgian investors 28 percent.</p>
<p>Ghillebaert said that Mobistar had invested 15 billion francs this year, nine billion for the licence to operate the system and six billion for the network.</p>
<p>He also said that it was still in negotiations with Belgacom about the interconnection fees between the two networks. He said Belgacom was asking &quot;substantially more&quot; from Mobistar than France Telecom was asking its French competitors.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
