<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134029" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Numbers cut in NH90 military helicopter programme.</title>
<headline>Numbers cut in NH90 military helicopter programme.</headline>
<dateline>LE BOURGET, France 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A four-nation programme for the NH90 military helicopter has had its total number of orders cut to 647 units from 726, an NH Industries executive said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>NH Industries is the project manager for the NH90 army transport and navy helicopter which is due to equip the forces of France, Germany, Italy and the Netherlands from 2003.</p>
<p>Eurocopter, the joint venture between France's SNI Aerospatiale and Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG, is the prime contractor for the NH90.  </p>
<p>France has cut its orders to 160 from 220 and Germany to 243 from 272, NH Industries commercial director Alain Gauthier said at the Euronaval trade exhibition for warships.</p>
<p>Italy has raised its order to 224 from 212 and the Netherlands is holding its order at 20.</p>
<p>France and Germany this year cut their defence budgets, hurting procurement programmes. The reduced NH90 orders were agreed this summer but were not announced.  </p>
<p>French-based NH Industries is currently negotiating a memorandum of understanding (MOU) for tooling-up and production,  which it expects to be finalised by the middle of next year and signed at the end of 1997 with the four governments.</p>
<p>That would allow the company to enter full contract talks with the industrial partners and complete them by the middle of 1998. The timing of the MOU and contract talks is driven by the need to deliver the first helicopter to the German and Dutch forces in 2003.  </p>
<p>NH Industries is still using the original unit purchase prices of 90 million francs for the army version and 145 million for the more electronically advanced navy model in the MOU talks, despite the reduced order total.</p>
<p>The French government has been asking defence contractors for an across-the-board price cut of around 30 percent to squeeze purchases into the smaller budget, in addition to reducing the procurement numbers.</p>
<p>-- Pierre Tran, Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5343</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE BOURGET, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
