<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134047" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Spain looks for more gas, business with Algeria.</title>
<headline>Spain looks for more gas, business with Algeria.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's visiting junior foreign minister has signed cooperation deals with Algeria and said that a possible second pipeline to carry more gas to the Spanish market might be needed.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot be ruled out,&quot; said state secretary in charge of cooperation Fernando Maria Villalonga Campos, quoted on Tuesday by Algeria's Liberte newspaper, when asked about a possible new gas pipeline.</p>
<p>Villalonga Campos reasserted that Spain intended to strengthen its economic cooperation with Algeria.</p>
<p>He wound up a two-day conference on cooperation by signing with Algerian officials cooperation accords, including joint ventures in fishing and agriculture.</p>
<p>Algeria's economic relations with Spain are poised to intensify shortly with the opening within the next two weeks of an Algerian gas pipeline, carrying more than 8.0 billion cubic metres to Spain via Morocco and the Strait of Gibraltar.</p>
<p>Algeria bought the equivalent of nine percent of its overall imports, which totalled $10.7 billion in 1995, from Spain which was ranked its fourth trader, with over $900 million in imports.</p>
<p>In a signal highlighting Spanish confidence in the Algerian potential market, Spanish builder Dragadose is to resume work, halted three years ago by violence, on Algeria's Beni Haroun dam, according to earlier official Algerian report.</p>
<p>Work on the 795 million cubic metre-capacity dam in the northeastern province of Mila, 280 km (175 miles) from Algiers, was, like other large water projects, abruptly stopped by violence blamed by Algerian authorities on Moslem guerrillas.</p>
<p>Beni Haroun dam will supply drinking water to the eastern provinces of Mila, Constantine, Jijel, Khenchela, Oum el Bouaghi and Batna, and irrigate farming projects in the high plains around Constantine city.</p>
<p>Villalonga Campos told Algerian media his country had stood by the Algerian authorites during the North African country's crisis in the past three years.</p>
<p>&quot;We kept our embassy, cultural centre, our consulate and other diplomatic missions open for business as usual,&quot; he said obliquely comparing that position to some other countries or companies which had cut back staff or closed completely in that time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
