<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134022" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy coalition parties fail to resolve tax row.</title>
<headline>Italy coalition parties fail to resolve tax row.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parties supporting the centre-left government failed to strike a deal on controversial plans to reform of the Italian fiscal system and will meet again on Wednesday, political sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Parliamentary party leaders from the government coalition met twice on Tuesday to try to resolve the dispute over the finance ministry's plans to shake-up personal taxation.</p>
<p>The proposals, which the government says will have a neutral impact on revenues, would reduce the number of tax brackets and raise the minimum income tax rate to 20 percent from 10 percent and cut the maximum tax rate to 46 percent from 51 percent.</p>
<p>The hard left Communist Refoundation wants the government to drop the plans, while the Italian Renewal party, headed by Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini, wants plans for the revision of personal taxation and the introduction of a new regional tax (IREP) to both be dropped.</p>
<p>The parliamentary party leaders are expected to meet again at 1230 GMT on Wednesday, political sources said.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
