<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134039" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish bishop assailed for peace mediation offer.</title>
<headline>Spanish bishop assailed for peace mediation offer.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of Spain's main political parties assailed a Roman Catholic bishop on Tuesday for offering to mediate between the government and Basque ETA rebels.</p>
<p>Ricardo Blazquez, bishop of Bilbao in Spain's Basque country, offered on Monday to try to end nearly three decades of violence, echoing a similar proposal last week by Bishop Jose Maria Setien of San Sebastian, also in the Basque country.</p>
<p>The conservative government described his offer as &quot;no help&quot; and its Socialist predecessors said he should shut up.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no place for mediation between ETA and the government,&quot; Justice Minister Margarita Mariscal de Gante told reporters when asked to comment.</p>
<p>The rebels have staged only minor attacks in the last couple of months, prompting press speculation about the possible reasons for the lull. Their latest action was last week, when explosives caused minor damage outside three Basque courtrooms.</p>
<p>While mainstream moderate Basque nationalist politicians applauded the bishop's suggestion, the government in Madrid repeated there would be no talks unless the rebels lay down their arms and renounced violence.</p>
<p>Development Minister Rafael Arias Salgado dismissed bishop Blazquez's idea as &quot;no help&quot; and &quot;senseless mediation&quot;. His colleague at the interior ministry, Jaime Mayor Oreja, said he respected the churchmen's ideas but that there was no scope for mediation.</p>
<p>ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) has killed nearly 800 people in a drive for independence begun in 1968.</p>
<p>The former government of Socialist party leader Felipe Gonzalez has been accused of waging a &quot;dirty war&quot; against ETA in which 28 people died between 1983 and 1987.</p>
<p>Gonzalez, now leader of the opposition and waiting to see whether the Supreme Court decides next month to question him, also voiced his disapproval at the bishop's suggestion.</p>
<p>&quot;In these matters, it should be possible to demand discretion even from the Church,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The ruling Popular Party's spokesman in Congress, Luis de Grandes, said mediation was not called for.</p>
<p>&quot;What is needed is a will for those who kill to lay down their arms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There have been no known contacts between ETA and the Spanish government since last year, when Argentine Nobel peace laureate Adolfo Perez Esquivel carried out a series of unsuccessful contacts. He kept his efforts secret until June this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
