<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134050" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Canadian TVX Gold blockade ends, threat lifted.</title>
<headline>Canadian TVX Gold blockade ends, threat lifted.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian TVX Gold lifted on Tuesday a threat to stop work at its mining plant in northern Greece after local residents ended a blockade of its access roads, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>TVX Gold Hellas, the company's Greek subsidiary, had threatened to stop work and halt wages for 650 workers at the Kassandra mines on Wednesday unless the access road was opened.</p>
<p>&quot;TVX Hellas is pleased with the lifting of the blockade, which averts the interruption of staff employment and allows the development of production potential with the resumed operation of the mines and other installations,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Greek riot police clashed on Thursday with local residents blockading the access road to the firm's plant south of the northern port city of Salonika, injuring several people and arresting eight.</p>
<p>Residents from the nearby villages of Varvara and Olympiada have blocked the main road since TVX bought the mine last December, saying the processing plant will wreck the environment and tourism.</p>
<p>Greece's socialist government had been trying to convince the villagers to end their 10-month protest with no success until Tuesday, when negotiations finally produced results.</p>
<p>A government spokesman told reporters that the environment ministry had given local representatives assurances that the it would closely monitor operations to assure no damage was done.</p>
<p>TVX agreed to buy the mines for $47 million, paying $19 million as downpayment. It has invested $28 million so far as part of a $250 to $270 million investment to develop the mines.</p>
<p>When completed, it will be the biggest foreign investment in Greece in 30 years. --Dina Kyriakidou, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
