<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134025" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Rights group says Total backs Burma junta.</title>
<headline>Rights group says Total backs Burma junta.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An international human rights group accused French oil and gas company Total on Wednesday of supporting Burma's military junta and said its construction of a pipeline there had caused an increase in rights violations.</p>
<p>The International Human Rights Federation (FIDH) said in a report that Total, the single largest stakeholder in the pipeline project in southeast Burma, had &quot;knowingly closed its eyes to massive, systematic and violations of human rights and thus made itself an accomplice&quot;.</p>
<p>Total, which owns 31 percent of the project, has denied the allegations.</p>
<p>FIDH said the Burmese army, in preparing for the pipeline project and guarding it, had &quot;displaced the local population, used forced labour and committed violence such as rape and torture&quot;.</p>
<p>The army also stepped up attacks on local rebel groups and carried out reprisals against civilian populations, it said.</p>
<p>The report echoed others issued by the United Nations special rapporteur on human rights and such groups as Amnesty International, which have denounced widespread violations under Burma's State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC).</p>
<p>Breweries Heineken and Carlsberg, Apple computers and Levi-Strauss are among multinational corporations that have decided to end business dealings with Burma in protest at state policies.</p>
<p>Burmese democracy campaigner and Nobel Prize winner Aung San Suu Kyi singled out Total in an interview with French daily Le Monde in July, saying &quot;it has become the strongest supporter of Burma's military system&quot;.</p>
<p>U.S. oil firm UNOCAL with a 28 percent stake, is the second largest owner of the 60 km (35 mile) pipeline designed to transport gas from the Yadana oil field, 70 km (42 miles) off the Burmese coast in the Andaman sea, to Thailand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
