<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134067" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Prodi says Italy means business with privatisation.</title>
<headline>Prodi says Italy means business with privatisation.</headline>
<byline>Jude Webber</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi said in an interview published on Tuesday that Italy meant business with its privatisation programme and was not being half-hearted by keeping a golden share or selling some groups off bit by bit.</p>
<p>The Treasury on Monday put a second tranche of energy group ENI up for sale in one of Europe's biggest privatisations this year and analysts forecast heavy demand as Italy gears up for the next big wave -- the sale of telecoms holding Stet and electricity group Enel.</p>
<p>Economists said they expected Italy's stop-go asset sale programme, which has been interrupted by four years of constant political upheaval and changing faces in government, to gather momentum next year, provided the stock market performs well.</p>
<p>Prodi conceded in an interview with financial daily Il Sole 24 Ore that the ENI sale was not yet a &quot;proper&quot; privatisation since the state will still retain three-quarters of the group, even if an over-allotment, or &quot;green shoe&quot;, option is triggered.</p>
<p>But he defended the drip-feed strategy, saying: &quot;It will be (a true privatisation), when the state sells all its stake...</p>
<p>&quot;There are no doubts about the final outcome -- Eni will be privatised right the way through.&quot;</p>
<p>Angelo Birondi, a veteran of the Milan stock market, said the ENI sale's bright prospects could end up making the government kick itself for offering less than 10 percent of shares this time.</p>
<p>&quot;If it had shown a bit more courage, it would have been rewarded,&quot; he told La Repubblica newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>But Pio de Gregorio, an economist at NatWest Capmarkets, said fears in the investment community that Italy's growth will be hurt in its drive for budget stringency ahead of European Economic and Monetary Union had taken their toll.</p>
<p>&quot;In this kind of environment, it's difficult for the Treasury to think the market could have absorbed a larger offer without a bigger sacrifice in price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;No doubt if the market performs...ENI could come to market with another, larger stake in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prodi insisted Italy will stick like glue to its March 31 1997 deadline for the Stet sell off &quot;otherwise we will lose credibility&quot; and dismissed suggestions that it would not be a real privatisation if the state retained a &quot;golden share&quot;.</p>
<p>Under that strategy, the government retains key powers in a privatised group even after the sell-off.</p>
<p>&quot;The golden share is indispensable to guarantee that Stet does not fall under the control of foreign groups,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's all we will use it for.&quot;</p>
<p>Prodi said he was confident that parliament would approve creation of a watchdog for the telecommunications industry by December, paving the way for the sale to go ahead on time.</p>
<p>A regulatory body must also be set up before Enel can be sold. No timetable for that privatisation has yet been set.</p>
<p>Other forthcoming sales include Banco di Napoli and motorway operator Autostrade. De Gregorio said smaller regional utilities could also be attractive candidates.</p>
<p>Economists reckoned that, with ENI under its belt and Stet on track, Italy will pursue privatisations more aggressively.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a bit more momentum than in the past year,&quot; said Giovanna Mossetti, chief economist at brokers Caboto.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (the government) will probably get some progress going in the hope they will be able to use the proceeds for help on reaching the EMU criteria,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The Maastricht treaty allows states to use privatisation receipts to pay down outstanding debt but forbids them from using it to cut budget deficits.</p>
<p>Rainer Masera, director general of IMI bank and a former budget minister, has said sell-offs due in the next three to five years will raise 300 trillion lire ($200 billion). Sales to date, including ENI, will have raised 40 trillion, he said. ($1=1,530 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
