<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134083" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures settled at their highest level this year as strength in the Bund market and the erosion of early losses in the United States late in the session pushed the contract through resistance at 126.60.</p>
<p>Traders said buying by a French brokerage in the afternoon encouraged local traders to push prices higher into the close, but that there was little fundamental news behind the move.</p>
<p>A larger-than-expected 2.9 percent increase in French manufacturing output in July and August had been a positive early influence but was not cited as a major market influence during the day, they said.  </p>
<p>The French brokerage had also provided the catalyst for the break through resistance at 126.28 earlier in the day, buying a large number of contracts in an otherwise quiet start on behalf of non-residents, they said.</p>
<p>The early rally caught some traders, who had been expecting the contract to fill a gap between 126.24 and 126.12 left during Friday's session, by surprise. The contract fell after the open but bounced off 126.16.</p>
<p>&quot;The gap was the obvious target and I thought we were set for a quiet sort of day,&quot; said a futures trader at a French bank. &quot;Then we followed Bunds higher.&quot;  </p>
<p>A trader at a French brokerage said there had been talk of big cash trade early in the day and the futures price had then been quickly driven higher amid low volume.</p>
<p>&quot;The (primary dealers) were running after it and the locals were running as well but there wasn't much liquidity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A trader at a U.S. bank said some domestic investors were looking to buy bonds earlier on Tuesday but that he did not think the volume had been that signficant.</p>
<p>The 10-year spread between OATs and Bunds moved as wide as minus five basis points during the day but ended unchanged at minus two basis points.  </p>
<p>The yield on the 6.50 percent October 2006 OAT moved down to 5.92 percent from 5.95 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Ciaran O'Hagan, bond analyst at JP Morgan in Paris, said French 10-year bonds looked expensive but the key for the market was whether domestic investors would continue to put new money into the bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;France is dear but the deciding factor is what domestics will do with their money,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>PIBOR contracts recovered from early weakness as the franc climbed above 3.38 per mark. December settled up two basis points at 96.44.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
