<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134036" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy government calls confidence vote on bank.</title>
<headline>Italy government calls confidence vote on bank.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian government on Tuesday called a vote of confidence in the lower house of parliament to ensure that a crucial cabinet decree covering a rescue plan for heavily indebted Banco di Napoli passes swiftly into law.</p>
<p>Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi announced the measure in parliament after the cabinet met to decide how the government should respond to filibustering tactics by the secessionist Northern League.</p>
<p>The League is seeking to block a Treasury salvage package for Banco di Napoli, the largest bank in southern Italy, which involves a huge injection of state funds to keep the group alive followed by a rapid privatisation programme.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a crucial provision to rescue and re-launch Banco di Napoli...which is an institution that has to re-assume its role promoting the economic development of the south,&quot; Ciampi told the Chamber of Deputies (lower house).</p>
<p>Victory in the vote would ensure the legislation passes into law while defeat would bring down Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left government.</p>
<p>According to parliamentary rules, at least 24 hours must elapse between the formal announcement and the actual vote. Parliamentary party leaders were meeting to decide the timing of a debate and the vote.</p>
<p>Prodi's coalition does not control the Chamber of Deputies (lower house) and depends for its majority on support from the hard left Communist Refoundation.</p>
<p>It will be the second confidence vote the government has faced since taking office in May. Prodi called, and won, a confidence vote in August to ram a mini-budget into law, with the legislation again being threatened by League obstructionism.</p>
<p>The League, which last month declared &quot;independence&quot; for the wealthy north of Italy from the poorer south, has presented 1,001 amendments to the Banco di Napoli decree.</p>
<p>The decree, which opens the way for the sale of the loss-making bank by year-end, expires on November 24.</p>
<p>Until now the government has always been able to re-submit expiring decrees, but a recent Constitutional Court ruling outlawed this practice.</p>
<p>Deputy prime minister Walter Veltroni said earlier this month that, while the ruling was justified, Italy could face paralysis unless parliament made a big effort to enact more than 50 outstanding &quot;repeat&quot; decrees into law.</p>
<p>Prodi is still seeking cross-party support to get most of these decrees ratified without resorting to confidence votes, which often alarm financial markets.</p>
<p>But in the face of dogged League opposition and an increasingly tight timetable, he has decided to force the tempo over Banco di Napoli.</p>
<p>The bank unveiled record losses of 3.12 trillion lire ($2.0 billion) in 1995 and it plunged a further 674 billion lire into the red in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>To keep the group afloat, the Treasury said it would underwrite some 12 trillion lire of the bank's bad loans and put two trillion lire into the firm as part of a capital increase.</p>
<p>It hopes to get some of this money back before the end of the year through the planned privatisation and has called on interested parties to place bids for the bank by December 20. $1 = 1,524 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
