<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134081" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French minister backs suspended policeman.</title>
<headline>French minister backs suspended policeman.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Paris crime squad keeps his job in spite of a court order suspending him from investigative duties, defiant Justice Minister Jacques Toubon told the National Assembly on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Senior policeman Olivier Foll was barred from his main role for six months on Monday for refusing to help a corruption probe into the ruling Gaullist party.</p>
<p>Rejecting opposition charges that he was in contempt of court, Toubon said the court had suspended Foll from his investigative duties, but not from administrative functions.</p>
<p>&quot;The Interior Minister has full power to appoint his staff. The ruling covers Foll's work but and in no way his job,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Can court rulings be flouted when they do not please the Interior Minister?&quot; a Socialist parliamentarian asked him.</p>
<p>Interior Ministry sources said Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre, who is close to Gaullist President Jacques Chirac, had no intention of sacking Foll after Monday's ruling.</p>
<p>Official sources said Foll could carry on as head of the Criminal Investigation Division but he would have to delegate investigative duties to subordinates.</p>
<p>The court punished Foll for refusing to let his men help investigating judge Eric Halphen search the home of Paris mayor Jean Tiberi in a July probe into Gaullist party fundraising.</p>
<p>Halphen, who was investigating allegations that the Gaullists received kickbacks on housing contracts in the Paris area, had to search Tiberi's home on his own.</p>
<p>Foll, who is appealing the suspension, has complained through his lawyer that Halphen only told the policemen when they got to Tiberi's door whose home they were going to search.</p>
<p>French media say the investigating judge feared police officers assigned to help him were in fact spying for their superiors and trying to delay a probe getting uncomfortably close to Chirac, who was mayor of Paris until elected president last year.</p>
<p>Gaullist Senator Hubert Haenel said the court had rightfully reminded police officers that they had to obey judges and had no business passing judgement on their decisions.</p>
<p>But the court ruling triggered an outcry from police and right-wing magistrates, while the government's stand angered the opposition and left-leaning judges.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must choose: either it protects its friends, or it guarantees the independence of justice,&quot; Socialist Party spokesman Francois Hollande told the daily Le Monde.</p>
<p>Hollande and the moderate Magistrates Union said the court, by punishing Foll, had indirectly pointed the finger at Debre who had publicly backed his subordinate.</p>
<p>Senior police officers who were present in court said the punishment was too harsh -- a criticism also voiced by the right-wing Professional Magistrates Association.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
