<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13405" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Dollar weaker on uncertainty over Japan.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Dollar weaker on uncertainty over Japan.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar opened European trading on Monday almost a pfennig weaker than Friday's levels with investors jittery over Tokyo's monetary policy ahead of a key Japanese economic survey due this week.</p>
<p>The U.S. currency had slipped to 1.4777 marks by mid-morning compared with Friday's European close of 1.4871 in dealings that were subdued as British markets were closed because of a seasonal holiday.</p>
<p>Equity markets in Frankfurt and Paris were mixed but again business was quiet because of London's closure.</p>
<p>On the foreign exchanges, the dollar, which began sliding from 1.49 levels last week as euphoria over a German interest rate cut fizzled out, fell further because of growing uncertainty over Japan.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan's quarterly Tankan survey on companies' expectations of future business is out on Wednesday and is regarded as an important reference for formulating monetary policy.</p>
<p>Although few expect the survey to change Japan's steady monetary policy stance markets become nervous because the lower the Tankan's index, the gloomier the outlook.</p>
<p>The dollar also fell to 107. 89 yen, compared to 108.50 in late European trading on Friday.</p>
<p>The mark was stronger against European currencies as well, gaining against the French franc and posted hefty gains on the lira.</p>
<p>Mark/lira was trading at 1022.90 from 1018.82 on Friday. Mark/French franc was at 3.4181 against 3.4137.</p>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said in La Repubblica newspaper that Italy did not want a revision of the Maastricht criteria.</p>
<p>Prodi's comments come after a weekend newspaper interview by his deputy, Walter Veltroni, who said that Italy and other European countries should consider the possibility of a Maastricht re-think.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, stocks were down with sentiment hit by lower German bonds, the weaker dollar and a negative close on Wall Street on Friday.</p>
<p>In early bourse trade the DAX index, which measures floor trade in 30 blue-chip German shares, was down 5.35 points at 2,549.81.</p>
<p>&quot;There is very little going on here today and volumes seem very thin. Also London is closed because of the bank holiday,&quot; said a Frankfurt dealer, adding that interest should pick up after the holiday season ends around next week.</p>
<p>French stocks too were weaker at the open, weighed down by the fragile franc, but picked up slightly later. The CAC-40 index was just in positive territory by mid-morning in trading kept thin by London's holiday.</p>
<p>Last Thursday and Friday, the bourse rose after the Bank of France cut its intervention rate to 3.35 percent following a surprise Bundesbank repo rate cut.</p>
<p>But dealers said the rate cuts would have a limited effect on the French economy and therefore its longer term boost to the CAC-40 was doubtful.</p>
<p>&quot;While the rate cut is positive, it wasn't big enough to completely change the economic situation, which is quasi-recessionist when you look at price indices and consumer confidence,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1030 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4777 marks and 107.89 yen compared with 1.4871 marks and 108.50 yen at the London close on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1030 GMT</p>
<p>The London stock market is closed for a public holiday. On Friday the FTSE 100 closed at 3,907.5 up 16.4 points.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was up 0.56 points to 2,021.38.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was down 5.35 points at 2,549.81.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was stronger at $388.45 versus $387.50 at Friday's London close. Activity was expected to be quiet with London markets closed for a public holiday. Silver was unchanged at $5.24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
