<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134060" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Santer's 1997 work programme fails to dazzle MEPs.</title>
<headline>Santer's 1997 work programme fails to dazzle MEPs.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Euro MPs were unimpressed by an annual work programme presented on Tuesday by Commission President Jacques Santer which gives priority to creating jobs and stimulating economic growth.</p>
<p>For the Socialists, the parliament's largest group, deputy leader Ben Fayot from Luxembourg urged the Commission to meet the needs of people, not those of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless action is taken very quickly,...demagogues of all sorts, Eurosceptics of every shade, nationalists and fascists will open up shop and prosper,&quot; he warned during a debate.</p>
<p>Fayot criticised the Commission for failing to meet parliamentary demands for laws on hotel fire safety and environmental damage, health passports and road accident insurance.</p>
<p>Fayot also criticised the Commission for ignoring its views on genetically modified food, TV broadcasting and postal services.</p>
<p>Liberal leader Gijs de Vries, of the Netherlands, called for an independent system to protect people's right to privacy in view of the growing amount of data supplied by member states to EU institutions, such as in the fight against fraud.</p>
<p>For the mainly Christian Democrat EPP group, Dutch member Ria Oonen-Ruijten complained about the EU's failure to help the peace process in the Middle East and noted that initiatives on the right of asylum and a refugee policy had got nowhere.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
