<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134013" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Santer makes EU jobs pledge for coming year.</title>
<headline>Santer makes EU jobs pledge for coming year.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union must press ahead in 1997 with ambitious plans to create more jobs in order to restore popular support for the bloc, European Commission President Jacques Santer said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Presenting the EU executive's annual work programme to the European Parliament, Santer said that preparation for a single European currency, completion of a review of the EU's treaty and progress on bloc enlargement eastwards were also key issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The main priority...is implementation of the confidence pact for employment,&quot; Santer said, referring to his plans to boost jobs.</p>
<p>Santer defended the plans, which were again rejected by EU finance ministers last week, to spend more than $1 billion on trans-European road and rail projects.</p>
<p>Member states are worried about meeting tough budget and debt targets to qualify for economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;It's not an empty gesture,&quot; Santer said. &quot;Unemployment undermines the confidence of EU citizens. We must restore that confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>Santer's streamlined work programme was in sharp contrast to grandiose plans proposed by some of his predecessors.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission is convinced that we must act less in order to act better,&quot; he reiterated. But he added: &quot;In 1997, as before, it will not balk at taking steps whenever it believes that a contribution from the Union is needed...&quot;</p>
<p>Santer said the Commission was right to insist on strict budgetary spending limits in preparation for a single EU currency on January 1, 1999, which he expected a significant number of member states to join.</p>
<p>&quot;Soon we shall see the beneficial effects on employment. That's our true objective. EMU is only a means,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Looking farther ahead, Santer said the EU must change the way it works in order to prepare for the next century.</p>
<p>&quot;Enlargement makes this even more necessary,&quot; he said, referring to the prospective membership of eastern European and Mediterranean countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Maintaining (decision-making) unanimity seems to me inconceivable in a Union of 20 or more members,&quot; he said, warning that otherwise the EU would grind to a halt.</p>
<p>Santer's reiteration of the need to cut back on member states' right to veto decisions was set to enrage Eurosceptics, notably in Britain, fighting to hold back federalist forces.</p>
<p>The EU was preparing to expand eastwards and in 1997, after the intergovernmental conference is over, the Commission will issue opinions on the membership applications, Santer said.</p>
<p>The Commission will take account of the heavy impact of enlargement on farm and regional spending when it draws up a report next year on financial guidelines from 2000 onwards.</p>
<p>For the socialists, the Parliament's largest group, deputy leader Ben Fayot from Luxembourg urged the Commission to meet the needs of people, not those of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless action is taken very quickly,...demagogues of all sorts, Eurosceptics of every shade, nationalists and fascists will open up shop and prosper,&quot; he warned during a debate.</p>
<p>Fayot criticised the Commission for failing to meet parliamentary demands for laws on fire safety and environmental damage and for ignoring its views on genetically modified food.</p>
<p>Liberal leader, Gijs de Vries of the Netherlands, called for an independent system to protect people's right to privacy in view of the growing amount of data supplied by member states to EU institutions, such as in the fight against fraud.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
