<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134027" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Havas, Gle des Eaux bid for SFP.</title>
<headline>Havas, Gle des Eaux bid for SFP.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French media giant Havas and utility Compagnie Generale des Eaux announced on Tuesday a joint bid for state-owned film production company Societe Francaise de Production (SFP).</p>
<p>&quot;The Havas and Generale des Eaux groups are to make a joint offer in which each will take an equal share for SFP, the production company now in the course of privatisation,&quot; the two companies said in a statement.</p>
<p>They gave no financial details about their offer.</p>
<p>&quot;We are giving no financial details for the simple reason that we want to present them to the unions and the privatisation committee,&quot; a Generale des Eaux spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said those details would be presented &quot;in the coming days or weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier Havas had been associated with a separate bid by Belgian company LBO Convoy group while Generale des Eaux supported a bid by William Butler's Global Studios.</p>
<p>The two companies, which already cooperate in other areas, had decided it was in their mutual interest to team up instead for SFP, a Generale des Eeaux spokesman said.</p>
<p>A third bidder is former SFP head Jacques Cressant, acting in association with a group of presenter-producers.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux and Havas said &quot;synergies with SFP will be realised through subsidiaries of the two groups in which they hold majority interest.&quot;</p>
<p>Those two companies are ITI/Tele Images, a production company belonging to Groupe Havas and Generale d'Images which belongs to Generale des Eaux.</p>
<p>Links between the two groups and their involvement in the audiovisual sector meant &quot;they are in a position to implement a plan for the long-term development of SFP which is likely to be approved by staff,&quot; the companies said.</p>
<p>The French finance ministry had been due to choose a bidder by October 10 but that decision has been delayed.</p>
<p>The European Commission ruled earlier this month that France had illegally granted 1.1 billion francs ($212.3 million) in subsidies to SFP between 1993 and early 1996. It is unclear whether the money will have to be repaid. ($1=5.182 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741112">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
