<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134088" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy holds out EU olive branch to Libya.</title>
<headline>Italy holds out EU olive branch to Libya.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy said on Tuesday it would support a review of a European Union decision to exclude Libya from a cooperation agreement between the EU and countries of the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini told parliament there were already signs that Libya, under limited U.N. sanctions since 1992, was changing its attitude towards the West.</p>
<p>He made clear that a review of the decision was not imminent, saying Italy would support such a rethink &quot;when the issue can be raised with our community partners&quot;.</p>
<p>His remarks to a joint session of the foreign affairs commission of Italy's two houses of parliament followed talks in Cairo on Monday between Prime Minister Romano Prodi and Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak that included a discussion of Libya.</p>
<p>The EU struck a wide-ranging partnership accord with 12 non-member countries of the Mediterranean, including Syria and Israel, in Barcelona, Spain in November 1995.</p>
<p>Dini said Italy was interested in reviewing Libyan exclusion not only because the two countries had substantial commercial and financial ties.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to think positively, in the sense that what today seems a difficult situation, blocked by controversies and factors of the past, can be overcome and lead Libya itself back into the mainstream of attitudes on general and foreign policy pursued by the other countries on the southern shore of the Mediterranean,&quot; Dini said.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me that there are already signs in this direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Libya has faced limited U.N. sanctions since 1992 because it refuses to let Britain or the United States try two Libyan men accused of blowing up a Pan Am plane over Scotland in 1988.</p>
<p>Prodi said in Cairo on Monday that Mubarak had tried to persuade him that Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi had changed his attitude to the West and was now trying to be cooperative.</p>
<p>&quot;President Mubarak insisted on the limits of the politics of embargo, especially with Libya,&quot; Prodi said.</p>
<p>&quot;He presented his opinion that now Gaddafi is changing his politics and trying to have a much more cooperative policy with the Western world, with Europe, and has done positive and concrete steps in this direction,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Gaddafi allowed France's chief anti-terrorism investigator Jean-Louis Bruguiere into Libya to gather information about the bombing of a UTA airlines DC-10 airliner over the Sahara in 1989.</p>
<p>All 170 passengers and crew died in the crash.</p>
<p>The bombing occurred at the height of tension between France and Libya over Chad, where forces from the two countries clashed repeatedly in the 1970s and 1980s.</p>
<p>Bruguiere wants six Libyans -- including Gaddafi's brother-in-law and two secret service agents -- to be tried in absentia next year if Libya does not turn them over.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
