<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134053" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FORECAST-Italy Oct inflation to slide to three pct.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Italy Oct inflation to slide to three pct.</headline>
<byline>Luca Trogni</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Preliminary CPI data from 10 Italian cities released on Tuesday increased analysts' optimism that inflation would now come in at 3.0 percent year-on-year in October and below that in November, spurring rate cut hopes.</p>
<p>&quot;I was already optimistic (of achieving three percent) before the last data and now I am even more so,&quot; said Lucia Trevisan at Caboto after initial figures from the last seven sample cities were released.</p>
<p>Three other cities released data on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;In November, inflation will be below three percent with almost mathematical certainty. Previously it was just a forecast,&quot; said Marcello Esposito of Banca Commerciale Italiana.</p>
<p>Martino Dolfini, economist at Chase Manhattan, said he now expected October CPI to come in at between 2.9 and 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The most striking aspect is that October is a typically inflationary month so it seems to me that after these figures, inflation is looking particularly under control,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't exclude finishing the year at 2.5 percent,&quot; Dolfini added.</p>
<p>Italy's official October inflation data will be published by the national statistics office Istat on November 6.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters on Monday after preliminary figures were released from Milan, Turin and Trieste had forecast an October CPI increase of 3.1 percent year-on-year and 0.2 percent month-on-month.</p>
<p>But they lowered their figures to 3.0 percent year-on-year and 0.1 percent month-on-month after Bologna, Venice, Perugia, Genoa, Naples, Palermo and Florence gave their initial data.</p>
<p>The 10 sample cities have a combined weighting of 69.8 percent in the total index.</p>
<p>Italy's consumer price index in September rose 3.4 percent year-on-year and 0.3 percent month-on-month.</p>
<p>Credito Italiano analyst Pompeo Pontone said expectations of 3.0 percent inflation or less by the end of the year &quot;with all that entails for a rate cut&quot; were now strengthening.</p>
<p>Analysts said on Monday they expected the Bank of Italy to cut its key discount rate in the middle of November by up to 75-100 basis points if progress with the 1997 budget was on track and official data confirmed their October CPI optimism.</p>
<p>The discount rate was last cut in July to 8.25 percent.</p>
<p>The Chamber of Deputies (lower house) is due to have finished debating Prime Minister Romano Prodi's austerity budget, which is designed to slash 62.5 trillion lire ($41 billion) off next year's deficit, by November 17.</p>
<p>Economists said that could be a timely moment for a rate cut, since the budget then passes to the Senate (upper house), which Prodi's centre-left coalition controls. The budget must by law be passed by both houses of parliament by the year's end. ($1=1,530)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
