<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134026" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. oil deal monitors postpone trip to Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.N. oil deal monitors postpone trip to Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An advance team of three inspectors from the Dutch firm Saybolt has postponed a visit to Iraq scheduled for this week because of the unstable situation in the north, diplomats said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Saybolt inspectors were pulled out of Iraq in early September when fighting flared in the northern Kurdish regions and the United Nations delayed putting into force an oil-for-food plan.  </p>
<p>That arrangement allows Iraq to sell $2 billion of oil over six months, on a renewable basis, to buy food, medicine and other necessities to help offset the effect on ordinary Iraqis of sanctions imposed after Iraq's August 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>The diplomats said the oil monitors were to be sent back this week to perform preliminary inspections ahead of a possible implementation of the plan. But the envoys said their visit had been delayed further because of the situation in the north where the United States is currently trying to implement a ceasefire between two Kurdish factions.  </p>
<p>In related comments, Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Tuesday said the United Nations was still trying to &quot;overcome all the difficulties because I believe it is a must to implement 986,&quot; a reference to the Security Council resolution that sets out the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that there is a war going on has complicated our situation on the ground.&quot; He said he was currently meeting with Gualtiero Fulcheri, the senior U.N. representative in Baghdad, who arrived in New York two days ago.  </p>
<p>U.N. Under-Secretary-General Chinmaya Gharekhan told reporters on October 9 that the plan could not be implemented yet because of Iraqi insistence on curtailing freedom of movement of U.N. personnel and for new local U.N. staff to be hired to replace those already working for the United Nations.</p>
<p>Arrangements to launch the plan were close to completion when Iraqi President Saddam Hussein sent troops into the largely Kurdish-inhabited north of the country at the end of August to back one side in an inter-Kurdish conflict.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
