<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134046" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU prepares measures to fight child sex tourism.</title>
<headline>EU prepares measures to fight child sex tourism.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union's executive Commission is preparing a report on measures to combat child sex tourism, the EU's commissioner for tourism, Christos Papoutsis, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to present this report early next month,&quot; Papoutsis said in reply to a question at the European Parliament.</p>
<p>He said that recent tragic events in Belgium, where four young girls were abused and murdered by a paedophile gang, had given impetus to calls for an EU-wide crack-down.</p>
<p>Closer judicial cooperation between EU member states and steps to make it easier to take action against paedophiles operating outside national borders were among measures being considered.</p>
<p>EU strategy would be to focus at first on tourist destination countries, such as Thailand and the Philippines, and then on steps to reduce demand for child sex tours.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to ensure private sector industry support,&quot; he said, adding that dissuasive information campaigns would be increased.</p>
<p>At the national level, Papoutsis said that tourist agencies would be targeted to make sure that everything was being done to curb such tourist traffic.</p>
<p>Separately, the Belgian charity &quot;Marc and Corine&quot; on Tuesday presented the European Parliament's all party &quot;Family, Children and Solidarity&quot; group with the results of a pilot project on the creation of a European network for finding lost children.</p>
<p>The charity is named after two Belgian children who were abducted in July 1992 and found murdered shortly afterwards.</p>
<p>The Spanish chairwoman of the parliament's all party group, Francisca Bennasar Tous, said 3.5 million Ecus would be sought as an allocation in the 1997 EU budget when the Parliament votes on Thursday at the first reading.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a tough battle given the climate of budgetary rigour,&quot; she said, adding that another problem was the lack of legal provisions for such EU expenditure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
