<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13401" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Price war hurts Lufthansa earnings.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Price war hurts Lufthansa earnings.</headline>
<byline>Catherine O'Mahony</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>German airline Deutsche Lufthansa AG on Monday blamed a 37 percent slump in its first-half profit mainly on price slashing by European rivals but said its full-year earnings should be stable.</p>
<p>The carrier posted pre-tax profit of 119 million marks for the first six months of 1996, sharply below the year-ago period's 189 million although slightly better than an estimate in July that profits would drop to 100 million marks.</p>
<p>Its shares dropped 1.5 percent to 208 marks on the news.</p>
<p>Disappointing growth in passenger and freight volumes limited expansion and the airline said its German business was hit by a flood of cheap flights from subsidised airlines, excess capacity and a fatal fire in April at Duesseldorf airport.</p>
<p>To compensate, it pledged to cut its spending budget for the rest of the year by 190 million marks, or three percent, as well as removing five aircraft from service and trimming staff accordingly.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of these measures, the management board expects to be able to achieve earnings for the full year of 1996 which are comparable with year-ago levels, given stable currencies and a sales rise of five percent,&quot; Lufthansa said.</p>
<p>Its pre-tax profit from ordinary activities rose to 756.4 million marks in 1995.</p>
<p>Sales in the first half of this year climbed 6.6 percent to 9.8 billion marks despite lower turnover at Lufthansa Cargo. Lufthansa AG, Condor Flugdienst, Lufthansa CityLine and Lufthansa Technik all contributed to the advance.</p>
<p>A Lufthansa spokesman said the German carrier's main price rival in the first half was Air France, which launched a strong assault on the lower end of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;There were Air France price cuts of up to 30 percent,&quot; he said, noting that the rivalry with the French carrier extended to non-European flights as well as French-German routes.</p>
<p>Lufthansa has repeatedly criticised rival airlines for using state subsidies to fund what it sees as unrealistic prices.</p>
<p>However, it distanced itself from an aggressive attempt by one of its sales teams to redress the balance in Lufthansa's favour, reported in the German press on Monday.</p>
<p>The carrier's North Bavarian sales team had sent letters to around 20 travel agents encouraging them to keep the British Airways share of the German market below 15 percent from mid-October through mid-December this year or risk getting worse terms of business from Lufthansa.</p>
<p>Lufthansa said the incident was unauthorised and that there would be &quot;consequences&quot; for the department involved.</p>
<p>The airline said passenger numbers virtually stalled at 19.7 million in the first six months of 1996. Freight and mail volume grew by 2.8 percent to 808,600 tonnes.</p>
<p>The Duesseldorf fire, which closed the airport for several days, caused Lufthansa to lose at least a high two-digit million mark figure in revenue, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Lufthansa said it would give top priority this year to its cost-cutting programme, which aims to reduce unit costs by around 20 percent by 2001 in a bid to compensate for high German wage costs and the strong mark.</p>
<p>As well as cutting spending, the airline said it planned to take three planes from its short-range and medium-range fleet and two from its long-distance fleet. The planes are likely to be sold, the spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
