<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134072" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Pakhoed says 1996 marks return to basics.</title>
<headline>Pakhoed says 1996 marks return to basics.</headline>
<byline>Philip Blenkinsop</byline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch tank storage and shipping group Pakhoed NV said on Tuesday it had focused on a &quot;back to basics&quot; strategy this year which should reap peak profits within two to three years.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to ask: what is our business?...The year 1996 has been one of transition. It's back to basics for our business,&quot; Pakhoed chairman Klaas Westdijk told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the basic strategy involved improving its logistics arms and then boosting profits in the chemical distibution unit.</p>
<p>Pakhoed's first steps will be to restore profitability of its newly acquired U.S. chemical logistics operations and to make savings in Europe following its purchase of the remaining 72 percent of shares in Univar Corp  UVX.N.</p>
<p>The chemicals logistics group's is concentrated in North America, although it also has European interests.</p>
<p>Growth on the distribution side will follow, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now well positioned for profit growth,&quot; executive board member Ton Spoor said.</p>
<p>The company believes its distribution arm will contribute between 50 and 85 million guilders within two to three years.</p>
<p>Logistics is expected to contribute between 70 and 110 million guilders.</p>
<p>&quot;The distribution potential means that in three years time, our minimum profit should be 125 million guilders,&quot; said Spoor.</p>
<p>Pakhoed also hopes to improve the profitability of its oil storage sector which has suffered prompt oil prices being more expensive than future ones. This market structure provides companies with little or no incentive to store oil.</p>
<p>However, company chairman said cost reduction and repositioning could return the sector to profit.</p>
<p>&quot;The first in line is to reduce the cost and, further down the line, reposition the business. The (oil) futures market may change, but we cannot rely on it to change,&quot; Pakhoed chairman Klaas Westdijk said.</p>
<p>Repositioning the business may involve a greater presence than now in the Asia Pacific region. Pakhoed said it expected a gradually increasing contribution from investments there.</p>
<p>The year was notable for Pakhoed's divestment of its Furness port services group and its decision in June to increase its stake in Univar from 28 to 100 percent. The full purchase of the U.S. firm at a cost of 521 million guilders made the Dutch group the world's largest distributor of chemical products.</p>
<p>Pakhoed said it was in talks with ING Barings on a financing package of 300-350 million guilders, consisting of 150-200 million guilders worth of cumulative financing preference shares and 150 million of subordinated loans.</p>
<p>&quot;To strengthen its financial basis Pakhoed will increase guarantee capital by at least 300 million guilders,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>The terms and conditions of the preference shares will be announced in the second half of November.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsroom, +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
