<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134065" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti shares slide in &quot;week of fire&quot;.</title>
<headline>Olivetti shares slide in &quot;week of fire&quot;.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in ailing Olivetti hit a new record low on Tuesday with worried investors continuing to sell as the Italian hi-tech group faced key meetings this week in what was described as &quot;the week of fire&quot; for the company.</p>
<p>Italy's industry minister Pierluigi Bersani appears before the Italian parliament's Senate industry committee late Tuesday on the Olivetti affair, while new chief executive Roberto Colaninno comes face to face with angry union leaders on Thursday.</p>
<p>Milan financial daily Il Sole 24 Ore described the next few days as &quot;the week of fire&quot; for Olivetti as it faced these critical events, and the shares slipped to a new record low of 435 lire (28 cents) before closing 2.95 percent lower at 436.9 lire.</p>
<p>Analysts said investors were still concerned at the plight of the group and were worried whether further skeletons may appear from the group's cupboard in the next few days.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a certain nervousness over the stock with Bersani speaking today and Colaninno due to meet the Olivetti unions on Thursday,&quot; said one industry analyst based in Milan.</p>
<p>Last Friday, Olivetti's workers took to the streets of Rome in a national demonstration and staged an eight-hour strike in protest at the group's precarious future, voicing their discontent at plans to sell-off bits of the company.</p>
<p>Union leaders are concerned at the future of the 1,750 people employed at Olivetti's up-for-sale personal computer company based near the group's headquarters at Ivrea in north-west Italy, and are also worried at the prospect of Italian hi-tech businesses being sold to foreign buyers.</p>
<p>Analysts are pondering whether Colaninno's recovery strategy will be enough to save the group and convince long-suffering investors to refinance the company for future growth.</p>
<p>Colaninno's plan calls for 1.2 trillion lire ($784 million) of disposals over the rest of 1996 and the whole of 1997, and he has said a capital increase may be needed at the end of 1997.</p>
<p>These disposals will include selling its loss-making personal computer company, a 5.6 percent stake in mobile phone consortium Omnitel, speciality computer unit Tecnost and also a flotation of office equipment company Lexikon in 1997.</p>
<p>One share trader said last year's record 2.26 trillion lire rights issue was to restructure the group and relaunch the PC company, but now the PC company was to be sold and this left investors confused about what happened to the rights money.</p>
<p>Many investors bought into Olivetti at the rights issue price of 1,000 lire which pushed foreign ownership up to 70 percent, but they have seen their investment halved in under a year and now face another looming rights issue.</p>
<p>In another twist to the Olivetti affair, the group said it planned to sue its ex-director general in charge of finance and auditing Renzo Francesconi for 100 billion lire for actions which led to the suspension of Olivetti share trading and the subsequent rapid slide in the company's share price.</p>
<p>Francesconi resigned in early September after only two months at Olivetti, one day after the group published its first-half 1996 figures following comments which cast doubts over the accuracy of Olivetti's financial accounts. ($1=1,530 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
