<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134031" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Gemina board member Pierri resigns - source.</title>
<headline>Gemina board member Pierri resigns - source.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paolo Pierri, one of the five members of the board of troubled Italian financial holding group Gemina, has resigned and will be replaced next month, a company source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear why Pierri, a former manager at state-controlled telecoms holding company Stet who was appointed to Gemina's board in February, had quit.</p>
<p>Five former managers of Gemina were released last week into house arrest after they were detained on suspicion of false accounting.</p>
<p>Gemina's financial affairs have been under scrutiny after an investigation into alleged fraudulent book-keeping opened last year into the company and its RCS publishing division.</p>
<p>The company intends to hive off its industrial interests into a new company with Gemina keeping control of a few financial activities.</p>
<p>The company source said Pierri's succession was already on the agenda for Gemina's next cabinet meeting, due on November 27 or 28, which is scheduled to consider the company split.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 6610 2321</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
