<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134011" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Hong Kong said urging UN watch after handover.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong said urging UN watch after handover.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong legislators called on Tuesday for United Nations supervision of human rights after the territory's return to China next year, and a senior official of the colony said this was being discussed with Beijing.</p>
<p>The legislators, backed by non-governmental groups from the British colony, said they felt it was vital for China to agree to continue regular reports on the situation to the U.N. Human Rights Committee after the transfer next July 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite pessimistic about the fate of human rights in Hong Kong after the transfer,&quot; Emily Lau, a member of the colony's current Legislative Council, told a news conference on the eve of a Committee hearing on the situation.</p>
<p>But Hong Kong's Solicitor-General Daniel Fung told a later news conference both the colonial administration and the British government were keen for the system of reporting to continue and were &quot;in dialogue&quot; with China on the issue.</p>
<p>Lau is a member of a delegation of critics of the terms on which the handover from British to Chinese rule is being made which came to Geneva to discuss the issue with the 18-member Committee, made up of independent human rights experts.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong government itself will also be appearing before the Committee over the next two days to answer questions on a report it submitted earlier this year on observance of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.</p>
<p>Fung will lead the Hong Kong group as part of the official British team for the two-day Committee hearing. Beijing will be sending an observer to the hearings, the first time it has done this and a step Fung said was &quot;an encouraging sign&quot;.</p>
<p>Lau, supported by fellow legislators Andrew Cheng and James To as well as Paul Harris of the Hong Kong Bar Association, told her news conference that China was giving no indication of readiness to continue the reports after next July.</p>
<p>Beijing has argued that it will have no obligation to the Committee Kong after the transfer as it is not a signatory to the Covenant, which the U.N. body monitors.</p>
<p>&quot;If China continues to refuse to make reports, or does not sign the Covenant itself, we hope the Committee will be agreeable to receiving reports from non-governmental groups to decide whether a full hearing should be held,&quot; said Lau.</p>
<p>The Committee, set up in 1976, studies reports by governments on the human rights situation in territory under their jurisdiction and also accepts comments from unofficial organisations in states which have signed the Covenant.</p>
<p>But it has not tried in the past to hold hearings on problems in countries which are not signatories, nor has it accepted unofficial reports from such states.</p>
<p>Lau said Hong Kong was a unique case because it was being transferred from a state which had signed the Covenant to one which had not. &quot;We hope some way can be found for the Committee to continue to receive reports,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Members of her delegation said they were especially concerned at growing signs from China that it would not allow Hong Kong's present degree of political and media freedom to continue after it takes over.</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen suggested public protests over official policies would be barred and Hong Kong's freewheeling media would face restrictions on what it could write after the transfer.</p>
<p>But Fung said other Chinese officials had later said Qian had been misunderstood. The Hong Kong government was seeking clarification from Beijing on the remarks, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
