<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134052" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. tells Abkhaz separatists to call off elections.</title>
<headline>U.N. tells Abkhaz separatists to call off elections.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Security Council called on the Abkhaz separatists in Georgia on Tuesday to call off parliamentary elections scheduled for next month, saying they should await settlement of the political status of the breakaway territory.</p>
<p>Some 250,000 Georgians fled Abkhazia in 1993 when separatists backed by mercenaries and arms from Russia's northern Caucasus region drove out Georgian government troops in a lightning campaign.</p>
<p>A 120-member U.N. Observer Mission in Georgia (UNOMIG) is stationed in the region, where a much larger Russian-led peacekeeping force is fielded by the Commonwealth of Independent States.</p>
<p>&quot;The Security Council is deeply concerned at the announcement made by the Abkhaz side that so-called parliamentary elections would be held on Nov. 23, 1996,&quot; a statement read at a brief council meeting said.</p>
<p>&quot;The holding of such elections would only be possible after the determination through negotiations of the political status of Abkhazia respecting the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Georgia within its internationally recognised boundaries,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The council...calls on the Abkhaz side to call off these elections and further calls on both sides to refrain from any action that could heighten tension.&quot;</p>
<p>The council statement noted with concern that no significant progress had yet been achieved towards a comprehensive settlement of the conflict, including on the political status of Abkhazia.</p>
<p>It called on the parties, in particular the Abkhaz side, to resume discussions and reach substantive progress in the negotiations.</p>
<p>The council also said it remained deeply concerned at the &quot;continued obstruction of the return of the refugees and displaced persons by the Abkhaz authorities, which is totally unacceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>The Georgian government wants Abkhazia, an autonomous republic in the former Soviet republic of Georgia, to accept that its territory lies inside the independent Georgian state while the Abkhazian leadership wants Georgia to recognise its self-declared independence.</p>
<p>Another cause of concern was the &quot;deterioration of the situation in the Ghali region,&quot; a security and restricted weapons zone where some of the U.N. observers operate. The council statement condemned mine-laying and other threats there against UNOMIG and CIS peacekeepers and called on both parties to take all necessary steps to prevent such acts.</p>
<p>Before the statement was read out the council adopted a brief resolution by a vote of 14 in favour to none against, with China abstaining, making a small human rights office in Abkhazia part of UNOMIG.</p>
<p>China said peacekeeping operations should not be overstretched by taking over matters that fell under the terms of reference of other agencies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
