<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134062" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission report hints at action on high fares.</title>
<headline>Commission report hints at action on high fares.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some air fares on intra- European Union routes are still excessive despite market deregulation, the European Commission said on Tuesday in a report which hinted at possible legal action to force airlines to cut fares.</p>
<p>&quot;On certain routes, fares could be described as excessive. It's becoming clear that a deeper examination is required in order to find out which fares would qualify as excessive (under EU aviation and competition rules),&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission will use its powers of inquiry...if it needs to, to bring an end to excessive fares,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>While the report did not specifically name airlines which had the highest fully flexible fares, it did provide tables showing the cheapest and dearest routes.</p>
<p>These included many domestic German flights, flights between the Netherland's Eindhoven and Amsterdam, France's Le Havre and London and between Germany's Stuttgart and France's Nice.</p>
<p>The remarks on fares, part of a Commission report on the EU's aviation deregulation efforts, came amid qualified praise for a gradually improving picture for the bloc's industry.</p>
<p>Passengers now have a greater chance of buying promotional fares on scheduled flights, with more than 70 percent flying on cheaper tickets in 1995 compared with about 60 percent in 1985.</p>
<p>At the same time the EU's charter carriers, with almost across-the-board cheaper fares than their competitors' scheduled traffic, have grabbed about 50 to 55 percent of the EU's total internal market, the report said.</p>
<p>The Commission welcomed the arrival of start-up airlines on the market, pointing to a net gain of 20 companies during the last three years, with 60 failing out of 80 that began operations.</p>
<p>Most airlines returned to profit in 1995, the Commission said, a picture it hoped would further improve next April once full market deregulation comes into affect.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
