<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134076" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Steady French wheat prices ignore Chicago fall.</title>
<headline>Steady French wheat prices ignore Chicago fall.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French wheat prices were flat on Tuesday, ignoring Chicago's retreat below four dollars a bushel, as nervous buyers and sellers kept apart, traders said.</p>
<p>Buyers were said to be pulling back in the face of lower world prices while sellers were playing it more cautiously.</p>
<p>Rouen-delivered wheat was sought at 860 francs per tonne for October and 855 francs for November-December. January-March suppies were bid at 835 francs.</p>
<p>The prices exclude carrying charges of 3.64 francs per tonne which must be added for every half-month elapsing between August 1 and the delivery period in question.</p>
<p>Traders said prices were edging towards levels that would make it difficult to go further.</p>
<p>Algeria was seeking 75,000 tonnes of extra French or Argentine wheat for November/December shipment, they noted.</p>
<p>There was unconfirmed talk on Tuesday afternoon that Algeria had bought wheat from both countries earlier in the day.</p>
<p>The Chicago Board of Trade's nearby wheat futures contract fell below the key $4.00 per bushel level on Tuesday with the market hit by a hike on Australia's wheat crop forecasts.</p>
<p>December Chicago wheat was trading at $3.96 a bushel, down 4-1/2 cents, near the end of the European business day.</p>
<p>November Matif fob-barge wheat futures in Paris were up 10 francs a tonne at 860 francs on volume of 61 lots.</p>
<p>French cash maize slipped as dry weather allowed the harvest to continue but business was slack, traders said.</p>
<p>Prompt fob Atlantic maize fell five francs to 910 francs.</p>
<p>The national weather service predicted rain for Thursday in western France followed by showers everywhere on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
