<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134007" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Ogata urges halt as fighting spreads in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Ogata urges halt as fighting spreads in Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the United Nations refugee agency appealed on Tuesday to warring sides in Zaire's volatile eastern region to halt ethnic fighting which has sent 220,000 Burundi and Rwandan refugees fleeing for their lives.</p>
<p>Sadako Ogata, U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, said in a statement that worsening violence in eastern Zaire could degenerate into a &quot;humanitarian catastrophe&quot;.</p>
<p>The Geneva-based agency also had unconfirmed reports that troubles had spread north to the Goma region along the Rwandan border, with reports of Rwandan Hutu refugees fleeing attacks by armed men.</p>
<p>Fighting had reportedly erupted around the three biggest camps near Goma, which have a total population of 510,000 Rwandan Hutus. Thousands of Rwandans had fled Kibumba camp, according to UNHCR, which cited Zairean military reports.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, nearly a quarter of a million refugees, including 143,000 Burundi and 75,000 Rwandans, who fled fighting near camps in Uvira at the weekend are believed to be hiding in the surrounding hills or heading north toward Bukavu.</p>
<p>&quot;I am deeply worried by the widening scale of violence in eastern Zaire in recent weeks that has once again sent tens of thousands of refugees -- women, children, sick and elderly -- fleeing for their lives,&quot; Ogata said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Unless all parties to this conflict step back, we are, I am afraid, heading toward a humanitarian catastrophe.</p>
<p>Ogata said: &quot;I thus appeal to all sides to halt the violence immediately and avoid another humanitarian disaster in a region that has already suffered enough.&quot;</p>
<p>The refugees fleeing Kibumba, the second largest camp in Zaire, seemed to be heading for Goma, according to the UNHCR spokesman. He did not know whether any refugees had fled Katale and Kahindo camps, where fighting was also reported between the Zairean army and Tutsi rebels.</p>
<p>Many among the refugees killed or watched others kill during 1994's Hutu-led genocide of more than half a million Tutsis and Hutu moderates in Rwanda and fear reprisals if they go home.</p>
<p>Eastern Zaire is a hodgepodge of rival ethnic groups. In Masisi region near Goma, hundreds of people have been killed in recent months in a worsening conflict between native Zairean tribes, ethnic Tutsis and Hutus.</p>
<p>&quot;Fighting has been reported around three of the biggest refugee camps in all of eastern Zaire, in the Goma region,&quot; the spokesman, Ron Redmond, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We now have reports that thousands of refugees are fleeing Kibumba camp,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't confirm the reports, but we are taking them very seriously as they come from the military...If it is true, it is very alarming.&quot;</p>
<p>The sprawling Kibumba camp, located some 25 kms (15 miles) northeast of Goma and blanketing a mountain valley next to Rwanda's borders, has a population of 194,000 Rwandans. Katale has some 202,000 refugees while Kahindo has some 112,000.</p>
<p>Earlier, Redmond expressed concern over Uvira.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation has now deteriorated to such an extent that we are almost back to an emergency phase like we were facing in 1994,&quot; he told a news briefing.</p>
<p>The agency was making contingency plans to receive 75,000 of the refugees in existing camps in the Bukavu area, 75 kms (50 miles) north of Uvira. About 3,000 Rwandans have already shown up at Nyangezi-Mulwa camp there.</p>
<p>UNHCR had reports of a column of 10,000 refugees on the road heading for Bukavu. Zairean troops were meeting the refugees at Nyantende and directing them to camps west of Bukavu, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
