<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134058" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Schiphol leads cargo traffic growth rates.</title>
<headline>Schiphol leads cargo traffic growth rates.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amsterdam's Schiphol airport recorded the highest percentage gain in cargo traffic last month among the EU's top cargo-handling airports, figures issued by the Paris airports authority, Aeroports de Paris (ADP) showed.</p>
<p>Schipol's cargo traffic in September 1996 totalled 87,200 tonnes, up 8.9 percent on the same month in 1995.</p>
<p>The three London airports (Heathrow, Gatwick and Stansted) handled 119,600 tonnes of cargo traffic last month, a rise of 5.5 percent on September 1995.</p>
<p>Frankfurt airport handled 114,500 tonnes in September, up 5.1 percent on the same month last year.</p>
<p>Last month's cargo volumet at the Paris airports (Charles de Gaulle and Orly) grew by four percent on September 1995 at 95,126 tonnes.</p>
<p>Of the EU's top four cargo-handling airports, Amsterdam also recorded the highest percentage gain in cargo traffic in the first nine months of 1996 with volume rising by 11 percent to 781,600 tonnes.</p>
<p>January-September 1996 cargo traffic handled at the London airports totalled 1,053,800 tonnes, up five percent on 1995 levels.</p>
<p>Frankfurt Jan-Sept cargo volume was 951,100 tonnes, up 2.5 percent on the same period last year.</p>
<p>Jan-Sept 1996 traffic at the Paris airports declined by 0.4 percent to 815,915 tonnes compared with last year. - Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
