<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134001" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish parties clash in parliament on EMU budget.</title>
<headline>Spanish parties clash in parliament on EMU budget.</headline>
<byline>Joelle Diderich</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conservatives and Socialists clashed on Tuesday when parliament began debating a 1997 budget that will make or break Spain's chances of joining a European single currency -- and which is already assured a safe passage.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Rodrigo Rato, opening the three-day debate, urged the opposition Socialists to look for points of agreement with the government despite their promise to cast a minority vote with the Communists against the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;The Socialist group's position is important,&quot; Rato told parliament. &quot;I hope in the name of the government that at this time...we will be able to hear about the instruments they think are required for the common goal of cutting unemployment and joining the (EU) economic and monetary union.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I believe there can be concrete issues on which we can agree,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But replying to Rato's invitation, the Socialists' Jose Borrell accused the government of outright lies and said the budget package was inconsistent and full of false promises.</p>
<p>&quot;Your draft budget reflects the failure of all the false promises, easy demagogy, the swindles and the incoherencies you sow in your path,&quot; Borrell told Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar.</p>
<p>The Socialists and the Communist-led United Left have introduced motions rejecting the budget, but it is guaranteed a safe passage on the combined votes of the ruling conservatives, their Catalan nationalist allies and smaller regional parties.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, Aznar criticised his Socialist predecessor Felipe Gonzalez for deciding to skip the debate.</p>
<p>Aznar and his aides blamed disarray in Socialist ranks for the main opposition party's decision to give the floor to two of its top economic men rather than to Gonzalez.</p>
<p>&quot;Gonzalez's absence shows the opposition is incapable of providing an alternative,&quot; Aznar told reporters.</p>
<p>The Socialist leader's silence could fuel the arguments of foes to his right and to his left who say the same corruption scandals and charges of a &quot;dirty war&quot; on Basque rebels that cost him his job continue to gag him now he is in opposition.</p>
<p>Gonzalez, who ruled Spain for 13 years until May and was the architect of Spain's 1986 entry to the then European Community, rejected the government's criticism as meddling in his party.</p>
<p>&quot;We are the ones who decide our strategy and our participation and we allocate (tasks), not others,&quot; he told reporters before the debate began.</p>
<p>Aznar's ministers hope the austere budget package will allow them to meet stringent European economic and monetary union (EMU) criteria during 1997, the year on which would-be participants in the single currency will be tested for fitness.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget slashes total spending growth to just 1.7 percent by cutting or freezing outlays in all sectors except for pensions, health and regional transfers.</p>
<p>With inflation expected at 2.6 percent next year, it is the toughest budget since Spain's return to democracy in 1975.</p>
<p>Gonzalez has been an ardent supporter of EMU all along, but the Socialists argue that if Spain manages to be among a first wave of participants in 1999 on this budget it will be at the expense of employment and of social welfare.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
