<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134015" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Four in five French people unhappy with government.</title>
<headline>Four in five French people unhappy with government.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly four out of five French adults are unhappy with the way France is being run, the highest level since the 1993 general elections in which a centre-right coalition drove the Socialists from power, a poll said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Just 18 percent were satisfied with the government, according to the BVA survey for the weekly Paris Match magazine.</p>
<p>The BVA poll and a second survey by the CSA polling firm for the weekly La Vie found support for French President Jacques Chirac and Prime Minister Alain Juppe dropping to near-record lows.</p>
<p>According to the CSA poll, 38 percent of voters trusted Chirac to tackle the country's problems against 44 percent last month, while the BVA poll found that 35 percent had a favourable opinion of Chirac versus 40 percent a month earlier.</p>
<p>The scores were Chirac's worst since late 1995, when his popularity plummeted amid crippling public sector strikes over a welfare reform plan.</p>
<p>The CSA poll showed Juppe's standing slipping to 31 percent from 33 while the BVA poll said that Juppe was viewed favourably by just 24 percent versus 31 percent in September.</p>
<p>La Vie said the CSA poll showed the premier had dragged the head of state down for the first time since Chirac took office in May 1995, a poll said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The confidence rating of the president, which had managed with difficulty to stay between 40-45 percent, is being pulled down by the prime minister's fall,&quot; La Vie said. &quot;People had become used to saying that Chirac could continue having his unpopular prime minister take the weight of strict measures.&quot;</p>
<p>Juppe has come under fire for budget austerity and high unemployment.</p>
<p>Civil service unions staged a one-day strike last Thursday against feared job cuts, record unemployment of 12.6 percent and austerity policies aimed at enabling France to qualify for a single European currency from 1999.</p>
<p>The CSA poll questioned 1,011 voters on October 11-12 while the BVA survey was based on interviews with 924 individuals conducted between Thursday and Saturday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
