<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134070" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stock indices buoyed by banking sector.</title>
<headline>Madrid stock indices buoyed by banking sector.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stock indices reversed earlier losses to close higher on Tuesday as a surge in banking stocks outweighed losses in the electricity sector, traders said.</p>
<p>The General index rose 0.16 points, 0.04 percent, to 383.38. The Ibex-35 gained 0.80 points, 0.02 percent, to close at 4,403.41.</p>
<p>Traders said banks had received a boost as traders focussed on the quality of results from BBV and as money flowed in from electricity stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors have nowhere to go after the rise in electricals. People are now looking at what other sectors to go into, and they're taking a bit of money out of electricals and putting it into banks,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Strong banking performers included BBV which rose 120 pesetas to 6,170. Banco Zaragozano rose 25 pesetas to 2,545 after posting an 80 percent rise in net attributable profit to 2.813 billion pesetas in the first nine months to September 1996.</p>
<p>The tumble in the electricity sector saw Union Fenosa slide 16 pesetas to 873 and Endesa drop 140 pesetas to 8,080, in what traders saw as a small correction to recent heady gains.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the market, Telefonica rose 15 pesetas to 2,545 and Repsol dropped 20 pesetas to 4,470.</p>
<p>In the short term, traders said they would remain cautious and did not rule out the possibility of a short term correction in the market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
