<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134091" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: OLOs steady, few threats seen to current levels.</title>
<headline>OLOs steady, few threats seen to current levels.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds made more progress in the course of the afternoon and were expected to hold steady with dealers seeing few threats to current levels.</p>
<p>The market saw how light buying helped prices recover from early sogginess, partly on the back of the view that many institutionals were still holding cash and would have to commit funds before year-end, only just over two months away.</p>
<p>But there was little concrete news and little expected in the form of market-moving data, dealers said. &quot;For now that leaves us little room to move,&quot; said one. He saw the key 10-year spread over Bunds holding in an eight to 12 basis point range.  </p>
<p>The yield spread of the benchmark 2006 OLO over the equivalent Bund was at 11 bps at 1515 GMT, widening from Monday's 10 bps, as OLOs lagged Bunds on the way up.</p>
<p>Some early OLO outperformance had pushed the spread down to nine basis points this morning. &quot;The market should be relatively stable for the rest of the week,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was mainly the players playing the ranges,&quot; said a trader of the day's action, adding it had been the professionals who had been driving prices higher in recent weeks. Domestic end-investors had not been buying &quot;for a long time&quot; since there were no capital gains for them to realise.  </p>
<p>For one trader the market was overbought. &quot;It has gone up too far on the EMU convergence plays,&quot; he said, adding the absolute bottom for the spread had to be five bps.</p>
<p>&quot;Even on only a pure credit risk basis the spread should be at least 10 to 15 basis points,&quot; he said. &quot;Those who have been buying the spread (OLOs for Bunds) have only got a free option on a larger spread.&quot; He saw the yield differential widening out 25 to 30 bps, but gave no timeframe.</p>
<p>&quot;Belgium is too expensive relative to Germany, but as long as there are buyers...&quot; he said. On that basis there was scope for the yield on the benchmark OLO to slip below six percent.  </p>
<p>The OLO yielded 6.05 percent in late trade after 6.08 percent late on Monday. &quot;Six percent does not depend on us,&quot; he said, &quot;it depends on Germany.&quot; Bund yields could fall further, although there were political risks to the German market.</p>
<p>For Belgium too there were political risks. These, however, were very much in the background for now, he said, pointing to a potential flare-up over Belgian Treasury swap deals which were threatening to cost the government billions of francs.</p>
<p>There was also a chance of fresh public outrage if there were no concrete reforms of the justice system after news of bungling in two prominent investigations.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
