<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134028" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Koipe sees lower olive prices in Q1.</title>
<headline>Koipe sees lower olive prices in Q1.</headline>
<byline>Dominique Vidalon</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's biggest olive oil producer Koipe SA said on Tuesday that rocketing olive prices were set to ease in the early months of 1997 after the 1996/97 crop hit the market.</p>
<p>But prices may fall significantly by late spring, at which time producers will have a better idea of the prospects for the 1997/98 crop, a senior company official told Reuters.</p>
<p>A five-year drought sent supplies to a 13-year low last year, driving prices to record highs.  </p>
<p>&quot;We hope that raw material (olive) prices will decline in the first quarter of 1997,&quot; foreign trade director Alex de Mendiola said in an interview at a Paris food fair.</p>
<p>The bulk of the olive harvest starts in December-January, though pickings begin as early as November.</p>
<p>&quot;Raw material prices will decline in December-January and the situation will further improve in May-June when the new crop will be in bloom and its potential can be assessed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Spain normally produces 550,000 to 650,000 tonnes of olives per year, supplying a third of world olive oil.  </p>
<p>But devastating drought cut the 1995/96 crop to some 270-280,000 tonnes, driving oil prices to record highs of 750 pesetas a litre in 1996 from 380-400 pesetas in October 1995, he said.</p>
<p>As a result domestic olive oil consumption fell by an estimated 40 to 50 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Spain's farm ministry predicted in August the new 1996/97 (November-October)  crop would recover to reach some 550,000 tonnes. A more ample olive supply is expected to put some pressure on prices and help boost demand.  </p>
<p>Koipe, which controls a third of the Spanish olive oil market, was severely hit by the crisis. It is a 66.3 percent owned unit of Franco-Italian food giant Eridania Beghin-Say, which has 16 percent of the world olive oil market.</p>
<p>Falling demand hit Koipe's sales volumes while margins were squeezed as it was unable to fully pass on to consumers a sharp rise in raw material prices.</p>
<p>Olive oil producers had initially feared consumers would switch to cheaper alternatives like sunflower oil. But Spaniards, for whom olive oil is a staple, just cut down consumption, De Mendiola said.  </p>
<p>Export sales are also expected to rise next year as demand picks up in key markets such as France, he said.</p>
<p>Importers of Spanish olive oil built up stocks in late 1995 in anticipation of a poor crop in Spain, enabling them to limit imports in the first half of 1996, but stocks are running low and demand is picking up.</p>
<p>At the end of June, Koipe's olive oil exports were down 20 percent in volume over last year but the company hopes to maintain export volume at the 1995 level of 20,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Provided prices do start easing in 1997, Koipe hopes to boost exports to between 25,000 and 35,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Olive oil sales accounted for 70 percent and olive oil exports for 10 percent of its 1995 group turnover of 110 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
