<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134056" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission urges greater tax coordination.</title>
<headline>Commission urges greater tax coordination.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission made a fresh call on Tuesday for greater coordination of national taxation policies in a bid to avoid tax arbitrage in the EU's single market and help create jobs.</p>
<p>But drawing the lesson from repeated failures in the past to get a single tax policy in the 15-nation European Union, European commissioner Mario Monti responsible for making the bloc's market work declined to propose new legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the Commission is concerned there is no point in spending time on proposals that will disappear,&quot; Monti told a news conference.</p>
<p>Instead, he proposed the creation of a tax policy group to work on better coordination of national tax systems.</p>
<p>There are currently almost 20 proposals blocked at the level of EU finance ministers including a plan to tax carbon dioxide emissions.</p>
<p>The lack of progress in the taxation field had also forced the Commission to withdraw as many as 30 proposals, Monti said. They include draft rules to avoid double taxation of royalty and interest payments between companies which are part of the same group but located in different EU states.</p>
<p>Although Monti shied away from saying that different tax levels, or no tax at all, effectively represented harmful tax competition, he did say the Commission would put forward the idea of a code of conduct on the issue.</p>
<p>The question of whether to harmonise taxation on capital gains -- on securities or bank deposits -- is the one which has best illustrated the debate on tax arbitrage with Germany and Belgium opposing neighbouring tax-haven Luxembourg.</p>
<p>The Commission's report also stresses that the constant rise over the years of taxation on labour --  which is proportional to a decrease on fiscal revenues from capital -- considerably undermines the chances of reducing the bloc's huge unemployment.</p>
<p>The report, addressed to EU finance ministers, says that the average tax rate on salary income rose to 40.5 percent in 1994 from 34.7 percent in 1980.</p>
<p>In the same period, taxation on other producing factors -- chiefly capital and self-employment -- dropped from 44.1 percent to 35.2 percent.</p>
<p>This is despite constantly growing unemployment since the early 80s to a current rate of 10.8 percent.</p>
<p>EU finance ministers have so far systematically prevented any significant progress in the taxation area. This will continue until the 15 EU states do away with the unanimous vote rule.</p>
<p>The report is expected to be discussed by finance ministers at their next meeting on November 11 before being forwarded to December's EU summit in Dublin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
