<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134023" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: East, West welcome Clinton's NATO speech.</title>
<headline>East, West welcome Clinton's NATO speech.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Cold War foes in western and eastern Europe welcomed President Bill Clinton's commitment on Tuesday to try and bring former communist states into NATO before the turn of the century.</p>
<p>Clinton's announcement in a key-note speech in Detroit, home to thousands of voters of east European stock, that he wanted the Atlantic Alliance to admit new members by 1999 was the first time he has publicly backed a target date.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome it for the very simple reason that U.S. leadership in NATO has been and will be an indispensable element of European security,&quot; Andrzej Krzeczunowicz, Poland's ambassador to NATO, told Reuters.</p>
<p>NATO officials said enlargement would now be a main plank of Clinton's foreign policy if he is elected for a second term in the November 5 U.S. presidential election as seems likely.</p>
<p>&quot;The prestige of the White House is now behind the project, and in the alliance -- as in much else -- once the U.S. goes ahead, others follow,&quot; said one official at the alliance's Brussels headquarters.</p>
<p>Speaking at a campaign rally, Clinton said he wanted to restate America's goal of admitting a first wave of countries &quot;by 1999 -- NATO's 50th anniversary and 10 years after the fall of the Berlin Wall&quot;.</p>
<p>He did not name any countries nor give a date for a heads of state summit next year at which countries will be invited to start membership negotiations, but critically he said the doors would stay open after the first new members were accepted.</p>
<p>&quot;This will encourage those countries that do not make the first round,&quot; another alliance official said.</p>
<p>Several countries, fearing they could be left in a vacuum while NATO seeks to clinch a new deal with Russia after a limited enlargement, have been pushing for assurances they can join at a later stage as their young democracies evolve.</p>
<p>Juri Luik, Estonia's ambassador to NATO, welcomed the speech saying it showed the U.S. intended to remain committed to the continent despite the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>&quot;It is extremely important, it promises an international commitment and U.S. involvement in eastern Europe,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>In Bucharest, President Ion Iliescu's spokesman also welcomed the speech.</p>
<p>&quot;We hail all political statements and all steps taken regarding NATO's expansion,&quot; Traian Chebeleu told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be among the first countries admitted to the alliance, in which we see a pillar of security and a guarantee for further democratic development, above all in Romania.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia reacted cautiously, but sacked security chief Alexander Lebed dismissed Clinton's comments as pre-election posturing.</p>
<p>&quot;(Clinton's comments) are just a pre-election statement, a kind of pre-election posturing,&quot; Lebed told Reuters.</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday,the Russian foreign ministry said it needed to see the details of Clinton's speech before commenting, but it signalled that its opposition to NATO's expansion had not softened.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's attitude to NATO's expansion has not changed,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Gennady Tarasov told a regular news briefing a few hours before Clinton delivered his speech.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
