<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134074" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French government popularity at low ebb-poll.</title>
<headline>French government popularity at low ebb-poll.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Less than a fifth of France's adult population are happy about the way their country is being run, according to a public opinion poll published on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The result was the lowest level of voter satisfaction since a centre-right coalition scored a resounding victory in the 1993 general election and replaced a Socialist government.</p>
<p>Just 18 percent of those polled were satisfied with the government, the BVA group survey carried out for the weekly magazine Paris Match found.</p>
<p>The BVA poll and a second survey, carried out by the CSA polling firm for the weekly La Vie, showed support for French President Jacques Chirac and Prime Minister Alain Juppe at near-record lows.</p>
<p>The CSA poll questioned 1,011 voters on October 11 and 12 while the BVA survey was based on interviews with 924 individuals conducted between Thursday and Saturday last week.</p>
<p>According to the CSA poll, 38 percent of voters trusted Chirac to tackle the country's problems against 44 percent last month, while the BVA poll found that 35 percent had a favourable opinion of Chirac compared with 40 percent a month earlier.</p>
<p>The scores were Chirac's worst since late 1995, when his popularity plunged amid crippling public sector strikes over plans to reform welfare benefits.</p>
<p>The CSA poll showed Juppe's standing slipping to 31 percent from 33 while the BVA poll said that Juppe was viewed favourably by just 24 percent versus 31 percent in September.</p>
<p>La Vie said the CSA poll showed the premier had dragged the head of state down for the first time since Chirac took office in May 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The confidence rating of the president, which had managed with difficulty to stay between 40-45 percent, is being pulled down by the prime minister's fall,&quot; La Vie said. &quot;People had become used to saying that Chirac could continue having his unpopular prime minister take the weight of strict measures.&quot;</p>
<p>Juppe has faced sharp public criticism for his austerity budgets and rising unemployment.</p>
<p>Civil service unions staged a one-day strike last Thursday against feared job cuts, a record unemployment rate of 12.6 percent and austerity policies aimed at enabling France to qualify to take part in a planned single European Union currency from 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
