<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134005" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Prodi sees Italy making EMU in 1999 - paper.</title>
<headline>Prodi sees Italy making EMU in 1999 - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi said he was convinced Italy will be among the first countries to join the single European currency and that the lira would be back in Europe's exchange rate mechanism as soon as possible.</p>
<p>In an interview with Wednesday's Die Welt newspaper, Prodi said German Chancellor Helmut Kohl would support Italy's bid.</p>
<p>&quot;We can profit from tHe presence of this German chancellor,&quot; Prodi said. &quot;He is such a strong personality. He can push Europe forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Prodi, who met Kohl in Bonn last week, said he and Kohl were both &quot;very concerned&quot; that a gap could emerge in Europe if Italy were not among the first EMU countries in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that Italy will make it, even if a difficult road lies ahead,&quot; he said. &quot;The future of Italy lies in Europe. At the same time, I am convinced that Europe would not be complete without Italy.&quot;</p>
<p>Prodi said he could offer no date when Italy would rejoin the exchange rate mechanism of the European Monetary System.</p>
<p>&quot;But because the return of Italy depends on negotiations, it is important that these are started as soon as possible. The faster we pass our budget law, the sooner we can start negotiations for a return to the ERM.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday, a German government spokeswoman said Germany supports Italy's efforts to join the single European currency but a decision on which nations will be founding members will be determined by objective criteria.</p>
<p>She declined to comment on Prodi's remarks in the Il Sole 24 Ore newspaper. He said that Kohl wants Italy in the first wave of countries joining the EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Those nations that fulfill the objective criteria will take part,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has always recognised Italy's efforts to save and consolidate its budgets,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Prodi said even if some sectors of German public opinion wanted to keep Italy out Kohl did not support them.</p>
<p>On Monday in Potsdam, Bundesbank council member Klaus-Dieter Kuehbacher said Italy should not take part in currency union from the beginning because it failed to meet the fiscal requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;The Italians want to get in, but they shouldn't get in,&quot; Kuehbacher, also president of the Berlin-Brandenburg state central bank, said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
