<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13411" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bombardier unveils ultra-long-range executive jet.</title>
<headline>Bombardier unveils ultra-long-range executive jet.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Edmonds</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Against the backdrop of a thousand choristers chanting a wordless corporate hymn, Bombardier Inc. on Monday unveiled its Global Express business jet -- a luxury aircraft the transportation and aerospace giant says will fly faster and farther than any in its class.</p>
<p>The sleek 99.5-foot (30.33 meter) long, US$34 million boardroom with wings will be able to travel 6,500 nautical miles -- halfway around the world -- without hitting the gas pumps and will be capable of reaching a top speed of 0.88 mach.</p>
<p>If it were configured like a commercial passenger jet, it would hold 50 passengers. But the luxurious appointments and boardroom in the sky mean the jet can only carry eight favoured business people and four crew members.</p>
<p>While Bombardier admits it is making a hefty bet on the specialised high-end executive jet market niche, it is sharing the risk with several global partners.</p>
<p>Company executives told reporters they were confident the wager will be a winning one.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very key programme and I would say all of these programmes are key,&quot; said Laurent Beaudoin, chairman and chief executive of Bombardier.</p>
<p>Bombardier, the fourth-biggest civil aviation company in the world and a leader in the executive jet category, has come a long way from its roots as a snowmobile manufacturer.</p>
<p>Beaudoin is the son-in-law of Joseph-Armand Bombardier, inventor of the Ski-Doo snowmobile and founder of the Montreal-based company.</p>
<p>He said this year marks the 10th anniversary of Bombardier's entry into the aerospace business with its purchase of the foundering Canadair.</p>
<p>The canny purchases of troubled Short Brothers in Belfast, Northern Ireland, Learjet of Kansas City and de Havilland in Toronto in the ensuing years catapulted it into the top ranks of civil aircraft manufacturers.</p>
<p>Robert Brown, president and chief executive of Bombardier Aerospace, told reporters the company already has 52 firm orders for its newest business jet, which flies at a maximum altitude of 51,000 feet. But it must sell at least 100 to break even.</p>
<p>Brown said the programme is on schedule, on budget and looks likely to fulfil all the expectations Bombardier had when it announced plans to build such a jet in 1991.</p>
<p>The Global Express, which sat gleaming white on a stage at the de Havilland plant in Downsview, is the product of a C$800 million ($588 million) investment by Bombardier and its co-developers.</p>
<p>Japan's Mitsubishi Heavy Industries; BMW Rolls-Royce, a joint venture based in Germany; Honeywell, Parker Bertea Aerospace and AlliedSignal Aerospace of the United States; Lucas Aerospace and Messier-Dowty International of the United Kingdom; and Sextant Avionique and Liebherr-Aerospace-Toulouse of France will invest C$400 million ($294 million) of the amount.</p>
<p>&quot;It is virtually a G-7 project,&quot; said Prime Minister Jean Chretien, who along with Ontario Premier Michael Harris helped launch the plane before 2,100 guests.</p>
<p>The partnership allows Bombardier to split the risk and also gives the suppliers a strong incentive to keep costs low because they benefit from increased sales.</p>
<p>Bombardier's newest aircraft will make its virgin flight in the next few days. It will then be shipped to Witchita, Kansas, where it will undergo a flight testing and certification programme.</p>
<p>Shipping will begin in the fourth quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The Global Express' only competition is the Gulfstream V aircraft, which has a comparable range and will beat the Global Express out of the hangar by about a year.</p>
<p>But Beaudoin noted that Gulfstream has only 11 more orders than the Global Express. Of the 63 firm orders for the Gulfstream V, 33 of those involve trade-ins of the Gulfstream V's predecessor, the Gulfstream VI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
