<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134142" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German court sentences ex-DG Bank trader to jail.</title>
<headline>German court sentences ex-DG Bank trader to jail.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A German court on Tuesday sentenced the former head bond dealer of DG Bank to five and a half years in jail for breach of trust, ending a mammoth trial which arose from a billion-mark ($650 million) trading scandal.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt district court found Friedrich Steil, 55, guilty of breach of trust for misuse of company funds relating to bond trades he conducted on his own account and at the bank's expense between 1987 and 1990.</p>
<p>Three other former traders at the bank, the central clearing bank for Germany's co-operative banks, were given suspended jail sentences of between 18 and 24 months.</p>
<p>The three-and-a-half year trial, one of Germany's longest-running financial cases, was linked to bond deals in the 1980s which plunged DG Bank into crisis, caused top executives to resign and led to a deep restructuring.</p>
<p>DG Bank lost 800 million marks as a result of write-downs when bond deals worth six billion marks it conducted with 25 French banks turned sour.</p>
<p>The deals were so controversial that they at one point looked set to upset Germany's financial relations with France.</p>
<p>But the part of the case relating to the French bond deals was shelved in 1995 and Tuesday's sentences relate only to trades the defendants did on their own account. Prosecutors said those deals alone cost DG Bank 40 million marks.</p>
<p>Throughout the trial, Steil insisted he was innocent and that management board members had been aware of and approved his actions.</p>
<p>Steil's sentence fell short of the prosecution's demand for a jail term of seven years and nine months. He has already spent 38 months in custody.</p>
<p>Following the scandal, several DG Bank executives resigned as it became clear that the bank's internal supervision system had failed to send out early warning signals that dubious transactions were under way.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Helmut Guthardt stepped down in 1991 after his reputation was shaken by the scandal. The bonds had been sold to the French banks with the promise to buy them back at a future date.</p>
<p>DG Bank bitterly disputed the validity of the unwritten pacts to repurchase the German government bonds whose market value had fallen considerably in the wake of a general market slump. The bank said that it had been the victim of criminal actions.</p>
<p>But in 1990 DG Bank gave in to pressure from the French banks and agreed to the buy-back. The French banks involved included Caisse des Depots et Consignations, Banque Nationale de Paris and Cie Financiere de Paribas unit Credit du Nord.</p>
<p>The bond writedowns caused DG Bank's profit to slump in 1991 and led to a financial restructuring which has since been completed.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.533 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
