<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134171" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Reclusive Taleban leader vows to defend Kabul.</title>
<headline>Reclusive Taleban leader vows to defend Kabul.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of Afghanistan's radical Islamic Taleban militia vowed on Tuesday to defend Kabul against ousted government forces led by Ahmad Shah Masood.</p>
<p>In his first interview since the Taleban captured Kabul on September 27, Mullah Mohammad Omar dismissed demands of an anti-Taleban alliance for the capital to be demilitarised.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forces are not in Kabul,&quot; the 38-year-old leader told the Afghan Islamic Press (AIP) agency. &quot;All our forces are outside, defending the city. Police control security in Kabul.&quot;</p>
<p>Omar, wearing a black turban, was sitting in a small room in the southern city of Kandahar, where he has had his headquarters since the Taleban burst on the Afghan scene two years ago.</p>
<p>The Pakistan-based AIP quoted Omar as saying he accepted proposals to form a joint commission comprising Taleban and opposing factions to monitor a ceasefire.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't reject a guarantor role for the United Nations and the Organisation of Islamic Conference,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>However, he said his Sunni Moslem militants would fight to hold on to the city they captured on September 27.</p>
<p>&quot;The Rabbani government was illegal and not Islamic, but defended Kabul for several years,&quot; he said, referring to ousted President Burhanuddin Rabbani. &quot;We will strongly defend Kabul.&quot;</p>
<p>Anti-Taleban factions led by northern Uzbek militia chief General Abdul Rashid Dostum on Tuesday demanded that the capital be demilitarised as a condition for any ceasefire.</p>
<p>Pakistani Interior Minister Naseerullah Babar, who has been trying to broker a truce, said in Islamabad he remained hopeful that a ceasefire agreement could be worked out soon.</p>
<p>Omar urged Rabbani and his allies in the ousted government, Gulbuddin Hekmatyar and Abdurrab Rasul Sayyaf, to give up all government property&quot; -- a reference to military equipment -- and &quot;cut their relations with people who are against Islam&quot;.</p>
<p>He appeared to be asking the three men to shun Dostum, a former communist general, but did not name him. He made no mention of Masood, now the Taleban's main battlefield foe.</p>
<p>Omar, who rarely meets visiting dignitaries let alone journalists, said the extent of Dostum's military involvement against the Taleban would become clear in the future.</p>
<p>Dostum has moved forces in support of Masood's men near frontlines north of Kabul, but witnesses say he appears to have stopped short of committing them in battle.</p>
<p>Omar, who lost his right eye while fighting against the former Soviet occupation of Afghanistan, appeared relaxed and confident, reminiscing with his companions about their experiences during the anti-Soviet struggle in the 1980s.</p>
<p>He said the Taleban, seeking to impose a purist version of Islamic Sharia law throughout Afghanistan, were not opposed to education for women, but time and a strong central government were needed before the modalities could be worked out.</p>
<p>&quot;In Islam it is a responsibility for men and women to have knowledge of Islam and we are not against that,&quot; he said. &quot;But the ulema (religious scholars) must work out the details.&quot;</p>
<p>He said women were needed to work in the medical sector and some other areas which he did not specify.</p>
<p>The Taleban have drawn international criticism since their seizure of Kabul for actions that have effectively banned most women from working and most girls from going to school.</p>
<p>Omar said the Taleban, or religious scholars originally recruited at Islamic colleges in Pakistan, were opposed to the narcotics trade, but could not immediately ban opium-growing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have already ordered that there should be no hashish in the country and have destroyed several heroin factories in Spin Boldak and Chattu (near the Pakistani border),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he had ordered the Taleban to stop large-scale movement of opium on main roads, but added: &quot;We cannot stop opium-growing now, though we are against it. We must go step by step because the people are poor and they need an alternative.&quot;</p>
<p>Afghanistan is the world's leading producer of raw opium, from which heroin is made, and has also gained a reputation as a haven for armed Islamic militants from around the Moslem world.</p>
<p>&quot;Islam does not want people to be killed,&quot; Omar said. &quot;If someone enters a country with that country's permission, it does not give him the right to kill people or set off bombs.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We allow refugees in our country, but do not give any military training,&quot; he added. &quot;But as an Islamic movement, we support all oppressed Moslems in the world.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
