<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134192" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Delhi shares end higher on new credit policy.</title>
<headline>Delhi shares end higher on new credit policy.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices on the Delhi Stock Exchange (DSE) closed sharply higher as speculators and investors made heavy purchases following the news of the new monetary policy which eased credit, brokers said.</p>
<p>The bourse's benchmark index closed 16.35 points or 2.30 percent higher at 725.69.  </p>
<p>Traders said price rise was also aided by speculators who squared positions amid rising prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The sudden jump in share prices was mainly influenced by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI), as it allowed banks to increase their investment to 10 percent in equities,&quot; said Sunil Prabhakar of brokers Spurt Equities.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the RBI announced a two-percentage point cut in the cash reserve ratio of banks to 10 percent, effective in four stages over the next four months.</p>
<p>The central bank also cut the ceiling on interest for bank deposits for maturities of 30 days to one year to 10 percent from 11 percent.</p>
<p>The announcements came as part of the monetary policy for the second half of the 1996/97 (April-March) financial year.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries was up 10.05 rupees, or 5.34 percent, to 206.70 rupees on heavy buying by financial institutions, brokers said.</p>
<p>Larsen and Toubro shot up 20.95 rupees, or 8.96 percent, to 234 rupees on mutual fund buying as speculators covered short positions.</p>
<p>State Bank of India jumped 11.05 rupees to 228.60.</p>
<p>Hindustan Lever quoted 15 rupees higher at 810.</p>
<p>ITC rose 7.10 rupees to 310.10.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
