<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134115" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish company joins bid to save Russian forest.</title>
<headline>Finnish company joins bid to save Russian forest.</headline>
<byline>Ilkka Virtanen</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Enso Oy, Finland's biggest timber buyer in Russia, said on Tuesday it would suspend timber harvesting in a large area of Russia as part of an effort to preserve fragile old-growth forests.</p>
<p>The company, which has come under fierce attack from consumers especially in Germany concerned about destruction of old-growth forests, also said it would work with environmental groups to chart the forests' environmental values.</p>
<p>The one-year moratorium would cover an area of almost two million hectares (five million acres) in Carelia and Murmansk, equivalent to more than half of the Netherlands, Enso said.</p>
<p>Enso said in a statement it would form a working group by the end of January next year to classify the forests in the Russian republic of Carelia, which borders Finland.</p>
<p>&quot;Stock will then be taken of the forest areas which should be preserved,&quot; the company said. It said the move was its initiative with the Finnish and German World Wildlife Fund (WWF) and the Finnish conservation association.</p>
<p>The working group will take three to five years to develop final criteria for &quot;an economically viable and sustainable forestry for Carelia&quot;, Enso said.</p>
<p>&quot;Enso will organise a moratorium for all regions which have so far been regarded by the WWF and (environmental pressure group) Greenpeace as being worthy of preservation,&quot; Enso said.</p>
<p>It said it had stopped renewing import contracts for the regions, with the last due to expire in December, and that the moratorium would also apply to all its sub-contracted wood suppliers.</p>
<p>Enso said it is currently importing 600,000 to 800,000 cubic metres of wood from the region, paying over $27 million annually for the wood, and it would continue to import wood from other areas in Carelia and Murmansk to cushion the economic blow.</p>
<p>The volume imported represents about 10 percent of Carelia's export volume in a structurally weak economy, Enso said.</p>
<p>&quot;As we are working on these matters together with at least two Finnish environmental organisations, I expect this will have impact on all our markets,&quot; senior executive vice-president Juhani Pohjolainen said at a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not lost any sales due to these discussions, but of course, in the long run, we have to take care that Enso product can be sold also to a critical consumer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the moratorium would not have a major impact on Enso's wood supply: Enso plans to import about four million cubic metres of wood in 1996, of which about three million cubic metres are expected to be purchased in Russia.</p>
<p>But a Greenpeace representative said the scheme was not enough: one year may well not be enough time for the group to search the area properly, he said, calling on Enso to completely halt timber cuttings in old-growth forests.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll join in the cheering as soon as Enso stops cutting old-growth forests,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
