<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134152" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: OPINION-BOMBAY STOCKS INDEX WEEKLY TECHNICAL OUTLOOK.</title>
<headline>OPINION-BOMBAY STOCKS INDEX WEEKLY TECHNICAL OUTLOOK.</headline>
<text>
<p>WEEKLY TECHNICAL OUTLOOK - By Dharmesh Rajdev, analyst</p>
<p>at SMIFS Securities. Reuters carries a weekly technical analysis by Rajdev on the 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange sensitive index (sensex).</p>
<p>							    -----oOo-----</p>
<p>CREDIT POLICY -- MUCH NEEDED BOOST</p>
<p>The credit policy gave a much needed impetus to the stock market at least on an immediate term and market is expected to perform better during the week.</p>
<p>On the other side, the sentiment of the market has been lacklustre during the last week. The sensex moved within a band of 100 points of 3065-3165 mark.</p>
<p>Prior to this the sensex has touched a bottom of 2930. From here a sharp bear covering coupled with investment buying by LIC and other domestic mutual funds took the sensex up by 245 points to touch the mark of 3175 and lately the sensex was trading in the band of 3075 to 3175.</p>
<p>SENSEX UNLIKELY TO CROSS RETRACEMENT LEVEL</p>
<p>Thus by now, the sensex has almost retraced its entire upmove from 2825 touched in January 1996 to the peak of 4130 in June 1996 -- it has almost come a full circle.</p>
<p>Now, the current fall from 4130 to 2930 has been of 1200 points. If one considers 2930 to be a very strong base, then this down move can be retraced up to 38.2 percent or 50 percent or 61.8 percent depending on the strength of the move.</p>
<p>This retracement level works out at 3388, 3530 and 3666.6.</p>
<p>Considering the current strength of the move it seems quite unlikely that the sensex can cross the retracement level of 38.27 i.e. 3388 at one go. Thus this mark itself will offer a strong resistance.</p>
<p>During the last fortnight the sensex opened at 3101.27 and went down to touch the low of 2930.93 on October 8. From here it bounced back to touch the high of 3176.97 on October 11.</p>
<p>At this level, some profit taking forced the index a bit down to touch 3,068.50 before closing the week at 3,130.21 on October 18.</p>
<p>SHORT-TERM INDICATOR</p>
<p>At this juncture the short term fast weekly stochastic oscillator is place at 27.77 with its trigger at 22.88. Here the indicator has just crossed the trigger from below and is confirming the current rally in the market.</p>
<p>MEDIUM-TERM INDICATOR</p>
<p>While the medium term weekly slow stochastic oscillator is placed at 13.71 with its trigger at 11.93. Here also the indicator has cut the trigger from below and is about to come out of the oversold zone. This also corraborates the continuation of current rally.</p>
<p>The nine weeks moving average on &quot;High&quot; is placed at 3,388 and is falling while 9 weeks moving average on lows is at 3,239.64. The sensex is below these averages and on ascent sensex is expected to face resistance at these levels.</p>
<p>The eight weeks moving average is at 3,296 with upper Bollinger Brand at 3,590 and lower Bollinger Band at 3,010.</p>
<p>During last week, the sensex pierced the lower Bollinger Band. Hence it is expected to touch the eight weeks moving average on the upside.</p>
<p>On ascent, sensex will face resistance at 3240-3315 band, while support lasts at 3075-3165 band. The sensex will move upward strongly if it closes above 3,315 mark.</p>
<p>(The opinions expressed in this article reflect the views of the author only. They should not be taken as reflecting the views of Reuters)</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
