<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134110" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: MEPs demand more funds for cultural heritage.</title>
<headline>MEPs demand more funds for cultural heritage.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Parliament insisted on Tuesday that the European Union should devote 86 million Ecus over the next four years to protecting and restoring Europe's cultural heritage.</p>
<p>MEPs said they would endorse a programme which will encourage the member states to cooperate on cultural projects but only if EU cultural ministers reverse their decision to axe the scheme's budget to 30 million Ecus.</p>
<p>When they gave the Raphael programme -- COM(95)110 -- a first reading in October 1995, they said the 70-million-Ecu budget originally proposed by the European Commission was insufficient and voted to raise it by more than a third to 96 million Ecus.</p>
<p>Instead of accepting the demand, the Culture Council decided in July to chop the funding by more than 50 percent.</p>
<p>On the advice of Spanish Socialist Francisco Javier Sanz Fernandez, the parliament's rapporteur on Raphael, Euro-MPs voted to reinstate their budget demand, minus the sum of 10 million Ecus, which was spent on pilot projects during 1996.</p>
<p>Since the programme needs the support of both parliament and Council to come into effect, conciliation talks between the two institutions now appear likely.</p>
<p>Sanz Fernandez told Reuters parliament would stick to its guns for three reasons.</p>
<p>&quot;Investments in cultural heritage give European citizens a more positive idea of Europe -- something which is more than the single currency and the internal market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Secondly, the programme creates jobs, which is one of the EU's essential goals.</p>
<p>&quot;And thirdly, it promotes cultural tourism in regions which are behind in their economic development.&quot;</p>
<p>Rafael should provide funding for four types of project:</p>
<p>- joint preservation projects, such as the restoration of the Parthenon</p>
<p>- exchange of information between professionals working on similar themes</p>
<p>- making cultural heritage more accessible to the public (including using videos and CD-rom, handbooks and multilingual presentations), especially to disadvantaged sectors of society</p>
<p>- cooperation on cultural projects with third countries and international organisations like UNESCO.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
