<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134173" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan opposition criticises economic package.</title>
<headline>Pakistan opposition criticises economic package.</headline>
<byline>Tahir Ikram</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's main opposition party said spending cuts and extra taxes announced on Tuesday under an IMF-approved rescue package would fuel inflation.</p>
<p>The tax measures along with the devaluation of the rupee will further escalate inflation, said former Finance Minister Sartaj Aziz, Secretary-General of the Pakistan Muslim League.</p>
<p>All the government will achieve after imposing so much misery and hardship on the people is to avoid an economic crisis for a few more weeks, Aziz told Reuters.</p>
<p>State (central) Bank of Pakistan Governor Muhammad Yaqub earlier devalued the rupee 7.86 percent against the dollar, raised the repo rate to 20 percent from 17 and outlined new steps to reform the economy and avert a foreign exchange crisis.</p>
<p>While this mini-budget may persuade the International Monetary Fund to initiate negotiations for another standby arrangement, the third in three years, it will not solve the basic problems facing the economy, Aziz said.</p>
<p>As a result, any new IMF standby is likely to collapse in the next few months, like the previous two arrangements.</p>
<p>The IMF has delayed disbursements of a $600 million standby loan agreed last December because Pakistan failed to meet agreed targets. An IMF team is due here on Thursday to review the Economy before the Fund decides whether to make more payments.</p>
<p>Under IMF pressure, Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's three-year-old government has taken drastic action to try to bridge Pakistan's yawning budget and current account deficits.</p>
<p>The government plans to narrow the budget deficit by 40 billion rupees ($995 million) through spending cuts and additional taxes in 1996/97 (July-June).</p>
<p>Aziz said the government would be unable to meet the IMF demand that it cut the deficit to four percent of gross domestic product because the new measures would cripple the economy.</p>
<p>He said the 20 billion rupee cut in development expenditure announced by Yaqub would increase unemployment.</p>
<p>Lahore-based businessman Shahid Amin said the package and the devaluation would drive up prices across the board. &quot;These are very drastic measures,&quot; he said. &quot;God have mercy on us.&quot;</p>
<p>Amin said the devaluation might provide a short-term stimulus to exports, but its long-term impact would be negative because most local industries relied on imported raw materials.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
