<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134134" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki stocks firm, strength holds in Merita.</title>
<headline>Helsinki stocks firm, strength holds in Merita.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares ended another solid session ahead after a hesitant start on Tuesday, the pace mounting during the day as Merita continued to rally, Nokia rose and there was renewed interest in forestries, brokers said.</p>
<p>The HEX index ended up 0.5 percent at 2,265.49 after again grazing year-high levels, with total volume a solid 480 million markka, quite well spread but boosted by an in-house transfer. Nokia was calm, ending up 1.40 markka at 216.00.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had some domestic and foreign clients seeing a number of shares are now again attractively priced,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>In his view this did not refer to recently strong Merita, but other brokers saw more upside in the bank: &quot;It will go and see what 15.00 markka feels like, then we'll see,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Another agreed, but said at around 15-16 markka Merita's appeal may be dampened by the weight of its property portfolio.</p>
<p>Finnish property markets remain in the doldrums despite a marked economic recovery from the depths of the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Forestries were boosted by encouraging profits from Canadian and U.S. paper companies, although many brokers were still bearish on the outlook for Finnish forestries next year.</p>
<p>&quot;If U.S. growth falls short of expectations, there may be extra supply from there to Europe,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Enso ended up 0.30 markka at 35.70 after its January-August results came in line with expectations, but failed to raise much interest. Metsa-Serla was the liveliest with over 50 million markka volume, picking up 0.10 markka to close at 33.00.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Huhtamaki continued to ease in fairly solid trade amid profit-taking after it surged on Friday's news of an asset-swap with Hershey.</p>
<p>Raision Tehtaat picked up sharp gains but in relatively thin volume after it said it would buy a leading Swedish margarine maker, which also gave it a marketing channel for its cholesterol reducing margarine.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors really liked this,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Total volume was boosted by Kesko's internal transfer of a 26 percent holding in Merita controlled real-estate firm Citycon from its recently acquired Tuko subsidiary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
