<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134100" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Pakhoed still sees profit in oil storage.</title>
<headline>Pakhoed still sees profit in oil storage.</headline>
<dateline>ROTTERDAM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch tank storage and shipping group Pakhoed NV said on Tuesday they could revive profits in their oil storing operations despite a futures market that provides little or no incentive for companies to store oil.</p>
<p>&quot;The first thing in line is to reduce the cost and, further down the line, reposition the business. The futures market may change, but we cannot rely on it to change,&quot; said Pakhoed chairman, Klaas Westdijk.</p>
<p>Pakhoed's response to sagging profits is a large-scale reorganisation plan, centred in the Rotterdam area and the company envisages no selling or scrapping of tank capacity.</p>
<p>Repositioning the business may involve a greater presence than now in the Asia Pacific region and Pakhoed said it expected a gradually increasing contribution from investments there.</p>
<p>While profits have fallen from tank storage in Europe, they have been stable elsewhere. Backwardation, when prompt prices are more expensive than futures, has hit storage companies like Pakhoed hard, particularly in traditional European markets.</p>
<p>Storage levels of oil products held by independent companies in the ARA area are currently about 20 percent below year-ago levels. Excluding essential stock requirements, enforced by the Dutch government, the inventories are 35-40 percent down.</p>
<p>Pakhoed's oil storage sector has experienced sagging profits since the start of the decade. Profits from oil storage dropped from 70 million guilders in 1991 to 25 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The poor state of the oil storage business has continued to dent overall profits in tank storage in the first half of this year. For European tank storage as a whole, including chemicals, the company made 26.5 million guilders in profit against 47.5 million in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>-- Philip Blenkinsop, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROTTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
