<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134108" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: FOCUS-Elkem says profit dip special case.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Elkem says profit dip special case.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian metals and materials group Elkem ASA on Tuesday blamed special conditions for a 48 percent slump in operating profits in the third quarter compared with the second.</p>
<p>The company booked third-quarter operating profits of 161 million crowns ($24.78 million), 148 million lower than in the second quarter and 115 million crowns down from the corresponding year-ago period.</p>
<p>Elkem said that discounting the effect in the second quarter of a bankruptcy compensation case over quartz mining company Minnor, the difference between second and third quarter operating results was 118 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The substantial reduction in profitability, compared with the second quarter, is due in part to conditions that were special to the third quarter, namely a shortfall in captive power production, a writedown of ferrochrome inventories and seasonally low sales volumes for several of the company's main products,&quot; a company statement said.</p>
<p>For the first nine months of the year profits before tax edged higher to 737 million versus 733 million, while operating profits rose five percent to 813 million crowns.</p>
<p>Elkem said a shortfall in captive power production, due to exceptionally light precipitation last winter and low reservoir levels for hydropower generation, had added 80 million crowns to the group's expenses for the first nine months of 1995.</p>
<p>A continuation of high power costs in the longer term could have an impact on the scope of operations at some Norwegian plants, it said.</p>
<p>Third-quarter operating profits for ferrosilicon slipped 22 percent to 69 million crowns from the second quarter due to a seasonal downturn in volumes, especially for foundry products. Prices in Norwegian crowns were stable, Elkem said.</p>
<p>But average prices for manganese alloys declined by around three percent from the second quarter to the third and continued to fall in the fourth quarter, it said.</p>
<p>Operating profits in manganese and chrome tumbled to 19 million crowns from 87 million crowns in the second quarter and from 118 million crowns in a year ago.</p>
<p>Elkem said demand for ferrochrome remained weak. Prices fell 20 percent from the second quarter and were 40 percent lower than in fourth quarter of 1995. &quot;The fall in prices necessitated a further writedown of inventories, which contributed to the loss recorded by this operation in the period.&quot;</p>
<p>The company has closed ferrochrome output at the Rana plant until January 1, 1997 due to the difficult market situation.</p>
<p>In the materials group , the market for silicon remained strong with prices rising slightly from the second quarter. The division booked an operating result of 93 million crowns versus 102 million.</p>
<p>($1=6.498 Norwegian Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
