<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134124" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU warns Belgium on Electrabel contracts.</title>
<headline>EU warns Belgium on Electrabel contracts.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission has issued a fresh warning to the Belgian government about Belgian electricity producer Electrabel's plan to lock local authorities into exclusive long-term electricity supply contracts, Commission sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The sources said European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert had written to the Belgian federal government last week after it became clear that the interested parties were going back on promises made before the summer aimed at correcting anti-competitive provisions in the contracts.</p>
<p>Early this year, privately owned Electrabel offered the so-called &quot;intercommunales&quot; -- joint ventures of municipalities for electricity distribution -- the chance to acquire five percent of its capital in return for signing long-term distribution contracts.</p>
<p>Van Miert told reporters recently the Commission would probably accept contracts lasting no more than 15 years, from Electrabel's initial desire to sign up the distributors for up to 30 years.</p>
<p>But the Belgian authorities still had to commit themselves to the 15-year contract length and clarify a number of questions regarding, in particular, the ability for local authorities to end the contracts with Electrabel and find another supplier.</p>
<p>Electricity production and distribution in the EU is still to a large extent in the hands of public monopolies, but there is an agreement for a partial and gradual opening of the market to competition.</p>
<p>Belgium, together with France, has been one of the strongest opponents to the liberalisation move.</p>
<p>The Commission sources said that the Flemish regional minister for housing and internal affairs Leo Peeters had agreed in a letter to the Commission to the principle of 15-year contracts. But this must still be cast in stone, the sources said.</p>
<p>The Commission was also seeking further information on the intercommunales stake in Electrabel, they said.</p>
<p>The Commission can prohibit Electrabel from going ahead with the contracts if it fails to make the necessary modifications to bring them in line with EU fair competition rules.</p>
<p>-- Brussels newsroom 322 2876841</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
