<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134197" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka lifts curbs on Tamils' travel south.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka lifts curbs on Tamils' travel south.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Sri Lankan military on Tuesday lifted restrictions on the entry of minority Tamil civilians into government-controlled areas from the rebel-held north, a military spokesman said.</p>
<p>Another military official who wished not to be identified said the government's intention was partly to curb the flow of Tamil refugees to India.</p>
<p>&quot;Now people can come to Vavuniya, buy provisions and return to their homes without too much of a hassle. It alone should be a good incentive for keeping them from becoming refugees in India,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western aid agencies say about 2,000 Tamils have sought refuge in southern India during the past two months to escape fighting between Tamil rebels and government forces.</p>
<p>&quot;All restrictions on people coming to Vavuniya have been lifted from today,&quot; the military spokesman said. &quot;Already about 3,000 people have made use of this and come to Vavuniya.&quot;</p>
<p>Vavuniya, 220 km (135 miles) north of the capital Colombo, is the gateway to the northern Wanni district, stronghold of Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) guerrillas, who are fighting for independence in the island's north and east.</p>
<p>The town contrasts sharply with the war-ravaged Wanni, its shops brimming with consumer goods which are hard to come by further north.</p>
<p>In addition to shopping, northerners converge on Vavuniya to travel south to Colombo for business, studies and work.</p>
<p>The government placed restrictions on northerners flooding to Vavuniya claiming that often the rebels managed to mingle with civilians and infiltrate the south.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear if the government was prepared to allow northerners to travel freely to Colombo.</p>
<p>The government says more than 50,000 people have died in the ethnic war, now in its 14th year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
