<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134182" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan unveils tough IMF-agreed reforms.</title>
<headline>Pakistan unveils tough IMF-agreed reforms.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan will slash spending and impose extra taxes under a tough IMF-approved plan to stabilise and reform the economy, State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) governor Muhammad Yaqub said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He was unveiling harsh measures approved by Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's three-year-old government to try to avert a possible foreign exchange crisis and bridge Pakistan's yawning budget and current account deficits.</p>
<p>Yaqub told a news conference the government would narrow the budget deficit by 40 billion rupees ($995 million) through spending cuts and additional taxes in 1996/97 (July-June).</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the central bank devalued the rupee 7.86 percent against the dollar and raised its key repurchase (repo) discount rate to 20 percent a year from 17 percent.</p>
<p>Yaqub said the devaluation was designed to encourage foreign remittances and boost foreign currency deposits which he said had declined due to rumours about the health of the economy.</p>
<p>He said the package had the blessing of the International Monetary Fund, which has withheld disbursements of a $600 million standby loan that were due in June and September.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF has accepted it (the package) as the basis to restore the presently suspended standby arrangement and it may in the long run lay the foundation of a new ESAF (enhanced structural adjustment facility) arrangement, probably beginning by next fiscal year,&quot; Yaqub said.</p>
<p>An IMF team is due in Pakistan on Thursday for an economic review that must be completed before payments can be resumed.</p>
<p>The IMF has insisted that Pakistan reduce its 1996/97 budget deficit to four percent of gross domestic product from anywhere between five and six percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Pakistan's foreign reserves, excluding gold, stood at $1.13 billion in September, compared with $1.52 billion a year earlier, but had sunk to $831 million by October 3, SBP figures show.</p>
<p>Yaqub said 20 to 21 billion rupees would be slashed from &quot;less essential&quot; development expenditure, while six to seven billion rupees would be cut from current spending. No cuts were made in allocations for defence and debt servicing.</p>
<p>He said more than 13 billion rupees would be raised from additional tax measures, including two billion rupees from an agricultural income tax to be levied by the four provinces.</p>
<p>All oil product prices had been increased by 10 percent with immediate effect, Yaqub added.</p>
<p>In Islamabad, the Central Board of Revenue (CBR) said it was imposing a 10 percent central excise duty on gas supplied to domestic and industrial consumers, except fertiliser plants.</p>
<p>It raised withholding tax on supplies to government departments and limited companies to 3.5 percent of their value from 2.5 percent. But the tax would continue to be charged at one percent on supplies of cotton, rice, wool, hides and skins, while cotton seed supplies would remain exempt.</p>
<p>The CBR said a two percent service charge had been introduced on imports that are subject to pre-shipment inspection to cover costs previously borne by the government.</p>
<p>It said withholding tax on imports had been increased to five percent from four percent, while a foreign travel tax had been raised to 1,500 rupees per ticket from 1,000.</p>
<p>Sales tax on newspapers, drugs and medicines had been withdrawn completely, the statement said.</p>
<p>The CBR statement said all the changes had been made under a presidential ordinance and took immediate effect.</p>
<p>($1 = 40.22)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
