<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134147" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Fighting continues among warring Afghan factions.</title>
<headline>Fighting continues among warring Afghan factions.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Wagstaff</byline>
<dateline>NEAR HUSSEIN KOT, Afghanistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghan forces arrayed against the fundamentalist Taleban militia have begun moving up armour and artillery in apparent preparation for an attempt to seize the heights above Kabul.</p>
<p>At the United Nations in New York, meanwhile, the Security Council unanimously called on Tuesday for a ceasefire and political negotiations to end the conflict.</p>
<p>In an obvious reference to the Taleban radicals who captured the Afghan capital last month, the council resolution denounced what it said was discrimination against women.</p>
<p>The Taleban have forbidden women to work or study.</p>
<p>In Washington, the U.S. State Department said it had postponed a plan to send an envoy to Kabul to talk to the Taleban because of the renewed fighting north of the city.</p>
<p>On the battlefield itself, the warring factions each claimed gains on the plains north of Kabul, but there was little sign the front-line had moved much either way.</p>
<p>The mainly Pushtun Taleban fighters, who control three-quarters of the country, said earlier they had traded rocket and artillery fire with forces of Ahmad Shah Masood, military chief in the ousted government of President Burhanuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>The Taleban said they had driven Masood's mainly Tajik forces from villages west of Hussein Kot, 18 km (11 miles) north of Kabul, and captured 150 prisoners.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent Chris Bird reported from Bagram, 35 km (22 miles) north of Kabul, that armour, artillery and hundreds of troops had reinforced Masood forces,</p>
<p>Trucks packed with fighters belonging to powerful northern Uzbek chief General Abdul Rashid Dostum also drove towards the front-line, with rocket-propelled grenade launchers, rifle barrels and bayonets pointing skywards, he said.</p>
<p>Everywhere along the front, Masood's fighters said they expected to be involved in a big and imminent attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We have orders to move forward and take the pass,&quot; Sabir (one name), a Masood commander in Hussein Kot told reporters.</p>
<p>Masood forces said they had taken hills west of the Khair Khana pass which leads into the capital, but there was no sign of fighting there on Tuesday morning and afternoon.</p>
<p>Taleban fighters who rocketed the village of Kareez Mir, west of the road to Kabul and some 10 km (seven miles) from the city's edge, said they had dislodged Masood commander Mullah Taj Mohammad from the area earlier in the day.</p>
<p>No independent confirmation was available.</p>
<p>Masood has in the past 10 days reversed a Taleban offensive on his Panjsher Valley stronghold and taken positions within rocket range of the city, including Bagram military airbase.</p>
<p>The Taleban meanwhile have been reinforced by an influx of fighters from other provinces.</p>
<p>Pakistan, which has denied accusations it backs the Taleban, said it was still hopeful for a ceasefire despite veiled criticism from U.N. Afghan envoy Norbert Holl and differing conditions set by both sides.</p>
<p>The Taleban want an exchange of prisoners while Masood has called for Kabul to be demilitarised -- a demand in which he was joined by other factions siding with him, including Dostum.</p>
<p>The Afghan factions against the Taleban also demanded that United Nations forces be deployed in Kabul to keep the peace.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no ceasefire agreement with the Taleban unless the conditions are met,&quot; said a Dostum spokesman. &quot;If the Taleban give a negative reply, that means war will continue.&quot;</p>
<p>The demands followed a meeting in the northern town of Mazar-i-Sharif of 155 commanders who elected Dostum as president of a Supreme Defence Council alliance, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The leader of the Taleban vowed from his headquarters in the southwestern city of Kandahar that he would defend Kabul.</p>
<p>Mullah Mohammad Omar also dismissed demands of an anti-Taleban alliance for the capital to be demilitarised.</p>
<p>&quot;We will strongly defend Kabul,&quot; the 38-year-old leader told the Pakistan-based Afghan Islamic Press (AIP) agency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEAR HUSSEIN KOT, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
