<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134154" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Masood forces head for strategic pass above Kabul.</title>
<headline>Masood forces head for strategic pass above Kabul.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>WITH MASOOD'S FORCES, HUSSEIN KOT VILLAGE, Afghanistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forces loyal to ousted Afghan government chief Ahmad Shah Masood were fighting their way towards the strategic Khair Khana pass on Tuesday on the main road into the Afghan capital.</p>
<p>&quot;We have orders to move forward and take the pass,&quot; Sabir (one name), one of Masood's commanders in the frontline village of Hussein Kot, 15 km (10 miles) north of Kabul, told reporters.</p>
<p>He said fighting overnight had dislodged forces belonging to the radical Islamic Taleban from the west side of the pass but said the Taleban, who captured Kabul late last month, still controlled the main road.</p>
<p>Other Masood fighters said the Taleban, a kilometre (half a mile) south of the command post, had two tanks up on the hill.</p>
<p>A shell crashed a few metres (yards) behind Sabir's control post, sending up a large cloud of yellow dust. One of his tanks made a deafening reply.</p>
<p>On the other side of the front-line, Reuters correspondent Patrick de Noirmont reported earlier on Tuesday that Taleban fighters poured rockets into positions held by Masood to the north and in villages to the west.</p>
<p>Doubt about where the front line is on maps has led to confusion over whether Hussein Kot was in Masood's or Taleban hands.</p>
<p>Some locals said the name applied to a string of villages along the road, parts of which may be held by each side.</p>
<p>Morale was high among Masood's forces.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps we will take Khair Khana tonight,&quot; said Faisal Ahmad, 18, wearing a long brown shirt over his combat trousers and leaning on a rocket-propelled grenade launcher.</p>
<p>The pass is important because it would give Masood's Jamiat-i-Islami army command of the heights along the main road into Kabul.</p>
<p>Masood made a lightning advance against the Taleban last week, pushing the militia back down through the flat territory south of the crucial Salang Pass.</p>
<p>But this week, attempts to negotiate a ceasefire and the Taleban's strong positions in a further cluster of mountains north of Kabul have slowed Masood down.</p>
<p>Further up the road beyond the command post, smoke rose from the charred wreckage of a Mercedes bus, hit by a rocket earlier on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Two boys were badly wounded,&quot; said Mahmud Hojon, a doctor at a crumbling field hospital in Hussein Kot. He said the other passengers had managed to escape the bus when a rocket landed nearby minutes earlier.</p>
<p>The doctor said a total of 12 people had been wounded overnight but he knew of no dead.</p>
<p>Hojon shook his head and clicked his tongue with disapproval as he watched shells whacking up the dust in the foothills around Khair Khana through the white iron gates of his hospital. Heavy cannon fire made a low, intermittent boom around the base of the mountains.</p>
<p>Back from Hussein Kot, a tank prepared to lumber off down to the front, a bunch of yellow marigolds stuffed into its barrel, while a second tank rumbled forward trailing a cloud of black diesel smoke.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WITH MASOOD'S FORCES, HUSSEIN KOT VILLAGE, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
