<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134106" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares regained ground near the close to end at the day's high, but dealers said trade was thin. The AEX share index added 0.68 points to 593.11.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch was the main outperformer throughout the day, rising 3.20 guilders to 294.30. Dealers said there was more to come after today's record close for the oil giant.</p>
<p>Shell Oil in the U.S. which posted record third quarter net income boosted the stock, but dealers said there was also support from a strong demand for Royal Dutch call options.</p>
<p>Philips dipped further ahead of the firm's third quarter results on Thursday, shedding 0.30 to 59.00 guilders.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is getting nervous as the release of Philip's third quarter results gets closer,&quot; said one dealer, adding there was quite a strong demand for put options.</p>
<p>The volume was high overall but strongest in the November put at a strike of 57.50 guilders and the January 50.00 guilder put. &quot;The market is hedging the risk since it is not clear what Thursday might bring,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Philips said last week that it no longer expected an improvement in operating profits in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the overall market would remain upbeat, despite some profit-taking seen today.  </p>
<p>&quot;I foresee more growth for Royal Dutch. Oce-van der Grinten, Ahold, DSM and Akzo Nobel will soon recover from today's dip,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Ahold slipped 1.20 guilders to 101.50, Oce shed 2.50 guilders to 182.00 and DSM dipped 3.70 guilders to 164.80.</p>
<p>Tank storage and shipping group Pakhoed gained 0.80 guilders to 53.00 after the firm said it was positioned for profit growth and would raise its capital base by at least 300 million guilders.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 fax #1 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
