<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134119" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Superga sees return to profit in 1996.</title>
<headline>Italy's Superga sees return to profit in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Superga Spa, the Italian sports shoe company controlled by financial services group Sopaf, will return to profit this year and plans a stock market listing by 1999, vice-chairman Carlo Mammola said.</p>
<p>&quot;This year has been a turning point and Superga will show a profit for 1996,&quot; he told reporters without elaborating.</p>
<p>Turnover this year was forecast at 120 billion lire against 104 billion in 1995, with a gross operating margin of 9.5 percent against 0.4 percent.</p>
<p>The Turin-based company said cash flow was 8.0 billion lire in the black against a negative 6.8 billion last year. The workforce had been cut to 172 from 307.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial situation is steady,&quot; said Mammola, adding that debt of 70 billion lire did not take into account the possible sale of its French Eider unit and a large unused part of its Turin headquarters.</p>
<p>Divestments, for which there were already contacts, should bring in 30 billion lire, he said.</p>
<p>A widescale reorganisation and product refocusing programme including price cuts on basic shoe models should also bear fruit this year, said Superga managing director Franco Bosisio.</p>
<p>Superga hoped to open up new shops either owned or franchised, reinforcing its presence abroad, and starting production under licence of new lines like sun glasses, perfumes and accessories.</p>
<p>The company aimed for a turnover of 210 billion lire and a gross operating profit of 42 billion lire in 1999.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
