<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134198" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan rupee devaluation seen boosting inflation.</title>
<headline>Pakistan rupee devaluation seen boosting inflation.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's central bank devalued the rupee and raised interest rates on Tuesday, drawing criticism from analysts who saw the moves as inflationary.</p>
<p>The State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) devalued the rupee 7.86 percent against the dollar and raised its repurchase (repo) discount rate to 20 percent a year from 17 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said both actions seemed to be part of a rescue package agreed with the International Monetary Fund and due to be unveiled later on Tuesday by SBP governor Muhammad Yaqub.</p>
<p>&quot;The devaluation will help the government offset the impact of import demand...But this will be at the cost of an additional cost-push inflationary impulse,&quot; Abid Naqvi, head of research at Taurus Securities, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pakistan ran a trade deficit of $3.07 billion in 1995/96 compared with $2.26 billion the previous year.</p>
<p>Official figures show the consumer price index rising 9.83 percent in September year-on-year against 12.49 percent a year earlier. Unofficial estimates say inflation is much higher.</p>
<p>The IMF, concerned about Pakistan's large current account deficit and shrinking foreign reserves, wants Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's government to reduce its budget deficit to four percent of gross domestic product in 1996/97 (July-June) from between five and six percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>An IMF team is due in Pakistan on Thursday for a review of the economy that must be completed before the fund will release any more money from a stalled  $600 million standby loan.</p>
<p>Naqvi said the devaluation would hit industries relying on imported raw material and machinery, while the higher repo rate would put upward pressure on all lending rates.</p>
<p>&quot;An increase in lending rates at a time when businesses are already complaining of high financial costs will further erode corporate profitability and decelerate growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analyst Arshad Arif at Ing Baring Securities said the devaluation was likely to trigger increases in fuel and energy prices, dealing a blow to company profits across the board.</p>
<p>&quot;We think the recent devaluation addresses the trade deficit problem aggressively, but will increase costs for industries dependent on imported raw material,&quot; Arif said.</p>
<p>Nauman Sheikh, analyst at Kasb Co, said the government would have to slash spending and borrowing from the banking sector to avert the inflationary impact of devaluation.</p>
<p>&quot;We are likely to see more restrictions on credit and money supply in the coming days,&quot; Sheikh said.</p>
<p>A foreign banker, who asked not to be named, said raising the repo rate seemed to be part of a central bank strategy to dampen corporate demand for credit, as banks now charging borrowers around 18 percent would raise their lending rates.</p>
<p>But higher interest rates would place extra strain on the government's domestic borrowing cost, he said.</p>
<p>Arif said devaluation might temporarily boost some energy and telecom stocks but its long-term impact would be negative.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect this event to adversely affect the market and we may see a five to seven percent downward movement in the very near term,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Karachi Stock Exchange 100-share index rose 29 points, or 2.12 percent, to end at 1,394.73. But dealers said the rally was speculative and likely to be short-lived.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
