<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13418" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German opposition rejects cuts, govt stands firm.</title>
<headline>German opposition rejects cuts, govt stands firm.</headline>
<byline>Ashley Seager</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's opposition Social Democrats (SPD) on Monday rejected a large chunk of Bonn's austerity package in a meeting of an arbitration committee of both houses of parliament.</p>
<p>But the government said it could, and would, override almost all the rejections next month in the lower house of parliament, using its so-called &quot;Chancellor Majority.&quot; It said it was determined to implement its austerity package as soon as possible and accused the SPD of cheap delaying tactics.</p>
<p>The SPD had signalled it would use its majority in the committee to reject proposed reductions in sick pay and workers' protection from firing and a raise in the pensionable age of women even though its objections could be overriden.</p>
<p>SPD parliamentary whip Peter Struck said he hoped the government would not be able to get a majority in the lower house on September 13 because some of its own members were opposed to some of the austerity measures.</p>
<p>Heribert Blens, chairman of the arbitration committee and a member of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), said there was no danger of this happening.</p>
<p>In the run-up to the meeting, the government and SPD had disagreed over the austerity package.</p>
<p>CDU General Secretary Peter Hintze said: &quot;(SPD leader) Oskar Lafontaine should use his energies not in these delaying tactics but should work constructively with us.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl unveiled the austerity plan in April. He aims to slash public spending by 50 billion marks ($33.84 billion) and social security spending by 20 billion next year to ensure Germany meets the entry requirements for the single European currency.</p>
<p>Of the 70 billion marks, well over half has been agreed on including the parts Bonn is currently pushing through despite SPD protest. Around 15 billion marks alone was saved through a moderate public sector wage deal.</p>
<p>While the SPD-dominated upper house of parliament, or Bundesrat, must be consulted on much of the package, it can only in reality block the parts related to tax and welfare changes which affect federal states' budgets directly.</p>
<p>SPD chief Lafontaine said just before the meeting: &quot;We are against attacks on sick pay, on workers' protection from firing and on pensions.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have the support of a majority of the population in this. The austerity package is an affront to employees and damages social cohesiveness,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the SPD would ensure a rise in child benefit would go ahead as planned in 1997. Kohl's government hopes to save three billion marks by delaying the hike by a year but the move requires upper house approval.</p>
<p>The arbitration committee rejected the delay and one side or the other will now have to call the committee again in about a month's time.</p>
<p>This coincides with the start of haggling over the 1997 tax bill which also requires upper house approval and where the SPD is determined to make a last stand against the austerity plans.</p>
<p>The lower house of parliament, or Bundestag, will hold a special session this Thursday where it will reject the conclusions of the arbitration committee, Blens said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
