<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134159" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - October 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - October 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Pakistani press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- The National Assembly (lower house) unanimously adopted a motion for the formation of a select committee which would draft a constitutional amendment bill to initiate the process of accountability of people holding public office.</p>
<p>- The rupee fell against the dollar in the kerb market amid massive demand for the dollar spurred by political uncertainty.</p>
<p>- The government has hired the services of a senior executive of Merrill Lynch, a U.S.-based brokerage firm, to act as an adviser in its talks with a delegation of the U.S.-based credit rating agency Moody's Investors' Services Inc.</p>
<p>- The retail prices of vegetable ghee and cooking oil have risen by three rupees.</p>
<p>- Pakistan, eager to build trade ties with oil-rich Central Asian states, has postponed the departure of a planned truck convoy to the Kazakh capital Almaty, an official said.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- The State (central) Bank of Pakistan is likely to withdraw exchange risk cover available to banks on private foreign currency deposits.</p>
<p>- Bank of America announced it had entered into agreements with two state-run banks to finance wheat imports worth up to $125 million by the government of Pakistan.</p>
<p>THE NEWS</p>
<p>- The United States and Pakistan have agreed to complete the process of delivering $370 million of military equipment, including three P-3C under the Brown Amendment by December 31.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's special envoy Zafar Hilaly arrived in Tehran with a letter for Iranian President Ali Akbar Rafsanjani. He met Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati for talks on regional issues, including Afghanistan.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
