<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134189" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India identifies states for oil palm cultivation.</title>
<headline>India identifies states for oil palm cultivation.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India, which started oil palm plantings in 1991, has identified 11 states to boost domestic palm oil production, a nutrition official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;About 150,000 to 200,000 tonnes of palm oil would be available domestically by the year 2010,&quot; said Umesh Kapil of the department of nutrition at the government-run All India Institute of Medical Sciences (AIIMS).</p>
<p>The government has set a target to plant 80,000 hectares of oilseed palm by 1996/97 (Nov-Oct).</p>
<p>Kapil told a news conference that oilseed palm had been planted over a 20,000 hectares and another 800,000 hectares was expected to be covered over the next 10 years.</p>
<p>India aims for self-sufficiency in edible oils. But due to rising consumption the country has had to import in recent years to meet domestic demand.</p>
<p>It is likely to import 1.25 million tonnes of edible oil in 1995/96 (Nov-Oct), 75 percent of which will be Malaysian palm oil, trade officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of Indian companies looking for joint ventures with Malaysian firms to produce palm oil,&quot; said Ashima Raheja, the Indian representative of the Malaysian Palm Oil Promotion Council (MPOPC).</p>
<p>Kapil said in India there was a wide variation in the intake of dietary fats between the rural and urban population.</p>
<p>He said a meeting was being organised in New Delhi later this month to review the nutritional aspects of dietary fats in relation to various diseases.</p>
<p>The event is being jointly organised by seven organisations including the Nutrition Society of India and the MPOPC.</p>
<p>-- Hari Ramachandran, New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
