<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134172" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan alliance demands demilitarisation of Kabul.</title>
<headline>Afghan alliance demands demilitarisation of Kabul.</headline>
<byline>Marie Frail</byline>
<dateline>MAZAR-I-SHARIF, Afghanistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghan factions opposed to the Taleban militia now ruling Kabul said on on Tuesday that the capital should be demilitarised before a Pakistani-proposed ceasefire can be agreed.</p>
<p>They also demanded that a U.N. peacekeeping force be deployed in Kabul to ensure security in the shattered city -- a suggestion already ruled out by the United Nations.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no ceasefire agreement with the Taleban unless the conditions are met,&quot; said a spokesman for northern Uzbek militia chief General Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Taleban give a negative reply, that means war will continue.&quot;</p>
<p>The spokesman, General Mohamed Youssef, said a meeting of about 155 commanders from anti-Taleban factions had elected Dostum as head of their new Supreme Defence Council alliance.</p>
<p>The demand for Kabul to be demilitarised had previously been voiced by Ahmad Shah Masood, military chief in the ousted government of President Burhannuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>Youssef made clear that the demand had the support of all anti-Taleban factions represented at Tuesday's meeting.</p>
<p>These included Dostum's Jumbish-i-Milli movement, the Shi'ite Moslem Hezb-i-Wahdat party and the Hezb-i-Islami party of ousted prime minister Gulbuddin Hekmatyar.</p>
<p>Taleban leaders have said their only condition for a ceasefire is an exchange of prisoners.</p>
<p>They also say that Kabul is already &quot;demilitarised&quot; because their fighters are all outside the city defending it against attack by Masood.</p>
<p>Pakistani Interior Minister Naseerullah Babar, who has been shuttling between the Dostum-held city of Mazar-i-Sharif and Taleban headquarters in Kandahar, said on Tuesday he was optimistic that a ceasefire agreement could be reached.</p>
<p>&quot;I am more than hopeful (for a ceasefire accord) because in principle they have all agreed,&quot; he said in Islamabad.</p>
<p>Youssef refused to say if Dostum, now an ally of his old rival Masood, planned to take part in the fighting that has been raging between the Taleban and Masood's men north of Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;If they (the Taleban) try to approach the north, we have to defend our position,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent Chris Bird reported from Bagram, 35 km (25 miles) north of Kabul, on Tuesday that armour, artillery and hundreds of troops had reinforced Masood forces, aiming apparently to try to wrest the strategic heights above Kabul from the Taleban.</p>
<p>Trucks full of fighters belonging to Dostum drove towards the front-line, with grenade launchers, gun barrels and bayonets pointing skywards, he reported.</p>
<p>Everywhere along the front, Masood's fighters said they expected to be involved in an imminent large attack.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAZAR-I-SHARIF, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
