<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134178" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Masood pushes for strategic heights above Kabul.</title>
<headline>Masood pushes for strategic heights above Kabul.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>BAGRAM, Afghanistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Armour, artillery and hundreds of troops reinforced a major attack on Tuesday by ousted Afghan government forces who aimed to wrest the strategic heights above Kabul from the Taleban militia.</p>
<p>Trucks brim full of fighters belonging to Uzbek chieftain General Abdul Rashid Dostum, with trademark moustaches and chequered turbans, drove towards the front line to join Afghan government commander Ahmad Shah Masood's troops.</p>
<p>Their vehicles bristled with grenade launchers, gun barrels and bayonets, pointing skywards.</p>
<p>Dostum had been one of the principal backers of a ceasefire proposal this week and has tried to keep his armed support for Masood as low key as possible.</p>
<p>His main commander, General Majid Ruzi, told reporters with a smile as he toured the front in his Russian-built jeep near Bagram, 35 km (25 miles) north of Kabul: &quot;They (Dostum troops) do not belong to us.&quot;</p>
<p>Everywhere along the front, Masood's fighters said they expected to be involved in a large attack late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have orders to move forward and take the pass,&quot; Sabir (one name), one of Masood's commanders in the village of Hussein Kot, 15 km (10 miles) north of Kabul, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps we will take Khair Khana (pass) tonight,&quot; said Faisal Ahmad, 18, wearing a long brown shirt over his combat trousers and leaning on a rocket-propelled grenade launcher.</p>
<p>A shell crashed in a few metres (yards) behind the control post where he stood, sending up a cloud of yellow dust.</p>
<p>The Khair Khana and De Sabz passes, through which two roads lead down into the north of the Afghan capital, would give Masood the strategic heights above Kabul.</p>
<p>But sources inside Masood's Jamiat-i-Islami faction said the radical Islamic Taleban militia, which took control of Kabul last month, had put up strong resistance on the two previous nights.</p>
<p>Ceasefire talks have also slowed last week's lightning advance by Masood through territory north of Kabul taken earlier this month by the Taleban.</p>
<p>Two ear-splitting roars announced the departure of Grad rockets, black darts with fiery tales, launched by government troops against Taleban positions to the south. Taleban forces hit back, shelling the two roads up to the pass.</p>
<p>In Hussein Kot, smoke rose from the charred carcass of a Mercedes bus, hit by a rocket earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Two boys were badly wounded,&quot; said Mahmud Hojon, a doctor at a crumbling field hospital in Hussein Kot. He said other passengers had managed to get out of the bus when another rocket landed nearby minutes earlier.</p>
<p>The doctor said a total of twelve people had been wounded overnight but said he knew of no dead. It was the only word on casualties</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGRAM, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
