<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134150" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian shares surge on easier credit policy.</title>
<headline>Indian shares surge on easier credit policy.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices across major Indian bourses rallied on Tuesday after a long weekend break, with a new credit policy buoying market sentiment, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentiment got a shot in the arm,&quot; said Bharat Dhanki at Vrajlal Dhanki, a Bombay-based broking firm.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the central bank cut cash reserve requirements of banks as part of its six-month 1996/97 (April-March) monetary policy and put pressure on high interest rates.</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) ended 96.92 points or 3.10 percent higher at 3,227.13, after soaring to 3,235.26.  </p>
<p>Indian stock exchanges were closed on Monday due to a national holiday.</p>
<p>Traders said the looser credit policy by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) gave some much-needed fizz to share prices.</p>
<p>Renewed buying by local punters and mutual funds drove up the market. &quot;There was heavy buying in index-linked stocks,&quot; Dhanki said.</p>
<p>The RBI announced a two-percentage point cut in the cash reserve ratios of banks to 10 percent, staggered in four stages over the next four months, releasing more than 85 billion rupees into the banking system.  </p>
<p>Analysts expect the uptrend to push the BSE index up by another 100 points, but see resistamce coming up.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall just because of the credit policy I don't see the fundamental situation changing, although it has improved the investment climate,&quot; Devesh Kumar, strategist at W.I. Carr said.</p>
<p>The 50-stock National Stock Exchange index rose 24.09 points to 919.09 and CRISIL 500-share index 14.98 points to 617.28.</p>
<p>SBI and Reliance rallied 10 rupees each, to 228.75 and 206.75 respectively. Bajaj Auto rose 32.50 rupees to 971.50, Indian Hotels 27.75 to 631.25, L&amp;T 19.0 to 234, Grasim 16.5 to 432.25, TELCO 8.0 to 430 and TISCO 2.75 to 175.25 at the BSE.</p>
<p>-- ANSHUMAN DAGA, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
