<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13413" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conseco buys insurance firms for more than $1.7 billion.</title>
<headline>Conseco buys insurance firms for more than $1.7 billion.</headline>
<dateline>CARMEL, Ind.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conseco Inc., the life insurer that has made a string of acquisitions, said Monday it would acquire two insurance companies and buy the rest of two others in deals worth more than $1.7 billion.</p>
<p>The transactions will sharpen Conseco's focus on serving the nation's ageing population and make it a major player in long-term and supplemental health care insurance and universal life insurance, officials and analysts said.</p>
<p>The Carmel, Ind.-based company said it agreed to acquire American Travellers Corp., which provides long-term care insurance, for $793 million in stock, and Capitol American Financial Corp., a provider of cancer insurance and other health coverage, for $650 milion in cash and stock.</p>
<p>It also said it plans to buy the stock of American Life Holdings that it does not already own for $165 million in cash and the rest of Bankers Life Holding Corp. for $117 million. American Life provides guaranteed investment contracts for retirement and Bankers Life provides supplemental health insurance products for senior citizens.</p>
<p>Analyst Seth Potter at Sands Brothers &amp; Co. said the acquisitions &quot;will give Conseco a lot of muscle, especially in long-term care.&quot;</p>
<p>Frederick Sandburg at Everen Securities said as those 45 to 60 years old continue ageing, demand for insurance in the markets targeted by Conseco will steadily rise.</p>
<p>&quot;After the transactions are completed, we will have a Number One position in long-term care&quot; insurance, Conseco Chairman Stephen Hilbert told reporters in a teleconference.</p>
<p>The deals will also make it the second biggest in universal life insurance, where the premiums and benefits are adjustable, behind State Farm Insurance, he said.</p>
<p>Investors applauded the announcements and Conseco's stock gained $2 to $44 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Hilbert said Conseco expects to realise savings of about $31 million from the transactions, which are expected to be completed by the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Savings will come mainly from consolidating data processing, investment management and other financial functions, he said, adding it was too early to gauge the extent of any staff cutbacks.</p>
<p>Some analysts have criticised the company for focusing too much on acquisitions and not enough on its finances.</p>
<p>But Hilbert, noting the industry was consolidating rapidly, said there was a misperception about its growth strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;Dig through the numbers and you'll find 60 percent of our growth has come from how we have taken those companies, created a better product line and broadened their distribution for internal growth,&quot; Hilbert said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to be looking at future transactions, but we're going to be very selective,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>After the transactions are completed, Conseco said it will have $30 billion of assets under management, $26 billion of assets on its balance sheet, $6.8 billion of annual premiums and revenues and more than $650 million of projected annual earnings.</p>
<p>Hilbert said the acquisitions were expected to boost the company's 1997 operating earnings.</p>
<p>American Travellers added $3.19 to $31.56 on Nasdaq market, Bankers Life Holding jumped $2.375 to $24.125 and Capitol American Financial jumped $9.875 to $34.875, both on the NYSE.</p>
<p>American Life was unchanged at $24 on Nasdaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARMEL, Ind."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
