<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134148" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Kashmir chief to help relatives of hostages.</title>
<headline>Kashmir chief to help relatives of hostages.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR, India 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new chief of India's Jammu and Kashmir state on Tuesday assured the relatives of three Westerners held by separatists that his government would &quot;leave no stone unturned&quot; in its search for the missing men.</p>
<p>&quot;Farooq Abdullah told families of the hostages that he and his goverment will extend full support in tracing the whereabouts of the captive tourists,&quot; K.B. Jandial, spokesman for the government of Jammu and Kashmir, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The chief minister told relatives of hostages that his government will leave no stone unturned in tracing their missing sons and husbands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The relatives of three of four tourists taken hostage in Kashmir 15 months ago broadcast emotional messages through a local radio station earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Hi Paul. If you can hear this, let me tell you Mom and friends send their love for you, and we hope to see you soon,&quot; Bob Wells said in a message to his son, Paul Wells, broadcast by All India Radio's Kashmir station.</p>
<p>Wells was seized in July 1995 along with fellow Briton Keith Mangan, American Donald Hutchings and German Dirk Hasert. Another hostage, American John Childs, escaped and the body of a sixth, Norwegian Hans Ostroe, was found beheaded.</p>
<p>Visiting Kashmir along with the senior Wells are Wells' girlfriend Catherine Mosley, Hutchings' wife Jane Schelly, Mangan's wife Julie and Mangan's parents, Charles and Mavis.</p>
<p>&quot;I am the girlfriend of Paul,&quot; Catherine Mosley said. &quot;Paul, if you can hear me, please be strong. I am waiting for you in hope that someday we will be back together forever.&quot;</p>
<p>The news editor of All India Radio in Srinagar, Ashok Handu, said the messages would be translated into Urdu so the Western tourists' captors might understand them.</p>
<p>A little known separatist group, Al-Faran, kidnapped the tourists. Indian authorities have not had contact with Al-Faran since last November, and diplomats have said they do not know if the Westerners are dead or alive.</p>
<p>Handu said the messages would be aired four times a day for the next month. &quot;It was all done on humanitarian grounds, and radio is the only way we can reach them,&quot; Handu said.</p>
<p>&quot;My son is held hostage in Kashmir,&quot; Charles Mangan said in a choked voice. &quot;If anyone has information please tell us. Keith be strong. We will soon be all together once again.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Don, please know that I love you very much,&quot; Jane Schelly said. &quot;You all are in the minds and in the hearts of very very many people.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sixteen months is too long for a mother,&quot; Keith Mangan's mother, Mavis, said. &quot;I would like to plead with you to pass on any information that can help us to get the hostages released.&quot;</p>
<p>The radio station broadcast a song recorded by Keith Mangan's uncle urging listeners to &quot;spare a thought for the hostages... it may help to set them free&quot;.</p>
<p>Kashmir has been the cause of two of the three wars India has fought with Pakistan since the nations gained independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>Since 1990, dozens of separatist groups in Kashmir, the only Moslem majority state in predominantly Hindu India, have been fighting for complete independence or merger with Pakistan. The violence has killed at least 20,000 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
