<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134193" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's tigers threatened with extinction - study.</title>
<headline>India's tigers threatened with extinction - study.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poachers are killing at least one Indian Bengal tiger a day, threatening the beast with extinction, an international wildlife protection agency said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The London-based Environmental Investigation Agency (EIA) said poaching for tiger bones used in Chinese medicine was responsible for the death of at least one tiger each day.</p>
<p>&quot;In India, the Royal Bengal tiger edges towards extinction because of a complete lack of political will to save it,&quot; the EIA said in a 37-page report released in the Indian capital.</p>
<p>EIA director David Currey released a letter to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda, signed by 34 international wildlife groups, urging him &quot;to reinstate real priority and political will in saving the last of India's wild tigers&quot;.</p>
<p>Officials with Project Tiger, a 24-year-old government programme in the Environment Ministry responsible for protecting the tiger population, were unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>Currey told Reuters his group estimated the Indian tiger population at around 2,500, below the government figure of about 3,750.</p>
<p>The EIA report was the second study in two months warning Indian officials that the nation's tiger, representing some two thirds of the world tiger population, faced extinction.</p>
<p>Last month a report by the independent Tiger Trust said the tigers could vanish in five years unless authorities cracked down on lucrative poaching. Like EIA, Tiger Trust estimated the current tiger population at about 2,500.</p>
<p>&quot;Poaching for bones for Chinese medicine, for skins, penises, teeth, and nails is responsible for the death of at least one tiger each day in India,&quot; the EIA study said.</p>
<p>The report said the main destination for tiger parts used in traditional medicines was China, but that there was a rapid increase in demand in Taiwan, Hong Kong, Japan and South Korea.</p>
<p>The EIA said the highest level Indian government body dealing with tigers, the Indian Board for Wildlife, had not met for eight years.</p>
<p>It called on the government to draw up an emergency plan to save the tiger, and urged the international community to provide financial support to ensure its success.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
