<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134177" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan offers banks 17 pct on forex deposits.</title>
<headline>Pakistan offers banks 17 pct on forex deposits.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The State (central) Bank of Pakistan (SBP) said on Tuesday it would offer a 17 percent annual return and other concessions to banks bringing in foreign currency deposits from abroad.</p>
<p>SBP Governor Muhammad Yaqub told a news conference banks placing foreign currency in a special deposit with the central bank by November 28 could earn a yield of 17 percent a year on an equivalent amount calculated in rupees.</p>
<p>These deposits will not be counted for the purpose of statutory cash reserve and statutory liquidity requirements, and the banks will not be asked to maintain the statutory requirements in respect of these deposits, an SBP statement said.</p>
<p>Yaqub said the move was aimed at encouraging forex inflows to shore up depleted reserves he said now stood at $756 million, excluding gold reserves of $800 million.</p>
<p>Forex reserves, excluding gold, stood at $831 million on October 3, SBP figures show.</p>
<p>Yaqub denied that Pakistan was close to defaulting on its foreign obligations, adding he had assured the IMF that an emergency loan was not needed for debt servicing.</p>
<p>Yaqub said he had also told the Fund that it could ease matters by releasing the next tranche of a $600 million standby loan in November. The IMF has held up payments of the standby loan because of dissatisfaction with Pakistan's economic policies.</p>
<p>Yaqub said Tuesday's 7.86 percent rupee devaluation against the dollar would have little impact on Pakistan's overall debt servicing cost.</p>
<p>He warned moneychangers that stern action would be taken against those found spreading rumours about the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
