<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134149" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, Russia oppose extremism at defence talks.</title>
<headline>India, Russia oppose extremism at defence talks.</headline>
<byline>Sunil Kataria</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov met Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda on Tuesday amid reports that New Delhi was ready to pay $1.8 billion for 40 warplanes.</p>
<p>Rodionov, who arrived in the Indian capital on Monday, was expected to sign a defence cooperation agreement during his three-day visit, the first by a Russian defence minister to India, officials said.</p>
<p>The Indian government released a statement saying Deve Gowda and Rodionov discussed bilateral issues as well as the regional situation.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister and the visiting dignitary expressed their opposition to fundamentalist and extreme forces and called upon all countries to desist from interference in the other internal affairs of other countries in the region,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The statement did not mention the countries involved. However, India has accused Pakistan of backing the purist Islamic Taleban movement which captured the Afghan capital Kabul last month.</p>
<p>Pakistan is trying to broker a peace agreement between the Taleban militia and forces loyal to ousted government military commander Ahmad Shah Masood.</p>
<p>Russia has expressed concern over strife in Afghanistan, which neighbours the central Asian republics.</p>
<p>Rodionov also met Indian Defence Minister Mulayam Singh Yadav and held wide-ranging talks, the Defence Ministry said.</p>
<p>Before Rodionov arrived New Delhi on Monday at the start of his three-day visit, Itar-Tass news agency said India had confirmed its intention to buy 40 multi-purpose Sukhoi Su-30 jets for a total of $1.8 billion.</p>
<p>The Press Trust of India (PTI) said the deal was expected to figure in Rodionov's talks.</p>
<p>But a Russian embassy official said the visiting minister was not expected to sign a warplane deal. &quot;The visiting minister cannot sign the agreement on the sale of planes as that involves more than one organisation,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Rodionov was expected to sign a defence cooperation agreement during his visit, the first since the collapse of the Soviet Union by a Russian defence minister, officials said.</p>
<p>As the former Soviet Union's main non-communist ally, India was one of Moscow's biggest arms clients.</p>
<p>PTI said India was also interested in buying MSTA-S self-propelled howitzer guns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
