<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134116" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FOCUS-ABB profit rises as expected.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-ABB profit rises as expected.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG, one of the world's largest electrical engineering groups, on Tuesday reported a 24 percent rise in nine-month net profit, largely in line with market expectations.</p>
<p>Chief executive Percy Barnevik said he expected business to remain tough next year before showing a substantial jump in 1998.</p>
<p>But an old worry of industry analysts -- the health of its high-profile power generation business -- resurfaced as the company reduced its expectations for that segment's earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;There are little problems but nothing that should be overemphasised,&quot; said Peter Knox of Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>This year and next ABB, created by the merger of Sweden's Asea AB and Switzerland's BBC Brown Boveri AG in 1988, is suffering from the effects of Western Europe's sluggish economy. But it has still been able to raise profits as it expands into the growth markets of Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1997 we have to look for a more tough year with respect to demand,&quot; Barnevik, also the group's president and chairman, said.</p>
<p>But by 1998 ABB expects the current improvement in Western Europe's economy to help its business, which is cyclical.</p>
<p>Barnevik also expects business in the fourth quarter, traditionally ABB's strongest, to be pretty good with the first booking of orders from Malaysia's Bakun hydrolectric dam project, the largest order ever awarded to ABB.</p>
<p>ABB estimated its share of the approximately $5.5 billion Bakun project exceeded $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>Its sales in the January/September period rose three percent to $24.08 billion.</p>
<p>Net profit rose 24 percent to $809 million, slightly above forecasts for $805 million, but ABB's shares were hit by profit-taking and pulled down by a weaker Swiss market overall to end eight francs lower at 1,570 francs.</p>
<p>ABB repeated that it still expected net profit for the full 1996 year to exceed 1995's net profit on a comparable basis.</p>
<p>In 1995 ABB reported a net profit of $1,315 million but this result was inflated by a one-time payment of $250 million.</p>
<p>Orders received in the nine months rose slightly to $25.4 billion from $25.3 billion and the order backlog by the end of September had grown to $33.9 billion from $33.5 billion at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>On a comparable basis, excluding transportation activities, orders and sales rose seven percent.</p>
<p>ABB's nine-month operating profit only rose four percent, partly due to lower customer advances for large projects. Excluding this effect, operating earnings gained 17.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement in operating earnings was achieved despite a competitive environment for new power equipment, higher material costs and a lower contribution from transportation activities,&quot; ABB said.</p>
<p>Unlike the past, when a squeeze on the profit margins in ABB's power generation business triggered panic-selling of its shares, analysts took the news in their stride.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing sensational, nothing bad. The figures were basically a non-event,&quot; said Felix Stadelmann of Credit Suisse.</p>
<p>ABB is now much more geographically balanced.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason we can do relatively well in spite of the recession in Western Europe for our products is that we had growth in Asia and Eastern Europe,&quot; Barnevik said.</p>
<p>ABB said operating earnings in the power generation segment were well below the level reported last year and &quot;are expected to remain so for the full year.&quot;</p>
<p>Barnevik said it was still difficult to catch up with a 30 to 40 percent decline in prices for new power plants over the last few years.</p>
<p>He did not see much improvement in the external environment for power plants and said that, while prices were unlikely to fall much further, they would not rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a matter for us of continuing a high pace of cost reduction,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
