<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134146" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: ABB's P&amp;G segment resurfaces as cause of worry.</title>
<headline>ABB's P&amp;G segment resurfaces as cause of worry.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The health of ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG's Power Generation Segment (P&amp;G) has resurfaced as a concern among analysts and could put some short-term pressure on the shares of the electrical engineering group.</p>
<p>But while worries over margin erosion in P&amp;G are hardly a new phenomenon, analysts are now much more relaxed and less panicky in their reaction to such price pressures due to the geographical and product diversification of ABB.</p>
<p>&quot;There are little problems, but nothing that should be overemphasised,&quot; said Peter Knox of Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS).</p>
<p>For the full year analysts expect the decline in earnings from P&amp;G to be compensated by higher earnings at Power Transmission and Distribution, Industrial and Building Systems and Financial Services.</p>
<p>Chris Heminway of Lehman International, who pointed to earnings weakness at P&amp;G a few years ago, said troubles that had haunted other power generation firms last year were now starting to catch up with ABB, which had been able to avoid the worst of past problems by good contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the year when all of that is unwinding,&quot; Heminway said.</p>
<p>Overall, analysts said ABB's nine month results were largely in line with expectations.</p>
<p>ABB reported a 24 percent increase in net profits to $809 million. Stripping out the effect of interest on advances, operating earnings rose 17.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing sensational, nothing bad. The figures were basically a non-event,&quot; said Felix Stadelmann of Credit Suisse.</p>
<p>&quot;The nine month results really aren't that bad,&quot; said Paola Orler of Zurich Kantonalbank.</p>
<p>But ABB itself highlighted P&amp;G's deteriorating profitability when it noted that the operating earnings were &quot;well below&quot; the level reported last year and were &quot;expected to remain so for the full year.&quot;</p>
<p>Although expectations for P&amp;G were already low and ABB had flagged the continuing margin pressures, analysts said the statement was more bearish than expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the market was not looking for such a big decline, even taking into account the changes in customer advances,&quot; said Klas Anderson of Goldman Sachs International.</p>
<p>The phrase &quot;well below&quot; is normally associated with a decline of around 25 percent.</p>
<p>However, an ABB spokesman added that about half of the expected decline in operating earnings at P&amp;G was due to lower interest on advances.</p>
<p>&quot;Half of the shortfall doesn't impact pre-tax profits,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>Interest on advances affects ABB's operating earnings, but is deducted to avoid double-counting interest income and does not affect pre-tax or net profit.</p>
<p>ABB does not report quarterly earnings for its segments, but makes qualitative comments.</p>
<p>During the year, its comments about P&amp;G's earnings have become bleaker and analysts said investors who had not closely followed the business in the last few months could be taken by surprise by the latest comments.</p>
<p>In its half-year report ABB said P&amp;G's operating earnings were &quot;below&quot; last year and this had now changed to &quot;well below&quot;.</p>
<p>In 1995 operating earnings at P&amp;G rose to $914 million from $878 million, but the operating margin eased to 8.8 percent from 9.8 percent.</p>
<p>Although earnings at P&amp;G might be lower than expected, analysts are mainly leaving their forecasts unchanged, although small revisions -- some up and some down -- were being pencilled in.  </p>
<p>Analysts queried today expect ABB on average to report a 1996 net profit of $1.31 billion, slightly below last year's reported $1.315 billion.</p>
<p>However, last year's earnings were inflated by a one-time payment of $250 million from Daimler-Benz AG in connection with the creation of a rail transportation venture.</p>
<p>Excluding this payment, ABB would have reported a net profit of $1,065 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Forecasts for 1997 look for a net profit of $1.49 billion.</p>
<p>ABB's shares have risen 17.1 percent since the end of last year, but ended nine francs lower today.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
