<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134125" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Frankfurt bourse seen consolidating, watching U.S..</title>
<headline>Frankfurt bourse seen consolidating, watching U.S..</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares were expected to continue to consolidate this week, hovering under record-high levels reached recently, with dealers saying the market would look to the U.S. for direction.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX, which measures all-day computer trade in the DAX index of 30 leading shares, was off 8.17 points, or 0.30 percent, at 2,725.50, mirroring movements on Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;We're dependent on the trend in the U.S., now that we've had the M3 figures and business confidence data,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;We're not seeing a consolidation where we drop down far, rather we're staying at the same levels.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dealers said the current consolidation phase could last up to a week until the overbought situation was corrected. They said the DAX index could slip as far as 2,684 points where there is strong support, but said it would first have to breach the crucial 2,700 level.</p>
<p>Of the blue-chip shares Dresdner Bank was the day's top gainer, climbing 2.5 percent, or 98 pfennigs to 40.98 marks, after Goldman Sachs increased its estimates for the firm.</p>
<p>The whole banking sector was also buoyed by Dresdner's gains.  </p>
<p>Retail group Metro AG lost almost three percent in late IBIS trade, falling 3.90 marks to 133.13 after it said it would hold its goal of pre-tax profits of 1.0-1.1 billion marks despite continued weak consumer demand in the third quarter.</p>
<p>One of the day's main losers in IBIS dealings was Fresenius Medical Care, which dropped 6.20 marks to 132.45 marks, after the firm said it would issue $710 million in new preference shares and debt to pay back bank debt.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
