<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134199" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan unveils IMF-agreed reform package.</title>
<headline>Pakistan unveils IMF-agreed reform package.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan will slash spending and impose additional taxes under an IMF-approved plan to stabilise and reform the economy, State (central) Bank of Pakistan governor Muhammad Yaqub said on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Yaqub told a news conference that the government planned to narrow the budget deficit by 40 billion rupees through a mixture of spending cuts and additional taxes in 1996/97 (July-June).</p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the central bank devalued the rupee 7.86 percent against the dollar and raised its key repurchase (repo) discount rate to 20 percent a year from 17 percent.</p>
<p>Yaqub said 20 to 21 billion rupees would be slashed from &quot;less essential&quot; development expenditure, while six to seven billion rupees would be cut from current spending.</p>
<p>He said no cuts had been made in budget allocations for defence and debt servicing.</p>
<p>Yaqub said more than 13 billion rupees would be raised from additional tax measures, including two billion rupees from an agricultural income tax to be levied by the four provinces.</p>
<p>He said all oil product prices had been increased by 10 percent with immediate effect.</p>
<p>&quot;These reforms have been approved by the prime minister and her cabinet collegues and (the package) is markedly different from the one proposed by the IMF,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A team from the International Monetary Fund is due in Pakistan on Thursday for an economic review that must be completed before the fund releases any further tranches of a stalled $600 million standby loan.</p>
<p>-- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
