<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134117" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EU Court upholds Eurotunnel usage contract.</title>
<headline>EU Court upholds Eurotunnel usage contract.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of First Instance rejected on Tuesday a European Commission decision to force French and British rail companies to give 25 percent of the channel tunnel capacity to competitors.</p>
<p>British Rail (BR) and Societe Nationale des Chemins de Fer Francais (SNCF) successfully showed the court that third parties have always had access to the tunnel, and the Commission's evaluation of the tunnel usage was based on factual error.</p>
<p>In fact, Eurotunnel, the joint venture between British and French rail groups, secures only 50 percent of the capacity for international trains, not 100 percent as the Commission claimed, according to the court judgment.</p>
<p>British Rail said in 1994 in a letter to the Commission that there was a &quot;profound misunderstanding&quot; on the part of the Commission over the usage contract governing access to the tunnel.</p>
<p>The Commission reasoned that the way the usage contract was structured, BR and SNCF had 100 percent of hourly paths available for international freight.</p>
<p>Alex Nourry, a competition lawyer based in Brussels with Clifford Chance, said the court's decision means the usage contract for the tunnel was not contrary to competition rules and also removes conditions the Commission set on the railway operators under its 1994 decision.</p>
<p>The Commission's decision  required BR and SNCF to make available to competitors 25 percent of the hourly capacity of the tunnel in each direction. The Commission took the decision after it received comments from 10 interested third parties.</p>
<p>The decision has been in effect since December, 1994, but no third parties have come forward to exercise this right, Nourry said.</p>
<p>Nourry also said the decision may have major implications for other Trans European Network projects. &quot;If the EU wants to promote private financing for transportation projects, it must let individuals exploit long term contracts,&quot; Nourry said.</p>
<p>The Court of First Instance's decision is based on an error of fact, not law, and as a result cannot be appealed to the Court of Justice.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>EXCERPTS FROM THE JUDGMENTS</p>
<p>(Court translation into English. Original language of the cases: English and French)</p>
<p>&quot;Competition - Channel Tunnel - Reservation of 50 percent of tunnel capacity for two railway companies - Restrictions on competition - Exemption - Access for third parties&quot;</p>
<p>In Joined Cases T-79/95 and T-80/95</p>
<p>Societe Nationale des Chemins de Fer Francais, applicant in case T-79/95</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>British Railways Board, applicant in Case T-80/95</p>
<p>supported by United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>Channel Tunnel Group Ltd,</p>
<p>France Manche SA</p>
<p>Eurotunnel.</p>
<p>British Railways Board, also supported by</p>
<p>European Passenger Services Ltd, interveners</p>
<p>v</p>
<p>Commission of the European Communities, defendant</p>
<p>applications for the annulment of Commission decision 94/894/EC of 13 December 1994 relating to a proceeding under article 85 of the EC Treaty and article 53 of the EEA Agreement (IV/32/490 - Eurotunnel) (OJ 1994 L 354, p. 66) and, in the alternative, for the annulment of the conditions laid down in article 2(A) of that decision</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE COURT OF FIRST INSTANCE hereby</p>
<p>1. Cases T-79/95 and T-80/95 are joined for the purposes of the judgment.</p>
<p>2. Commission decision 94/894/EC of 13 December 1994 relating to a proceeding under article 85 of the EC Treaty and article 53 of the EEA Agreement (IV/32/490 - Eurotunnel) is annulled.</p>
<p>3. The Commission shall bear its own costs together with those of the applicants, including the costs relating tot he applications for interim measures. It shall also bear the costs of the intervener Euroopean Passenger Services, Ltd.</p>
<p>4. The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, together with Channel Tunnel Group Ltd and France Manche SA (Eurotunnel), shall bear their own costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
