<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134292" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lotus seeks partner.</title>
<headline>Lotus seeks partner.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Huddart</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British auto engineering group and sportscar maker Lotus Group declined to comment Tuesday on a report from Asia that it was selling a stake to Malaysian carmaker Proton, but said it was still looking for a partner.</p>
<p>Lotus spokesman Alastair Florance told Reuters he could neither confirm nor deny a report in the Asian Wall Street Journal that Proton is to buy 80 percent of the company, which has been actively seeking new investors for much of this year.</p>
<p>But he said he could confirm that Proton had purchased a Lotus car, which it was planning to evaluate, adding that it &quot;is in the process of developing a technical collaboration with Lotus.&quot;</p>
<p>Lotus' Italian owner Romano Artioli has said he was close to concluding a deal with a new investor who would help secure the private company's future. Artioli owns the company via the Luxembourg-registered Bugatti International SA group, which in turn is the parent of the Italian car company Bugatti Automobili, which went into receivership last year.</p>
<p>Despite several false dawns and widespread media and industry speculation, the company has not yet confirmed that it has identified a preferred partner and Florance said Tuesday that situation had not changed.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Artioli) is still looking for a co-investor or a partner, but not a purchaser,&quot; Florance said by telephone from the company's headquarters in the eastern English county of Norfolk.</p>
<p>He said no further details were available and added that the company was not able to reveal any more about the nature of the likely technical contract with Proton.</p>
<p>Lotus supplies automotive consultancy services ranging from component and engine technology to whole car design. This work represents most of its annual revenues and the company has contracts, many of which are strictly confidential, with a large number of the world's car manufacturers.</p>
<p>According to the newspaper report, Proton was to acquire a Lotus stake for 210 million ringgit ($84 million) in cash and would also assume debt of 51 million ringitt ($20.4 million).</p>
<p>Three weeks ago South Korea's Daewoo Motor Co. said its long-running talks with Lotus had broken down as the two sides had been unable to narrow their differences.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
