<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134279" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. more competitive, but still way to go.</title>
<headline>U.S. more competitive, but still way to go.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>The United States has sharply boosted its competitiveness over the past decade but it remains vulnerable to challenges from abroad because of long-term economic weaknesses, the Competitiveness Council said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The non-partisan council, which groups 150 business, labour and academic leaders, said those weaknesses include rising income inequality, paltry savings and an education system that is not providing workers with the skills they need.</p>
<p>Unless those challenges are met, the United States will face difficulties in maintaining living standards for most Americans, much less improving them, the council said.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has out-performed all of the advanced industrial economies during the 1990s, but the payoff has been slim in terms of increasing the incomes of many Americans,&quot; the council said in a its report.</p>
<p>It attributed the gains in competitiveness over the last decade to a variety of factors, including corporate restructuring, budget deficit cuts, a weaker dollar and success in opening up markets abroad.</p>
<p>The increased competitiveness has meant that the United States has enjoyed faster growth, lower unemployment and bigger exports since 1985 than rival industrial nations.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the next 10 years, nearly all the council members surveyed expect the United States to perform as well or better than its fellow members of the powerful Group of Seven -- Britain, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and Japan.</p>
<p>Germany in particular is expected to lose out, with 40 percent of those surveyed forecasting that it will fall behind over the coming decade.</p>
<p>Increasingly, though, council members see the main foreign competitive threat to the United States coming not from the G7, but from the emerging market economies of China, South Korea, India, Brazil and Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;The G7 countries are not the challenge anymore,&quot; said Harvard University professor Michael Porter. &quot;The challenge now comes from the newly emerging economies.&quot;</p>
<p>Those nations pose both a threat and an opportunity because as they grow, their demand for foreign goods will rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a good news/bad news story for the United States,&quot; said W. R Timken, chairman of Timken Co., which makes bearings and special steels. &quot;There are tremendous opportunities and tremendous threats, so advanced competitiveness is even more important to maintain and enhance our standard of living.&quot;</p>
<p>Council members overwhelmingly pinpointed upgrading worker skills as the most important competitiveness challenge facing the United States in the next decade. Increasing savings and investment were also mentioned as important.</p>
<p>For its part, the federal government should focus on improving education and cutting the budget deficit, the council said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a difference between the end of competitiveness and the means,&quot; said Jack Sheinkman, President Emeritus of the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. &quot;High and rising living standards are the main goal, while economic growth and strengthened competitiveness are only the means.&quot;</p>
<p>On that score, council members were not so optimistic.</p>
<p>While they expect the United States to continue to do well in terms of job creation, a majority see wages at manufacturing companies staying stagnant over the next decade, although employees at service firms should do better.</p>
<p>&quot;While U.S. industry looks stronger and some progress has been made in putting the nation's financial house in order, there are good reasons to be concerned about our economy,&quot; said former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker. &quot;The toughest choices and most difficult adjustments still lie ahead.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
