<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13427" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conseco buys insurance firms for more than $1.7 billion.</title>
<headline>Conseco buys insurance firms for more than $1.7 billion.</headline>
<dateline>CARMEL, Ind.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Life insurance and financial services giant Conseco Inc. said Monday it would acquire two insurance companies and increase its stakes in two others in deals having a total price tag of more than $1.7 billion.</p>
<p>The Carmel, Ind.-based company said it would acquire American Travellers Corp., which provides long-term care insurance, for $793 million in Conseco stock.</p>
<p>It also said it agreed to buy Capitol American Financial Corp., a provider of cancer insurance and other supplemental health insurance, for $650 milion in cash and Conseco stock.</p>
<p>Conseco said it intends to acquire the stock of American Life Holdings that it does not alredy own for $165 million in cash. It said it would distribute the stock of American Life that had been held by Conseco Capital Partners II LP to all partners. American Life is a provider of retirement savings annuities.</p>
<p>Conseco also said it will acquire the remaining shares of Bankers Life Holding Corp. that it does not already own for $117 million and intends to merge with the provider of supplemental health insurance products for senior citizens.</p>
<p>Conseco's stock gained $1 to $43 in early trading on the New York Stock Exchange, while American Travellers shot up $2.875 to $31.25 on the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>American Life was unchanged at $24 on Nasdaq. Bankers Life Holding gained $1.875 to $23.625 and Capitol American Financial was untraded after a pre-weekend close of $25, both on the NYSE.</p>
<p>After the transactions are completed, Conseco said it will have $30 billion of assets under management, $26 billion of assets on its balance sheet, $6.8 billion of annual premiums and revenues, $4.2 billion of equity market capitalisation and more than $650 million of projected annual earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;The life insurance industry is undergoing rapid consolidation,&quot; said Conseco Chairman Stephen Hilbert. &quot;Conseco is positioned as a proven consolidator.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;After the transactions, Conseco expects to have $5.4 billion of total capital, comprised of $3.5 billion of equity, including the planned issuance of about $300 million of a new tax-deductible preferred stock and assuming the conversion of all convertible instruments, and $1.9 billion of debt,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hilbert said that the acquisitions will boost the company's 1997 operating earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming completion of these transactions before the end of 1996, as expected, we believe Conseco's operating earnings will be able to reach our previously announced goal of $5.00 per fully diluted share in 1997, compared to current analyst expectations of $4.25 to $4.65,&quot; Hilbert said.</p>
<p>He said the company is focusing on acquisitions that complement its long-term business strategy and maintain both its earnings momentum and its conservative capital structure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARMEL, Ind."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
