<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134201" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian forward dlr premia ends down, may dip again.</title>
<headline>Indian forward dlr premia ends down, may dip again.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The forward dollar premia ended sharply lower on Tuesday as a result of Reserve Bank of India's (RBI) weekend initiatives to boost liquidity and prompt a cut in lending rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>The forward dollar premia opened sharply lower, as was expected after the RBI's announcement on Saturday on cut in cash reserve ratio, releasing over 85 billion rupees to bank coffers.</p>
<p>April dollar opened at 1.33/1.38 rupees, sharply down from the weekend closing of 1.57/1.60 rupees. The closing rates were 1.30/1.34 rupees. The six month annualised premium was around 7.5 percent, down from the weekend closing of 8.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel this is the bottom,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank. &quot;It's a good level for importers to enter.&quot;</p>
<p>A bank dealer said the forward dollar market saw at least 40 percent surge in volumes over the daily average on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel this (premia of 7.5 percent) is the right level, on fundamentals,&quot; said Ranjit Shah, director at Su-Raj Diamonds, a leading exporting firm. &quot;If corporates borrow at LIBOR plus one to 1.5 percentage point, it would be about 7.5 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Shah said the average rupee borrowing cost of an Indian exporter was about 14 percent per annum. &quot;The difference between this and LIBOR plus is about the same as the six month premium.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise there would be arbitrage opportunities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But some dealers said the forward market could see lower premia in the days to come.</p>
<p>&quot;I think 120 paise (1.20 rupees for April dollars) is the next level the market will aim,&quot; said Yeshwant Rao, deputy general manager (forex) at textile exporting firm Arvind Mills.</p>
<p>The rupee edged up against the dollar in the spot market.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 35.6200/6250 rupees. The day opened at 35.66/69 rupees to a dollar but the rupee edged up immediately to 35.64/65 range on plentiful dollar supply, dealers said.</p>
<p>The chief dealer at a state-run bank said large dollar remittances, especially from the Middle East, accumulated over the weekend, helped the rupee's rise in the spot market.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people had overbought dollars on the weekend, expecting large buying this week - this didn't happen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the RBI did not buy dollars on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Shyam Kumar, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
