<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134237" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Stanchart poll sees India rupee at 36.50 in 6 mths.</title>
<headline>Stanchart poll sees India rupee at 36.50 in 6 mths.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A poll of top 100 company treasurers conducted by Standard Chartered Bank showed the Indian rupee would dip to a median of 36.50 in six months, the bank said.</p>
<p>The rupee is now quoted around 35.65 per dollar. The bank said, at the weekend, that it also polled treasurers on their expectations on the forward dollar premia and Bombay Stock Exchange sensitive index.</p>
<p>The poll showed:</p>
<p>SPOT DOLLAR-RUPEE:</p>
<p>-----------------</p>
<p>			     1 Month     3 Months     6 Months</p>
<p>			     -------     --------     --------</p>
<p>Mean			  35.76	  36.11	  36.63</p>
<p>Median			35.80	  36.13	  36.50</p>
<p>COMMENT: The strength we are now seeing in the rupee was not anticipated by the treasures as they had earlier polled the rupee to be at 35.76 by the beginning of November (The rupee was 35.72 at the time of polling).</p>
<p>The rate of depreciation expected in the rupee over the next six months are 0.11 percent (1.34 percent per annum) over one month, 1.9 percent (4.37 percent per annum) over the next three months and 2.55 percent (5.10 percent per annum) over the next six months.</p>
<p>DOLLAR-RUPEE FORWARD PREMIUMS:</p>
<p>-----------------------------</p>
<p>			     1 Month     3 Months     6 Months</p>
<p>			     -------     --------     --------</p>
<p>Mean			  9.30	   9.61	   10.16</p>
<p>Median			9.65	   9.65	   10.00</p>
<p>COMMENT: Although premiums were supposed to have bottomed out last month, they dropped again during the month to reach a low of around 8 percent (it was 9.97 percent per annum at the time of polling).</p>
<p>From this month the premiums are expected to remain relatively flat, moving up just above the 10 percent mark by April 1997.</p>
<p>BSE SENSITIVE INDEX:</p>
<p>-------------------</p>
<p>			     1 Month     3 Months     6 Months</p>
<p>			     -------     --------     --------</p>
<p>Mean			  3,300	  3,421	  3,554</p>
<p>Median			3,300	  3,400	  3,570</p>
<p>COMMENT: The sustained bear run on the BSE has changed the expectations of the treasurers this month. Last month they had a little more positive outlook with the BSE Index looking to reach approximately 3,800 points by March '97. This month the treasurers do not expect the market to move up more than 200 points in the next six months.</p>
<p>91 DAY TREASURY BILL:</p>
<p>---------------------</p>
<p>			     1 Month     3 Months     6 Months</p>
<p>			     -------     --------     --------</p>
<p>Mean			  10.02	 10.06	   10.07</p>
<p>Median			10.04	 10.00	   10.08</p>
<p>COMMENT: Benchmark interest rates are expected to remain flat at slightly lower levels. The market seems to have already discounted at 0.5 percent to 1.0 percent cut in CRR to be announced in the credit policy due on 19/10/96. (The poll was conducted before the policy announcement on Saturday.</p>
<p>PRIME LENDING RATES (Standard Chartered India's PLR):</p>
<p>-------------------------------------</p>
<p>			     1 Month     3 Months     6 Months</p>
<p>			     -------     --------     --------</p>
<p>Mean			  17.92	 17.69	   17.55</p>
<p>Median			18.00	 17.50	   17.50</p>
<p>COMMENT: Treasurers expect banks to further reduce their PLR. More banks have already followed State Bank of India's move and cut its PLR by 0.5 percent to 1.0 percent.</p>
<p>The monthly poll began in April this year. The latest poll was conducted in early October.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the six-month summary of the results, in most cases, the trend of the indicators has been predicted correctly,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
