<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134271" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bristol-Myers, Eli Lilly post strong results; stocks jump.</title>
<headline>Bristol-Myers, Eli Lilly post strong results; stocks jump.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drug maker Eli Lilly &amp; Co. said Tuesday its earnings jumped 34 percent in the third quarter, and Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. posted a 9 percent profit gain as strong worldwide sales outweighed the loss of a key U.S. patent on a heart drug.</p>
<p>Wall Street rewarded the drug makers by boosting their stocks to new highs for the year. Warner-Lambert Co., however, reported lower earnings and its stock fell.</p>
<p>Eli Lilly's stock was up $1.25 at $70 on the New York Stock Exchange in early afternoon trading after hitting a new high for the year of $71, and Bristol-Myers was up $1.625 at $105.625 after rising to $105.75.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said its profits rose 9 percent to $753 million, or $1.50 a share, in the third quarter on revenues of $3.74 billion. The results compared with year-ago earnings of $689 million, or $1.36 a share, on revenues of $3.41 billion.</p>
<p>The New York-based company said strong worldwide sales of its pharmaceutical products more than offset a large drop in U.S. sales of its Capoten heart drug following the expiration of its U.S. patent.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said U.S. Capoten sales plunged 72 percent in the quarter as a result of the patent's loss in February and competition from lower-priced generic versions.</p>
<p>It did not provide a dollar figure for Capoten sales, but noted that worldwide Capoten sales were still expected to exceed $1 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>The drug maker said its overall revenues were boosted by a 35 percent jump in sales of its cholesterol-lowering drug Pravachol to $261 million.</p>
<p>Consumer product sales rose 12 percent in the quarter, driven by hair-colouring and hair care products, including Nice n Easy and Natural Instincts.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers said its nutritional product sales grew 10 percent, while medical device product revenues were flat.</p>
<p>Eli Lilly said its profits increased 34 percent to $415.6 million, or 76 cents a share, compared with year-ago profits of $310.5 million, or 54 cents a share. Sales rose 11 percent to $1.804 billion from $1.632 billion.</p>
<p>The Indianapolis-based company said its results were boosted by the sale of the U.S. marketing rights for its Ceclor CD and Keftab antibiotic drugs to Dura Pharmaceuticals Inc. for $100 million, which increased earnings by 12 cents a share.</p>
<p>&quot;The third quarter marked accelerated growth in the sale of our products and improved control of our costs,&quot; said Eli Lilly Chairman Randall Tobias. &quot;In addition, we have heavily supported the launches of several important new products.&quot;</p>
<p>Eli Lilly said sales of its anti-depressant drug Prozac increased 10 percent despite competition from generic forms of Prozac in Canada and substantial competition in France.</p>
<p>Morris Plains, N.J.-based Warner-Lambert Co. said its third quarter profits fell to $152.8 million, or 56 cents a share. That compared with year-ago earnings of $214 million, or 79 cents a share, which were boosted by the company's sale of its PRO toothbrush business to Gillette Co.</p>
<p>Revenues edged down to $1.76 billion from $1.77 billion.</p>
<p>Warner-Lambert's stock was down 62.5 cents at $65.50 on the NYSE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
