<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134258" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian rupee seen stable after new monetary policy.</title>
<headline>Indian rupee seen stable after new monetary policy.</headline>
<byline>Shyam Kumar</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's central bank governor Chakravarty Rangarajan said on Monday he expected the rupee to remain stable following weekend moves to inject liquidity into the banking system and trigger lower interest rates.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India, in its half-yearly monetary statement, announced measures to boost banks' liquidity and allow them to lend to Indian firms out of expatriate Indians' dollar deposits for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;As of now the demand/supply situation is well balanced and the rupee will remain basically stable around this level,&quot; Rangarajan said in an interview with Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>In recent months the central bank has been buying dollars almost continuously following a surge in overseas equity issues by Indian firms and foreign direct investments, which increased the domestic dollar supply.</p>
<p>And foreign exchange dealers said the rupee will strengthen further on the forward market partly as a result of the RBI's moves.</p>
<p>The annualised premium on six-month dollars may fall to a low of 7.5 percent, compared with Friday's closing level of 8.5 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Premia should fall in any case,&quot; said the chief dealer at a Bombay brokerage, saying the cut of two percentage points in cash reserve requirements for banks had affected the sentiment.</p>
<p>RBI has been preventing the rupee from strengthening below 35.65 per dollar on the spot market. It was quoted around 35.580/710 on Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>Bankers said the policy appeared to be to allow the rupee to slide very gradually, although Rangarajan said there was no policy to allow the rupee to depreciate.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not looking for any rate of depreciation,&quot; he said, when asked on RFTV what rate of depreciation the RBI was looking for. &quot;All that I would say is that we do look into the real effective exchange rate because that has some impact on the competitiveness of Indian exports,&quot; the governor said.</p>
<p>The RBI policy for the second half of the financial year 1996/97 (April to March) mapped out a staggered cut in banks' cash reserve ratio to 10 percent from 12 percent over the next four months. Those cuts will free up over 85 billion rupees ($2.4 billion) for banks to lend.</p>
<p>Rangarajan told a news conference on Saturday he expected a pool of about $2.0 billion with Indian banks to lend out of their foreign currency non-resident deposit accounts.</p>
<p>Bankers said Indian firms will find borrowing from the expatriate accounts cheaper than arranging external commercial borrowings, particularly for smaller amounts, as it will avoid the costs attached to syndicated loans.</p>
<p>Indian companies currently resort to external commercial borrowing for amounts as small as $15 million. ($1=35.67 rupees)</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
