<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134240" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan woman appeals to Taleban to ease strictures.</title>
<headline>Afghan woman appeals to Taleban to ease strictures.</headline>
<byline>Michael Battye</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Afghan woman has made a passionate appeal to Kabul's new fundamentalist rulers to let women work and go to school, saying preventing them was unIslamic.</p>
<p>In a translation of the appeal made available to Reuters on Tuesday, Archeology Professor Sidiqa Sidiq quoted extensively from the Koran to tell the Taleban they were wrong to order women to stay at home.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are depriving them from doing sound and reputable jobs and if you are depriving them from acquiring knowledge, they would be compelled to resort to filthy jobs aimed at rescuing their children and their family from hunger,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>Sidiq, in her mid 50s and the great granddaughter of an Afghan king, appeared to be suggesting that many of the women who are the sole support of their families might resort to prostitution to keep them fed.</p>
<p>Western aid workers say there are at least 30,000 women in Kabul who have been widowed in Afghanistan's 17 years of war and are the sole support of their families.</p>
<p>The Taleban, who captured the capital three weeks ago, promptly imposed Islam's stern Sharia law on the city, forbidding women to go to work or continue their education. Men were ordered to pray five times a day at mosques and grow beards.</p>
<p>Sidiq, in an appeal she delivered to the Taleban authorities a few days ago, said the Taleban would be to blame if women suffered.</p>
<p>&quot;No mother has been known in the world to see her children dying from starvation and this unforgivable sin will be on your shoulders,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the orders of the holy Koran and based on the above mentioned reasons, I am requesting all the concerned brothers and individuals to release us from this detention and these chains and let us continue our education and our jobs under the Islamic law that is the prime meed for the development of our ruined homeland.&quot;</p>
<p>Sidiq's appeal is the first known to have been sent to the Taleban, who also ordered women to appear on the streets only if clad in the burqa, an all-enveloping garment with a cloth mesh across the eyes.</p>
<p>Western aid groups, many of which focus on helping women and need women to carry out their work, have also appealed to the Taleban to ease their restrictions.</p>
<p>They say they have been told that the policies would be reviewed once Afghanistan was at peace. With war again at Kabul's doorstep and efforts to organise a ceasefire still underway, peace may still be some way off.</p>
<p>The forces of former government military chief Ahmad Shah Masood have pressed to within 25 km (16 miles) of the city over the past 10 days.</p>
<p>He has been joined by men of northern Uzbek chief Abdul Rashid Dostum. The two men were allies when Islamic guerrillas took Kabul in 1992 on the collapse of a Moscow-backed communist government, but split two years later.</p>
<p>Sidiq said under the guerrilla government, women were harrassed &quot;by different inhuman means like insults, betraying our dignity and chastity&quot;.</p>
<p>The Taleban, she said, must change their policies. &quot;Acquiring knowledge is compulsory to both man and woman in Islam,&quot; she wrote, adding an appeal to Afghan women to fight for their rights.</p>
<p>&quot;Oh, sisters, we have to be determined and not like our grandfathers have the expectation of assistance from our compatriots abroad and from foreign organisations and countries, because they are shouting only for political propaganda.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
