<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13424" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's interest rate cut said not enough.</title>
<headline>Israel's interest rate cut said not enough.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shoshanna Solomon</p>
<p>The Israeli stock market fell on Monday despite a 0.5 percentage point cut in the central bank's key lending rate which business leaders said was not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have been better had the Bank of Israel not changed the interest rate, because this insignificant step will only undermine the stability of the economy,&quot; said Dan Gillerman, president of the Federation of Israeli Chambers of Commerce.</p>
<p>Dan Propper, president of Israel's Manufacturers Association, told Israel Radio that the rate cut was a small step in the right direction, but not enough.</p>
<p>The Bank of Israel said on Monday it was lowering its key lending rate to commercial banks for September by 0.5 percentage point to an annualised 15.8 percent.</p>
<p>Israeli shares closed lower across the board despite the cut in the rates because big provident funds were selling stocks and because interest rates were still too high, traders said. Provident funds are long-term savings funds with special tax benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing happens in the market. The high interest rate is killing the market and today's cut is not enough,&quot; said a trader at Lehava Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The session opened with mild gains following the lowering of the interest rate and activity remained low during most of the day. Just before the end of the trading day the First International Bank of Israel started selling (stocks) and pushing the whole market downwards,&quot; said Ron Weisberg at I.B.I Investment House.</p>
<p>Provident funds have been dumping bonds and selling off stocks to meet massive public redemptions.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares fell 0.88 percent, to 174.38 on an all-share turnover of 57 million shekels while the Maof 25 index lost 1.22 percent to 184.98.</p>
<p>Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel said the central bank would further lower interest rates only if inflation is seen to go down.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters Financial Television, Frenkel said: &quot;We will not lower interest rates on the hope of a lower inflation. When we see positive results (in inflation) interest rates will be adjusted further.&quot;</p>
<p>Frenkel said the 0.5 percentage point cut in its key lending rate to commercial banks was justified because there is a reversal of inflation expectations and Israel is already seeing some benefits of the monetary restraint exercised by the central bank.</p>
<p>But, he said: &quot;Inflation is still above the set target of the government and calls for a continuation of monetary restraint.&quot;</p>
<p>Finance Minister Dan Meridor said at a meeting of the parliament's finance committee that &quot;without healthy capital markets it will be difficult for the economy to continue to grow and we will act to make the capital markets healthy.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the central bank had a unique independence which needed to be preserved and its policies were based on those set by the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
