<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134205" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan hopes Afghan ceasefire will be agreed.</title>
<headline>Pakistan hopes Afghan ceasefire will be agreed.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan pursued its attempt to broker an Afghan ceasefire on Tuesday despite veiled criticism from the United Nations, which is running its own peace mission.</p>
<p>Pakistani mediation has also coincided with efforts of the Organisation of Islamic Conference (OIC), whose envoy on Monday proposed a truce and a peace conference in Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;I am more than hopeful (for a ceasefire accord) because in principle they have all agreed,&quot; Pakistani Interior Minister Naseerullah Babar told a news conference in Islamabad. &quot;The ceasefire will be applicable all across Afghanistan.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected a positive response by Wednesday from the man he said had first proposed the ceasefire, northern Uzbek militia leader General Abdul Rashid Dostum, a key figure in an alliance opposed to the radical Islamic Taleban militia.</p>
<p>Babar said his proposals envisaged a ceasefire between the Taleban movement now ruling Kabul and forces loyal to the ousted Burhanuddin Rabbani government's military commander Ahmed Shah Masood.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the two sides were still trading tank, rocket and artillery fire on the plains north of Kabul on Tuesday,</p>
<p>Other parties to the accord would be Dostum and Shi'ite Moslem leader Karim Khalili, who both signed a defence pact with Masood earlier this month but have not joined the fighting.</p>
<p>Dostum has sent troops and tanks towards the front-line in support of Masood's forces, but an Islamabad-based spokesman for the Uzbek leader said they had not clashed with the Taleban.</p>
<p>Babar said the proposed agreement provided for an exchange of prisoners and bodies, as well as formation of a 12-member commission representing the Taleban and their opponents.</p>
<p>Once the draft had been accepted, a ceasefire deadline would be announced and a formal agreement prepared by Pakistan in collaboration with the United Nations would be signed by Dostum and Taleban leader Mullah Muhammad Omar in Islamabad, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel we cannot do it alone,&quot; Babar said. &quot;We feel the United Nations has to be there.&quot;</p>
<p>U.N. officials could not immediately be reached for comment, but U.N. special envoy Norbert Holl said on Monday that no single country could bring peace to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>&quot;People may think in Kabul it is more important to follow the advice of other negotiators but in the long run help for reconstruction will only come from the international community,&quot; Holl said after talks with Taleban representatives in Kabul.</p>
<p>Pakistan on Monday also sent an envoy to Tehran, which recognises the Rabbani government, to discuss the Afghan crisis with Iranian leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;The Pakistani government declared that it wanted an end to the Afghan war and reiterated that Pakistan did not want a particular group to rule in Afghanistan,&quot; Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akr Velayati said after meeting the envoy.</p>
<p>Pakistan denies charges made by the Rabbani government and echoed by the Iranian media that it supports the Taleban.</p>
<p>Babar said Pakistan's immediate goal was to halt the fighting. &quot;We have separated the ceasefire agreement from the overall settlement of Afghanistan. That is purely for the Afghan people to decide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The main obstacle to a truce seems to be a demand by Masood, apparently backed by Dostum, that talks on demilitarising Kabul should start as soon as a ceasefire was in place.</p>
<p>Babar described this as an &quot;unfair condition&quot; that went beyond the terms of the proposed accord. &quot;We said that when the commission sits, this can be discussed,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Dostum's spokesman in Islamabad, General Paynda (one name), said the question of security arrangements for Kabul, possibly involving a U.N. force or a neutral force drawn from different factions, should be part of any ceasefire agreement.</p>
<p>A Taleban spokesman contacted in Kandahar, headquarters of the purist Islamic movement, said on Tuesday the leadership was awaiting Dostum's response to the ceasefire proposal.</p>
<p>&quot;A ceasefire will take place when an exchange of prisoners takes place,&quot; he said. &quot;If they don't agree to the prisoner exchange there is no use in stopping the fighting.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISLAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
