<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134270" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: W.R. Grace to divest four non-core businesses.</title>
<headline>W.R. Grace to divest four non-core businesses.</headline>
<dateline>BOCA RATON, Fla. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>W.R. Grace &amp; Co. said Tuesday that it plans to divest four non-core businesses within six months in order to focus on its packaging and speciality chemicals businesses.</p>
<p>The company said the sales of the four units, which previously had been classified as discontinued operations, are expected to generate about $300 million in pre-tax proceeds, before paying off certain other obligations, including minority interests.</p>
<p>Grace said the businesses -- Grace TEC Systems, Grace Speciality Polymers, Grace Cocoa and Amicon -- do not fit in with its strategy of becoming a dominant packaging and speciality chemicals company.</p>
<p>Grace TEC supplies dryers for the paper industry and Grace Speciality Polymers supplies materials used in making circuit boards and components.</p>
<p>Grace Cocoa produces and sells cocoa and chocolate while Amicon supplies biotechnology and pharmaceutical companies with molecular separation and purification products.</p>
<p>&quot;We already have received interest from numerous parties for each of these businesses and, through the divestitures, we expect to generate greater value for Grace shareholders,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Grace's stock rose 87.50 cents to $55.125 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOCA RATON, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
