<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13422" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Yugoslav trade mission wraps up Sarajevo visit.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav trade mission wraps up Sarajevo visit.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Yugoslav trade mission wrapped up a one-day visit to Sarajevo on Monday, the first such trip to Bosnia's capital since war broke out here in 1992.</p>
<p>Headed by Yugoslav Deputy Prime Minister Nikola Sainovic, the Yugoslav mission reciprocated a July 23 Bosnian trade delegation visit to Belgrade.</p>
<p>Bosnian central government Prime Minister Hasan Muratovic, who met the trade delegation, said discussions had focused on setting up a &quot;more intensive economic relationship&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We agreed concretely for experts to meet in the shortest possible time to define a (common) payment system and to define border crossings and procedures,&quot; Muratovic told reporters.</p>
<p>Sainovic said his delegation's meetings with Bosnian government officials and private businessmen had furthered the cause of the Dayton peace agreement, which ended the 43-month Bosnian war in December of 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic development needs to be the long-lasting cement of the peace agreement,&quot; the Yugoslav Deputy Prime Minister said.</p>
<p>Bosnian Vice-President Ejup Ganic, who led the Bosnian trade mission to Belgrade in July, said Monday's talks were a continuation of what began in the Yugoslav capital last month.</p>
<p>&quot;The main issue of today's talks was trade in order to create a new urgency for resolving other problems,&quot; Ganic explained.</p>
<p>Bosnian President Alija Izetbegovic met Sainovic, Bosnian radio reported.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia lost four of its six republics in recent years as Slovenia, Croatia, Bosnia and Macedonia gained independence. Croatia and Bosnia fought protracted wars, in part against the republics of Serbia and Montenegro which remained behind and formed rump Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia and Croatia signed a mutual recognition accord on Friday, ending five years of hostility between those two countries.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia and Bosnia have not yet recognized one another, but the exchange of trade delegations is viewed by diplomats as a practical step in that direction and a further sign that stability is returning to the Balkans.</p>
<p>&quot;We of course welcome this visit,&quot; U.S. Ambassador to Bosnia John Menzies said of the Yugoslav trip to Sarajevo.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought it was a major breakthrough when Mr. Ganic visited Belgrade. We are very glad to see the return visit.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
