<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134289" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New earthquake insurance leaves California exposed.</title>
<headline>New earthquake insurance leaves California exposed.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A multi-billion dollar scheme offering earthquake insurance to homeowners in California would fall short of covering them fully for the &quot;big one&quot; -- a giant quake the like of which the region has not yet seen and which some scientists warn may strike at any moment.</p>
<p>California has within the last few weeks set up its own $10.5 billion earthquake insurance pool, which is designed to draw domestic insurers back into a homeowner market they backed away from after an earthquake more than two years ago caused $12.5 billion of damage in and around the city of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>But representatives for the scheme said on Tuesday that the new public-private partnership, which is expected to generate $1.0 billion in premium income annually once it begins selling policies to customers in early December, may be unable to provide protection against an earthquake of unprecedented size.</p>
<p>State insurance commissioner Chuck Quackenbush and senior colleagues fear that the private sector, even with the help of the state of California, would struggle to meet the damage bill from an earthquake measuring over 8.0 on the Richter scale.</p>
<p>&quot;The big one hasn't really happened yet. For that we are not fully prepared,&quot; said David Knowles, chairman of the Californian state assembly insurance committee, at a London press briefing.</p>
<p>A federal sponsored disaster programme may be the answer, but Quackenbush said there was no industry consensus on this.</p>
<p>Insurers must under Californian law include earthquake cover in homeowner policies. But ninety percent of providers in that market scaled back their underwriting after the expensive 1994 Northridge shock, reluctant to insure against this sort of risk in one of the most earthquake-prone zones of the world.</p>
<p>Under pressure from insurance industry representatives and following months of delay, Californian legislators at the end of September moved to resolve the situation by establishing the California Earthquake Authority (CEA).</p>
<p>&quot;We turned to the private sector and came up with the concept of the CEA,&quot; said Quackenbush. &quot;This limits exposure to earthquakes which makes us able to price a product.&quot;</p>
<p>He told reporters that if such a disaster policy had been in place in time to insure against the 1994 earthquake, losses from this would have been reduced to $4.2 billion. Losses from an earthquake equalling in strength the 1906 San Francisco Bay tremor would be no more than $7.0 billion with the CEA.</p>
<p>Quackenbush has just sealed one of the biggest reinsurance deals ever. Around $1.8 billion of backing for the CEA has been pledged by the world's top reinsurers in the London market, continental Europe, the U.S. and Bermuda. The final contract was signed last week and Quackenbush visited London firms this week.</p>
<p>Lloyd's of London, the insurance market which last month secured its own future with the completion of a $5.0 billion recovery plan, will with companies operating in the rest of the London market provide just under $300 million of reinsurance.</p>
<p>Continental European reinsurers have pledged $600 million of cover, with the giants Munich Re, Swiss Re and Axa Re providing $100 million each directly. Bermudan reinsurers have committed $500 million and the United States market $350 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
