<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13425" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares end lower after lacklustre trade.</title>
<headline>German shares end lower after lacklustre trade.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares ended a lacklustre session on Monday almost unchanged from their closing levels on Friday.</p>
<p>The listless mood, initiated during the floor session, continued in afternoon electronic trade, with the IBIS DAX index of electronically-traded shares moving in a range of only ten points or so.</p>
<p>Traders said that sentiment was hit by lower German bonds, a still-weak dollar, an unhelpfully low close on Wall Street on Friday and a bank holiday in London.</p>
<p>At the end of bourse trade the DAX index, which measures floor trade in 30 blue-chip German shares, was down 2.80 points at 2,552.36 points.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX index, which measures all-day electronic trade, ended the day down 7.70 points, or 0.30 percent, at 2,554.42.</p>
<p>A Frankfurt dealer said that interest should pick up after the holiday season ends around next week.</p>
<p>Among shares on the move over the course of bourse trade was the specialty chemical SKW Trostberg AG, which ended bourse trade up 1.35 marks at 39.40 marks.</p>
<p>SKW Trostberg ended electronic trade up 1.35 marks, or 3.55 percent, at 39.40 marks.</p>
<p>The increase was attributed to an announcement that SKW was buying Master Builders Technology (MBT), a subsidiary of the Swiss chemical group Sandoz and the SKW would not increase its capital to finance the deal.</p>
<p>Chemical shares were lower in pre-bourse trade on Monday after performing strongly on Friday, but they picked up again in bourse trade.</p>
<p>BASF ended IBIS trade up four pfennigs at 43.74 marks, Hoechst was down five pfennigs at 24.90 marks, Bayer was down 15 pfennigs at 53.60 marks and Degussa was up 4.40 marks at 512.20 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
