<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134245" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: RBI policy to boost Indian banks' profits - I-Sec.</title>
<headline>RBI policy to boost Indian banks' profits - I-Sec.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ICICI Securities and Finance Company (I-Sec) said it upgraded the earning estimates of some of India's listed commercial banks following the monetary policy announced by the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) on Saturday.</p>
<p>I-Sec said it upgraded the earnings forecasts of State Bank of India (SBI), Oriental Bank of Commerce, Federal Bank and Vysya Bank.  </p>
<p>It revised SBI's 1996/97 (April-March) earnings forecast to 32.2 rupees from 30.0, Oriental Bank of Commerce's to 10.4 rupees from 9.80, Federal Bank's to 30.3 rupees from 28.0 and Vysya Bank's to 66.4 rupees from 62.5 rupees.</p>
<p>&quot;The reduction in CRR (cash reserve ratio) by two percentage points as also the decrease in maximum term deposit rate by one percentage point will positively impact banking sector profitability,&quot; I-Sec said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;Both these announcements will reduce the cost of funds and should theoretically result in a proportionate increase in profits,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>However, depending on the extent of reduction in the effective lending rates, the gross spreads and correspondingly the net profit of each bank will vary, it said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
