<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134265" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Three big publishers report higher earnings.</title>
<headline>Three big publishers report higher earnings.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three major newspaper publishers Tuesday reported sharply higher earnings for the third quarter, boosted by growth in advertising revenue and moderating newsprint costs.</p>
<p>Knight-Ridder Inc. said earnings rose fivefold, helped by lower losses from the 15-month-old strike against its Detroit Free Press newspaper; Times Mirror Co. reported a 50 percent jump excluding one-time charges and Washington Post Co. said earnings rose 33 percent.</p>
<p>The results were in line or slightly better than expectations on Wall Street. Analysts said a long hard round of cost-cutting by newspapers was starting to pay off.</p>
<p>&quot;All the cost-cuts put in place six to nine months ago -- the smaller newsholes, the narrow margins and staff reductions -- are going right to the bottom line,&quot; said media analyst Rita Zanella of Gruntal &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Prices for newsprint, the raw material used in newspapers, peaked at $743 a ton in January, which hurt industry profits. Publishers reacted by cutting the pages dedicated to news stories or trimming subscriber lists. Some newspapers even trimmed the white margins on each page. Jobs were cut too.</p>
<p>Newsprint now averages about $550 a ton and should stay in the $550 to $600 a ton range through next year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Knight-Ridder, based in Miami, said earnings rose to $35.4 million, or 37 cents a share, in the quarter, from $6.6 million, or 7 cents a share, in the 1995 quarter. The latest period excluded a one-time gain of $90.9 million, or 94 cents a share, on the sale of Knight-Ridder Financial news for $275 million to Global Financial Information Corp. in July.</p>
<p>Revenue rose 2 percent to $653.8 million from $638.0 million.</p>
<p>The company cited lower losses from the 15-month old strike in Detroit and strong growth in advertising revenue despite continued sluggishness in retail advertising, an important source of newspaper revenue.</p>
<p>The strength in newspaper ads helped offset lower revenues from its business information services, the company said.</p>
<p>In addition to the Detroit Free Press, the company publishes the Miami Herald, Philadelphia Inquirer and 28 other newspapers in the United States.</p>
<p>The company said it would invest heavily in a plan to make its Knight-Ridder Information service available on the World Wide Web portion of the Internet, depressing profits at the unit through 1998 in a bid to bolster results in the long run.</p>
<p>Times Mirror Co., based in Los Angeles, said earnings rose to $55.7 million, or 43 cents a share, from $37.1 million, or 21 cents a share, in the 1995 quarter. The year-ago period excludes $435 million in one-time charges and losses from a restructuring programme and discontinued operations.</p>
<p>Revenues grew 2 percent to $885.6 million from $864.8 million.</p>
<p>Times Mirror said results were paced by its newspaper group, where operating profit more than doubled in the quarter as ad revenues grew 4 percent and expenses fell due to the cost-cutting programme and lower newsprint costs.</p>
<p>The company publishes the Los Angeles Times, Newsday and The Baltimore Sun, as well as other newspapers and magazines.</p>
<p>The company announced the charges a year ago as Mark Willes, who joined as president and chief executive officer last year, closed New York Newsday, Baltimore's Evening Sun and parts of the Los Angeles Times in a bid to cut costs.</p>
<p>The Washington Post Co. cited revenue gains in newspapers, broadcasting and at Newsweek magazine. It said net income grew to $55.4 million, or $5 a share, from $41.8 million, or $3.79 a share. Revenues grew to $460.3 million from $417.9 million.</p>
<p>Knight-Ridder stock fell $1 to $36.625, Times Mirror lost 25 cents to $44.875 and Washington Post fell $3.375 to $330.875, all on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
