<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134202" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India moves to install new government in key state.</title>
<headline>India moves to install new government in key state.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian cabinet has decided to revoke New Delhi's direct rule of the western state of Gujarat, paving the way for the formation of a new local government, the Press Trust of India said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Gujarat was brought under New Delhi's direct rule last month after the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) split into two there, forcing the fall of its government in one of India's most prosperous regions.</p>
<p>The Hindu-nationalist BJP, the single largest party in the federal parliament, looks unlikely to recapture power in the state and instead BJP rebels backed by the Congress party of former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao's seem set to take office.</p>
<p>The rebels, the Mahagujarat Janata Party (MJP), have 50 members and Congress 44 in the 181-seat state assembly, giving them, on paper, a majority.</p>
<p>PTI said the cabinet's decision came a day after the MJP presented its claim to the Gujarat governor to form a new government.</p>
<p>The agency said the MJP elected Shankarsinh Vaghela as the party's leader on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The state governor had asked the BJP, ruling the state until the party split in August, to prove its majority by Tuesday.</p>
<p>But a BJP spokesman said the party was not planning to meet the condition. The BJP won 121 seats in Gujarat assembly polls in March last year. August's split reduced its presence to 82 seats and there are apparently no supporters in the assembly to give it majority for a second time.</p>
<p>PTI said Gujarat governor Krishna Pal Singh had told the federal government that direct presidential rule could be lifted as he believed a stable state government could now be formed.</p>
<p>The formation of a non-BJP government in Gujarat would be a major blow to the BJP whose campaign to capture federal power in Delhi suffered a setback earlier this month in the most populous state of Uttar Pradesh.</p>
<p>The BJP won 177 seats in the 425-seat Uttar Pradesh assembly polls, belying pre-poll predictions of a wider lead.</p>
<p>Uttar Pradesh, with 140 million people, is regarded as the main launching pad of the party which rose from the political fringes to become India's main opposition party in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
