<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134218" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India, Russia begin defence talks.</title>
<headline>India, Russia begin defence talks.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov met Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda on Tuesday amid reports that New Delhi was ready to pay $1.8 billion for 40 warplanes.</p>
<p>Rodionov, who arrived in the Indian capital on Monday, was expected to sign a defence cooperation agreement during his three-day visit, the first by a Russian defence minister to India, officials said.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency said India had confirmed its intention to buy 40 multi-purpose Sukhoi Su-30 jets for a total of $1.8 billion. The Press Trust of India (PTI) said the deal was expected to figure in Rodionov's talks with Indian leaders.</p>
<p>But a Russian embassy official said the visiting minister was not expected to sign a warplane deal. &quot;The visiting minister cannot sign the agreement on the sale of planes as that involves more than one organisation,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Indian Defence Ministry said details of the talks were expected to be released later.</p>
<p>As the former Soviet Union's main non-communist ally, India was one of Moscow's biggest arms clients.</p>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin visited India in January 1993, helping clinch a debt repayment pact covering money which New Delhi owed Moscow mainly for military purchases.</p>
<p>Relations soured again after the United States forced Moscow to cancel a $250 million sale of cryogenic rocket engines on the grounds they could be used to build missiles.</p>
<p>But Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov's Indian visit last March helped revive relations.</p>
<p>During Primakov's visit, the two countries agreed to set up a &quot;hotline&quot; telephone link between New Delhi and Moscow for the leaders of the two countries to hold crisis talks.</p>
<p>PTI said agreements on the training of Indian military personnel and a new service-to-service exchange between the armed forces of the two countries were likely to be finalised during Rodionov's visit.</p>
<p>The news agency said India was also interested in buying MSTA-S self-propelled howitzers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
