<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13420" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco stocks rebound after win in Indiana case.</title>
<headline>Tobacco stocks rebound after win in Indiana case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tobacco stocks rallied Monday after an Indiana jury sided with tobacco companies on Friday in a case filed by the widow of a smoker who died of lung cancer.</p>
<p>The stocks have taken a beating since early August after a jury in Florida found Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp. liable for $750,000 in a separate case filed by the family of a smoker who had lung cancer. That verdict -- only the second time a jury had ever awarded damages against a cigarette maker -- sent shudders through the industry and across Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a small victory for tobacco stocks,&quot; Peter Cardillo, research director at Westfalia Investments, said of the Indiana ruling. &quot;The market is going to have a positive reaction.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares of Philip Morris Cos. Inc., the world's largest cigarette maker, rose $2.875 to $90.875, RJR Nabisco, owner of R.J. Reynolds Tobacco, added $1.125 to $26.625, and Loews Corp., parent of Lorillard Tobacco, jumped $1.75 to $76.50, all on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>UST, owner of United States Tobacco, the nation's biggest smokeless tobacco maker, added 37.5 cents to $31, also on the NYSE.</p>
<p>While the victory in the Indiana case was welcomed by the industry, legal experts said the case was a tiny skirmish in a full-blown war.</p>
<p>President Clinton on Friday announced strict new rules to control tobacco sales and advertising -- including requiring proof of age to buy cigarettes. Fourteen states as well as San Francisco and Los Angeles have sued the industry to recoup health care costs of smokers.</p>
<p>In the Indiana case, a jury found for R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., Philip Morris, The American Tobacco Co., now owned by Brown &amp; Williamson, and Liggett Group Inc., the smallest of the nation's major tobacco companies.</p>
<p>The suit had been filed by the family of Richard Rogers, an Indianapolis lawyer who died aged 52 in 1987. They sought unspecified damages, contending that the tobacco industry peddled an addictive product that caused Rogers' cancer.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the Rogers family said during the trial that he knew he was addicted and tried to quit, but the industry, by selling an addictive product, took that choice away from him.</p>
<p>Tobacco industry lawyers countered that Rogers for at least 20 years was exposed to warning labels on cigarette packs and should have been fully aware of the risks.</p>
<p>Tobacco stocks had fallen as much as 20 percent since the Aug. 9 verdict in the Florida case. Experts said there was a major difference between the Florida and Indiana cases: the Jacksonville, Fla., jury had seen inflammatory internal tobacco documents relating to the industry's knowledge of nicotine and addiction while the Indianapolis jury had not.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
