<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134394" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Digital falls, bigger than expected Q1 loss.</title>
<headline>Digital falls, bigger than expected Q1 loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Digital Equipment Corp fell after the company reported a wider-than-expected first quarter loss and several analysts started cutting earnings estimates after its conference call.</p>
<p>Digital shares were off 2-3/4 to 31-5/8 in very active trading after the company reported a first quarter loss of $0.48 a share, much bigger than the consensus estimate of a $0.14 per share loss.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is, it was a lousy quarter,&quot; said one trader. Cowen &amp; Co analyst Richard Chu confirmed that he cut his rating on Digital to a neutral from a buy.  </p>
<p>Chu said he was looking at cutting his earnings estimates, but he declined to be any more specific until later. Traders said that he was looking at cutting his fiscal 1997 estimate from $3.70 per share to between $1.00 and $1.70 per share.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley analyst Steve Milunovich also cut his Digital estimate for fiscal year 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The guidance near-term is fairly cautious,&quot; Milunovich said.</p>
<p>&quot;I question whether the slowdown in Alpha servers is totally due to the sales reorganization,&quot; he said, adding that Digital may have lost momentum due to increased compeition.  </p>
<p>Milunovich noted that Digital is citing a $0.45 negative hit from currency as adding to its losses.</p>
<p>&quot;They do a lot of business in Europe,&quot; Milunovich said, adding that Digital saw very little benefit from cutting expenses in the quarter.</p>
<p>Milunovich said that Digital expects a modest profit in the second quarter and that its troubled personal computer business is also expected to reach a break-even point.</p>
<p>Milunovich also said he was surprised by the steep 11 percent drop in revenues in the quarter. &quot;They were short on revenues,&quot; he said, adding that he had forecast flat revenues in the first quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
