<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13436" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>Ukraine: FEATURE - Fertile Ukraine faces drought of cash and rain.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Fertile Ukraine faces drought of cash and rain.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>BATKIVSHCHYNA COLLECTIVE FARM, Ukraine 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four shiny new green-and-yellow John Deere combines parked at this 1,750-hectare (4,325-acre) farm in the grain-growing regions south of Kiev don't fill its chief agronomist with enthusiasm.</p>
<p>&quot;They did a good job this year, but they need good diesel and good engine oil,&quot; said Ivan Odnosum. &quot;God help us if there is a breakdown,&quot; he said of the machinery, loaned to the farm after the Ukrainian government bought it earlier this year.</p>
<p>The country's grain harvest this year is forecast to fall by more than 23 percent to only 28 million tonnes and two harsh factors are to blame.</p>
<p>A drought scoured the steppes in May and June, stunting the growing wheat. And the farming sector, making the painful transition from Soviet central planning to a market economy simply has no money.</p>
<p>Ukraine's black soil is so fertile that a diplomat described it as &quot;rich enough to grow rubber boots&quot;.</p>
<p>But recently Ukraine has been losing its reputation as a breadbasket of Europe, earned in the years before brutal forced collectivisation under Soviet dictator Josef Stalin.</p>
<p>&quot;The wheat will not be of a good quality this year,&quot; said Hryhory Borsuk, a scientist at the Mironivka Wheat Institute, run by the Ukrainian Academy of Agrarian Sciences.</p>
<p>&quot;The temperature on the ground reached 62 decrees Celsius (143.60 Fahrenheit) this summer. We've never seen anything so bad,&quot; he said in an interview in his office, unlit since the government cut off electricity because of unpaid power bills.</p>
<p>The harvest is gathered in the dry areas, but rainfall in Western Ukraine has delayed harvesting there.</p>
<p>While Mironivka's scientists, some unpaid for months, carry on developing new strains of wheat resistant to Ukraine's extreme continental climate, Borsuk said the lack of cash in Ukraine's agricultural sector is as bad as the drought.</p>
<p>Collective farms and Ukraine's nascent private farming sector have no money for fertiliser, no money for herbicides and pesticides, no money to repair old or buy new machinery, no money for fuel, and none to buy good seed.</p>
<p>This year's harvest is down from last year's 36.5 million tonne harvest, which in turn compares with  50 million tonnes in 1990, the year before independence.</p>
<p>The decline is all the worse for people who recall wasteful Soviet times, when the Kremlin imported grain but priced bread so cheaply that people bought it to feed their pigs.</p>
<p>&quot;Agriculture is very expensive, and there are no solutions to our problems on the horizon,&quot; said Odnosum.</p>
<p>He said his farm, its 260 workers now readying the fields for winter wheat sowing, expected the land to yield 5.2 tonnes per hectare (2.5 acres) but ended up with 3.9 tonnes -- still better than the national average of 2.11 tonnes per hectare this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not have money for fertiliser, we're in debt for fuel, and we're borrowing diesel,&quot; Odnosum said.</p>
<p>A few kilometres (miles) down the two-lane road which passes Odnosum's farm, where the occasional horse-drawn buggy passes by, is the 1,700-hectare (4,200-acre) Shevchenko collective farm, built next to a village still neat and tidy despite post-Soviet decay.</p>
<p>Chief Accountant Natalya Sypron said the collective is strapped for cash, earlier this year bartering 220 tonnes of grain for diesel to fuel six rickety grain combines and tractors badly in need of repairs and basic maintenance.</p>
<p>The average family earns 160-200 million karbovanets a year ($800-$1,000) -- but many have not been paid in months, Soprun said. &quot;People are working out of their own dedication.&quot;</p>
<p>Borsuk said the farm sector has two options: &quot;We can sit down and cry, or we can do something.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the government plans to increase the sowing of the winter wheat which will be harvested next year.</p>
<p>Planted in late summer and early autumn, the grain is Ukraine's largest export item and traditionally grows better than summer wheat in Ukraine's soil.</p>
<p>Further plans, he said, called for full provision of resources like fertiliser and herbicides for 25 percent of Ukraine's arable land next year, for 50 percent in 1998 and 100 percent of the land in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;If we follow this we'll be able to sell 10 million tonnes of grain by the year 2000,&quot; Borkus said.</p>
<p>The government has been trying to phase out huge subsidies to the farm sector, and in a move back to pre-Soviet days has given up to 50 hectares (124 acres) of land to some 36,000 private farmers willing to go it alone.</p>
<p>Collective farms will last for the next few years, because most private farms now only produce enough to feed themselves with maybe a little extra to sell, said one private farmer: &quot;In the future, maybe, but it's better not to hurry.</p>
<p>&quot;Collectivisation brought us a lot of pain. And it went too fast. Privatising too quickly can also have a negative outcome.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATKIVSHCHYNA COLLECTIVE FARM, Ukraine"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
