<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134398" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ABC Rail sees FY '97 Q1 below last year.</title>
<headline>ABC Rail sees FY '97 Q1 below last year.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABC Rail Products Corp said Tuesday it expects to report lower sales and substantially lower earnings for its fiscal 1997 first quarter ending October 31, 1996.</p>
<p>ABC Rail, which makes and markets replacement products and original equipment for the railroad industry, said it expects fiscal 1997 first quarter earnings per share possibly as low as $0.05 compared with the $0.27 reported a year ago.</p>
<p>The current backlog is $38 million and sales for the first quarter are expected to approximate $54 million compared with $58.6 million reported a year earlier, it said in a statement.  </p>
<p>ABC Rail said it upgraded equipment and processes at its wheel foundry and trackwork plants which resulted in production slowdowns. However, the company said the upgrades were part of the company's strategic plan to sharply improve manufacturing efficiencies.</p>
<p>The company is upgrading its foundry processes at its Calera, Ala., rail and idler wheel plant. It is also restructuring its trackwork plants in the areas of manufacturing, engineering design and order processing in Chicago Heights, Ill., Pueblo, Colo., Anderson, Ind., and Superior, Wis., to significantly cut lead times and reduce inventories. The upgrades require major reconfiguring of the shop floors' layouts into cell manufacturing centers.</p>
<p>&quot;The seasonal lull -- coupled with the new orders expected now that the Union Pacific-Southern Pacific merger is complete -- made this an opportune time to absorb a mild short-term setback in exchange for improved capacity and profitability in the long term,&quot; ABC Rail Chairman Donald Grinter said in a statement.</p>
<p>ABC Rail shares were trading off 1/8 to 16.</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
