<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134314" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British cable merger competitive, boost to sector.</title>
<headline>British cable merger competitive, boost to sector.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless Communications, the major new UK cable player formed from a group led by Cable &amp; Wireless Plc, has scope and size to make it competitive, analysts said, and focuses attention on the fast-growing area.</p>
<p>&quot;The logic is irrefutable...the advantages of scope and size are undoubtedly there,&quot; said Societe Generale Strauss Turnbull analyst John Tysoe.</p>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless, NYNEX Corp of the U.S. and Bell Canada International announced they would merge the operations of their British subsidiaries in a complex deal, culminating in a float of 15 percent of the new company.  </p>
<p>&quot;That creates an integrated second force, which will give BT a run for its money,&quot; Tysoe said.</p>
<p>Shares in Cable &amp; Wireless were up 25 pence to 466 pence by 1221 GMT, after touching a high of 476-1/2 pence, while NYNEX Cable Communications gained 27-1/2 pence to 123-1/2 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a jolly bold and impressive move,&quot; said one sector analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>The merger should result in &quot;quite significant&quot; cost savings, said Chris McFadden of Merrill Lynch, including tax offsets, refinancing of high yield cable television funding and possibly through staff cuts.  </p>
<p>&quot;The new company can offer the complete range of services and it will be competing with BT in the franchises which it operates,&quot; the sector analyst said.</p>
<p>Analysts added that the deal was expected to be slightly earnings dilutive in the first year but enhancing from year two.</p>
<p>BT's shares edged down four pence to 354 pence as the market weighed the emergence of a new competitor.</p>
<p>But BT welcomed the consolidation in the sector, saying it would create a market &quot;where competition can become the natural regulator.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts said BT's calls to be allowed into cable television provision, which the Conservative government has so far rebuffed, could gain impetus from the emergence of Cable &amp; Wireless Communications.</p>
<p>For other cable companies, the move has focused market attention, which had been flagging, back on the fast-growing sector, analysts said, with valuations now looking a little low.</p>
<p>&quot;People are reassessing the value (of cable companies), there could be more consolidation, they have to respond,&quot; McFadden said, adding that calculations suggested a 2.9 billion stg tag for C&amp;W's Mercury unit from the deal.  </p>
<p>The cable market in the UK is growing fast, with around 7.5 million homes now within striking distance of connections, as around six billion stg has already been invested in building cable networks and a further six billion stg is planned.</p>
<p>Telewest Communications jumped 12 pence to 135p, while General Cable gained 18p to 197p.</p>
<p>The new company will eclipse its rivals in terms of market share, with 2.47 million homes passed compared with its nearest rival, Telewest, with around two million.</p>
<p>But analysts said it will not be in direct competition with other cable network companies as they mainly operate in different franchises.</p>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless Communications may flex another strength in securing more favourable terms for programming from BSkyB, the satellite broadcaster in which Rupert Murdoch's News Corp has 40 percent stake, analysts said.</p>
<p>BSkyB shares were down 16-1/2p to 680p, after touching a low of 678p.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that is why BSkyB has come under pressure, people think the merged company might secure more attractive rates,&quot; the sector analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Jo Winterbottom, London Newsroom +44 171 5427717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
