<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13438" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Liam Gallagher pulls out of Oasis's U.S. tour.</title>
<headline>Liam Gallagher pulls out of Oasis's U.S. tour.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liam Gallagher, the lead singer with British rock superstars Oasis, pulled out of the group's U.S. tour at the last minute on Monday -- to go house-hunting.</p>
<p>Gallagher, 23, refused to board a plane at London's Heathrow airport shortly before the chart-topping band was due to leave for Chicago at the start of a three-week tour.</p>
<p>Speaking later outside the house he shares in the plush St John's Wood district of London with actress Patsy Kensit, Gallagher said he urgently needed to hunt for a new home.</p>
<p>&quot;The house has just been sold and I'm having moving problems. We have go to be out by the weekend. I am not going around touring in the U.S. when I've got nowhere to live,&quot; he told reporters, according to British newspaper reports.</p>
<p>Gallagher said he might fly out later to join Oasis, who have been described as the Beatles of the nineties.</p>
<p>In the meantime Liam's brother, guitarist Noel, will sing in his place. The two have had a frequently fiery relationship.</p>
<p>&quot;The band are going to try to do it without me. If they can't do it I guess I'll go back. I don't care about the tour. I am sick of living my life in hotels. I need to be happy. I've got to find a place to live,&quot; Liam was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>It was the second time in days the temperamental star had let down his fans.</p>
<p>On Friday Gallagher failed to appear on stage when Oasis performed for 400 select fans at London's Royal Festival Hall.</p>
<p>Instead, he watched the show from a private box, pleading a sore throat.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Oasis's record company, Creation Records, said Gallagher had no intention of quitting the band.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
