<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134307" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: INSTANT VIEW - Canadian consumer price index.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Canadian consumer price index.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a selection of analysts reactions for the consumer price index for Canada, released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>DAVID ROSENBERG, SENIOR ECONOMIST WITH NESBITT BURNS:</p>
<p>&quot;I think these numbers bode very well for further Bank of Canada easing and I think continued bond market outperformance vis-a-vis the U.S.&quot;  </p>
<p>MARK MULLINS, CHIEF ECONOMIST WITH MIDLAND WALWYN CAPITAL INC.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally speaking, these are completely in line with the Bank of Canada inflation targets and given that the market is opening the way for another rate cut there's no reason why they wouldn't want to jump on top of it.  </p>
<p>HARVINDER KALIRAI, CANADIAN ANALYST WITH FINANCIAL ANALYSIS FIRM I.D.E.A.</p>
<p>&quot;The highlight of the data I'd say was the dip in the year-on-year core rate to 1.2 percent. That's the lowest it has been since January 1995. It's very close to testing the floor of the Bank of Canada's 1.0-3.0 percent target. Given the fact of the sluggish domestic economy, wide output gap and still subdued price pressures, it gives further incentive for the Bank of Canada to keep easing rates.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
