<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134380" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: American Home Q3 drug sales up six pct.</title>
<headline>American Home Q3 drug sales up six pct.</headline>
<dateline>MADISON, N.J. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Home Products Corp said on Tuesday that its third quarter worldwide pharmaceutical sales rose six percent to $2.0 billion.</p>
<p>Its U.S. drug sales increased 13 percent in the quarter, driven by anti-obesity products Pondimin and Redux and Premarin hormone replacement therapies.</p>
<p>Some cardiovascular drugs had lower sales in the quarter, the company said, although it did not provide details.</p>
<p>International drug sales rose five percent in the quarter, American Home said.  </p>
<p>Its worldwide drug sales rose 10 percent on a pro forma basis --  reflecting all businesss disposed of, discontinued or acquired in 1996 and 1995, the company said.</p>
<p>American Home reported third quarter earnings of $0.77 a share, up from $0.64 a year ago excluding a charge. The quarter's earnings were in line with Wall Street consensus.</p>
<p>American Home said its consumer health care sales were flat in the quarter on both a reported and pro forma basis at $564.7 million. The division's U.S. sales rose one percent, while its international sales were flat.</p>
<p>Medical device sales rose 12 percent on a reported basis to $321.1 million in the quarter but were off five percent on a pro forma basis, the company said.</p>
<p>Agricultural products rose four percent to $304.2 million on both pro forma and reported basis. U.S. agricultural product sales fell six percent while international agriculture sales gained nine percent.</p>
<p>Sales of food products rose 22 percent on both a pro forma and reported basis to $254.8 million in the quarter. Last month the company said it was selling 80 percent of the food unit to private investment firm Hicks, Muse, Tate &amp; Furst Inc for $1.2 billion in cash.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADISON, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
