<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13431" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan outlines economic reforms after riots.</title>
<headline>Jordan outlines economic reforms after riots.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan announced measures to boost private investment in the economy and create jobs in the wake of bread riots, officials and businessmen said on Monday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Abdul Karim al-Kabariti told them late on Sunday the government's commitment to free market reforms was unaffected by riots that followed the doubling of bread prices, the worst unrest in Jordan since 1989.</p>
<p>Kabariti pledged a two-pronged policy of encouraging private sector investment while strengthening a safety net to protect Jordan's poor, the majority of its 4.2 million people, during the transition period.</p>
<p>Businessmen welcomed the package they believe meets long-standing demands, adding it showed the government's resolve to go ahead despite the political cost shown by the riots.</p>
<p>Some remain sceptical the government will be able to proceed quickly to trim red tape and a stifling bureaucracy they blame for deterring private investment, seen as the real solution to Jordan's economic woes.</p>
<p>Kabariti said the government had drafted key laws to boost export industries and attract foreign investment to create jobs. Unemployment and poverty were widely blamed for the bread riots this month.</p>
<p>Jordanian officials say unemployment is 15 percent of a 900,000 labour force but economists believe it is at least 25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The economic package will include improving the investment climate by new economic legislation and amending existing laws ...and proceeding with privatisation,&quot; Kabariti said.</p>
<p>He also announced the ending in September of tariffs on 492 items to boost industrial investment, and an end to inspection of certain imports for industry to cut red tape under a new customs law.</p>
<p>Kabariti promised several new laws: a companies law that would ease taxation on companies raising capital, a securities law for the stock market, a law to prohibit dumping of imports by foreign countries, a law against monopolies and a law to create mutual funds to channel small savings.</p>
<p>Kabariti defended the decision to double bread prices but acknowledged policies during a transition period may cause social upheaval.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not deny that we are passing through a difficult transitionary phase on the economic and social level and the battle is intensifying at the cross-roads,&quot; Kabariti said.</p>
<p>But he vowed not to backtrack on reforms that harmed &quot;vested interests and marginal producers&quot; cushioned by what he termed structural distortions that harm ordinary citizens.</p>
<p>The IMF-sanctioned plan to remove bread subsidies was needed before implementation of broader free market reforms which have been delayed by successive governments since Jordan embarked on monetary stabilisation reforms after a severe economic crisis in 1989.</p>
<p>Officials say the World Bank and the IMF have pledged support to expand a safety net for Jordan's poor during the reforms to prevent social upheaval.</p>
<p>Kabariti said the government would spend more to develop infrastructure in poor areas of the kingdom, enhance vocational training for unemployed youths and extend credit to small businesses.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
