<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134386" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAL sees slight rise in Q4 load factor.</title>
<headline>UAL sees slight rise in Q4 load factor.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Airlines parent UAL Corp said Tuesday it expects to show a slight increase in its passenger load factor in the fourth quarter compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Fourth quarter bookings look very good,&quot; John Edwardson, president, told reporters in a teleconference.</p>
<p>He added that fuel costs are still an issue for United, but some relief is expected.</p>
<p>Jet fuel costs for the fourth quarter are expected to decline to about $0.78 a gallon from $0.80 early in the quarter, he said.  </p>
<p>Edwardson said UAL generated cash flow of $923 million in the third quarter, which was partially used to pre-pay debt and also to purchase aircraft.</p>
<p>The company said it retired $63 million in principal amount of long-term debt in the third quarter, which was part of its continuing efforts to achieve an investment-grade credt rating.</p>
<p>UAL also said that this debt retirement, combined with similar initiatives completed in the first and second quarters, will save more than $100 million annually in gross interest expense and dividends.  </p>
<p>&quot;A continuing theme at the company is to move towards an investment grade credit rating,&quot; Edwardson said. &quot;We continue to hope that this will happen within about an 18-month period. And we have made great progress (toward this goal) and are actually ahead of schedule.&quot;</p>
<p>Also in the the third quarter, UAL took a pretax charge of $30 million, or $19 million after tax, to write-down the value of aircraft seats.</p>
<p>Edwardson said improving aircraft seats is part of United's efforts to improve customer satisfaction. &quot;Our customers tell us they're (seats) uncomfortable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another customer issue, he added, is on-time performance. United currently rates fourth among the 10 major airlines in on-time performance, Edwardson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be working hard to improve on-time performance this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that, for the first time, executive compensation for about 600 people will be linked to on-time performance.</p>
<p>He later said it's unclear at this time how compensation and on-time performance will be linked.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
