<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134448" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tenneco cites packaging, auto parts for rise.</title>
<headline>Tenneco cites packaging, auto parts for rise.</headline>
<dateline>GREENWICH, Conn. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tenneco Inc Tuesday reported a 26 percent rise in third quarter earnings per share from continuing operations saying its specialty packaging, auto parts and energy businesses contributed significant increases in operating income.</p>
<p>Earnings per share from continuing operations rose to $0.67 from $0.53 cents in the year-ago period. Profit in the latest quarter amounted to $0.78 per share prior to a reserve of $0.11 at Newport News Shipbuilding.</p>
<p>Operating income increased 13 percent to $282 million after the Newport News Shipbuilding reserve of $31 million.  </p>
<p>The reserve covered estimated contract losses related to construction of commercial product tankers at Newport News Shipbuilding.</p>
<p>Quarterly revenues increased 31 percent,to $2.8 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The solid performance of our specialty packaging and automotive parts businesses in the third quarter again demonstrated the great potential of the two businesses that will comprise the new Tenneco going forward,&quot; said chief executive Dana G. Mead. &quot;We are building a less cyclical, faster-growing global manufacturer with strong brand names and leading market positions.&quot;  </p>
<p>The third quarter results included the initial results from two recent acquisitions.  Clevite, acquired in late June, added $57 million in revenues for Tenneco Automotive and the former Amoco Foam Products unit, acquired by Packaging in late August, added another $28 million in revenues. Both businesses contributed operating income well above management expectations at the time of the acquisitions, Tenneco said.</p>
<p>Tenneco Automotive reported record quarter-over-quarter revenues for the 12th consecutive quarter and a record for the third quarter in operating income.  </p>
<p>Specialty packaging also set records in both operating income and revenues in the quarter. Moreover, Tenneco said, Automotive and Packaging significantly exceeded the average performance of their respective industry peer groups.</p>
<p>Linerboard pricing was at the lowest level in three years. However, Packaging's profitability was significantly higher than in the previous linerboard pricing downturn as it continued to shift its business focus toward higher valued-added products, Tenneco said.</p>
<p>These include new high-end graphics capabilities in containers for industrial customers and consumer products.  </p>
<p>&quot;Packaging and Automotive have maintained or increased market share this year as leaders in several product categories,&quot; Mead said. &quot;New product introductions, acquisitions, aggressive marketing programs and successful cost reduction efforts continue to strengthen their competitive positions.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said its program to improve processes reduced failure costs by $114 million in the quarter, adding $71 million to operating income.</p>
<p>Mead said Tenneco expects to complete restructuring actions in December that include the spin off of Newport News Shipbuilding, the merger of Tenneco Energy with El Paso Energy, and the creation of a &quot;new&quot; Tenneco consisting of the Packaging and Automotive divisions.</p>
<p>The actions, announced earlier this year, are subject to a favorable ruling by the Internal Revenue Service, review by the Securities and Exchange Commission, and approval by Tenneco shareowners.  -- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GREENWICH, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
