<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134414" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Philip Morris Q3 up on cigarette volume.</title>
<headline>Philip Morris Q3 up on cigarette volume.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philip Morris Cos Inc said it registered double-digit earnings gains in its third quarter as a result of higher worldwide cigarette volume and solid North American food volume gains.</p>
<p>The company said worldwide tobacco operating revenues rose by 12.6 percent to $9.5 billion in the third quarter, while operating income rose 15.9 percent to $2.2 billion.</p>
<p>Philip Morris sold 238 billion cigarettes in the third quarter, an increase of 9.3 percent over last year, while volume for its top-selling brand, Marlboro, advanced 11 percent on both domestic and international gains.  </p>
<p>International tobacco sales rose 12.9 percent to $6.2 billion in the third quarter, and domestic sales grew 12.2 percent to $3.3 billion, Philip Morris said. Cigarrette shipments totalled 60.4 billion, up 7.8 percent from last year.</p>
<p>Third quarter shipments of Marlboro cigarettes rose 13 percent to 41.2 billion cigarettes, it said. Marlboro reached a 32.8 percent share of industry shipments, up 3.2 points over 1995. Retail share for the Marlboro brand rose 3.1 points to 33.7 percent, helping to raise the company's total retail share of the premium segment to a record 58 percent, it said.  </p>
<p>Worldwide food revenues rose 2.7 percent to $6.7 billion in the third quarter, while operating income increased 7.8 percent to $941 million, according to the firm.</p>
<p>It said the revenue growth reflected volume gains, and the inclusion of sales from previously unconsolidated businesses. Income improvement was driven by volume gains in North America and Europe, improved margins and continued cost reductions.</p>
<p>The company said third quarter profit growth at Kraft Foods was outstanding, as income from operations in the U.S. and Canada reached $642 million, up 9.4 percent on volume gains, higher margins and continued productivity savings.  </p>
<p>Operating revenues at Kraft were $4.1 billion, 4.1 percent ahead of last year.</p>
<p>Third quarter international food operating income climbed 4.5 percent to $299 million, while revenues grew slightly to $2.6 billion, it said. International income growth was driven by volume gains in Europe and improved product mix.</p>
<p>Beer revenues fell 3.9 percent in the third quarter to $1.1 billion at the company's Miller Brewing Co division. Total worldwide volume declined 6.5 percent to 11.4 million barrels, on softness in most of Miller's major brands in the U.S. and in international business.  </p>
<p>The domestic beer shipment decline was largely driven by reductions in distributor inventory levels during the quarter, according to the company.</p>
<p>During the quarter, Miller took a number of actions to restore growth and streamline its organization. These included the announced elimination of about 500 salaried positions to take effect in November, and the reorientation of media spending to increase both exposure and efficiency in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Philip Morris hit another home run in the quarter,&quot; said chairman and chief executive Geoffrey Bible.</p>
<p>&quot;Our three largest businesses are absolutely flying, with terrific momentum in both domestic and international tobacco, and growth in North American food that is clearly outstanding by industry standards. Our international food business is also continuing to show progress, and we're moving aggressively to reinvigorate our beer business.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;With three quarters already in the bank, we're heading toward year-end in great shape,&quot; Bible said.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
