<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134428" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Avon Products Q3 U.S., intl sales rise.</title>
<headline>Avon Products Q3 U.S., intl sales rise.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Avon Products Inc said on Tuesday that U.S. sales in the third quarter increased 10 percent, helped by strong orders and increases in the average order size and the number of customers.</p>
<p>Overall international operations also posted a 10 percent sales increase, boosted by strong global growth in the number of active sales representatives and customers, Avon said. Excluding the impact of foreign currency, sales rose 22 percent in the quarter, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are particularly pleased with the strong performance of the U.S. and Latin America in the quarter, as well as with the rapid growth in the emerging markets of Asia Pacific and Russia,&quot; said James Preston, chairman and chief executive officer. &quot;We're well on the way to our eighth consecutive year of increased sales and earnings.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said its color cosmetics, fragrance, personal care and gift products all posted solid gains over last year's third quarter.</p>
<p>In the Americas region, Avon said sales rose 11 percent in the third quarter and pretax profits rose 17 percent.  </p>
<p>Avon said almost all of its markets in the Americas performed better. Mexico, down in last year's third quarter due to a weak economy after the peso's devaluation, saw sharp increases in sales and pretax profits in this year's quarter, the company said. Brazil sustained last year's strong performance, it said.</p>
<p>In the Pacific region, sales rose 9 percent in the third quarter with strong growth in almost all of the region's markets, Avon said. But pretax profits declined 20 percent in the region in the third quarter, due mainly to the ongoing operating challenges in Japan.</p>
<p>Sales growth was particularly strong in the Philippines, Malaysia and China, the company said.</p>
<p>Pretax profits were also down in Europe, due to investments in new customer access programs, Avon said.</p>
<p>But third quarter sales there rose 9 percent, driven by rapid expansion in Russia and Central Europe as well as solid gains in the U.K.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
