<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134445" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: VW top execs must face GM charges-US court.</title>
<headline>VW top execs must face GM charges-US court.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volkswagen AG Chairman Ferdinand Piech and management board member Jens Neumann must remain as defendants in General Motors Corp.'s industrial espionage lawsuit against the German automaker, a federal judge decided on Monday.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Nancy Edmunds has not yet issued a written opinion, but told lawyers in the case on Monday that she will deny VW's motion to exclude Piech and Neumann from the suit, a court clerk said Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Edmunds also ruled that Volkswagen AG, in addition to its Volkswagen of America Inc subsidiary, must continue to defend itself against GM's charges.</p>
<p>GM alleges that Volkswagen's production chief, Jose Ignacio Lopez de Arriortua, conspired with Piech, Neumann and others to steal GM corporate secrets when he left GM to join VW in March 1993. GM claims Lopez and several executives who followed him to VW took vital parts pricing data, future product plans and proprietary manufacturing techniques, along with other information. The lawsuit seeks unspecified damages.  </p>
<p>Edmunds last week denied VW's motion to dismiss the case, a decision that allows GM its day in court in the heartland of the U.S. auto industry instead of in Germany.</p>
<p>In a hearing last week, lawyers for GM argued that Piech and Neumann should remain as defendants in the lawsuit based on claims that they conspired with Lopez to steal the secrets when they hired him away from GM.  </p>
<p>Lawyers for VW argued that the two executives should be dismissed from the case because of their infrequent visits to the United States and GM's lack of proof of their direct involvement in the events dealt with in the case.</p>
<p>But Edmunds last week said that GM's complaint contained a lot of detail and merited further consideration in regard to Piech's and Neumann's roles.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a bare-bones complaint. It names names, it cites dates of lunch meetings and phone conversations,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>A GM spokesman said in a statement that the Detroit-based automaker was pleased that Edmunds extended the court's jurisdiction over Piech, Neuman and the VW parent company.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's ruling reinforces our confidence that the substantial dmaages we suffered in connection with Lopez' departure for VW will be remedied,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On October 28, Edmunds will hear oral arguments on VW's motions to dismiss other GM claims in the case, including those accusing VW of copyright and trademark infringement, that VW engaged in unfair trade practices and that it conspired in violation of the federal Racketeer-Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) Act.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
