<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134416" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nissan to boost North American output.</title>
<headline>Nissan to boost North American output.</headline>
<dateline>TORRANCE, Calif. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nissan North America Inc said Tuesday it will increase North American production by about 150,000 units over the next three years to meet U.S. sales goals of 900,000 units by 2000.</p>
<p>Part of the increase will come from adding a new model at Nissan Motor Manufacturing Corp in Smyrna, Tenn.  Nissan North America, a unit of Nissan Motor Co Ltd, did not provide details of the new model.</p>
<p>Industry reports have said previously that Nissan plans to make 40,000 to 50,000 units of a new small sport/utility vehicle at the plant for introduction in the fall of 1998.  </p>
<p>Nissan said it plans to shift production of its Sentra compact sedan to the company's manufacturing facility in Aguascalientes, Mexico, from Smyrna. The automaker's pickup truck and Altima midsize sedan will continue to be made in Smyrna.</p>
<p>Nissan's Mexican operations have been producing a limited number of Sentras for the U.S. market since May 1995. Nissan expects to make all U.S. Sentras in Mexico by 2000.</p>
<p>Shifting Sentra to Mexico will allow the company to more fully utilize its Aguascalientes plant, free capacity at Smyrna and increase production without additional investment for expanding production capacity, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;With Smyrna running at full speed the last few years, nearly 70 percent of what we sell here is manufactured in the U.S.,&quot; said Minoru Nakamura, president of Nissan North America, in a statement.</p>
<p>Nissan Motor Manufacturing said production is scheduled to begin next spring at a new $80 million facility in Decherd, Tenn., that will make engines and transaxles for Nissan vehicles.  Including the new parts plant, Nissan Motor Manufacturing has invested $1.43 billion into its operations, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORRANCE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
