<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13440" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: McLaren F1 team to switch sponsors after 23 years.</title>
<headline>McLaren F1 team to switch sponsors after 23 years.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Maclaren formula one motor racing team is to switch sponsorship from Marlboro to Germany's Reemtsma, makers of West cigarettes, at the end of this year McLaren said in a statement on Monday.</p>
<p>Since 1974, McLaren has been virtually synonymous with the Marlboro brand, winning nine drivers' world titles and seven constructors' titles, but the relationship will end with the last race of this year in Japan in October.</p>
<p>The five-year deal with Reemtsma includes a change of name to the &quot;West McLaren Mercedes formula one team.&quot;</p>
<p>McLaren's switch to the West cigarette brand is widely expected to be accompanied by a switch in livery from the familiar red-and-white to silver in what may be a recreation of the famous Mercedes-Benz Silver Arrows of the 1950.'s. McLaren racing cars are currently powered by Mercedes-Benz engines.</p>
<p>McLaren managing director Ron Dennis said that it became clear to him earlier this year, after his preliminary talks with Reemtsma, that &quot;we shared a common vision.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Aside from McLaren's clearly defined sporting objectives, we also have certain other values. Image has always been important to McLaren and we have to date enjoyed the most consistent team imagery in world class motorsport.</p>
<p>&quot;This change to West affords us the opportunity of implementing the more dynamic and exciting image that we believe is important for our future.&quot;</p>
<p>The chairman of Reemtsma Ludger Staby said: &quot;Their track record alone would be enough to justify our investment.&quot;</p>
<p>Marlboro said it would carry on in Formula One and in motor sport in a &quot;meaningful and a significant way.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
