<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134532" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries open narrowly lower before supply.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries open narrowly lower before supply.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury prices opened narrowly lower on Tuesday as players positioned themselves in front of new supply.</p>
<p>The Treasury will sell $18.25 billion in two-year notes this afternoon. The deadline for bids is 1300 EDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>Another $12.5 billion in securities -- this times five-year Treasury notes -- will be auctioned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The market also gets two weekly reports on U.S. chain and department store sales.  </p>
<p>The Bank of Tokyo/Mitsubishi survey of chain store sales, due at 0900 EDT/1300 GMT, is rumored to be up 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Such a strong report (would) put the market on the defensive early,&quot; said analysts at MMS International.</p>
<p>The Redbook chain store sales report is due at 1455 EDT/1855 GMT.</p>
<p>Other data on tap are not expected to move the market. The government will report September import and export prices. Those slipped 0.2 percent and 0.1 percent, respectively, in August.  </p>
<p>September federal budget figures, due at 1400 EDT/1800 GMT, are expected to show a monthly budget surplus of $29.4 billion after a deficit of $41.83 billion in August.</p>
<p>In terms of data, the emphasis comes later this week with jobless claims data on Thursday and September durable orders figures on Friday, analysts said.</p>
<p>Even those data will not hold as much sway as the data that come next week, including the Employment Cost Index, the National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) index, third-quarter GDP and the October employment report, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Next week is littered with economic numbers, culminating in the (October) payroll numbers (on Friday),&quot; said Steve Ricchuito, chief financial economist at BZW Securities.</p>
<p>But with new supply dominating the focus of Tuesday's trading session, the question is whether demand for the new Treasury notes will emerge at current levels, Ricchuito said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen some fundamental decisions by some portfolio managers that they're less bullish than they had been,&quot; he said. &quot;We're looking to see whether foreign buying materializes at these yield levels. Can we sell paper at these levels? If we can't, we might have a problem.&quot;  </p>
<p>In when-issued trade early Tuesday, the two-year notes to be sold in the afternoon were yielding 5.925 percent. The five-year Treasury notes to be auctioned on Wednesday were yielding 6.265 percent.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the 6-3/4 percent 30-year bond was down 4/32 to 99-5/32, yielding 6.87 percent.</p>
<p>Three-month bill rates were unchanged at five percent.</p>
<p>Six-month and year bill rates were each up one basis points to 5.13 percent and 5.25 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The 6.5 percent ten-year note was down 3/32 to 99-25/32 to yield 6.53 percent. -- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
