<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134576" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Demand for Chinese remedies threatens Indian tiger.</title>
<headline>Demand for Chinese remedies threatens Indian tiger.</headline>
<byline>Dale Faulken</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian tigers are under serious threat from a rapid growth in demand for traditional Chinese medicine which advocates cures such as &quot;tiger penis soup&quot;, the Environmental Investigation Agency (EIA) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>At least one Indian tiger is killed each day to satisfy demand across Asia for such remedies, the agency said. There are only about 2,500 tigers left in India, down from around 4,300 in 1989.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade in tiger body parts is thought to have intensified as a result of...a rapid increase in the demand for traditional Chinese medicine in China, Taiwan, Hong Kong, Japan and South Korea,&quot; EIA members told a news briefing in London tied in with a 37-page report that was also issued in New Delhi.</p>
<p>Increasing wealth in many Asian countries has made tiger products accessible to more people and, in many places, the use of such medicines is seen as a symbol of high status.</p>
<p>Economic expansion is also threatening the tiger population by encroaching on its habitat, the EIA report based on a year-long study into the fate of the Indian tiger said.</p>
<p>Accusing India of &quot;criminal neglect&quot; of its threatened tiger population, the EIA implored New Delhi to enforce existing laws to protect the species.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian government has looked on as the tiger population has plummeted. The situation is desperate and the Indian government must act now,&quot; EIA chairman Allan Thornton said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not asking for any new commitments. We are only asking the Indian government to uphold their existing laws.&quot;</p>
<p>India is a signatory to the Conference on International Trade in Endangered Species (CITES), which has outlawed trade in tiger products since 1975.</p>
<p>The Indian government had put its tigers in further danger by granting timber and mineral companies rights to operate in and around wildlife reserves, threatening the habitat of tigers as well as other endangered species, including rhinoceros and elephant, Thornton said.</p>
<p>India was not the only government at fault. One of the biggest markets for Chinese medicines is in Japan where legislation bans trade in endangered species, but does not cover products &quot;not readily recognisable&quot;, such as pills.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan is one of the largest consuming nations not even to have legislation banning sale of products from this highly endangered species,&quot; Thornton said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is the main importer of Chinese tiger products, accounting for nearly half of the business, the EIA said.</p>
<p>From there, the products are sold on in the form of medicines to Chinese communties throughout Asia, the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>Even though China has been a signatory to CITES since 1981, the laws are widely flouted and it remains the primary destination for Indian tiger parts.</p>
<p>China's medicine factories supply traditional remedies to Chinese communities throughout the world, the EIA Said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
