<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134588" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent extends losses on NYMEX heat slide.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent extends losses on NYMEX heat slide.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE Brent crude oil futures extended their fall soon after the NYMEX open, lead down by NYMEX heating oil on news that more distillate fuel will be transported through the Colonial pipeline to the U.S. northeast, brokers said.</p>
<p>IPE December Brent shed 45 cents to $24.19 per barrel by 1404 GMT and November gas oil slumped $6.50 to $227.75 per tonne.</p>
<p>The Colonial pipeline, which runs from the Gulf coast to the northeast United States, said on Monday night that it would open its gasoline line to distillate shipments for at least the next 40 days.  </p>
<p>A spokesman said he had received a surge in distillate shipping orders since Friday's meeting between the government and oil companies about low distillate stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a continuation of the weakness we saw on heating oil on the Colonial pipeline story,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Technically, we could go further, but that might have to wait for the API data,&quot; he added, pegging Dec Brent support at $23.70 per barrel. He said the market was expecting a two million barrel build in distillate stocks in the week ending October 18. He also expected a two million barrel drop in crude stocks and a 700,000 barrel build in gasoline.  </p>
<p>The Dec gas oil/Brent crack spread weakened from $6.00 to $5.75 per barrel as the distillate market began to lose steam.</p>
<p>-- Tom Ashby, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
