<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134555" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Avery Dennison Corp plans to report record third-quarter profit and sales as well as recommend a stock split and dividend increase, the Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Avery will report a net income for the quarter totalling $46.6 million or $0.89 per share.</p>
<p>Other top stories included:</p>
<p>- The United States might lose a challenge made against its quota on underwear imported from Costa Rica in a case brought before the World Trade Organization.</p>
<p>- General Motors Corp and the Canadian Automobile Workers union are close to reaching an agreement to end a 19-day strike.</p>
<p>- Seagram Co Ltd and Viacom Inc are trying to settle a lawsuit over their jointly owned cable television networks.</p>
<p>- Investors are expected to buy up some large stock offerings in Europe this week including one to be made by from Russian natural gas company Gazprom.</p>
<p>- Japanese authorities are about to file charges against Yasuo Hamanaka, former Sumitomo copper trader who is at the center of a trading scandal.</p>
<p>- IBM Corp's quarterly profit was a little higher than analyst expectations but the current quarter might take a revenue hit as customers lease mainframes rather than buy them.</p>
<p>- Microsoft Corp reported earnings that were better than the market expected.</p>
<p>- Oil companies like Exxon Corp, Chevron Corp and Texaco Inc reported higher quarterly profits.</p>
<p>- RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp reported a 4.0-percent increase in quarterly profit.</p>
<p>- Integrated Health Services Inc agreed to acquire Coram Healthcare Corp for $280 million in stock and the assumption of $375 million in debt.</p>
<p>- Molten Metal Technology Inc's stock fell 49 percent after the U.S. Department of Energy declined to renew a reasearch pact with it.</p>
<p>- U.S. Postal Service's top advertizing official left the service after an internal audit disclosed that his department overspent its budget.</p>
<p>- Some investors complain that Warren Buffett's Berkshire Hathaway Inc took advantage of a trying period in FlightSafety International Inc's earnings to get a bargain price for the pilot-training company.</p>
<p>- The Dow Jones industrial average ended 3.36 points down at 6,090.87 as trading closely followed IBM's presentation.</p>
<p>- U.S. bond market traded sluggishly as it got ready to bid on more than $30 billion of new government securities.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
