<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134582" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major bids for moral high ground for election.</title>
<headline>Major bids for moral high ground for election.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>With the government and opposition vying to gain advantage from a new crusade for moral values, British Prime Minister John Major on Tuesday staked his electoral future on tough new law and order measures.</p>
<p>As public support swelled behind a movement to curb violence and renew civic values among the young, the government sought to portray its new legislative programme as a crucial step towards a nationwide moral revival.</p>
<p>The programme, the last before a general election due any time in the next seven months, is to be announced by Queen Elizabeth in a traditional parliamentary ceremony on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government gave strong hints it will include bills bringing in new minimum sentences for serious crimes and a crackdown on unruly pupils, as well as a law to ban most handguns introduced in the wake of a school massacre in March.</p>
<p>The new political emphasis on morality has been sparked by a campaign for a nationwide drive to teach the young moral and civic values which was launched by the widow of a headmaster murdered at his school gates by a teenage gang member.</p>
<p>Philip Lawrence, 48, was killed in December as he tried to protect a pupil from the gang. A 16-year-old boy was given a life sentence last week for the murder.</p>
<p>The verdict came hard on the heels of the government's announcement it intended to ban most handguns after the massacre of 16 children and their teacher by crazed gunman Thomas Hamilton in the Scottish town of Dunblane.</p>
<p>It fuelled growing anxiety about a collapse of values after a series of horrific recent crimes like the sexual abuse and murder of at least 10 young girls by Fred and Rosemary West and the killing of two-year-old James Bulger by two 10-year-olds.</p>
<p>Lawrence's widow, Frances, on Monday launched a seven-point manifesto calling, among other things, for a ban on the sale of combat knives, new primary school courses in good citizenship and government action to help the family.</p>
<p>The ruling Conservatives, the opposition Labour party and the minority Liberal Democrats all rushed to back her crusade.</p>
<p>But, in line with the bitterness of the election campaign so far, all claimed to be leading the way with their policies in contrast to their political opponents.</p>
<p>In another move to seize the inititiative, Home Secretary Michael Howard on Tuesday announced an annual good citizenship award for young people, in Lawrence's memory.</p>
<p>In an article in The Times, Howard said the murder of the headteacher had torn at the heart of the nation, adding: &quot;We shall discuss the details with Frances and her children and ensure that Philip Lawrence's example lives on.&quot;</p>
<p>The government's drive to claim the moral high ground is a high risk tactic after a string of sleaze scandals.</p>
<p>Major was boosted on Sunday when an opinion poll put his party just 14 points behind the opposition Labour Party, the narrowest gap for nearly three years.</p>
<p>But political analysts questioned whether in fact there had been a change in the government's fortunes.</p>
<p>The sleaze question is unlikely to go away, with an investigation by a key parliamentary committee into allegations a former minister took money to ask parliamentary questions for outside interests in breach of rules.</p>
<p>Major is banking on an economic revival to boost support for the Conservatives, who have now been in power for 17 years.</p>
<p>But crucial to this is whether Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke can find enough public savings to deliver the tax cuts being called for by Conservative strategists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
