<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134578" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British police chief warns of &quot;dangerous months&quot;.</title>
<headline>British police chief warns of &quot;dangerous months&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A police chief warned on Tuesday that Britain faced &quot;dangerous months&quot; in which Irish guerrillas could mount major attacks on key targets on the mainland.</p>
<p>David Veness, assistant commissioner of the Metropolitan Police, was commenting on newspaper reports that IRA guerrillas could be planning a spectacular strike before Christmas, possibly in revenge for the killing by police last month of one of their activists.</p>
<p>&quot;I regret that the threat we confront is likely to be in the long term and looking at the period ahead, we are entering dangerous months,&quot; Veness told ITN television in a rare interview.</p>
<p>The Irish Republican Army broke a 17-month truce in February with a series of bombings in Britain, including a blast in June in the northern city of Manchester which injured 200 people.</p>
<p>Earlier this month the IRA planted a bomb inside British army headquarters in Northern Ireland, killing one soldier.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland's chief police officer Sir Hugh Annesley warned in an interview published on Monday that IRA guerrillas would attempt further bomb attacks before laying down their arms again.</p>
<p>Police were reported to have stepped up security round political and military targets ahead of the ceremonial opening of parliament in London on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman at London's Scotland Yard police headquarters said: &quot;There is a continuing campaign of violence by terrorist criminals and we are not being complacent about it.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokeswoman urged Britons to be alert and encouraged people to call its anti-terrorist hotline to report any suspicions.</p>
<p>The threat of another IRA attack comes despite some notable successes against the guerrillas, who seek an end to British rule of Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Last month police seized 100 tonnes of explosives and bomb-making equipment during raids in London which resulted in charges against four people. A fifth man, whom the IRA said later was one of its activists, was shot dead during the raids.</p>
<p>London and Dublin have excluded Sinn Fein, the IRA's political wing, from multi-party peace talks on Northern Ireland, saying the IRA must first end its war against British rule of the province.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
