<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134599" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Chronology of highlights in the LME copper saga.</title>
<headline>Chronology of highlights in the LME copper saga.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Scandal in copper took a new turn on Tuesday with the Tokyo arrest of ex-Sumitomo Corp star trader Yasuo Hamanaka.</p>
<p>Here is a chronology of some key events surrounding copper trading on the London Metal Exchange (LME) since 1991.</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 1991 - The International Wrought Copper Council (IWCC) representing the industry asks the LME to investigate alleged distortions in the market. LME stocks were at seven-year highs of 315,000 tonnes. Yet prices were up.</p>
<p>US broker David Threlkeld asks LME to investigate a letter in which he said Hamanaka asked him to confirm fictitious trades. The LME informs the British regulatory Securities and Investments Board (SIB) and US authorities.</p>
<p>SEPTEMBER 1993 - Sumitomo denies manipulating copper by hoarding it. Hamanaka will contend that it needed large stocks to cover delivery commitments in Asia.</p>
<p>OCTOBER 1993 - LME broker Credit Lyonnais Rouse apologises to the exchange over any involvement in an alleged squeeze and pays 100,000 sterling ($125,000) towards exchange costs.</p>
<p>JANUARY 1994 - Chile Copper Corp (Codelco) announces losses on LME trading eventually fixed at around $170 million. Head dealer Juan Pablo Davila has since denied fraud.</p>
<p>JULY 1994 - LME asks members if they are having difficulties with payments from state firm China International Trust and Investment Corp. A CITIC unit has debts of $40 million with some 14 LME brokers. It says some trades were unauthorised.</p>
<p>MARCH 1995 - CITIC agrees a settlement with brokers.</p>
<p>APRIL 1995 - LME opens copper warehouses in the US. By December stocks in Long Beach will soar above 61,000 tonnes. Largely controlled by Sumitomo.</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 1995 - IWCC voices new concern about the market. LME Chief Executive David King seeks information on client positions and credit.</p>
<p>DECEMBER 1995 - US regulator the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) contacts the British SIB. Codelco starts lawsuits against some brokers.</p>
<p>MARCH 1996 - US funds sell copper short. Price falls.</p>
<p>APRIL 1996 - Traders report rumours China seeks to buy copper. Price rises towards a 1996 peak at $2,715 early May as funds are squeezed on short positions.</p>
<p>MAY 17 1996 - Rumours circulate that Hamanaka has moved from his post. A rise in LME stocks despite talk of Chinese withdrawals of metal triggers a huge sell-off</p>
<p>JUNE 5 1996 - Sumitomo says this was the day when it found evidence of unauthorised trading.</p>
<p>JUNE 6 1996 - Copper crashes from $2,378 to $1,880 a tonne.</p>
<p>JUNE 11 1996 - New rumours that Hamanaka has resigned. Price falls $200. Sumitomo denies the rumour the next day.</p>
<p>JUNE 14 - Sumitomo reports losses of $1.8 billion on unauthorised copper trades. It sacks Hamanaka. Banks are soon asked to unwind a huge long position that Hamanaka built up. The UK Serious Fraud Office opens its own criminal inquiry to be followed in the US by a Grand Jury investigation. Prices drop.</p>
<p>JUNE 17 - Price as low as $1,800.</p>
<p>JUNE 19 - The UK SIB opens a top-to-bottom review of metals trading and inquiry into Sumitomo involvement of UK brokers.</p>
<p>AUGUST 11 - Hamanaka makes his first appearance since he was sacked to say he is well and living quietly in Tokyo.</p>
<p>SEPTEMBER 2 - Reports say that Japanese prosecutors will set up a task force to investigate Sumitomo losses.</p>
<p>SEPTEMBER 19 - Sumitomo says these are now put at $2.6 billion.Copper price barely reacts. Sumitomo also says it asks for criminal charges against Hamanaka.</p>
<p>OCTOBER 22 - Tokyo prosecutors arrest him on charge of falsifying documents. But Sumitomo says in a statement it has no evidence of market manipulation against foreign brokers. UK Serious Fraud Office says its inquiry will continue.</p>
<p>($1=.7986 Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
