<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134580" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Irish paper lets people speak for themselves.</title>
<headline>N.Irish paper lets people speak for themselves.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Belfast daily newspaper declared itself &quot;a politician-free zone&quot; on Tuesday and let the people of conflict-riven Northern Ireland speak for themselves.</p>
<p>Instead of a standard diet of news stories quoting bitterly divided Protestant and Catholic politicians, the Irish News devoted most of its pages to the views of people across the sectarian divide about the region's deep-rooted troubles.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians normally dominate the headlines. But not today,&quot; the paper proclaimed alongside an opinion poll that showed an overwhelming desire for peace and articles giving the verdict of people of all ages on the long-running instability.</p>
<p>The province has been in upheaval for decades during a guerrilla conflict about the future of British sovereignty and tension between majority Protestants who support rule from London and minority Catholics who want an all-Ireland state.</p>
<p>An opinion poll in the paper showed that more than two-thirds of supporters of Sinn Fein, the political wing of the Irish Republican Army, wanted IRA guerrillas to call a new truce to replace the 17-month-old ceasfire that ended in February with a series of bombs.</p>
<p>But there was considerable pessimism across the community about the short-term prospects for peace. The poll was conducted two weeks after the IRA killed a British soldier in its first attack in the province for more than two years.</p>
<p>The paper, which is bought mainly by Catholics, gave its editorial column over to two university students who made a plea &quot;for a new consciousness within politics&quot;.</p>
<p>Teenagers and school principals wrote about the need for &quot;cross-community co-operation&quot; and police officers disabled by Irish guerrilla attacks gave their views.</p>
<p>A centre double-page spread reported on &quot;the biggest ever vox pop carried out in Northern Ireland&quot;, with photographs and views of 80 people on how to break a political impasse.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians should just get their act together and talk instead of fighting,&quot; said Melanie Flanagan of Enniskillen, County Fermanagh. &quot;They should stop competing with each other and just get on with it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing is to get down to talks and include Sinn Fein,&quot; said Eileen McMullan of Belfast. &quot;We will never have a solution here until we have some talks about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Sinn Fein, political arm of the banned IRA, is barred from peace talks because the guerrillas refuse to end their campaign of violence against British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;The MPs (members of parliament) are not doing their job and not even trying to do it,&quot; Robert Porter of Antrim said.</p>
<p>Editor Tom Collins said the special edition was aimed at giving an avenue of expression to rarely heard people but it was not a &quot;goody-two-shoes&quot; exercise about how wonderful reconciliation would be.</p>
<p>&quot;What we wanted to do was maybe to make politicians think about the role they have and how they are performing, and to offer practical suggestions about how they might move forward,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
