<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134592" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British manufacturing recovering, but slowly - CBI.</title>
<headline>British manufacturing recovering, but slowly - CBI.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's manufacturers are riding along the road to recovery, but slowly, leading employers group the Confederation of British Industry (CBI) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Economists said manufacturing recovery was evident, if fragile, and warned the pound could snuff it out if it continued its relentless climb of the past three months.</p>
<p>The CBI's latest quarterly trends survey showed total new orders for British manufacturers rose at their highest rate since April 1995 over the past four months.</p>
<p>Output rose at its fastest pace in 15 months but did not grow as quickly as had been expected.</p>
<p>&quot;More evidence that a recovery in manufacturing is imminent,&quot; said Dharshini David, economist at HSBC Markets. &quot;But a further rise in sterling could still threaten this.&quot;</p>
<p>The pound has appreciated by more than six percent on a trade-weighted basis since early August.</p>
<p>Andrew Buxton, chairman of the Confederation of British Industry's Economic Affairs Committee, said UK exporters had yet to suffer from the pound's rally. &quot;At present levels industry is not worried about the recent stength of the pound.&quot;</p>
<p>But he conceded that there would come a point where the pound's appreciation would start to hurt exporters as they saw their prices pushed ever higher.</p>
<p>The CBI's survey of 1,155 manufacturing firms showed domestic and export orders are expected to grow more strongly over the next four months, although the CBI warned that manufacturers' expectations have tended not to be fulfilled over the past 18 months.</p>
<p>&quot;The strong and strengthening UK economy is confirmed by the CBI survey,&quot; said Marian Bell, economist at the Royal Bank of Scotland. &quot;There is little sign that exports have been affected by sterling's recent rise.&quot;</p>
<p>More firms expected export orders to increase rather than fall in the next four months, giving a positive balance of 15 percent, the same reading as in the July survey.</p>
<p>That indicates overseas markets remain sluggish, analysts said, but no tougher to break into. And the domestic demand side looks more buoyant.</p>
<p>A positive balance of 20 percent of companies expected domestic orders to rise over the next four months. In July, that balance was 12 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's survey suggests manufacturers have broken free of the inventory stranglehold that has smothered activity for the best part of a year,&quot; said Alex Garrard, UK economist at UBS.</p>
<p>British industry has been hamstrung by mountains of unsold goods, made when demand was healthier over a year ago. But the CBI survey showed those stocks are finally unwinding.</p>
<p>Stocks of finished goods levelled off and further reductions are expected over the next four months.</p>
<p>But Garrard said the recovery will be far from explosive with the strength of the pound possibly exposing exports as manufacturing's Achilles' Heel.</p>
<p>&quot;An erosion of UK competitiveness and export markets could undermine the manufacturing recovery in its infancy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>That concern will be pushed to the hilt by Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke in his crusade to keep interest rates on hold, or maybe even lower, before elections which must be held by May 1997.</p>
<p>To that end, Clarke could also point to the CBI's finding that domestic prices fell at their sharpest rate since January 1993, over the past four months and unit costs also fell.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking forward, the inflation prospects remain soft with unit costs, output prices and export prices expected to remain soft even before the latest advance in sterling,&quot; Garrard said.</p>
<p>&quot;Like the CBI, we suspect that the Chancellor's base rate view will prevail in the election approach.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
