<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134586" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Activity eases in Ldn freight, index bounds.</title>
<headline>Activity eases in Ldn freight, index bounds.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dry cargo freight market was relatively quiet on Tuesday after the feverish activity of the last week.</p>
<p>The BFI still managed a significant increase of 23 points to 1199 on the strength of continuing improvement in the Panamax sector, and brokers believe further gains for owners are likely. But some charterers appeared to be taking stock of the current situation more than engaging in further firm negotiations.</p>
<p>Analysts said FFA figures have not moved up in line with the rapidly advancing BIFFEX prices - the volume of newbuilding deliveries, weak scrap prices influencing owners to defer demolition of old units and firm bunker prices restraining timecharter business, are all cited as negative factors in the current situation.</p>
<p>Grain traders are said to be looking more closely at the possibility of switching grain shipments from US Gulf to NoPac in order to choke off the advancing Atlantic market. Meanwhile ironore rates from Brazil to China have stiffened a little in a dull Caper market but brokers believe this is largely because owners are still reluctant to commit tonnage to an uncertain eastern market.</p>
<p>Handymaxes and smaller geared tonnage are said to be in short supply in the US Gulf but elsewhere it is hard to detect signs yet of much better prospects for these types.</p>
<p>GRAIN</p>
<p>HMM fixed the 1982-built Olympic Galaxy 64,931 dwt on subjects delivery Passerobout Oct 25 trip via US Gulf with grain to S Korea at $11,750 daily but failed on dates. Charterers have instead now fixed the prompter 1980-built Poros 62,185 dwt delivery US Gulf early Nov at $11,000 daily plus $200,000 bonus.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed reports suggest Halla have fixed a K Line-relet mid-1980's-built 68,000 dwt vessel delivery prompt Japan for one US Gulf round at $9,000 daily and that unnamed charterers have fixed Andre tonnage for 54,000 HSS US Gulf/Japan for Nov 15/30 at $23.00/22.50 mbo/no combo. Zalongo 71,730 dwt was believed fixed from E Coast S America for grain business on private terms.</p>
<p>Irisl have booked the 1978-built Amber 63,000 for heavy grain from NoPac to Iran at $17.00, up about 75 cents from last week's fixture of the 1973-built Schubert. Glencore have been linked with Ioannis 77,300 dwt NoPac/Continent for end Oct, not necessarily for grain. New grain orders Tuesday included Toepfer 55,000 barley NoPac/Saudi Arabia for Nov 9/15 and 1.5/1.6m cft grain Paragua/Gibraltar-Hamburg, Cargill 50,000 barley Rostock-la Pallice range/Saudi for Nov 5/11, and Transfield 60,000/85,000 dwt dely US Gulf Nov 1/20 trip China (grain or fertilizers).</p>
<p>Once again only a handful Handy-size fixtures saw the light of day. The few owners with tonnage in the US Gulf appeared to be in a commanding position following Monday's reports of 25,000 HSS US Gulf/Tunisia and Buenaventura for October each at $20.00, up $3.00 and $4.00 respectively on the previous ftures. Reports circulated that Dreyfus fixed both 21,000 wheat Rouen/W C Italy for early Nov at $11.00 (possibly an old fixture) and also Leodas for 25,000 wheat Vancouver/Bangladesh on private terms. in addition Dreyfus booked 45,000 barley Mersin/Jeddah for Oct/NOV AT $14.00.</p>
<p>MINERALS</p>
<p>Nafsika M 162,458 dwt open prompt Gibraltar and Catherine venture 132,016 dwt prompt Continent have been fixed for unknown business. In the East Bocimar fixed Wah Shan 149,507 dwt on subjects dely Kaohsiung trip via Australia to the Continent/Med but full details are still awaited. Also lacking full details were reports that mosk fixed Caribbean Sky 64,282 dwt for coke from Sakaide to Brazil and that HMM took Maritime King 61,395 dwt for coke from Xingang to the C</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7729</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
