<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134528" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lilly says Prozac sales up despite pressure.</title>
<headline>Lilly says Prozac sales up despite pressure.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eli Lilly and Co said sales of the blockbuster antidepressant Prozac rose 13 percent in the first nine months of 1996 over the year-ago period.</p>
<p>For the first nine months of 1996, worldwide sales of Prozac were $1.753 billion, up from $1.551 billion in the year-ago period, the drugmaker said.  Sales of the drug were up 10 percent in the third quarter over year-ago levels. Quarterly sales figures were not immediately available.</p>
<p>Lilly said Prozac's gains were made &quot;despite continuing competition from generic forms of Prozac in Canada and substantial competitive pressures in France.&quot;  </p>
<p>Sales of the human insulin Humulin increased 15 percent for the quarter, Lilly said. For the first nine months of 1996, worldwide sales of Humulin were $645 million, an increase of 11 percent compared with $582 million in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>ReoPro, a blood clot breaking drug, &quot;continued to show very steady sales growth,&quot; Lilly said.  For the first nine months of 1996, worldwide sales of ReoPro were $98 million.</p>
<p>Sales of the ulcer medication Axid in the first nine months of 1996 were $394 million, compared with $399 million a year ago.  </p>
<p>Sales in the first nine months of the antibiotic Ceclor/ceflacor were $385 million, compared with $539 million a year ago, Lilly said.</p>
<p>Worldwide sales of animal health products increased two percent compared with the third quarter of 1995, it said.</p>
<p>Worldwide sales for the quarter were $1.804 billion, an increase of 11 percent compared with sales of $1.632 billion in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Sales growth was led by Prozac, Humulin and two of the company's newer products, Gemzar and ReoPro, Lilly said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In addition, the quarter benefited from increased health care management revenues, primarily PCS.  Revenue growth was partially offset by lower sales of anti-infectives,&quot; Lilly said.</p>
<p>Manufacturing costs as a percent of sales for the quarter were higher due primarily to a sales mix that included increased revenues from lower margin lines, such as ReoPro and health care management services, the company said.</p>
<p>Marketing and administrative expenses rose seven percent from the third quarter of 1995 partially due to the new product launches of Gemzar and Humalog, Lilly said.</p>
<p>Also adding to higher expenses were the anticipated launches of Zyprexa and the cost of reserves taken to cover outstanding receivables from FoxMeyer Health Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Increased information technology capabilities and continued globalization of the company's products, particularly in emerging markets, also contributed to the increase in marketing and administrative expenses,&quot; Lilly said.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
