<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134542" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: InsWeb launches new products amid growing interest.</title>
<headline>InsWeb launches new products amid growing interest.</headline>
<dateline>SAN MATEO, Calif. 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>InsWeb Corp, a marketplace for insurance on the Internet, said on Tuesday that it was offering four new products to consumers as insurers grow increasingly interested in selling insurance on the Internet.</p>
<p>Insurance companies are &quot;now getting turned on to the fact that it does work,&quot; Gordon Gaddy, chief executive of InsWeb's Life &amp; Health division said in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>In addition, many of the companies are finding that no matter how large and sophisticated they are, &quot;making an Internet site work is not that easy.&quot;  </p>
<p>About 20 insurers currently offer products and services through InsWeb, which was launched a year ago.</p>
<p>InsWeb provided its first insurance policy application over the Internet in November 1995 and currently provides thousands of insurance quotes a month, Gaddy said.</p>
<p>The new products include a financial needs estimator, a dental, vision and hearing discount plan, an insurance quote service and a benefits product for business owners.  </p>
<p>The Zurich Kemper Financial Needs Estimator is an interactive online financial planning tool that helps consumers plan their family's future by calculating their specific needs for life, disability, retirement and college savings.</p>
<p>The needs estimator was developed by InsWeb and is being marketed by Zurich Kemper Life Insurance, a unit of Zurich Insurance Group.</p>
<p>Zurich Kemper Life, Zurich Insurance Group,  </p>
<p>The Agent Quotes product allows consumers to get quotes and information from local area agents that specialize in their specific needs.</p>
<p>Avesis Inc, a nationwide network of over 15,000 dental, vision and hearing care providers based in Phoenix, will offer consumers discounts of up to 60 percent on services though the InsWeb site.</p>
<p>Unlike insured benefits, the Avesis plan requires no claim filing.  </p>
<p>MATRIX Benefits Communications, based in Minnesota, will offer plans on InsWeb that allow employees to use pre-tax dollars to pay their share of health-care costs, including deductibles and co-insurance payments. Employers can fill out an interactive form to estimate their potential tax savings.</p>
<p>These four new products will be in addition to the auto, life and health insurance products already available on InsWeb, said Lisa Mayer, vice president of marketing and operations for InsWeb.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a new way (for companies) to market their products,&quot; Gaddy said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's a way to reach more people more effectively,&quot; he said. &quot;The consumer selects the company they want to do business with. It's a situation where the consumer is in control.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN MATEO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
