<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134669" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major hopes crime crackdown will be poll winner.</title>
<headline>Major hopes crime crackdown will be poll winner.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As Britain reels under the impact of a series of shocking crimes, Prime Minister John Major was putting the finishing touches on Tuesday to a tough law and order package he hopes will boost his re-election chances.</p>
<p>The Conservative government's legislative programme for a new session of parliament aims to reflect growing public demand for a new moral climate.</p>
<p>The programme, to be announced by Queen Elizabeth in a traditional parliamentary ceremony on Wednesday, is expected to include a bill introducing new minimum sentences for serious crimes and an education bill cracking down on unruly pupils.</p>
<p>The speech is written for the queen by a cabinet committee headed by Major, who is keenly aware of the need to present an attractive legislative shop window with an election due by May.</p>
<p>Crimes such as the Dunblane tragedy in March, in which 16 four and five-year-old children were gunned down, and the fatal stabbing of London headmaster Philip Lawrence while protecting a pupil have shocked Britons.</p>
<p>Major has said he will bring in legislation banning most handguns in the aftermath of Dunblane.</p>
<p>Lawrence's widow, Frances, launched a crusade this week for a more moral society, calling for moves to banish violence, encourage children to learn civic values and promote the family.</p>
<p>All political parties have responded enthusiastically to her call.</p>
<p>Major's hopes of an unexpected victory at the election he must call by May were boosted on Sunday when an opinion poll put his party just 14 points behind the opposition Labour Party, the narrowest gap for nearly three years.</p>
<p>But to overhaul Labour, Major needs to stress his party's traditional strengths -- a reputation for sound economic management and a no-nonsense attitude to crime.</p>
<p>Home Secretary (interior minister) Michael Howard told the Conservative Party annual conference last month;&quot;If criminals are ready to commit serious crimes they've no right to complain about the rough sentences they receive.&quot;</p>
<p>Howard is expected to propose mandatory life sentences for criminals convicted for a second time of serious offences such as manslaughter, rape or burglary carrying a firearm.</p>
<p>The bill would also give local authorities powers to close down night clubs which police believe are being used by drug pushers, and would allow police to confiscate alcohol being drunk by under-18s in public places.</p>
<p>An education bill is expected to give schools extra powers to make unruly children stay behind after classes and exclude real trouble-makers completely.</p>
<p>However the most important day in parliament in the next few months is November 26 when finance minister Kenneth Clarke introduces his budget.</p>
<p>Many commentators believe that the Conservatives' future could depend more on whether Clarke can deliver sustainable tax cuts than on any new laws.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
