<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134656" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's OFT yet to decide on Bass deal.</title>
<headline>UK's OFT yet to decide on Bass deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spokesman for Britain's Office of Fair Trading said it had yet to decide what advice to give the Secretary of State over the proposed takeover of Carlsberg-Tetley by brewer Bass.</p>
<p>&quot;We still haven't reached a decision and we don't expect to for at least a couple of weeks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is advice given in strict confidence. I do not know what advice we are going to give the Secretary of State.&quot;</p>
<p>An article in today's Independent newspaper said the OFT will recommend the government refer the takeover to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission.  </p>
<p>John Haywood, corporate manager at Carlsberg-Tetley, said &quot;as far as we are concerned this article is pure speculation. They (OFT) have not told us that.&quot;</p>
<p>The OFT spokesman denied that it had bought forward a meeting of the Mergers Panel. The panel is still likely to meet at the end of this month as originally planned, he said.</p>
<p>The 200 million stg merger would create a business with 38 percent of the beer market and more than 4,000 pubs, making it easily the country's largest brewer, supplanting Scottish &amp; Newcastle. A spokesman for Bass said the company would not comment on what it termed &quot;speculation&quot;.  </p>
<p>Officials at Allied Domecq, half owners of Carlsberg Tetley with Danish brewer Carlsberg A/S, were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>When the deal was announced brewers Wolverhampton &amp; Dudley and Whitbread said they expected a referral.</p>
<p>Small, regional brewers are concerned that if the merger is allowed to go ahead it would leave Bass and S&amp;N with too much control over beer prices and too powerful a grip in the Midlands and Yorkshire.</p>
<p>If the deal is waved through, Carlsberg will be left with a 20 percent stake in the enlarged brewing group.  </p>
<p>But if it is blocked, Carlsberg has agreed to buy back Bass's 50 percent for 110 million stg and sell on just under 15 percent to Allied. In turn, Allied will pay Bass 30 million stg.</p>
<p>Bass's potential loss is estimated at 60 million stg, but this would be offset by profits earned from its 50 percent interest in Carlsberg-Tetley.</p>
<p>Under the agreement Allied, which will become the UK's largest independent pub company with more than 4,000 houses, will retain the right to sell the Tetley, Ansell's and Nicholson's brands in its pubs. Bass shares were off 9p at 786p and Allied down 4p at 471p by 1125 GMT.</p>
<p>-- Tim Farrand, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6437</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
