<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134636" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bubbling oil prices pose threat to bond rallies.</title>
<headline>Bubbling oil prices pose threat to bond rallies.</headline>
<byline>Kate Kelland</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global debt markets have been quietly ignoring a forceful rise in oil prices since the beginning of the year, but analysts say a few fingers may get burnt if investors don't sit up and take notice soon.</p>
<p>The risk of inflation -- a dirty word for bond markets -- seeping through from higher energy prices into wage demands in some already tightening labour markets is real, they say, and is threatening to squeeze bond prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflation risks are creeping into the picture from rising oil prices,&quot; said Klaus Baader of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;What the (bond) markets fail to aprreciate here is that this could definitely lead to a stoke up in inflation on a broad front,&quot; said Baader, a London-based economist.</p>
<p>World oil prices have gained almost 40 percent since January, with November NYMEX crude oil breaking above $26 a barrel on Monday -- heights not seen since early 1991. December Brent is currently around the $25 a barrel level.</p>
<p>Analysts said an end to the rally is not yet in sight.</p>
<p>Economic recovery in Europe, although only embryonic in some countries, is marching steadily forward in others. It will boost demand for oil, they said, while growth in the U.S. economy will push that even further.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, tensions between the U.S. and Iraq, whose exports are blocked by U.N. sanctions, mean supply from there is likely to remain capped at least until early next year, and a bitter winter last year has left heating oil stocks in Europe and the U.S. heavily depleted.</p>
<p>Despite this, debt prices across Europe and the dollar-bloc have ignored the potential price threat from oil and staged impressive rallies recently, with yields scuttling lower.</p>
<p>&quot;Current bond market yield levels, be it in Germany or the U.S., are somewhat exaggerated to the downside,&quot; said Stefan Schneider, chief German economist at Paribas in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;Once we see inflation picking up -- even though it will mainly be because of oil prices -- bond yields should move closer to their fair value.&quot;</p>
<p>Schneider forecast that German 10-year Bund yields -- currently trading at around 5.98 percent -- should rise to 6.25 percent as debt prices are hit by the energy component.</p>
<p>But analysts said bonds in Germany -- a high consumer of heating oil -- and traditionally inflation-sensitive nations such as Spain, Italy and France would not necessarily be the most heavily affected by the rise in oil prices.</p>
<p>Nations with tight labour markets -- rendering them more susceptible to inflationary risks translating into higher wage demands -- were more at risk, they said.</p>
<p>Deutsche's Baader said Germany, where unemployment remains crippling at 10.4 percent, Spain, where nearly 14 percent of the popoulation is jobless, and France, where unemployment was 12.6 percent in August, have a buffer against high oil prices.</p>
<p>In the U.S., with almost 95 percent employment, and Britain where joblessness has steadily fallen to 7.6 percent, the risks are greater. With a relatively large number of people in work, any demand for higher pay to cover rising energy prices would have a much more substantial effect, analysts said.</p>
<p>But there is little danger of an oil crisis of the scale seen in the early 70s and again in the early 90s, analysts said.</p>
<p>Peter Osler, economist at GNI in London, said as long as prices across the spectrum remain relatively subdued, the inflation risk to global bond markets too would be capped.</p>
<p>Osler noted the rise in oil prices was more for political than economic reasons, with President Saddam Hussein's recent attacks against Kurds in northern Iraq hampering U.S efforts for an aid-for-oil policy to increase world energy supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;What tends to really worry bond markets is a broad-based increase in prices due to aggregate demand rather than inflation being pushed on by a single input like oil which is moving for political and not economic reasons,&quot; he said. &quot;That's why the markets are not that worried.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
