<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134677" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Abbey National says progress continued in Q3.</title>
<headline>Abbey National says progress continued in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK financial services group Abbey National Plc said on Tuesday it had continued the progress made earlier in the year during the third quarter of 1996, strengthening its position in traditional markets with the integration of the National &amp; Provincial Building Society.  </p>
<p>Abbey National said it was also diversifying profit away from mortgage and savings activities.</p>
<p>It said a &quot;substantial proportion of the expected ongoing cost savings (from the integration of National &amp; Provincial) have already been realised&quot;.</p>
<p>The group said the process of rapid integration had been demanding on both management and staff but put it in a strong position going forward.</p>
<p>&quot;The costs directly associated with the integration are expected to be around 60 million pounds,&quot; it added.  </p>
<p>Abbey National's UK Retail Banking arm had increased its share of new mortgage business during the quarter, chairman Lord Tugendhat said in a statement.</p>
<p>It had also seen improved savings flows and a mortgage interest spread &quot;just below that of the first half&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>Tugendhat said there had been particularly good growth in the personal banking business. &quot;The level of bank account openings and credit cards issued continue to be encouraging, as is the ongoing success of the Abbey National UK Growth PEP.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the Abbey National General Insurance joint venture with Commercial Union  was progressing well.  </p>
<p>Total funds under management in the group for the year to September had increased by over 1.0 billion stg, he said.</p>
<p>He also confirmed the group had met a forecast made by Abbey National directors in the transfer document for National &amp; Provincial, that profit retained for the month of July 1996 and the first five days of August 1996 would be no less than 65 million stg.</p>
<p>Abbey National's shares were down 4.0 pence at 600.5 pence at 1010 GMT.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
