<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134645" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK fraud inquiry in copper scandal to go on.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK fraud inquiry in copper scandal to go on.</headline>
<byline>Eric Onstad</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British fraud squad will continue its own inquiry into scandal in world copper although Japan's Sumitomo Corp said after the arrest of Yasuo Hamanaka that it had no evidence to warrant legal moves against foreign brokers.</p>
<p>Nor did the company think that he had manipulated the international copper market, based on the London Metal Exchange, in the world's most costly financial scandal.</p>
<p>&quot;The investigation continues,&quot; said James O'Donoghue, head of information for Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO). He added on Tuesday that his office had not made any arrests or filed complaints.</p>
<p>Tokyo prosecutors on Tuesday arrested Hamanaka for forgery and raided his modest home in the Tokyo suburbs. He had dominated LME copper for almost a decade. Sumitomo alleges he lost it $2.6 billion on unauthorised trades.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese investigation is obviously different from the SFO's investigation so our investigation continues as it has done,&quot; The SFO's O'Donoghue said.</p>
<p>He was asked if Sumitomo's own statement that it had no evidence to warrant complaints against foreign brokers or of any Hamanaka manipulation would make the SFO inquiry more difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;I couldn't comment on that. I've not seen the information to indicate that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The SFO had a good relationship with Japanese officials and &quot;we shall continue to liase closely with the Japanese authorities as we have done throughout&quot;.</p>
<p>He could not say when the SFO inquiry might end.</p>
<p>The LME was shaken and copper prices tumbled when Sumitomo said in June that it had fired Hamanaka as an alleged maverick. Copper dropped from a 1996 peak of $2,715 per tonne in May to stabilise at around $1,950 now.</p>
<p>A British regulatory agency, the Securities and Investments Board (SIB), is carrying on a separate top-to-bottom review of the opaque trade in metals in which dealers say that Hamanaka hoarded stocks of copper. It had no comment on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hamanaka always denied manipulating copper and said Sumitomo needed to hold big stocks to cover commitments to deliver metal to Pacific Rim customers, under contracts that had no force majeure clause. Experienced traders see a fine line between putting on a technical squeeze and manipulating a global raw material market.</p>
<p>Copper is now struggling to break out of its depressed lower range but it shrugged off the news of Hamanaka's arrest during early trading.</p>
<p>&quot;These announcements have had no impact on the price because there is nothing really new in them,&quot; said analyst Robin Bhar of LME ring dealing broker Brandeis.</p>
<p>Traders assumed that sceptics would continue to suspect the market has been held artificially high.</p>
<p>Sumitomo said recently it had liquidated nearly all of a huge long position in copper that Hamanaka built up but analysts say it sold them on to banks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
