<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134678" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. Treasuries in London may ease slightly.</title>
<headline>U.S. Treasuries in London may ease slightly.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries were slightly higher on Tuesday in a quiet London market, traders and analysts said, but some price erosion was likely later, especially at the short end.</p>
<p>The supply of two-year paper will be boosted by an auction of two-year T-notes at 1745 GMT, but there was little U.S. data to provide a focus of attention for the market, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're rangebound and I think we're going to test support levels,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. bank in London.</p>
<p>The U.S. long bond was at 99-09 to yield 6.806 percent by 0917 GMT, versus 99-07 Tokyo and 99-09 at the New York close.</p>
<p>At the short end, the two-year T-note was at 100-06 to yield 5.911 percent, compared with 100-05 in Tokyo and 100-06 in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;I've had bids at six percent for the when-issued two-years. It probably won't get there today but people have some interest to buy there. It's a strong support level,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Later in the session the U.S. Treasury will auction $18.25 billion of two-year T-notes.</p>
<p>Brian Hilliard, chief economist in the fixed income division at SG Strauss Turnbull in London, said the tone of the market was fairly sound and the auction would provide some focus for the market on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a bit of a challenge because it is probably going to have a coupon below six percent, which might make the market gulp a little bit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal budget for September is due at 1900 GMT, after the session close in London. It is forecast to be set at $29.4 billion compared with a $41.8 billion deficit for August.</p>
<p>But the market would not pay too much attention to the budget, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The budget is meaningless because you don't know who is going to be the administration,&quot; said the U.S. bank trader. &quot;We've got to get the election out of the way first.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. presidential and congressional elections will be held on November 5.</p>
<p>At 0931 GMT, December T-bond futures were at 111-02 in automated trade, unchanged from Monday's Chicago settlement.</p>
<p>The trader said the futures contract would also move towards support at 110-30, 110-23 and 110-17.</p>
<p>--Deepthi Wickremasinghe, Bonds Unit +44 171 542 4041</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
