<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134619" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel - cracked sector balanced, SR available.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel - cracked sector balanced, SR available.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fuel oil was unchanged on Tuesday with high sulphur seen balanced to tight and low sulphur balanced and quiet.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges were very slow with prices about $2 a tonne lower at $125-127 fob ARA. Traders said slow bunker enquiries was weighing on the market as was Russian straight run material.</p>
<p>Two, possibly three Russian cargoes were sold on Monday with a trader, a major and a utility the suggested buyers. No prices were given, but dealers said good quality straight run with low water content offerred around $125 a tonne cif ARA, broadly on parity with high sulphur cracked fuel levels. Cargoes with higher water content were still talked in the low $120s, traders said.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked cargoes were quiet and balanced. &quot;I see a couple of cargoes and a couple of buyers for second half November material,&quot; said one trader. Prices for November cargoes were offered at November swaps +$10-11, which at today's paper levels was $137-140 cif Italy. News that Turkey's Mersin refinery was halting production from Wednesday in a pricing dispute is expected to stop fuel oil output which should help the Med straight run market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
