<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134606" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar/mark softer in Europe as durability assessed.</title>
<headline>Dollar/mark softer in Europe as durability assessed.</headline>
<byline>Mike Dolan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar extended its retreat from 4-1/2-month highs against the mark here as traders cited a plethora of influences from changing sentiment to profit-taking, and from softer oil prices to Deutsche Telekom's share sale.</p>
<p>Losses were limited to 1.53 marks, however, as players assessed whether the recent period of dollar strength has run its course for now or whether the U.S. currency is merely building strength for a fresh push higher.</p>
<p>Analysts were divided on the seriousness of the retreat, and many said it was driven by cross rate plays like mark/yen.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that some of the recent forex moves were overcooked and a lot of trend-followers, who are always first to go when momentum stalls, have pulled positions,&quot; said Peter Von Maydell, senior currency economist at Swiss bank UBS in London.</p>
<p>Von Maydell said he's a keen oil-price watcher, however. He believes that Monday's pause in the recently rampant surge in oil prices has served to underpin the currencies of oil import dependant countries, like the mark, yen and Swiss franc, and cap the units of oil price producers, like sterling.</p>
<p>At 1117 GMT, the dollar was trading at 1.5342 marks compared with 1.5350 late Monday.</p>
<p>The UBS analyst said he remains a dollar bull, however, and feels a dollar breather about current levels is healthy for a fresh push higher as long as the oil price rise resumes.</p>
<p>Others are more worried about the dollar's potential.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar had been running on sentiment alone for a little too long,&quot; said Paul Meggyesi, currency strategist at German investment house Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rate expectations and trade trends turned negative for the dollar a few weeks ago at least.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are bits of stories flying about all over the place but I think we can safely describe the easier dollar/mark as a timely bout of profit-taking,&quot; said Meggyesi at Deutsche.</p>
<p>There were several background influences cited for a firmer mark across the board in early trade, which were initially lead by its sharp gains to six-week highs against the yen.</p>
<p>Traders cited the partial privatisation of Deutsche Telekom, the largest share sale ever in Europe, as lifting mark demand.</p>
<p>The share sale aims to raise about 15 billion marks ($9.8 billion) and more than 30 percent will be sold to overseas investors, about 12 percent in Britain alone.</p>
<p>Others said Italy's sale of 100 billion yen ($886.5 million) worth of 20-year bonds roday also boosted mark as the yen proceeds of the bond are likely to be swapped into marks to build foreign currency reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The mark/yen rally is a key feature of the latest mark move and it has approached levels where people could start to press panic buttons,&quot; said Tony Norfield, treasury economist at Dutch bank ABN Amro. Mark/yen's fortunes will be key to the near-term direction of the mark across the board, he said.</p>
<p>Meggyesi at Deutsche said an excessively benign view of German interest rates was gradually changing to more realistic terms and that should underpin the mark for now.</p>
<p>Von Maydell at UBS, however, said the modest interest rate expectations were justified because the industrial upturn was still export driven and final German demand remained weak.</p>
<p>Economic data released today was largely ignored. Real German retail sales dropped 4.4 year-on-year percent in June compared with a drop of 3.4 percent in May. Analysts said the numbers were a little dated.</p>
<p>Yen weakness persisted, meantime, and the latest Japanese economic data did little to suggest any change in the Bank of Japan's low interest rate policy.</p>
<p>The Economic Planning Agency said its closely-watched index of leading economic indicators for August fell below the &quot;boom or bust&quot; 50 level for the first time in five months.</p>
<p>($1=1.5323 Mark)</p>
<p>($1=112.8 Yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
