<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134615" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BFI at four month high as Panamaxes lead the way.</title>
<headline>BFI at four month high as Panamaxes lead the way.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Baltic Freight Index (BFI) rose a further 23 points on Tuesday to 1,199, its highest since June 27 this year.</p>
<p>Panamaxes continued to set the pace for the BFI and brokers reported Despina 65,644 dwt fixed by Korea Line delivery USGulf mid-November for trip Far East at a firmer $13,250 daily plus $260,000 bonus.</p>
<p>The South African market was also strengthening and PAN Ocean were reported to have fixed Gortys 71,500 dwt delivery Richards Bay trip German North Sea in the region of $9,000/$9,500 daily.</p>
<p>On the BIFFEX moderate selling and profittaking emerged which made buyers nervous of a correction to the recent sharp rise and saw losses of between 12 and 20 points recorded by 1200 GMT. Turnover totalled 172 lots.</p>
<p>In a market report Cargill Investment Services said the physical market was still roaring ahead with shorts nervous of a tight November market, and higher fixtures were expected especially for USGulf/Far East. Higher bunker prices were also affecting rates, it added.</p>
<p>London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7771</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
