<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134642" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Wolseley profits slip, Euro market grim.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Wolseley profits slip, Euro market grim.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>British building materials company Wolseley Plc reported a one percent slip in year pretax profits on Tuesday, but despite topping analysts' forecasts in a tough market shares slid on the poor outlook for mainland Europe.</p>
<p>Pretax profits for the year ended July 31 fell to 242.9 million pounds ($387 million) from 245.4 million. But sales rose to 4.31 billion from 3.78 billion pounds and the dividend was raised to 10.35 pence from 9.80 last year.</p>
<p>The fallback in profits had been flagged in a profit warning earlier this year.</p>
<p>But Wolseley survived the difficult conditions better than others partly thanks to its lower European exposure. The group has 50 percent of its sales in the U.S.</p>
<p>Chairman Richard Ireland reported organic sales growth across all three divisions blaming the lower profits on &quot;poor economic conditions in mainland Europe and volatile lumber prices in the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The results for 1996 should be set against the background of economic difficulties in France and Austria and a flat home (UK) market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But in an interview with Reuters chief financial controller Stephen Webster said &quot;I do not see an upturn in the next 12 months in France, Austria or Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>He denied it would seriously dampen profits this coming year, explaining that conditions remain stable.</p>
<p>The UK market showed a glimmer of recovery, with spending on repair and maintenance of homes moving ahead.</p>
<p>But Webster said the housebuilding sector had seen companies using up existing stock so there has been little feed-through to companies like Wolseley. He predicted it would be spring before the industry felt the benefits.</p>
<p>The finance chief also expressed concern about the threat of an interest rate hike in the U.S. &quot;A half a percent would not be a big deal but one percent could damage confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>The caution in all its markets was enough to push shares lower. By 1045 GMT they were down 13 pence at 494.</p>
<p>The new chief executive John Young did not signal any departure from the group's existing strategy.</p>
<p>But Webster signalled the possibility of some change &quot;We are keen to keep the good things. If anything it may mean a change of style. &quot;But there are no sacred cows in Wolseley. We will take difficult decisions if needed.&quot;</p>
<p>Young said in the interim statement he wanted to look to expansion into new regions and products. With gearing at a low 7.7 percent, there is scope to raise it to around 30 percent if a big acquisition comes along, said Webster.</p>
<p>$1=.6270 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
