<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134690" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada auto union still hopes for GM deal.</title>
<headline>Canada auto union still hopes for GM deal.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contract talks between the Canadian Auto Workers union and General Motors Corp remained stuck on overtime issues but the union said on Tuesday it still hoped a deal could be reached to end a 19-day-old strike by about 26,000 Canadian workers.</p>
<p>Union President Buzz Hargrove told reporters after an early morning caucus meeting that the two sides had settled &quot;95 percent&quot; of contract issues but were still hung up over the union's refusal to accept mandatory overtime at GM's Oshawa assembly plant.</p>
<p>&quot;All I can say is we're working like hell to try and get this thing done today,&quot; Hargrove said.</p>
<p>Talks continued overnight past a self-imposed Monday midday deadline after both sides agreed they were too close to a deal to recess the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We've come a long way ... we're not going to let this thing slip away,&quot; Hargrove said shortly before midnight Monday.</p>
<p>Both sides have been saying since early Monday that they were just hours away from a bargain.</p>
<p>GM spokesman Stew Low said the overtime issue was crucial to both sides but that it remained solvable.</p>
<p>&quot;(Hargrove) is as tough on the issue as he says we are,&quot; said Low. &quot;We'll see how it goes.&quot;</p>
<p>Hargrove and GM chief negotiator Dean Munger stepped into the overtime fray, a local-level issue, after other issues at the master bargaining level were virtually all settled Monday.</p>
<p>Agreement on what had been seen as the most contentious issue of contracting out work to non-union factories, known as outsourcing, was reached Monday.</p>
<p>GM said Monday the ripple effect of the Canadian strike idled 18,371 GM workers in the United States and Mexico.</p>
<p>GM's stock was up 50 cents at $54.375 in morning trading on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
