<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134641" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Brent CFDs tumble with outright prices.</title>
<headline>Brent CFDs tumble with outright prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brent CFDs took a tumble on Tuesday in thin market trade and lower outright levels.</p>
<p>On the physical side refiners and traders alike looked for premiums on non-Brent North Sea sweet grades to fall as high freight rates took their toll on refining margins.</p>
<p>North Sea crudes like Forties, Ekofisk and Oseberg were expected to lose some of the rich premiums seen last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The grades were overdone and some are seeing a large build in unsold cargoes. Buyers are looking at margins that have been seriously hit in the last week and are not interested in paying high premiums,&quot; one refiner said.  </p>
<p>Outright December Brent on the IPE lost over 20 cents on Tuesday morning to trade at 1028 GMT at $24.43 a barrel.</p>
<p>Although this weeks CFDs were still bid at Nov evens, next week (Oct 28-01) was offered as low as Dec +24 cents -- down 10 cents on the day.</p>
<p>The Oct 28-01 11-15 roll traded earlier at +18 cents and was last done at +16 cents.</p>
<p>A Forties Nov 10-12 cargo offered at Dated +40 cents saw no buying interest emerging, traders said. The one Brent cargo in today's chains was expected to be kept and Monday's big Brent buyer was there again to buy, traders said.  </p>
<p>Urals in the Med talked a couple of cents firmer, underpinned by loading delays at Novorossiisk, but with refiners preferring sweeter barrels traders said the upside was limited.</p>
<p>&quot;The sours are not actively traded at the moment -- all the interest is in West African,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Maintenance work on the main pipeline supplying the 650,000 barrels per day (bpd) terminal was delaying late October loadings by three to four days, a Med refiner said.</p>
<p>Price talks for November barrels of Syrian crude were deadlocked on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
