<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134682" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Sumitomo fraud inquiry continues - officials.</title>
<headline>British Sumitomo fraud inquiry continues - officials.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Serious Fraud Office (SFO) said it continues its own inquiry into the copper scandal even though Sumitomo Corp said it had no evidence for complaint against foreign brokers or that the market was manipulated. &quot;The investigation continues,&quot; James O'Donoghue, head of information for the SFO, said on Tuesday. He added that his office has neither made any arrests nor filed any complaints.</p>
<p>Tokyo prosecutors said on Tuesday they arrested ex-Sumitomo star copper trader Yasuo Hamanaka on two counts of forging documents. But Sumitomo said it had found no evidence that he had manipulated the copper market.</p>
<p>The world market is based on the London Metal Exchange (LME) which is the subject now of a top-to-bottom review by the British regulator, the Securities and Investments Board, separate from the fraud inquiry. The Japanese metals conglomerate also said it had found no evidence that would lead it to take formal action against foreign metal brokers. &quot;The Japanese investigation is obviously different from the SFO's investigation so our investigation continues as it has done,&quot; O'Donoghue at the British SFO said.</p>
<p>Asked whether Sumitomo's statements would make the SFO investigation more difficult, he said, &quot;I couldn't comment on that. I've not seen the information to indicate that.&quot;</p>
<p>The SFO had a good relationship with Japanese officials and &quot;we shall continue to liase closely with the Japanese authorities as we have done throughout&quot;.</p>
<p>He could not say when the SFO inquiry might end.</p>
<p>Early LME copper trading was routine on Tuesday despite the fresh Hamanaka news.</p>
<p>Any further impact on prices depends on whether there are fresh disclosures about how far the huge holdings of copper that he is alleged to have built up have been unloaded.</p>
<p>Copper is down from $2,700 per tonne to around $1,950 since he lost his job in June and allegations that he cost Sumitomo $2.6 billion in maverick trades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
