<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134725" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon's new parliament gets down to work.</title>
<headline>Lebanon's new parliament gets down to work.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanon's new parliament began work on Tuesday, re-electing pro-Syrian Shi'ite Moslem leader Nabih Berri to a second term as speaker before preparing to appoint a new prime minister.</p>
<p>Caretaker Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri was widely expected to be nominated to a third term of office within the next few days.</p>
<p>The 128-member parliament, dominated by pro-Syrian deputies, voted 121-0 with four abstentions at its first meeting to reappoint Berri, a civil war militia leader considered Syria's closest political ally in Lebanon.</p>
<p>The parliament, elected in five rounds of voting in August and September, includes 49 newcomers. Many members are wealthy businessmen who ran on government-backed lists of candidates but 19 seats are still being contested in the courts following widespread allegations of electoral fraud.</p>
<p>Eighteen losing candidates have appealed to the Constitutional Council to cancel the victories of their rivals and declare them elected, alleging fraud and intimidation, mostly by pro-government forces.</p>
<p>Another defeated candidate has asked the council to cancel the entire election on grounds that the law under which it was held was unconstitutional and that voting was subject to intolerable fraud.</p>
<p>With 35 millionaires and three billionaires among its members, the new parliament is probably one of the wealthiest in the world.</p>
<p>Hariri, a construction tycoon, heads the billionaires, followed by two newcomers -- Issam Fares, also a construction tycoon who made his fortune in Saudi Arabia, and Ahmed Hbous, who has business interests in Canada, the United States and Asia as well as in Lebanon, Syria and the Gulf.</p>
<p>Hariri, who stepped down routinely last week to make way for the selection of a new prime minister and government by the new parliament, is expected to form a new government by the end of the month.</p>
<p>Hariri has held office since October 1992, launching a reconstruction drive that has made big strides towards rebuilding Lebanon from the ruins of the 1975-90 civil war.</p>
<p>His continuance in power is widely considered indispensable if Lebanon is to continue its recovery, despite warnings from some politicians, labour unionists, clerics and commentators that he must pay more attention to social problems and poverty.</p>
<p>Acting speaker Kabalan Issa el-Khoury, parliament's oldest member, echoed the concerns in his opening speech: &quot;The ghost of hunger is knocking on the doors of the Lebanese people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>President Elias Hrawi is due to consult all the deputies in the next few days on their choice of a prime minister and must appoint the majority preference.</p>
<p>Consultations begin after parliament completes its election of officials, expected on Tuesday, but it was was not immediately known whether Hrawi would start summoning deputies to his palace immediately, or wait until French President Jacques Chirac completes an official visit to Beirut on Thursday and Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
