<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134772" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices down 1/8, deals loom.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices down 1/8, deals loom.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices dipped about 1/8 point in early trade as players waited for close to $2.2 billion of new competitive and negotiated supply to hit Tuesday's market.</p>
<p>&quot;We're waiting on supply, that's the deal, that's the whole deal today,&quot; one trader said, adding that pricing largely will determine how supply fares.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you need a little price concession to get it well received,&quot; the trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Their minds are focused elsewhere. A 5-1/2 percent 20 (year), 30-year bond doesn't do anything for them, and do you blame them?&quot;</p>
<p>Competition for the retail investor's dollar grows every year, he said, citing stocks as one example.</p>
<p>&quot;When I started in this business, muni buyers were muni buyers, they never bought anything else,&quot; the trader said. &quot;Now the next generation who has money is looking at a lot of different things, and it's got to be attractive.&quot;  </p>
<p>The day's competitive deals include a $500 million California offering scheduled for 1200 EDT, while a $459 million New York City Transit Authority deal via Dillon Read &amp; Co tops Tuesday's negotiated slate.</p>
<p>A trader who focuses on New Jersey paper said that state &quot;has a calendar this week for the first time in a long time.&quot;</p>
<p>He estimated the New Jersey calendar at close to $900 million. While he expects to see some institutional demand, retail interest is less certain, the trader said. Included in that total is a $713 million New Jersey Transporatation Trust Fund Authority offering through competitive sale.</p>
<p>&quot;Retail is just not a participant right now,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Tuesday's actively quoted secondary issues included Massachusetts Bay Transportation Authority's 5-1/4 percent bonds of March 2020. The bonds were bid at a 5.76 percent net yield, versus a 5.73 percent net yield for Monday closing bid.</p>
<p>In debt futures, the December municipal contract was down 3/32 at 114-3/32. The December T-bond contract was down 3/32 at 110-31/32. The MOB spread was 100.</p>
<p>In the government market, the benchmark 30-year bond was down 6/32 at 99-3/32 to yield 6.82 percent.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
