<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134745" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait to start futures trading on stock exchange.</title>
<headline>Kuwait to start futures trading on stock exchange.</headline>
<byline>Inal Ersan</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait has approved futures trading on its stock exchange only by investment portfolio managing institutions, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But they told Reuters that actual futures trading will not start immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;A decree has permitted futures trading but actual trading will take place at a later stage,&quot; said one official refusing to give a target date.</p>
<p>The decree issued by the Ministry of Commerce and Industry stipulates that only institutions licensed to manage portfolios can carry out futures trade deals, he said.</p>
<p>They also should have a paid-up capital of no less than five million dinars ($16.7 million), said the official, noting that they need to hand regular reports on their financial position to the exchange.</p>
<p>The decree also says interested firms should acquire permission from the Central Bank and that their applications should be approved by the exchange.</p>
<p>Institutions licenced to deal in futures will not be allowed to place their own shares on that market, the decree published in this week's official gazette said.</p>
<p>Officials said the Kuwait Stock Exchange plans to issue further technical guidelines to govern futures trading.</p>
<p>Officials see the move as a profitable expansion of business but critics want the exchange to set tough controls to avoid dangerous uncontrolled speculation.</p>
<p>In 1982 an unofficial exchange crashed, resulting in tens of billions of dollars in losses and debts.</p>
<p>Officials have said futures trading will run for six months on a trial basis after which a fully fledged futures market could be launched in the oil-rich state.</p>
<p>The exchange has been riding high for several weeks. The index and trading volume and value have been setting almost weekly records in recent months during the short 2-1/2-hour trading sessions five days a week. On Monday, the index closed at 1,901.7 points, almost a 40 percent rise so far this year.</p>
<p>Only nationals of Gulf Arab states -- Saudi Arabia, Bahrain, the United Arab Emirates, Qatar, Oman and Kuwait -- can trade on the exchange. Foreign residents can invest through mutual funds ran by local firms.</p>
<p>Kuwait is considering opening trade for foreign investors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
