<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134729" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>OMAN: Oman edges close to gas export potential.</title>
<headline>Oman edges close to gas export potential.</headline>
<dateline>MUSCAT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gulf Arab Oman struck a $1.4 billion funding agreement on Tuesday to tap gas supplies vital to realise its ambitions to be a leading gas exporter at the turn of the century.</p>
<p>Oman's Ministry of National Economy announced that Royal Dutch Shell Group, France's Total SA and independent Partex would plough around $1.4 billion into the the sultanate's untapped gas fields to feed an export-orientated liquefied natural gas (LNG) plant in the sultanate.</p>
<p>&quot;The Government would pay the investment value to private shareholders as of 2001 through 2006 from the income earned from selling gas and condensate associated with natural gas,&quot; a statement released by the economy ministry said.</p>
<p>Shell, Total and Partex together own 40 percent in Oman's leading oil firm Petroleum Development Oman (PDO), which already accounts for more than 90 percent of the country's oil and natural gas production.</p>
<p>&quot;The funding agreement...requires that the private shareholders (Shell, Total, Partex) shall make available the funds needed for constructing the upstream project,&quot; a statement from the ministry said.</p>
<p>Under a separate deal signed Tuesday the three partners will operate the upstream facilities for 25 years and supply gas to a liquefaction plant at Sur, a fertiliser plant, a power project</p>
<p>Oman is aiming to build a $6 billion LNG project that will begin gas exports to lucrative power markets in Asia at the turn of the decade.</p>
<p>A gas supply deal with South Korea's Korea Gas Corporation is expected to be signed on Wednesday, while sales to Thailand are also expected to be concluded shortly.</p>
<p>Oman -- a modest oil producer of some 900,000 barrels per day (bpd) of crude -- has said that the LNG project had the potential to boost the country's income by 20 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUSCAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="OMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
