<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134704" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait prison deportees on hunger strike.</title>
<headline>Kuwait prison deportees on hunger strike.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twenty-five inmates at Kuwait's deportation centre have gone on hunger strike and one of three who injured themselves was taken to hospital, the Interior Ministry said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty-five inmates at the Talha prison went on a hunger strike yesterday (Monday),&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Three of them (inmates) intentionally inflicted wounds to themselves using a sharp object,&quot; it said. &quot;One of them was taken to hospital for medical attention.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement did not say why the inmates were on hunger strike. &quot;The concerned departments at the ministry took the necessary measures to end the strike,&quot; it said without elaboration.</p>
<p>A member of parliament who declined to be identified said earlier he had been told by private sources that 28 prisoners at ward five at the centre, where hundreds of people are held prior to deportation, had been on hunger strike for five days.</p>
<p>He said the strikers were protesting against being held without conviction. &quot;Their demands were merely to meet any senior official,&quot; the deputy said by telephone.</p>
<p>Talha, a converted school, was set up after the 1991 Gulf War. It houses foreigners suspected of violating national security, people who lack work permits and criminals who have completed prison terms and are awaiting deportation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
