<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134756" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wildfire races toward Malibu's homes of the stars.</title>
<headline>Wildfire races toward Malibu's homes of the stars.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A wind-driven firestorm on Monday raced across the mountains of southern California to the Pacific Ocean near the star colony of Malibu, destroying a number of structures in its path.</p>
<p>The fire, which started near the suburb of Calabasas, 35 miles (56 kms) northwest of downtown Los Angeles, had charred at least 4,000 acres (1,600 hectares) by nightfall as it made its relentless march across the Santa Monica Mountains.</p>
<p>Hundreds of residents fled their homes, and the blaze spread so fast that authorities were unable to provide reliable damage estimates.</p>
<p>Fire officials said they had confirmation of destruction of at least one large home, several out-buildings and two mobile homes, but TV news helicopter pilots reported seeing at least 20 structures burned. No deaths or injuries were reported.</p>
<p>The Calabasas wildfire brought back memories of the Malibu fires of 1993 in which hundreds of homes, including those of movie stars, were burned to the ground.</p>
<p>Flames reached the scenic Pacific Coast Highway just north of Malibu on Monday as another branch of the wildfire approached the hills above the city.</p>
<p>The highway, the main coastal route, was closed to normal traffic as fire engines raced from one hot spot to another. Smoke billowed overhead and visibility was reduced to only a few feet in some areas as a line of fire made its way down mountain ridges to the coast.</p>
<p>&quot;The fire continues to move toward Malibu,&quot; said fire Capt. Michael Freeman. He said 1,500 firefighters were battling the fierce blaze on the ground, aided by water-dropping helicopters and fixed-wing planes.</p>
<p>Residents of the area were forced to flee their homes, many of them taking horses and family pets with them. Four schools were evacuated as the blaze spread at an alarming rate, with the dense smoke virtually blocking out the sun in some areas, and Pepperdine University in Malibu cancelled its evening classes.</p>
<p>To the southeast of Los Angeles, another wildfire destroyed at least 12 expensive homes and damaged eight others in an exclusive Orange County community.</p>
<p>California's notorious Santa Ana winds, gusting up to 50 mph (80 kph), spread both blazes quickly, forcing hundreds of people to evacuate their homes.</p>
<p>The Orange County blaze in a posh suburb near Tustin was brought under control in about three hours, but not before it had wreaked havoc in the neighbourhood of million-dollar homes.</p>
<p>The Santa Ana winds, which spring up every October and often last for several weeks, were responsible for spreading the flames in the southern California firestorms of the autumn of 1993, which destroyed nearly 1,000 homes and caused hundreds of millions of dollars in damages.</p>
<p>Orange County officials said the blaze near the town of Tustin, about 30 miles (50 km) southeast of Los Angeles, appeared to have started when a tree limb snapped by the strong winds fell on a power line. A nearby house burned and embers from the fire carried by the wind spread to other homes.</p>
<p>Those who chose to stay in their homes dampened their roofs with fire hoses and made fire breaks of garden dirt with shovels and spades.</p>
<p>The Santa Ana winds also caused havoc with power supplies in Orange County, downing lines and leaving about 50,000 people without electricity at one point, said Southern California Edison spokesman Steve Conroy.</p>
<p>Both fires were fought on the ground and from the air, but high winds were also hampering the efforts of water-dropping helicopters, turning the water into a fine spray that had little effect on the flames.</p>
<p>So-called &quot;super-scooper&quot; planes, which scoop up thousands of gallons of water at a time and then deposit them on the flames, were grounded for a while in the Calabasas fire because of high winds and dense smoke.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
