<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134702" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish money/forex/bond closing report.</title>
<headline>Turkish money/forex/bond closing report.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Turkish central bank injected a total of 16.8 trillion lira on Tuesday via overnight lending and an open market t-bill repurchase auction to relieve the cash squeeze gripping the market in the past five weeks.</p>
<p>It fed 8.8 trillion lira overnight at 75 percent to banks after buying 8 trillion lira of nine-day repos in the morning at an average annual rate of 73.50 percent, up from 72.67 percent at last Thursday's seven-day repo auction.</p>
<p>Overnight money also traded at 74.75 percent. The central bank had lent 25.5 trillion lira overnight at 75 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>The lira closed slightly easier at 95,350 to the dollar on banks' dollar demand in the afternoon, despite the dollar's weakness against the mark in world markets. It had opened firmer at 95,240 against Monday's 95,320 close.</p>
<p>The central bank set its dollar rate for banks' compulsory currency transfers at 95,050 lira at the opening, down from 95,150 at Monday's close. It first raised, then decreased the rate during the day to close it at 95,050 lira.</p>
<p>T-bill yields dropped by around one point across the board in rising trade volume.</p>
<p>&quot;The market expects the Treasury to open an auction on Friday with a maturity date longer than June 1997. This fuelled buying,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The Treasury usually holds auctions on Tuesdays, but Turkish markets will be closed from noon on Monday to Wednesday next week due to an official holiday. Next Wednesday, the Treasury will repay 140 trillion of t-bill maturities.</p>
<p>The average yield on the most heavily traded June 4 fell to 121.85 percent from Monday's 122.89 percent. The second most active April 9 paper yielded 115.69 percent, down from yesterday's 117.13 percent average.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 08 75</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
