<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134718" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: FORECAST-Israeli economy seen slowing down.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Israeli economy seen slowing down.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's economy will grow by just 3.0-3.5 percent next year and even less if the government does not maintain fiscal discipline and keep the Middle East peace process on track, Israel Discount Bank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Under certain conditions (for example, the failure to keep to decisions taken concerning the 1997 budget and/or a freeze in the diplomatic process) the slowdown in growth will probably worsen and perhaps slide into a recession,&quot; the bank said in its monthly economic review.</p>
<p>It said gross domestic product would expand by 4.5 percent in 1996 thanks to strong growth at the start of the year. Last week, the Central Bureau of Statistics estimated GDP growth of just 3.8 percent this year against 7.1 percent last year.</p>
<p>Discount Bank estimated the government's domestic deficit would reach 4.0 percent of GDP this year -- well above the 2.5 percent target and the 3.4 percent deficit in 1995.</p>
<p>The wider deficit was due to lower-than-expected tax revenues, a situation likely to recur in 1997 because of the slowing economy, the bank said. Therefore, Discount said, the government would have to reduce spending by another one billion shekels beyond the 4.9 billion already approved by the cabinet.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has indicated that the government would make further spending cuts after parliament has approved the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>Discount said Israel's current account deficit would widen to more than five percent of GDP this year. &quot;In the event that movement towards reducing the extent of the deficit does not begin soon, Israel's credit rating will be hurt,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The widening deficit would also offset the dampening effects of the slowing economy on inflation. The bank said net borrowing by the Treasury this year would reach 8.5 billion shekels, two thirds of that occurring in the final four months of the year.</p>
<p>As a result, &quot;it appears that the certain slowing in the rate of consumer price increase in recent months does not yet signal a significant change in the inflationary environment,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
