<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134797" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West Coast crudes track WTI higher.</title>
<headline>U.S. West Coast crudes track WTI higher.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices for U.S. West Coast crudes tracked rises in West Texas Intermediate (WTI), while traders expected lighter restrictions on Line 63 to increase trade for the crude on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Light-quality Alaska North Slope (ANS) pared early losses and finished at $23.40/23.70 a barrel, up five cents from Friday.</p>
<p>WTI gained 10 cents as refiners ran at high capacity to build low heating oil stocks.</p>
<p>Official ANS discounts stayed $2.30 below WTI, but buyers said they bid $2.50 under and producers offered $2.10 below.  </p>
<p>A major producer said a West Coast refiner, based in Houston, bid ANS at $2.30 below WTI.</p>
<p>Earlier, a refinery trader took himself partly out of the ANS market by buying a 2,000 barrel-per-day parcel of British Columbian light crude.</p>
<p>The crude is slated for November pipeline delivery into his plant in Anacortes, Washington.</p>
<p>Traders said they heard rumours that high volumes of Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) crude moved east on the All-American pipeline, reducing load on Line 63 and easing allocations for November.</p>
<p>But other market players said Unocal's crude train, scheduled to begin carrying OSC and other crudes from interior California to Los Angeles next month, may have cut into Line 63 nominations.</p>
<p>Arco, which runs Line 63, set October nominations at 46.06 percent of nominations.</p>
<p>&quot;Barrels that were coming to L.A. via the pipeline are coming via the Unocal train,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Others said weak margins could also trim demand for shipments on California's Line 63. Space restrictions will be announced on Tuesday, said ARCO, which runs the Line.  </p>
<p>Traders forecast that individual shippers could send more crude on Line 63, which has been crowded since a 1994 earthquake damaged a companion line.</p>
<p>Discounts for Line 63 crude stagnated at $3.20 to $3.00 off November WTI, with outright prices up five cents to $22.60/90 a barrel.</p>
<p>Heavy California crudes were unchanged.</p>
<p>--David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles energy +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
