<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134748" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Middle East oil kings turn to gas.</title>
<headline>Middle East oil kings turn to gas.</headline>
<byline>Steven Swindells</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Middle East oil exporters are adding another string to their bow by developing their gas reserves to meet Asian power demand in the next century.</p>
<p>Gas, previously flared across the Middle East as a waste product, is now a high value commodity that could emerge as one of the financial foundations for many of the region's energy-dependent states.</p>
<p>Exporting gas trapped under the desert sands or shallow waters of the Gulf is being realised through multi-billion-dollar liquefied natural gas (LNG) projects and cross-border pipeline projects with the help of foreign backing.</p>
<p>The investments are being made to take advantage of forecasts of surging power generation demand for gas, particularly in South Korea and other thirsty Asian gas importers.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the next 15 years, world LNG demand will approach seven percent a year, while total energy demand is expected to be less than two percent,&quot; Daniel Nelson, Mobil Corp's executive vice president for LNG development, told delegates at a gas conference in the United Arab Emirates earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Asia will continue to be the world's primary demand centre,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>A flood of LNG and pipeline projects from Iran to Yemen are based on the abundant gas reserves held in the region, second only to those in Russia.</p>
<p>Iran's reserves are independently assessed at 742 trillion cubic feet, giving the Islamic republic a staggering reserve to production ratio of 595 years.</p>
<p>Qatar, which has the largest non-associated gas field outside the former Soviet Union, has a reserve production rate of 525 years.</p>
<p>The sultanate of Oman -- until now a medium-sized oil producer -- will take its major step into the gas export business on Wednesday when it signs a 25-year LNG supply deal with South Korea's Korea Gas Corp.</p>
<p>Qatar will start to reap the rewards of its first joint venture gas project with foreign firms when its Qatargas LNG project sends its first tanker to Japan in December.</p>
<p>Iran, sitting on the world's second largest reserves of gas behind Russia, is eyeing laying gas pipelines to Europe after signing a $23 billion supply deal with Turkey in August and is reviving plans for its own LNG project.</p>
<p>Oil giant Saudi Arabia is developing its gas base to fuel the kingdom's plans for an expanding petrochemical sector which is now the cornerstone of its industrialisation programme.</p>
<p>The gas trade could also become a part of the fruits of Middle East peace with plans to supply Israel with LNG from Qatar and natural gas from Egypt actively being promoted.</p>
<p>&quot;Middle Eastern LNG supply will increase significantly over the next few years. Based only on contracted volumes, its share of total supply to Asia-Pacific markets will increase from seven percent in 1995 to around 25 percent by 2003,&quot; said Andrew Flower, British Petroleum's LNG business development manager.</p>
<p>Project designs fill the in-trays of state energy firms, while the same multinationals which developed the oil before the pan-Arab nationalisation programmes of the 1970s are frequent visitors looking to develop largely untapped gas deposits.</p>
<p>Though it may lack some of the romance attached to oil, LNG has a mystique and a financial complexity all of its own because of the vast investment sums required and the need to guarantee supply contracts long term -- some 25 years.</p>
<p>LNG is produced by freezing gas, mostly methane, to minus 160 Celsius in a sophisticated liquefaction plant and loading the frozen gas onto specialist tankers for export.</p>
<p>Insulated tankers with 40-metre-plus diameter domes sailing from Gulf ports to growing power markets in Japan, South Korea, Taiwan, India, China and Thailand is expected to become a common sight in the next decade.</p>
<p>These countries are facing increased power generation requirements to keep pace with growing economies and urban populations.</p>
<p>Backers of a new grassroots LNG plant face project costs of at least $6 billion, long construction lead times and lengthy though sustained pay-back schedules.</p>
<p>&quot;The LNG business is more a way of life than a series of short-term ventures. Without a truly long-term corporate commitment, it is illogical to spend a dime&quot;, Mobil's Nelson said.</p>
<p>Middle East oil states have already understood the economic virtue of patience.</p>
<p>-- Dubai Newsroom, +971 4 6071255</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
