<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134744" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Leading Turk polyester firm to float part capital.</title>
<headline>Leading Turk polyester firm to float part capital.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sabanci Holding, one of Turkey's leading industrial conglomerates, will open its 11th unit to the public when it floats partial capital of Turkey's biggest polyester fibre and thread producer SASA Suni ve Sentetik Elyaf Sanayii A.S. on Wednesday, a senior Sabanci official said.</p>
<p>The two-day public offer of seven percent capital of SASA, the biggest industrial firm in the Sabanci group, will be followed by partial flotation of Sabanci Holding in 1997, Hasan Gulesci, general coordinator of the Holding, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The price will be 7,200 lira per 1,000 lira nominal-valued share in the offer where 360.5 billion lira of SASA shares owned by Sabanci's banking arm Akbank will be put on sale by a 15-member consortium led by T. Sinai Kalkinma Bank and co-led by T. Is Bankasi.</p>
<p>Sinai Kalkinma said 154.5 billion lira of the offer would be allocated to foreign investors, another 154.5 billion lira to domestic investors and the remaining 51.5 billion to institutional investors. SASA's capital stands at 5.15 trillion lira.</p>
<p>&quot;SASA produces its own raw material which distinguishes it from other polyester producers in the world,&quot; Omer Sabanci, general manager of SASA, told the news conference.</p>
<p>SASA has a yearly polymerisation capacity of 246,000 tonnes and DMT (raw material) production capacity of 123,000 tonnes which it plans to raise to 246,000 tonnes in 1998.</p>
<p>Sabanci said 72 percent of the firm's activity was related to the textile sector and 28 percent to the packaging sector.</p>
<p>SASA which has 65 percent share in Turkey's polyester fibre market, 20 percent in polyester fibre, 100 percent in PET pellets and 50 percent in PET bottles, would service the packaging sector more in 1996 and 1997, Sabanci said.</p>
<p>The company, which posted $468 million of net sales in 1995, including $142.4 million of exports, targets $410 million of turnover in 1996, $450 million in 1997 and $1 billion by 2000. The initial export target is $200 million.</p>
<p>Its net profits stood at 2.86 trillion lira in the first half of 1996 after 3.84 trillion in the whole of 1995.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
