<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134740" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: AIRBUS SAYS WORLD AIR CARGO TO GROW AT 6.7 PCT ANNUAL AVERAGE TO 2015.</title>
<headline>AIRBUS SAYS WORLD AIR CARGO TO GROW AT 6.7 PCT ANNUAL AVERAGE TO 2015.</headline>
<byline>Humphrey Hudson</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>World air cargo traffic will rise at an annual average of 6.7 percent a year to the year 2015, the Airbus Industrie consortium said.</p>
<p>It added that intra-Asian trade would lead cargo traffic growth with a rise of 9.3 percent annually, and the region will almost double its share of the world total by 2015 with over 55 percent of world scheduled traffic.</p>
<p>In its &quot;Air Cargo Market&quot; forecast released here on Tuesday, Airbus said that North to South America traffic will rise seven percent annually. Europe to the Asia-Pacific region will gain 7.3 percent, while intra-European and U.S. domestic markets will show the least growth at 3.9 percent and four percent respectively.</p>
<p>Airbus expects &quot;a fairly constant increase of two percentage points above the passenger traffic rate, leading to global cargo traffic volume, being more triple the current figure by the year 2015...sectors like Europe to Asia-Pacific and Transpacific will have displaced the North Atlantic flow from its present predominant position.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Boeing Co forecast 6.6 percent growth annually to 2015, while McDonnell Douglas estimated growth of 7.4 percent to 2014 for air cargo volumes.</p>
<p>The overall fleet of cargo jets will grow to 2,799 planes by 2015, with the biggest prospects seen for aircraft with payload capacities of up to 50 tonnes, Airbus said.</p>
<p>The fleet will comprise almost 800 planes of up to 30 tonnes capacity against just over 500 in 1995, 1,200 planes between 30 and 50 tonnes compared to just over 400 last year. There will be around 400 planes in use in the 50 to 80 tonnes category,against about 100 and also 400 in the over 80 tonnes sector against 180 in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
