<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134781" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Salomon turned Q3 net equity trading loss.</title>
<headline>Salomon turned Q3 net equity trading loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Inc's third quarter net equity sales and trading revenues fell into negative territory in the third quarter, pulling overall results at the firm well below second quarter and year-ago levels.  </p>
<p>Salomon said net equity sales and trading revenues registered a loss of $26 million in the third quarter compared with a $268 million profit in the second quarter. Salomon's third quarter fixed income sales and trading revenues fell to $598 million from $706 in the second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;While quarter-to-quarter trading results are variable, overal Salomon Inc results for the first nine months of 1996 ($679 million net income) and the latest 12 months ($847 million net income) are very strong,&quot; said Salomon Chairman and Chief Executive Robert Denham in a statement.  </p>
<p>Salomon said its third quarter net income was $176 million compared with $525 million in the second quarter. It also said that Phibro income rose to $7 million in the third quarter versus a $17 million loss in the second quarter. Basic Petroleum had a loss of $46 million versus a loss of $13 million in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The firm's third quarter global investment banking revenues fell to $187 million from $251 million in the second quarter.</p>
<p>In August, Basis' Residfiner/ROSE unit complex became operational at it Texas City refinery. Basis estimates that its pretax loss would have beem reduced by $20 million to $25 million assuming the operation of a fully optimized Residfiner/ROSE unit complext for the entire quarter.</p>
<p>Corporate and other includes a pretax gain of $48 million or $31 million after tax resulting from the third quarter sale of The Mortgage Corporation Limited and its affiliates to First National Building Society of Ireland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
