<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134790" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton to call for NATO expansion by 1999.</title>
<headline>Clinton to call for NATO expansion by 1999.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mixing politics and foreign policy, President Bill Clinton will announce on Tuesday that he wants new members to join NATO no later than the 1999 50th anniversary of the security alliance, U.S. officials said.</p>
<p>In the middle of a five-state campaign trip, Clinton was using the foreign policy speech to strike a statesmanlike pose with two weeks to Election Day and to appeal to the many people of eastern European descent in the politically crucial Midwest.</p>
<p>A senior U.S. official said some countries seeking to join the North Atlantic Treaty Organization would be able to do so &quot;no later than 1999,&quot; meaning they could become members earlier, depending on how long their negotiations take.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said Clinton would not name the eastern European states he would like to see at the front of the queue for NATO membership, but would unveil his preferred date.</p>
<p>&quot;He will not likely indicate by name any specific countries but certainly will indicate what he thinks the timing should be for the accession of new members,&quot; McCurry told reporters.</p>
<p>Although McCurry declined to confirm the 1999 target date, several U.S. officials said this would be in Clinton's speech.</p>
<p>NATO ministers are to meet in December to pave the way for an alliance summit in 1997 that would name the first candidates for membership and lead to the opening of negotiations.</p>
<p>Leading his Republican opponent Bob Dole by double digits according to most national opinion polls, Clinton was clearly seeking to use the foreign policy speech to underline his role as commander-in-chief as the Nov. 5 election approaches.</p>
<p>The president's stance on NATO was close to that of Dole, who said in June that the 16-member alliance should take on additional countries in 1998 and that the first three to join should be the Czech Republic, Hungary and Poland.</p>
<p>The conventional wisdom within the alliance, which was founded in 1949 to confront the Soviet threat, is that these three are the most likely to be the first in line.</p>
<p>Adding members to NATO is a delicate matter for the United States, which is sympathetic to the demands by most former Soviet satellites to join the 16-country alliance but wary of alienating Russia.</p>
<p>Western diplomats have argued that Russia may be growing more accustomed to the prospect of the alliance expanding, but McCurry suggested there was still some unease on the subject.</p>
<p>Asked if Russia was reconciled to NATO enlargement, McCurry said: &quot;That would be an optimistic, forward-leaning reading of what has been very deep concern within the Russian Federation. The Russian people think of NATO as a Cold War institution.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was due to make the foreign policy speech at 10:45 a.m. EDT (1445 GMT) on Tuesday in Detroit, with U.S. National Security Adviser Anthony Lake expected to be in attendance.</p>
<p>However, Clinton/Gore campaign spokesman Joe Lockhart said the speech was being treated as a campaign appearance, noting that the election was close at hand.</p>
<p>With only 14 days until Election Day, Clinton was focusing this week on some of the crucial states of the Midwest, where U.S. presidential elections are often won and lost.</p>
<p>The issue of NATO expansion plays well in a state like Michigan, which has sizeable Polish and Hungarian ethnic populations.</p>
<p>Clinton flew to Detroit from Ohio on Monday, after spending Sunday campaigning in New Jersey and New York. He was scheduled later on Tuesday to fly to Florida for two days of campaigning in a state that has gone to the Republicans for the past two decades but where he now holds a narrow lead over Dole.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
