<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134783" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Scant cheer for Clinton, Dole in smalltown America.</title>
<headline>Scant cheer for Clinton, Dole in smalltown America.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Doughty</byline>
<dateline>WHAT CHEER, Iowa 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>If this small town in the heart of the American farming belt is anything to go by, neither U.S. President Bill Clinton nor Republican challenger Bob Dole have much to cheer about.</p>
<p>Set amid rolling hills and fields of corn deep in the Midwestern state of Iowa, What Cheer belies its name. A depressed farming community of around 800 people, its days of prosperity have long gone.</p>
<p>Huge trucks roll through Main Street on their way somewhere else, past rundown shops, two cemeteries, four churches, a gas station and U.S. flags fluttering in the autumn breeze.</p>
<p>For most people, the biggest issues seem to be the problems brought by a late harvest and the election of the county sheriff next week --- on the same day as the U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p>In a country that prides itself as the world's greatest democracy, disillusion with politics seems to be rife.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't pay much attention to Washington,&quot; says Beverley Hanna, 45, as she serves a drink to a solitary customer in Marilyn's Bar. &quot;They're just gonna do what they want, like always.&quot;</p>
<p>Donna Rogers, assistant manager in the general store, runs a farm with her husband. Like most people around here, they make their living from hogs, grain and cattle -- and feel that hard-pressed farmers do not get enough support from the U.S. government.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think my vote counts,&quot; she says. &quot;These people don't have our interests in mind.&quot;</p>
<p>In the nearby town of Sigourney, Chief Deputy Greg Brower leans back in his chair at the county jail and complains that a way of life is disappearing.</p>
<p>&quot;People used to leave their cars and houses unlocked around here. Now, nothing is sacred and it all gets locked up. We have problems with drugs and alcohol and most of the kids leave if they can,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing here for a young person to do. In fact, there's nothing here for an old person to do.&quot;</p>
<p>It was not always so. Founded in the 1850s, What Cheer was given its name by English and Welsh immigrants who settled here to mine coal. The name comes from the daily greeting they would use: &quot;Be of Good Cheer&quot;.</p>
<p>The town was built on the traditional virtues of smalltown America which both Republicans and Democrats claim as their own -- thrift, decency, hard work and down to earth community values.</p>
<p>But mining ended in the 1940s and a pottery factory that helped provide local employment closed in the early 1970s. Now, many of the wooden houses with their porches look uncared for and some are derelict.</p>
<p>Interest in the outside world is low, whether the subject is Bosnia or Russian President Boris Yeltsin's heart problems. Many people say the United States should concentrate more on problems at home and less on its role as the world's only remaining superpower.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States needs to take more care of its own people, instead of giving a bunch of money to other countries,&quot; says Hanna. &quot;There's people right here that need help. Money is tight. There's not much cheer in What Cheer.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WHAT CHEER, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
