<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134701" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Murdoch says Israel tax probe may deter investors.</title>
<headline>Murdoch says Israel tax probe may deter investors.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Media magnate Rupert Murdoch said the investigation by Israeli authorities of tax fraud at his News Datacom Research company could deter foreign investment in the country, the daily Yedioth Ahronot reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is bad news for those thinking of investing in Israel,&quot; Murdoch said in an interview translated into Hebrew. But, he added, &quot;I will continue to be a supporter of Israel and I will continue to invest in Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>News Datacom Research, which develops encryption systems for pay television, has become the subject of an extensive investigation by the Israel Income Tax Authority on suspicions it concealed up to $150 million in income over several years.</p>
<p>Investigators raided News Datacom Research's Jerusalem offices on Sunday, carrying off computers and boxes filled with documents.</p>
<p>Murdoch denied the company had evaded taxes and promised to cooperate with investigators. &quot;They can ask me what they want and I will tell them what I know: I know that we paid all taxes that we needed to pay according to the law, as we do every place,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Income Tax Authority has denied reports in the Israeli media that it is seeking a court order to detain Murdoch if he were to enter Israel. The authority has made no arrests in the investigation but on Monday said News Datacom Research officials were cooperating with investigators.</p>
<p>Murdoch's News Corp, which controls News Datacom Research, sharply criticised Israeli tax authorities on Tuesday. &quot;We are outraged that despite giving full co-operation to the Israeli Income Tax Authority...they have taken this large and intrusive action against the company and its employees,&quot; News Corp said in a statement issued in London.</p>
<p>News Corp said it had been &quot;assured as recently as three weeks ago by these same authorities that News Datacom Research Limited was not under investigation.&quot;</p>
<p>It said that prior to the fiscal year ending June 30, 1996, neither News Datacom Research nor News Datacom Ltd UK, the British-based parent company, had cumulative operating profits.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, the question of tax evasion in any one country regardless of the manner in which the accounting between the companies is done, is irrelevant,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
