<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134733" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt to negotiate with British group on media city.</title>
<headline>Egypt to negotiate with British group on media city.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt has sent a British-based consortium led by Sony Broadcast and Professional an invitation to start negotiations on a contract likely to be worth more than $300 million, a consortium executive said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Sony consortium was the lowest bidder for the contract to build Egypt a television production complex including six television studios, along with administrative buildings, workshops and support facilities.</p>
<p>It is part of a massive project dubbed &quot;Hollywood on the Nile&quot; in Sixth of October City, an industrial satellite city in the desert about 30 km (20 miles) west of Cairo.</p>
<p>The consortium includes Sony Broadcasting and Professional, Trafalgar House Construction International, Strand Lighting and Quantel, said Robin Blackmore, director of international marketing at the Trafalgar House company.</p>
<p>&quot;We have received a letter from the Egyptian Radio and Television Union inviting us to start negotiations. The negotiations will start on Sunday,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be negotiating the contract conditions and no doubt some technical issues. Hopefully this will lead to us signing the contract,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The authoritative Middle East Economic Digest said last week the Sony consortium had put in a bid of 1,097 million Egyptian pounds ($323 million) for the contract, about 10 percent lower than a bid by Philips of the Netherlands, with French partners BTS Studios and SAE International.</p>
<p>Blackmore confirmed the figure was about right for the Sony consortium's bid.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a major project of its kind and would mean about five years of work for Trafalgar House,&quot; said an industry analyst.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741112">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
