<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134755" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE cocoa ends lower after uneventful session.</title>
<headline>CSCE cocoa ends lower after uneventful session.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE cocoa futures ended lower in quiet dealings Monday, but key December futures held well above near-term chart support levels, trading sources said.</p>
<p>New York cocoa drifted a notch below unchanges for most of today's session, hit by carry-over speculative liquidation following the market's $23 tumble last Friday. The selling pressure appeared to dry up toward midday, but a brief upside retracement failed to gather steam.</p>
<p>Benchmark December fell $6 a tonne on the day, to $1,383, having ranged from $1,377 to $1,391. Second-position May also eased $6, to $1,412, while the remaining months fell $4 to $8.</p>
<p>With the last of the major third quarter grindings figures out of the way following last Friday's U.S data, dealers said the market may drift in a range until West Africa's harvest begins to flow in.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think cocoa will go too far up or too far down in the near-term,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Market participants took note of an announcement today that top-grower Ivory Coast would open its official marketing season in two to three days, but they said the news had little impact on the futures market.</p>
<p>On the charts, December would encounter support in the $1,375-1,380 range, while $1,400 was viewed as a key upside psychological hurdle. Further resistance was seen toward last week's high of $1,418.</p>
<p>The day's volume reached an estimated 5,267 lots, with 80 percent of the turnover posted during the first two days of trading.</p>
<p>--Wendy Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
