<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134750" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall St stocks seen opening lower.</title>
<headline>Wall St stocks seen opening lower.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A continuation of Monday's profit-taking is expected to take Wall Street stocks lower at the open on Tuesday, as the market continues to digest the rally of the last three months.</p>
<p>Analysts said that investors would be keeping an eye on Microsoft Corp, which reported earnings per share of $0.95 a share after Monday's close. The net was $0.05 per share above the First Call estimate.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are in for another profit-taking day,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, analyst at Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;When you measure the Dow's progress from its July 16 intraday low of 5182 to yesterday morning when it reached 6134, you see that the average has gone 1,000 points in only three months,&quot; Wachtel said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the major hurdle for the Dow.  We've had blue chip mania.  The broad market has not been as strong, and it's now time for the blue chips to take a pause.  A period of backing and filling is likely.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that he did not expect a strong rally in shares of Microsoft as the net per share came in at a mere $0.05 per share above estimates, which does not qualify as a blowout.</p>
<p>&quot;If you want a blowout, you need to come in strongly like Intel Corp,&quot; Wachtel said.  Intel climbed to record stock highs earlier this month after reporting third quarter net per share which was $0.23 above the First Call forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;Sun Microsystems reported earnings which were $0.04 above the forecasts, and it got slammed and taken down 10 points,&quot; Wachtel said.</p>
<p>Sun Micro, while it beat the First Call estimate, failed to live up to unofficial &quot;whisper&quot; estimates.</p>
<p>Microsoft was down 1-1/2 at 132-1/2 in trading before the open.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks ended lower, with the Nikkei Average down 179 points at 21,124.</p>
<p>In London, the FTSE 100 Index was down 15 at 4058.</p>
<p>Among U.S. shares traded in London IBM was down 1/4 at 129-3/4. General Motors Corp slipped 1/4 to 53-5/8. Philip Morris Cos Inc Inc dipped 1/4 to 93-1/4.</p>
<p>The dollar slid against the yen in Tokyo and pushed higher against the mark in Europe.</p>
<p>The long bond was down 5/32 to yield 6.82 percent.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal's Heard on the Street writes that some investors complain that Warren Buffet's Berkshire Hathaway Inc took advantage of a trying period in FlightSafety International Inc earnings to get a bargain price for the pilot-trading company.</p>
<p>The New York Times Market Place writes that U.S. corporate credit quality is improving as rating agencies raise the ratings of many companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
