<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134796" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE-Haitian voodoo - more than dolls and zombies.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Haitian voodoo - more than dolls and zombies.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The photo comes from the centre of Port-au-Prince and its image of a woman praying to a giant crucifix looks appropriate for a nation whose population is 80 percent Roman Catholic.</p>
<p>But in Haiti the saying is that 80 percent of the people are Catholic but 100 percent believe in voodoo, and the woman in the photo from the exhibition &quot;Sacred Arts of Haitian Vodou&quot; may be standing before Jesus Christ but she is holding her arms in a &quot;V&quot; used to pray to voodoo deities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very Catholic but only superficially,&quot; said Donald Cosentino, Chairman of the Folklore and Mythology Programme at the Unversity of California at Los Angeles and a curator of the exhibition. It was the blend of Catholicism and the culture of western Africa in Haiti's voodoo religion and its art -- as well as the power and beauty of the art -- that inspired Cosentino, an expert on African culture who grew up Catholic, to mount the first serious U.S. look at the creative arts of voodoo.</p>
<p>Eight years in the making, the exhibition's message is that voodoo is a rich religion and culture that has given birth to a range of beautiful objects, not Hollywood's &quot;black magic&quot; of living dead zombies and pin-filled dolls.</p>
<p>Currently on a three-year U.S. tour, it opened last spring at UCLA's Fowler Museum after eight years of planning including overcoming opposition from the National Endowment for the Humanities, which made a grant only after President Bill Clinton's inauguration in 1993. It will stay at Miami's Centre for the Fine Arts until December and then move to Chicago, Detroit, New Orleans, Baltimore and New York.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm an Africanist and had lived and worked in Africa for 20 years before going to Haiti,&quot; Cosentino said. When he first got to the Caribbean nation, he said, &quot;I went nuts. It was just much more interesting than I had ever imagined.&quot;</p>
<p>Although relatively little known compared with that of many African and Latin American nations, Haiti's art, a respite from grinding poverty for its people, has captivated foreigners for decades. It has enjoyed a renaissance since the U.S. occupation in 1994 brought Haiti into the news, but half a century ago the French author, adventurer and politician Andre Malraux wrote that Haiti produced the finest popular art in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Haiti's (art) stands absolutely alone,&quot; Cosentino said.</p>
<p>The exhibit's organisers used the spelling &quot;vodou,&quot; which means sacred in the West African Fon language, rather than the Anglicized &quot;voodoo&quot; to name the exhibition because &quot;vodou&quot; is what the religion is called in Creole, the language spoken in Haiti. &quot;We wanted to acknowledge the point of view of those who practice rather than comment on it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The exhibit includes more than 500 objects such as brightly coloured sequinned flags, sacred bottles, dolls, musical instruments, paintings, videos and photographs, as well as a full-sized replica of a voodoo temple, complete with three altars to voodoo gods, or &quot;loa.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sacred Arts of Haitian Vodou&quot; drew record crowds to the Fowler Museum. Although Los Angeles does not have a large Haitian community, visitors left offerings at the altars during its stay in that city, eventually amassing small piles of jewelry, perfume and money in the exhibit hall.</p>
<p>Cosentino said voodoo as it exists today was born during the six decades that followed Haiti's birth as the world's first black-ruled republic in 1804. During those years, the nation on the western half of Hispaniola island was virtually cut off from the outside world. Even the Catholic church had pulled out its priests in the wake of Haiti's violent, and successful, slave rebellion.</p>
<p>The ties between African religion and the Catholicism of Haiti's former French masters are evident throughout the Sacred Arts show, as painted bottles feature Catholic images that double as voodoo &quot;loa&quot; and dour-faced European saints stare out from sequin-encrusted voodoo flags. Erzulie, the voodoo spirit of love, is similar to the Virgin Mary.</p>
<p>&quot;The place was like a gigantic grandma's attic. It was as if they said, 'Let's recreate a culture for ourselves of fabulous stuff that was left,'&quot; Cosentino said of the decades after the French departed. That the process of appropriation has continued is evident in the show.</p>
<p>For example, the phallic canes carried by Baron Samedi, the male spirit of death and sex, have often been adorned with condoms since AIDS arrived in Haiti. The Sylvester Stallone action hero Rambo has found its way onto altars for war loa, and the popular 1980s poster of the actress Nastassia Kinski draped with nothing but a snake has found its way into voodoo temples, appropriated as a symbol of the spirits of life and wisdom, among whose attributes is the serpent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
