<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134723" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt suspends &quot;Alexander the Great&quot; excavation.</title>
<headline>Egypt suspends &quot;Alexander the Great&quot; excavation.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Egyptian authorities have suspended excavations by the controversial Greek archaeologist who announced last year that she had found the long-lost tomb of Alexander the Great near Siwa oasis is northwestern Egypt.</p>
<p>The suspension is part of an overall review of foreign archaeological missions by the newly apppointed head of the state's Supreme Council of Antiquities.</p>
<p>But the council has singled out the private mission led by Greek archaeologist Liana Souvaltzi for immediate suspension, pending expert assessment of its work.</p>
<p>The council said in a statement available on Tuesday that a committee would examine the Siwa site and study the architectural features that Souvaltzi's team has uncovered.</p>
<p>It gave no reasons but other foreign archaeologists said it was clearly linked to her apparently premature announcement in January 1995 that she had identified the tomb of Alexander, who died in Babylon in Mesopotamia in 323 BC.</p>
<p>An official Greek team of experts went to Siwa to investigate her claim and decided that the centrepieces of her argument, three crumbling tablets covered in Greek inscriptions, dated from a different era.</p>
<p>The council's statement said the new chairman, Ali Hassan, insisted that foreign archaeological missions must abide by the Egyptian government's regulations.</p>
<p>The regulations require that mission leaders be competent archaeologists, that they be present at the excavation site and that they restore whatever they discover.</p>
<p>The head of one large archaeological institute said he did not think it would affect what he called serious missions.</p>
<p>&quot;They were obviously suspicious about the Greek lady because of her claims. But I have been assured that all the well-established missions are not affected,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But the cultural attache at a Western embassy said he interpreted the review as the start of restrictions on foreign archaeology. &quot;Ali Hassan is of the view that very rarely will permission be granted to foreign missions,&quot; added the attache, who asked not be named.</p>
<p>The council statement quoted Ali Hassan as saying the work of the foreign missions was important and essential. The chairman himself was not available to comment on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Archaeologists said Souvaltzi has recently resumed her excavation work, which is privately financed, but it was not clear what progress she had made.</p>
<p>The three tablets were found in a grave similar to the burial site in Macedonia of Alexander's assassinated father Philip II. The grave lies about 20 km (12 miles) west of Siwa.</p>
<p>Most historians believe that Alexander, who died in Babylon after conquering much of the ancient Persian empire, was buried in the Egyptian Mediterranean city of Alexandria.</p>
<p>But he did visit Siwa in 331 BC and in the local temple to the pharaonic god Amun he was proclaimed to be the god's son.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
