<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134722" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu apologises to Chirac over security flap.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu apologises to Chirac over security flap.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu apologised on Tuesday to French President Jacques Chirac, who had complained about the tight security Israel imposed during his visit to the Old City of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>&quot;I want first of all to apologise for what happened this morning. President Chirac told me what happened...I am very sorry. We did that for a good cause, to protect a friend,&quot; Netanyahu said during a photo opportunity with Chirac.  </p>
<p>Chirac made no comment as he sat beside Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Earlier, Chirac's spokeswoman said the French leader would lodge an official protest with Netanyahu over the all-embracing protection for his visit to Moslem and Christian holy sites in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>A red-faced Chirac, teeth clenched and elbows flailing, snapped at Israeli security men to &quot;go away&quot; as he got his first taste of the type of protection that has been in force in Israel for local and visiting leaders since Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin was assassinated a year ago.</p>
<p>Security men wrestled journalists away from his party and armed border guards stood poised outside each Palestinian shop on the walking tour of the walled Old City.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
