<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134738" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar emir names third son heir apparent.</title>
<headline>Qatar emir names third son heir apparent.</headline>
<byline>Kedar Sharma</byline>
<dateline>DOHA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's emir on Tuesday named his 18-year-old third son as heir apparent, the first step in a reshuffle of the Gulf Arab state's top jobs expected to introduce changes to its vital energy industry.</p>
<p>A royal decree by the Emir Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani named Sheikh Jassim bin Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani crown prince with immediate effect.</p>
<p>Sheikh Jassim, 18, a second lieutenant in the Qatari army, is one of four sons of the emir. He graduated from the British military academy at Sandhurst in August.</p>
<p>Diplomats and officials said the emir was also expected to name his brother Sheikh Abdullah bin Khalifa al-Thani prime minister.</p>
<p>Western-educated Sheikh Abdullah was named deputy prime minister and interior minister after Sheikh Hamad toppled their father, Sheikh Khalifa bin Hamad al-Thani, in June 1995.</p>
<p>The new emir himself had been prime minister since then.</p>
<p>The decree naming the crown prince said the emir consulted other members of the royal family, the largest single family in Qatar, about the appointment as well as tribal leaders, members of the consultative council and the armed forces.</p>
<p>Diplomats and officials had said on Monday the emir was expected to announce this week a cabinet reshuffle that was widely expected to include setting up a supreme council of energy to replace the energy and industry ministry.</p>
<p>The current minister Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah, who has held the energy portfolio since 1992 and heads most of Qatar's energy projects, may move to the public health ministry. The emir was expected to head the new council himself, officials said.</p>
<p>Qatar is a small oil exporter whose native population of 120,000 is among the world's richest with gross national product of $22,000 each. Some 440,000 foreigners, mostly from the Indian subcontinent and Iran, work in Qatar.</p>
<p>Qatar's oil reserves are overshadowed by its natural gas deposits which are exceeded only by those of Russia and Iran.</p>
<p>The diplomats and officials said the looming cabinet reshuffle, which had been expected in September, gained momentum after the ruling family said on Sunday it had ended a row over billions of dollars missing from the treasury since the former emir was ousted.</p>
<p>They said the changes were prompted by the need to give adequate representation to different sections of the ruling al-Thani family, whose members currently hold 11 of the 19 cabinet posts.</p>
<p>In the reshuffle, Foreign Minister Sheikh Hamad bin Jassim bin Jabr al-Thani, may be named deputy prime minister. The Minister of State for Defence, Sheikh Hamad bin Abdullah al-Thani, may be moved to the interior ministry with the same rank.</p>
<p>Some new faces were also expected in the reshuffled cabinet.</p>
<p>The diplomats and officials said the settlement between the emir and the father he deposed helped consolidate Sheikh Hamad's power and paved way for the expected appointments.</p>
<p>They said the deposed emir was expected to return to Qatar soon as part of the settlement over the disputed accounts. Unofficial estimates say the sum controlled by the deposed emir ranged from $3 billion to $7 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
