<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134719" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco's SNI ceded 30 pct stake in car firm.</title>
<headline>Morocco's SNI ceded 30 pct stake in car firm.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco's second largest private conglomerate Societe Nationale d'Investissement, ceded its 30 percent stake in a car accessory firm worth 2.9 million dirhams ($0.34 million), Upline Securities stockbroker said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;SNI ceded its stake in Renault Industrie Maroc due to risks related to the dependance on one sole client and one sole supplier,&quot; Mohamed Mekouar, analyst at the Casablanca-based Upline Securities said.</p>
<p>The client and supplier is the leading French-Moroccan company Renault Maroc.</p>
<p>SNI's move confirms the holding is focusing its interest on the traditional activities which are finance, agro-industry and cement, Mekouar added.</p>
<p>Its most profitable listed companies are cement firm Ciments Artificiels de Meknes, edible oil firm Leusieur, and sugar refinery Cosumar,</p>
<p>One of the 46 listed stocks on the Casablanca bourse, SNI has a market capitalisation of 5.6 billion dirhams and was last traded at 570 dirhams.</p>
<p>SNI holding was established in Casablanca in 1966 and has a capital of 990 million dirhams.</p>
<p>It made a net profit of 30 million dirhams in the first half of the year but gave no comparison for the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>($1= 8.7 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
