<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134784" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wind-whipped wildfires threaten Malibu, California.</title>
<headline>Wind-whipped wildfires threaten Malibu, California.</headline>
<byline>Matt Spetalnick</byline>
<dateline>MALIBU, Calif 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Firefighters battled through the night into Tuesday against wind-driven wildfires that cut a path of destruction from the mountains to the sea and sent thousands fleeing the celebrity enclave of Malibu.</p>
<p>It was the biggest of three major blazes that altogether consumed about 13,000 acres (5,300 hectares) across southern California on Monday, damaging or destroying more than 30 homes and dozens of other structures.</p>
<p>Malibu was the focal point of a massive firefighting effort early on Tuesday after a two-mile-wide (three-km-wide) wall of smoke and flame roared across the Santa Monica Mountains to the edge of the Pacific Ocean, threatening seaside mansions and beachfront bungalows.</p>
<p>With the fire continuing to burn out of control, more than 1,500 firefighters descended on the area along with a small fleet of water-dropping tanker planes and helicopters.</p>
<p>While many residents heeded the call to evacuate, some of the city's most famous homeowners stayed behind to defend their properties.</p>
<p>Actress Shirley MacLaine watered down the roof of her home to protect it from flames that licked dangerously close by. After nightfall, it appeared to have weathered the threat but was covered with ash and cinders. &quot;My place is a mess,&quot; she told Los Angeles TV station KCBS.</p>
<p>The fire started on Monday -- almost three years after southern California's devastating firestorms of 1993 -- near the suburb of Calabasas, 35 miles (56 kms) northwest of downtown Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Fueled by fierce, dry Santa Ana winds, flames raced to the coast in less than six hours, scorching nearly 9,000 acres (3,600 hectares) along the way. The blaze spread so fast that authorities were unable to provide reliable damage estimates.</p>
<p>Fire officials said they had confirmation of destruction of at least one large home, several sheds and two mobile homes, but TV news helicopter pilots reported seeing at least 20 structures burned. No deaths or injuries were reported. Authorities said they had no clues to the cause of fire.</p>
<p>Earlier on Monday, a wind-whipped blaze destroyed 10 homes and damaged 19 others in an exclusive neighborhood in the hills of Orange County southeast of Los Angeles. Officials believe it was caused by a downed power line.</p>
<p>Firefighters were also battling a 4,500-acre (1,800-hectare) blaze that destroyed at least 10 structures, some of them houses, north of San Diego, officials said. Hundreds of other homes were reportedly threatened.</p>
<p>The Calabasas wildfire brought back memories of the Malibu fires of 1993 in which three people died and about 350 homes were destroyed.</p>
<p>Authorities credited tougher safety standards, better planning and sheer luck with limiting the damage this time, but with more 40 mile-per-hour (65-km-per-hour) wind gusts expected on Tuesday, they were far from ready to declare victory.</p>
<p>Another 600 to 700 firefighters were on the way from other parts of the West.</p>
<p>Malibu, a trendy town best known as a haven for the rich and famous, looked more like a war zone as it struggled with its second major fire disaster in three years.</p>
<p>Black smoke billowed skyward, sometimes reducing visibility to a few feet, and gray ash fell like rain. The scenic Pacific Coast Highway was closed to normal traffic to allow emergency vehicles to rush from one hot spot to another.</p>
<p>Residents of the area were forced to flee their homes, many of them taking horses and family pets with them. Several schools were evacuated and were expected to remain closed Tuesday. Malibu's Pepperdine University canceled all classes.</p>
<p>Emergency shelters were opened, but many of the town's well-heeled evacuees chose to seek refuge at hotels further inland or at the homes of friends and relatives.</p>
<p>The main culprit in southern California's latest firestorm was the Santa Ana winds, which arrive each fall. Wind gusts were clocked on Monday at more than 50 miles (80 km) an hour. The hot, dry winds sweep in from the desert, picking up speed as they squeeze through the region's canyons and mountain passes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MALIBU, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
