<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134760" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soyoil expiry seen calm despite open interest.</title>
<headline>CBOT soyoil expiry seen calm despite open interest.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tuesday's expiry of Chicago Board of Trade October soyoil and soymeal contracts will likely go off quietly despite a recent increase in soyoil open interest, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's going to be too wild,&quot; said a cash-connected analyst. &quot;The people who had to get out, got out today.&quot;</p>
<p>CBOT October soyoil and soymeal contracts expire at 1201 CDT Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Open interest in October soyoil increased by nine lots on Friday to 619 lots, CBOT reported. But traders downplayed the increase saying the total remained small.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got some funds short in the October (soyoil) and there was a little export business done,&quot; said one floor trader, explaining the increase in activity. &quot;I don't think it's significant at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Open interest in soymeal fell by 452 lots to 1,262 as of Friday, CBOT reported.</p>
<p>Funds were said to be holding long positions in soymeal but many liquidated those on Monday, pit sources said.  </p>
<p>CBOT price action supported that contention as October soyoil closed 0.09 cent a lb higher while soymeal ended $4.70 per ton lower.</p>
<p>Commercials likely account for the remaining open interest in soyoil, the cash-connected analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Commercials can ride past the last trading day,&quot; he said, noting commercials likely intend to make or take delivery.</p>
<p>CBOT registrations of soyoil in deliverable locations increased by 28 lots late Friday, bringing the total as of Monday to 3,510 lots.</p>
<p>&quot;I did see we had a little more oil registered,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;Commercials may have posted that, so open interest would increase at that point.&quot;</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
