<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134716" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Italy to set up interest section in Baghdad.</title>
<headline>Italy to set up interest section in Baghdad.</headline>
<byline>Hassan Hafidh</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy, seeking to revive its once lucrative trade with Iraq, will open an interest section in Baghdad next week, an Italian official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Antonio Loche, Secretary-General of the government-funded Italian Institute for Asia, said an Italian charge d'affaires would arrive in Baghdad early next week to head an interest section that would open under the Hungarian flag.</p>
<p>&quot;Cesare Ragaglini will arrive on Saturday or Sunday as president of Italy's Interest Section in Baghdad,&quot; Loche told Reuters.</p>
<p>Loche said an Iraqi diplomat left for Rome on Monday to head Iraq's interest section, operating under the Sudanese flag.</p>
<p>&quot;Qais al-Yakoubi who will head the Iraqi interest section in Rome has left Baghdad yesterday (Monday),&quot; said Loche, who is invited by the ruling Baath party.</p>
<p>In February, Italy sent a mission to Iraq to assess possibilities of opening an interest section in Baghdad working under the Hungarian embassy.</p>
<p>Iraq severed diplomatic ties with Italy and other Arab and Western countries which took part in the U.S.-led military coalition which drove Iraqi troops out of Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>Scores of Italian businessmen and traders have flocked to Baghdad recently to secure deals in the lucrative market. Italy was Iraq's fourth trading partner before the Gulf crisis.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini announced in July that the planned interest section would be opened but gave no date.</p>
<p>Loche, who met several Iraqi officials including Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz, said Italian companies had obtained permission from the U.N. sanctions committee to send to Iraq in December $130,000 worth of medicine and medical equipment.</p>
<p>Iraq is under stringent U.N. trade sanctions imposed on it after its 1990 invasion of Kuwait. The curbs include a ban in Iraq's oil exports and imports of all commodities except for food and medicine, for which Iraq has little cash to pay for.</p>
<p>On May 20, Iraq and the U.N. signed an &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal allowing it to sell $2 billion worth of oil to buy urgent needs. The long-awaited agreement has been stalled because of the inter-Kurdish fighting in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Loche said that 30 Italian firms would organise a medical fair in Baghdad on December 14 to 18.</p>
<p>Last June, representatives of 35 Italian firms discussed in Baghdad possible trade deals with Iraq in accordance with the oil pact.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, Italian companies have not signed any contract with Iraq, but they signed several cooperation minutes,&quot; Loche said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
