<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134728" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt warns Israel of dangers to peace.</title>
<headline>Egypt warns Israel of dangers to peace.</headline>
<byline>Mona Eltahawy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian Minister Amr Moussa warned Israel on Tuesday that the Middle East would &quot;enter a very serious phase&quot; unless it fulfils its peace promises.</p>
<p>Moussa was speaking after French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette met Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak for talks on what Europe could do to help the peace process and to prepare for the visit to Egypt on Friday by French President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>&quot;Either Israel implements the agreements or the Middle East will enter a very serious phase,&quot; said Moussa, whose country in 1979 became the first Arab state to make peace with Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a serious responsibility. We are not playing games with peace and the world will not permit that. We shall definitely not permit that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>PLO negotiators stormed out of talks with Israel on Monday night in protest at the attitude of Israeli delegates, which they described as that of &quot;occupiers toward the occupied.&quot;</p>
<p>Moussa said Egypt had since been in contact with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat. &quot;There will of course be action,&quot; he added but did not elaborate.</p>
<p>De Charette said he discussed with Mubarak suggestions that France co-sponsor the peace process along with the United States, which Arabs believe favours Israel.</p>
<p>Chirac, on a Middle East tour aimed at promoting his country's vision of peace, suggested in Syria on Saturday that the European Union should co-sponsor the peace process.</p>
<p>He ruffled the Jewish state further on Monday by telling Israeli students in the northern city of Haifa that only a Palestinian state could guarantee them real security.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone must work in the direction of peace. It is legitimate to couple the efforts of all the countries that have responsibilities in the world. Europe, and at its heart France, has particular responsibilities,&quot; de Charette said.</p>
<p>&quot;Peace in the Middle East is for us something essential. It meets a vital objective. There are essential interests for France,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Moussa said the policies of rightwing Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu had encouraged the European Union to throw its weight behind the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;It is up to the European Union to decide for itself and to understand the situation and understand where the obstinancy is coming from but the situation is not just dependent on what Israel says,&quot; said Moussa when asked about Israel's objection to an increased European role.</p>
<p>&quot;Peace has many parties and the different parties welcome the European role. What has Israel along with the American role done? Nothing. Therefore it must bear the responsibility. The European role is important and desirable in addition to the American role and the world role,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
