<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134897" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UNHCR warns of humanitarian disaster in E. Zaire.</title>
<headline>UNHCR warns of humanitarian disaster in E. Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations refugee agency UNHCR sounded a warning on Tuesday that the worsening situation in eastern Zaire could degenerate into a humanitarian disaster.</p>
<p>Spokesman Ron Redmond expressed concern for the safety of 220,000 Burundi and Rwandan refugees seeking safe haven after fleeing camps near Uvira at the weekend due to heavy fighting between the Zairean army and ethnic Tutsi rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to all sides to step back from the brink of what now threatens to become a very real humanitarian disaster in a region that has already suffered enough,&quot; Redmond told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation has now deteriorated to such an extent that we are almost back to an emergency phase like we were facing in 1994,&quot; he added, referring to the massive exodus in Africa's Great Lakes region following massacres and civil war in Rwanda.</p>
<p>Most of the 222,000 Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi have fled to the surrounding hills and banana plantations near Uvira and are awaiting the outcome of the fighting, according to the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR).</p>
<p>But the spokesman said the agency was making contingency plans to receive 75,000 of the refugees in existing camps in the Bukavu area, north of Uvira. About 3,000 Rwandans have already shown up at Nyangezi-Mulwa camp there.</p>
<p>UNHCR had unconfirmed reports of columns of several thousand more refugees on the road in several places heading for Bukavu.</p>
<p>The agency expected that the 143,000 Burundi refugees would stay in the Uvira region, according to Redmond. It was looking into the possibility that some Rwandan refugees may wish to go home, but no spontaneous arrivals have been reported there.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, all supply lines for bringing in water and food by truck to the refugees in Uvira have been cut due to the fighting, according to Redmond.</p>
<p>&quot;We set up supply lines and aid networks over period of years. That is now jeopardised. We are back to almost an emergency operation, at least in Uvira region,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a huge population in inhospitable territory. It has taken us years to try to get some sense of stability and get enough assistance to provide minimum aid,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the Geneva-based agency was hoping that 54 stranded foreign aid workers, including eight UNHCR expatriate staff, could be evacuated from Uvira.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now they are in harm's way,&quot; Redmond said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely concerned about not only their safety but the fate of tens of thousands of innocent refugees,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing our best to try to get them out. The situation is so dangerous that it is difficult to do.&quot;</p>
<p>UNHCR staff in Uvira reported on Tuesday morning that fighting was continuing in the region and the sound of gunfire could be heard in Uvira town itself.</p>
<p>The Zaire army has been battling the Banyamulenge Tutsis for more than six months but fighting has so far been largely on the high plateau above Uvira. Clashes have now spread to the plains, threatening settlements and closing most of the 100 km (60-mile) road between Uvira and Bukavu.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
