<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134815" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: WTO sees New Zealand as model reform economy.</title>
<headline>WTO sees New Zealand as model reform economy.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Trade Organisation on Tuesday hailed New Zealand, a decade ago among the world's most protected economies, as a model of reform and saluted its commitment to work for global free trade.</p>
<p>In a report on the trade policies of the country, ranked global number three for competitiveness by an authoritative Swiss study earlier this year, WTO analysts said the switch had brought it sustainable economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;In an effort to break from a history of poor economic performance, New Zealand has transformed its economy from among the most heavily protected and regulated to one of the most market-oriented and open in the world,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;New Zealand now provides a clear, positive example of liberalisation,&quot; the WTO analysts declared.</p>
<p>&quot;Its persistence in carrying through bold reforms in virtually every aspect of its economy has begun to pay substantial dividends, with an increase in the economy's sustainable growth potential.</p>
<p>Trade liberalisation, which New Zealand launched together with its other reforms in the mid-1980s as a unilateral initiative, &quot;has been vital to this achievement,&quot; said the analysts, economists in the WTO Secretariat.</p>
<p>The report is part of a series started during the late 1980s under the WTO's predecessor, the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, subjecting the trade policies of all member countries to regular review by the Secretariat and other trading states.</p>
<p>As well as opening up on the trade and investment fronts, it said, successive New Zealand governments had reformed virtually every part of the economy through privatisation and deregulation in the labour market and other domestic areas.</p>
<p>&quot;New Zealand has taken the view that lowering barriers is primarily for its own benefit. Reform has aimed at improving competition and thus moving resources towards their most efficient uses....</p>
<p>&quot;Trade liberalisation has been undertaken primarily on the unilateral track, in the recognition that liberal trade policies are in New Zealand's best interest, whatever the policies of other countries,&quot; the WTO analysts said.</p>
<p>In a report of its own for the review, New Zealand said that as a country with a population of little more than 3,5 million international trade was vital to its prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall goal of New Zealand's trade policy is strightforward: to achieve sustainable economic growth through trade.&quot;  This objective was directed at complete multilateral free trade, the government report said.</p>
<p>In two low-key notes of criticism, the WTO analysts said tariffs for textiles, clothing and footwear -- areas of interest to developing countries -- and motor vehicles remained relatively high, lagging behind radical cuts on other products.</p>
<p>They also implicitly urged New Zealand, where negotiations on a new government are under way after recent inconclusive elections, to lower the level of its tariff bindings -- or the upper limit beyond which it pledges they will not rise.</p>
<p>This, they said, would provide exporters in other countries with greater assurance about future applied tariffs.</p>
<p>The report also suggested the country should move to abolish its system of agricultural export licensing controls -- which the analysts said amounted in some cases to export monopolies -- operated through marketing boards.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
