<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134841" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Ciba, Sandoz Jan-Sept sales up, but Ciba growth disappoints.</title>
<headline>Ciba, Sandoz Jan-Sept sales up, but Ciba growth disappoints.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH, Switzerland</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ciba-Geigy AG and Sandoz AG posted higher nine-month sales and predicted good full-year earnings Tuesday, but Ciba's growth fell below expectations as sales lagged for its flagship drug Voltaren.</p>
<p>The two Swiss pharmaceuticals giants are planning to merge, forming a new company called Novartis.</p>
<p>Both companies also said in separate statements that, excluding merger-related special factors and barring any unforeseen developments, they should report higher net income for the full year.</p>
<p>Sandoz reported an 8 percent rise in sales to 11.3 billion Swiss francs ($9 billion) for the first three quarters of 1996.</p>
<p>Sandoz Chief Financial Officer Raymund Breu said he expected the growth trend in pharmaceuticals and agri-business to continue into the fourth quarter. &quot;We have no reason to think that the strong growth trend of the first three quarters should not continue into the fourth quarter,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Ciba said its sales rose 2 percent to 16.26 billion ($12.9 billion), below market expectations of an increase of between about 5 and 7 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sandoz was in line with out expectations. Ciba on the other hand has figures which are slightly disappointing, but were due to special factors in the pharma area,&quot; Union Bank of Switzerland pharmaceuticals analyst Birgit Kulhoff said.</p>
<p>Total sales growth was limited by the impact of generic competition in the U.S. market for the anti-rheumatic drug Voltaren and the anti-hypertension medication Lopresor, Ciba said.</p>
<p>&quot;This means that generic competition is rising ... it had been a positive surprise that they could hold sales volume at high levels, but the momentum is falling,&quot; said Gerd Ramsperger, head of Brokerage Research at Zurich Kantonalbank.</p>
<p>Voltaren is Ciba's most successful drug. But it began facing generic competition when exclusive rights in the United States expired in September 1995. Since then, market share erosion accelerated during in the third quarter this year, a Ciba spokeswoman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
