<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134834" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Doubts said to delay Aerospatiale missiles merger.</title>
<headline>Doubts said to delay Aerospatiale missiles merger.</headline>
<dateline>LE BOURGET, France 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A merger of the missiles businesses of Aerospatiale and Daimler-Benz Aerospace (DASA) needs more clarity over political priorities and the course of French defence restructuring for it to move forward, a European defence executive said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We want clear decisions on (missile) programmes so we can plan for the next two to three years. We need to know the government's priorities,&quot; the executive, speaking on grounds on anonymity, said at the Euronaval warship trade exhibition.</p>
<p>SNI Aerospatiale and DASA have been negotiating for at least two years to complete parallel mergers of their missiles and satellite businesses, but have so far not closed the deals.</p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal said on Tuesday that DASA was re-evaluating the planned Franco-German missiles merger following Paris's stated preference to sell Thomson SA to Lagardere, which would create a new force in the French missiles industry by combining Matra with Thomson-CSF.</p>
<p>&quot;We need more information on the French defence industry restructuring,&quot; the executive said.</p>
<p>For example, one of the uncertainties is what will happen to Aerospatiale's missiles division when the group is privatised, he said.</p>
<p>Lagardere wants to be the natural centre for a European missiles and satellites business and has joint ventures with British Aerospace in missiles and GEC Plc in satellites.</p>
<p>It sees itself as the better partner for Germany, rather than Aerospatiale.</p>
<p>The next Franco-German summit due in early December is expected to give some political direction on a number of co-operation programmes, including the Tiger and NH90 helicopters, the Trigat and Polyphem missiles and the Helios II spy satellite.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a political framework,&quot; the executive said.</p>
<p>At the programme level, meanwhile, Aerospatiale and DASA are continuing to develop new products.</p>
<p>The two companies announced on Tuesday their Vesta project, a technology demonstrator for the next generation of supersonic anti-ship missiles, which is due to enter full-scale development in 1998 and will go into service in 2005.</p>
<p>-- Pierre Tran  Paris Newsroom (33 1) 42 21 53 43</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LE BOURGET, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
