<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134817" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for October 21, 1996</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London fluctuated within a narrow range without any clear direction. December lost $1.30 to close at $317.40. In New York raw sugar futures closed easier across the board in a thinly traded session. March lost seven points to close at 10.57 cents/lb while May lost 4 points to close at 10.61 cents/lb. The deferreds lost between one and four points. The easier tone can be ascribed to sluggish end- user demand and predictions of another surplus in 1996/97.Z</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>THAILAND - Thai raw sugar premiums eased recently as physical demand waned and the market was rife with bearish news. Even the lower than expected cane crop is not likely to support the premium. The Ministry of Agriculture recently cut its cane output projection for 1996/97 to 61.53 million tonnes down from the previous estimate of 62.42 million tonnes but still up on last year's figure of 57.7 million tonnes. The projection for 1996/97 sugar cane planting area was also lowered to 1.058 million ha from the previous forecast of 1.073 million ha. The reduction in the cane estimate is not pronounced enough to have any positive impact on the Thai premium given current sluggish demand. China is pursuing a restrictive import policy while the Philippines is unlikely to import sugar in the next six months because it has overbought in 1995/96. This should prevent any significant rise in the premium for Thai sugar unless the 1996/97 Cuban crop proves to be a real disaster. However, it is too early to give a precise estimate of the damage caused by hurricane Lili. Official Cuban sources recently said 1.4 million acres of cane were affected in the provinces of Havana, Matanzas, Cienfuegos, Villa Clara, Sancti Spiritus and Ciego de Avila.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Sugar exports in June 1996 amounted to 70,469 tonnes, raw value, sharply down from last year's 143,539 tonnes. This brought cumulative exports in the first three quarters of 1995/96 (October/June) up to 1.11 million tonnes, unchanged from the level of exports in the corresponding period the previous year. Total exports in 1994/95 amounted to 1.45 million tonnes, down from 1.92 million tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of destination in October/June 1995/96 were the United Arab Emirates with 116,076 tonnes whites against 129,412 tonnes, Belgium-Luxembourg with 125,289 tonnes against 743,964 tonnes, Switzerland with 74,853 tonnes compared to 73,426 tonnes and Italy with 62,421 tonnes up from 43,451 tonnes. Sugar imports in June 1996 amounted to 25,475 tonnes, hardly changed from last year's 25,726 tonnes. This brought cumulative imports in October/June 1995/96 up to 164,515 tonnes against 160,419 tonnes in the like period the previous year. Total imports in 1994/95 amounted to 225,848 tonnes against 213,664 tonnes in 1993/94. Major countries of origin in October/June 1995/96 were France with 122,129 tonnes whites against 116,738 tonnes and the Netherlands with 11,387 tonnes against 9,627 tonnes.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Sugar imports in August 1996 reached 19,839 tonnes, raw value, down from last year's 22,209 tonnes. This brought cumulative imports in the first eight months of 1996 (January/August) up to 161,507 tonnes, hardly changed from last year's 161,957 tonnes. Total imports in 1995 amounted to 237,332 tonnes, up from 208,640 tonnes imported in 1994. Major countries of origin in January/August 1996 were South Korea with 76,152 tonnes whites against 78,835 tonnes and Australia with 19,864 tonnes, up from 16,012 tonnes. Sugar exports in August 1996 amounted to 4,151 tonnes, up from last year's 3,969 tonnes. This brought cumulative exports in January/August 1996 up to 46,727 tonnes, slightly up on last year's 42,992 tonnes. Total exports in 1995 reached 67,970 tonnes compared to 42,696 tonnes in 1994. The major country of destination in January/August 1996 continued to be China with 30,998 tonnes whites against 20,603 tonnes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
