<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134859" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: NATO enlargement debate focuses on outsiders.</title>
<headline>NATO enlargement debate focuses on outsiders.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Clayton</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton's strong endorsement of NATO's plans for eastwards expansion on Tuesday will focus attention on what to do about those countries which do not gain membership, particularly the jittery Baltic states.</p>
<p>Clinton is set in a key-note foreign policy speech in Detroit to throw the prestige of the White House behind enlargement, formally presenting a concrete timetable for the completion of negotiations by 1999.</p>
<p>Alliance diplomats and analysts say Clinton will not name the most likely new members nor set a date for a much-awaited heads of government summit next year at which certain countries will be invited to open negotiations.</p>
<p>But they describe the speech -- in an area full of voters of east European stock -- as highly significant, confirming the issue as one of the key foreign policy goals of a Clinton second term whatever noises come out of Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;It (enlargement) was pretty much a done deal, but there can be no question of back-sliding now,&quot; said Philip Gordon, an expert on enlargement at London's International Institute for Strategic Studies (IISS).</p>
<p>On Monday, NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana repeated the alliance's official line that no decision on who to admit had yet been taken, stressing again no country was &quot;in&quot; and no country was &quot;out&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are moving to the point of taking a decision, probably at a summit next year, on whom to invite,&quot; he said, adding NATO had a &quot;moral obligation&quot; to admit countries that had sought membership after the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>But it is an open secret in military circles that Hungary, Poland and the Czech Republic are the leading candidates with Slovenia from former Yugoslavia a late arrival, attracting several votes as a stable state in the turbulent Balkans.</p>
<p>Clinton plans to visit those countries after the November 5 U.S. presidential election he appears set to win. He is then expected to fly to Scandinavia for a meeting with the leaders of the Baltic states, Lithuania, Estonia and Latvia.</p>
<p>In recent months, Russia has accepted it cannot block at least three or four of its former allies from the now-defunct Warsaw Pact joining the alliance, but Moscow would baulk at the former Soviet republics joining its old enemy.</p>
<p>The West, keen to negotiate a new NATO-Russia treaty or charter, sympathises with Moscow's fears, but at the same time feels it owes a historic debt to countries forcibly annexed to the Soviet Union under the notorious 1940 Moscow-Nazi pact.</p>
<p>Last week, Lithuanian President Algirdas Brazauskas came to Brussels to push his country's case for swift European Union and NATO membership. He urged the West to consider the price of not granting them membership rather than the cost of doing so.</p>
<p>&quot;The Baltic states must not be left out again,&quot; he told reporters, adding that even partial exclusion played into the hands of those &quot;who advocate a zones of influence&quot; policy in Europe.</p>
<p>Diplomats say the problem for the alliance is that those countries also meet several of the conditions for membership.</p>
<p>&quot;Moscow is now trying to limit expansion to three or four countries and influence the terms those countries get,&quot; said Gordon.</p>
<p>Analysts say Clinton's public endorsement of expansion also throws the gauntlet down to the European allies, some of whom have recently indicated less enthusiasm for expansion as related problems become clearer.</p>
<p>&quot;It increases the pressure on the European allies to make progress both on European Union enlargement and on the internal reforms of the alliance,&quot; said a senior European diplomat.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO), the Atlantic Alliance created to defeat the Soviet Union in a war that never took place, has started a reform process designed to allow it to take on a new post-Cold War role.</p>
<p>Crucially, that involves the creation of a distinct European security identity within the alliance -- a key demand of France which has said it will then be ready to rejoin the military wing it left in 1966.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
