<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134854" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian Jewish art looted by Nazis goes on show.</title>
<headline>Austrian Jewish art looted by Nazis goes on show.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An exhibition of Jewish artworks pillaged by Adolf Hitler's Nazis in World War Two opened on Tuesday in Vienna ahead of a landmark auction of over 8,000 items next week.</p>
<p>The auction, organised by British auctioneers Christies, marks the last chapter in a controversy over Austria's delay in returning the artefacts to their owners after the Allies handed them over to their countries of origin at the end of the war.</p>
<p>&quot;Today is no cause for celebration,&quot; said Peter Noever, director of the Vienna Museum for Applied Arts where the auction will take place. &quot;Here is displayed the legacy of those who were murdered, exiled and forgotten.&quot;</p>
<p>The proceeds of the sale, estimated to reach around $3.5 million, will go to Austrian victims of the Holocaust, including non-Jews.</p>
<p>&quot;The auction...is an important milestone in the countless years of attempted restitution that has not only occupied us for over five decades but often cast a great shadow on our relations with the Austrian government,&quot; Paul Grosz, president of Vienna's Jewish community, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Among the collection are a rediscovered bust of Alexander the Great from 3 B.C., paintings including one by Flemish master Pieter Brueghel, Flemish tapestries, Persian carpets, coins and a range of 19th century landscapes and society portraits.</p>
<p>A 15th century painting by Sienese artist Pietro di Francesco degli Orioli, depicting the Madonna and child and valued up to $110,000, is expected to fetch the highest price.</p>
<p>Austrian-born Hitler had planned to erect a museum in the city of Linz to house the works.</p>
<p>Grosz said that three items of seven claimed had been returned to their original owners ahead of the auction on October 29 and 30.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision to withdraw items from the sale and return them to their actual owner or to their heirs has proven the most important and rewarding aspect of our work,&quot; he said. The low number of claimants showed that whole families had been wiped out in the Holocaust, he added.</p>
<p>Much of the material was stored for the past 40 years in a monastery in Mauerbach, Austria. It was only last year that Austria finally handed over the works to the Federation of Austrian Jewish Communities after a vote in parliament.</p>
<p>Asked why it took until 1994 for the Austrian government to restore the artworks to the Jewish community, Grosz answered: &quot;Obviously there was negligence in this matter.&quot;</p>
<p>For most of the post-war era Austria sought to distance itself from the wartime Nazi regime, presenting itself as the first victim of Hitler's aggression.</p>
<p>The position only changed in 1993 when Chancellor Franz Vranitzky acknowledged during a visit to Israel that Austrians were not only victims but also &quot;willing servants of Nazism&quot;.</p>
<p>Last year the Austrian parliament, in a ground-breaking move, voted to pay compensation to an estimated 30,000 Austrian victims persecuted during Hitler's Nazi rule.</p>
<p>&quot;If this benefit auction helps to make people aware of this injustice so they understand it and can be cathartically relieved of the burden of their past, then this auction will already have been a success,&quot; Grosz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
