<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134894" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss admit Polish Jews' funds compensated Swiss.</title>
<headline>Swiss admit Polish Jews' funds compensated Swiss.</headline>
<byline>Felix Bauer</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Switzerland acknowledged for the first time on Tuesday that unclaimed assets of Polish Holocaust victims were used to compensate Swiss citizens whose property was nationalised by Poland after World War Two.</p>
<p>Researchers have found a previously undisclosed protocol attached to a bilateral compensation treaty that shows &quot;Jewish money was used to compensate Swiss citizens,&quot; a foreign ministry spokesman, Hans-Ruedi Bortis, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There are protocols that show who had how many assets and so on,&quot; he added. &quot;We hope to have this in its complete form and then we will release it,&quot; he said, adding this was planned for later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Under pressure from Jewish groups, Switzerland acknowledged on Friday that a secret exchange of letters accompanying the 1949 compensation treaty ceded Poles' bank accounts and life insurance policies to Warsaw if unclaimed by 1954.</p>
<p>It had denied that the assets, which Jewish groups said included the wealth of Holocaust victims, had benefited Swiss citizens whose property was taken by Poland's then-communist government.</p>
<p>A World Jewish Congress official said last week the admission proved that the Swiss &quot;immorally transferred Jewish assets to Poland&quot; and he demanded the Swiss pay millions of dollars in compensation to a Jewish restitutions group.</p>
<p>The Swiss foreign ministry had said it would study the case more closely and find more details about what payments had been made before responding to allegations that Switzerland improperly stripped Holocaust victims of their wealth.</p>
<p>The 1949 bilateral treaty publicly called for Poland to pay Switzerland 52.5 million Swiss francs ($41.5 million at 1996 rates) for property which the then-communist regime had seized.</p>
<p>Switzerland also struck post-war compensation accords with Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Yugoslavia, Romania and Hungary, it said. It was still checking whether they contained similar provisions on assets seizures and whether they were enacted.</p>
<p>The Swiss Bankers Association also said on Friday it had discovered a 1950 memo which it circulated drawing banks' attention to the 1949 exchange of letters and asking how much money was at stake. It did not give a figure.</p>
<p>Swiss banks have never disputed they were a popular refuge for the wealth of European Jews fearing Nazi persecution after Hitler came to power in Germany in 1933. Many were drawn by Switzerland's strict bank secrecy and neutral status.</p>
<p>But the banks reject WJC claims that they may be sitting on billions of dollars in assets left behind by Jewish account holders murdered in the Holocaust without having passed along their secret bank details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
