<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134861" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Euro-MPs endorse Ariane programme.</title>
<headline>Euro-MPs endorse Ariane programme.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A programme which will provide European Union money to help translate and distribute books written in lesser-known EU languages like Welsh, Basque or Gaelic was approved by the European Parliament on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The idea of a 34-million-Ecu programme, championed by Greek singer and Euro-MP Nana Mouskouri, was first mooted by the European Commission in 1994 -- COM(94)356.</p>
<p>MEPs finally agreed to a much reduced version of the original five-year Ariane programme in the hope of persuading all 15 EU culture ministers to support it.</p>
<p>Last year Britain single-handedly blocked the scheme, on the grounds that it concentrated too much on translating and would be a waste of money.</p>
<p>The programme needs the unanimous support of ministers and the endorsement of the parliament before it can be set up.</p>
<p>On the advice of Mouskouri, who sits on the parliament's culture committee, Euro-MPs accepted parts of a provisional compromise hammered out by the Culture Council on July 15.</p>
<p>They agreed to cut the programme from five to two years and widen its scope to fund other activities, such as joint projects by publishers from different countries to promote little-known but promising works of litterature.</p>
<p>But there may still be problems in breaking the deadlock since parliament refused to accept the ministers' proposal to axe the Ariane budget to seven million Ecus, a fivefold drop.</p>
<p>Euro-MPs said 10.5 million Ecus was the minimum acceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;Ariane is not so expensive but it is very important. It is about communicating knowledge,&quot; Mouskouri told Reuters earlier this month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G159">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
