<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134838" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: U.S.-focused Danish shares fall on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>U.S.-focused Danish shares fall on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed lower on Tuesday hit by profit-taking with buyer interest in Tele Danmark unable to prevent the market from falling and dealers fearing more declines if Wall Street ends down again.</p>
<p>&quot;The huge focus by domestic investors on Tele Danmark in the wake of the Deutsche Telekom share issue was not sufficient to scotch the general downward trend. The dollar and the U.S.A. will determine the course of events tomorrow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 0.38 point down at 128.88, while the KFX December future fell 0.05 point to 129.30 with 255 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 1.060 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Tele Danmark was the day's most traded paper with almost 500,000 shares changing hands to end four crowns higher at 305.</p>
<p>FLS Industries rose 15 crowns to finish at 785 on a major new order in Indonesia, while Danisco and Carlsberg both fell, the former ending the day one crown down at 342, the latter shedding four crowns to 376.</p>
<p>Leading banks Den Danske and rival Unibank also closed lower, both dropping three crowns to finish at 432 and 280 respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
