<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134847" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Mayr-Melnhof 9-mth net profit up 60 pct.</title>
<headline>Mayr-Melnhof 9-mth net profit up 60 pct.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian carton board maker Mayr-Melnhof Karton AG said on Tuesday net profit in the first nine months of the year jumped to 342 million schillings from 214 million a year ago.</p>
<p>The group said in a statement it expected a &quot;significantly higher net profit&quot; for the full year.  </p>
<p>Mayr-Melnhof added it would certainly pay a dividend for the current year. &quot;The dividend is secure,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company scrapped its dividend last year despite a 75 percent jump in net profit after a large write-down on its German operations.  </p>
<p>Nine month group sales fell to 7.9 billion schillings, from 9.55 billion in the same period last year, partly because of depressed prices in the carton, packaging and waste paper markets, it said.</p>
<p>Despite a decline in prices, which the company said was halted in the third quarter of the year, its carton division reported operating earnings of 470 million schillings, up from 187 million. The division accounts for 58 percent of turnover.</p>
<p>Operating earnings in the packaging division were up at 99 million schillings from 56 million last year, while waste paper earnings fell to 50 million from 237 million last year.</p>
<p>Mayr-Melnhof added its expansion in Asia and eastern Europe was proceeding on schedule.</p>
<p>Looking ahead to the fourth quarter, the company said it expected prices to remain stable while capacity utilisation should continue to run at high levels for most of the period. &quot;December traditionally is marked by weaker utilisation,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Before the release of the figures, Mayr-Melnhof's shares closed unchanged at 520 schillings in an otherwise limp Vienna market on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Knut Engelmann, Vienna newsroom +431 53112 274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
