<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134846" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: No German rate cut seen this week - analysts.</title>
<headline>No German rate cut seen this week - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's central bank, presiding over a moderate economic recovery and facing a slightly weaker mark, has no reason to lower interest rates this week, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the economy continues to develop as it has been doing, there is no need to change interest rates,&quot; said Stephan Schneider, economist at Banque Paribas in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Ten economists polled by Reuters unanimously agreed the Bundesbank would leave its discount rate at 2.5 percent, the Lombard rate at 4.5 and its main money market rate, the repo, fixed at three percent at Thursday's regular council meeting.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank faces no pressure to adjust interest rates and can afford to stick to its steady-hand policy, they said.</p>
<p>Most importantly, economists said, currency market conditions had changed markedly since the Bundesbank surprised markets with a 30 basis point repo cut in late August.</p>
<p>As the mark has depreciated against several currencies, including the dollar, the central bank no longer needs to act so aggressively to support Germany's economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency is doing it for them,&quot; said Alison Cottrell, senior international economist at PaineWebber in London, adding changed currency conditions also offered other nations room to adjust policy.</p>
<p>&quot;It helps, allowing France to do what it did,&quot; when it lowered call money by 1/16 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Ulrich Hombrecher, senior economist at WestLB in Duesseldorf, forecast another interest rate easing &quot;would occur only if everything went wrong on the currency side.&quot;</p>
<p>Another factor seen to be dissuading the Bundesbank from taking any policy steps in the near term is the uncertainty hanging over the German tax situation as well as contentious metal industry wage talks.</p>
<p>The ruling coalition briefly flirted with collapse last week when member parties fell out over how to raise extra funds for the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>&quot;In light of the government's fiscal situation, the Bundesbank will certainly not take any interest rate steps now,&quot; Paribas' Schneider said.</p>
<p>As German monetary policy is already considered expansive, economists said the Bundesbank would stop short of further loosening, if only to avoid having to quickly hike rates later if inflationary pressures build up.</p>
<p>Even slowing M3 money supply growth -- seen as signalling future inflation -- will not be enough to tempt policy makers to shift course now, economists agreed.</p>
<p>While September M3 grew at a slightly slower 8.4 percent rate than August's uptick to 8.7 percent, M3 is still not within striking distance of the four to seven percent target growth corridor, making any easing now highly unlikely.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Franz-Christoph Zeitler, commenting on the figures on Monday, said the data underscored the bank's &quot;steady-hand policy&quot; on interest rates.</p>
<p>Council members have all stressed recently the bank was happy with current interest rate levels, helping to convince the market there will be no change on Thursday. --Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
