<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134898" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Clock ticking for German engineering wage talks.</title>
<headline>Clock ticking for German engineering wage talks.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The spectre of mass worker protests hung over German engineering employers on Tuesday as they resumed talks with trade union IG Metall on the 1997 wage claim and controversial planned cuts in labour costs.</p>
<p>The Gesamtmetall employers federation is seeking to secure agreements that would substantially reduce the non-wage labour costs which it says have made Germany's metal and engineering sector internationally uncompetitive.</p>
<p>But IG Metall reaffirmed before talks, which broke off on Monday evening, restarted that it would not accept any reductions in sick pay allowances, one of the main areas that employers are banking on to secure cost savings.</p>
<p>&quot;Full sick payments must be maintained,&quot; IG Metall chairman Klaus Zwickel said before the negotiations with the employers in a hotel on the outskirts of Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Zwickel said preparations were going ahead for a second day of nationwide protests by workers on Thursday if no progress towards an agreement on labour costs and 1997 wages had been made by then.</p>
<p>A 20 percent cut in sick pay allowances, currently made at full salary, was in principle made possible by a new federal law which came into effect earlier this month. Such a cut would shave 12 billion marks ($7.8 billion) off German labour costs.</p>
<p>But employers such as leading industrial group Daimler-Benz AG, which had sought to implement the law immediately, were forced to postpone the cuts after demonstrations across the engineering sector involving more than 100,000 workers.</p>
<p>IG Metall, which represents around 3.5 million workers, is now seeking to link an inflation-based 1997 wage rise with concrete pledges from employers on job protection measures.</p>
<p>Zwickel said the negotiating room left between the positions of the two sides was very narrow.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall still insists that a cut in labour costs is now critical for the engineering sector, which has lost around one million jobs in the last five years.</p>
<p>But Werner Stumpfe, head of the employers federation, has in recent days displayed a noticeably less hardline approach to implementation of the new law on sick pay.</p>
<p>Earlier this week he said the law should be reflected in the wage deal about to be negotiated, in contrast to his initial recommendation -- unsuccessfully adopted by Daimler and others -- that they put the cuts into effect immediately.</p>
<p>IG Metall's proposal that more than half its 1997 wage demand be set aside for measures related to securing employment levels effectively means it could settle for headline increase in wages of barely higher than inflation.</p>
<p>Such a rise is something Gesamtmetall has said it could discuss if accompanied by measures that would significantly cut non-wage costs.</p>
<p>IG Metall's Zwickel said on Tuesday that a solution was still possible &quot;when both sides want one&quot;.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($1=1.5386 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
