<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134850" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spanish bonds shrug off realism, bet on EMU.</title>
<headline>Spanish bonds shrug off realism, bet on EMU.</headline>
<byline>Manuel Maria Ruiz</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Though central banks have begun to dampen the Spanish market's euphoria over European Monetary Union (EMU), experts still see convergence going forward due mainly to political considerations.</p>
<p>Only on Monday, Bank of Spain Governor Luis Angel Rojo, cautioned the country must persist in fiscal restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still not inside (EMU) yet and a long way remains,&quot; said Rojo. &quot;It is not clear that the whole world can get in. The country has to make bigger efforts to stabilize.&quot;</p>
<p>The Spanish bond market has enjoyed an impressive rally in recent months, buoyed by optimism over a restrictive 1997 budget that would put the country on course for joining the founders of monetary union in 1999.</p>
<p>But the market turned cautious last week amid strong signals from the Bundesbank that peripheral European countries like Spain and Italy have not yet fulfilled the Maastricht criteria for convergence.</p>
<p>Still many dealers are betting political considerations will lead the founders of EMU to opt for a wider group from the start rather than a strict interpretation of Maastricht.</p>
<p>&quot;I think every day the two positions become clearer. On one side, the political one and on the other, the economic,&quot; said Juan Antonio Mielgo, economist at Bank of America in Madrid.</p>
<p>Despite improving Spanish economic data, such as a slimming CPI and a strict 1997 budget, official statements seems aimed at restoring doubts about a wide EMU from the start.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes sense to me that Bundesbank and Bank of Spain advise some caution, something which could counterbalance dealers' optimism,&quot; said Xavier Segura, chief economist at Caja de Cataluna.</p>
<p>Analysts explained central banks are suggesting a certain degree of realism. Up to now, only Luxembourg could really pass the exam and enter EMU, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Spain, is not yet meeting virtually any of the Maastricht criteria,&quot; said Segura.</p>
<p>German investors fear EMU could be weakened by allowing in too many countries with volatile economies, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany seems really interested in a stability pact to keep all the economic variables under surveillance,&quot; said Segura.</p>
<p>But from a political point of view, very rigid economic criteria are less important. Politically, Europe should be able to present itself as a whole and unique country.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe has a very big strength from a commercial point of view. Outside it should present itself in a homogeneous form,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>For this reason, the market remains optimistic a political will toward a wider union will assert itself.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank is recommending a more cautious approach, but people know this is its duty,&quot; said Mielgo. &quot;It would have been much worse if any member of the (German) government would have said the same words.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom, + 34 1 585-2154</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
