<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134889" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Kohl wants Italy in EMU first wave - Prodi.</title>
<headline>Kohl wants Italy in EMU first wave - Prodi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl wants Italy in the first wave of countries joining Europe's planned single currency, Italian Prime Minister Romano Prodi was quoted on Tuesday as saying.</p>
<p>Prodi, who met Kohl in Bonn last week, told Il Sole 24 Ore newspaper that even if some sectors of German public opinion wanted to keep Italy out the German leader did not support them.</p>
<p>&quot;I received confirmation that the Chancellor has no intention of seconding any sector of German public opinion that might want to keep Italy out of Europe,&quot; Prodi said in the interview.</p>
<p>&quot;He understands that the problem of Europe's southern flank is very important and he takes account of the enormous purchasing potential for German goods in our country.&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prodi has presented a stringent 1997 budget to parliament to try to meet the criteria for membership of Europe's planned monetary and economic union (EMU) from its start in 1999.</p>
<p>Several senior Bundesbank officials, however, have recently cast doubt on whether Italy will make the grade.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl is convinced that an Italy inside Europe creates far fewer political and economic problems than an Italy kept out,&quot; Prodi said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is his political intuition. On that basis the economic aspects, even though they are important, always remain secondary compared with the great European scheme.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
