<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134879" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Russian Economy minister confident on IMF loan.</title>
<headline>Russian Economy minister confident on IMF loan.</headline>
<byline>Jude Webber</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Economy Minister Yevgeny Yasin said on Tuesday he hoped the International Monetary Fund (IMF) would not delay payment of the next tranche of a $10 billion loan, saying to do so would be &quot;very unjust.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want that to happen. I think that would be unjust. If we take as a base the formal requirements it is clear that this is possible, but in the situation which Russia is in I think it would be a very unjust thing,&quot; Yasin told Reuters during a visit to Milan.</p>
<p>Asked whether he was confident that the IMF would not delay payment, he said, &quot;I am confident.&quot;</p>
<p>Yasin, speaking through an interpreter after inaugurating a Milan centre for the promotion of investment in Russia, said the current IMF talks were very tough.</p>
<p>An IMF mission arrived in Moscow last Wednesday for talks expected to last about a week.</p>
<p>Sources close to the discussions said on Monday that the IMF was worried about low Russian tax collection.</p>
<p>Asked how the talks had kicked off, he said &quot;things are still very difficult. Russia can't collect taxes as it should and if it can't collect enough taxes, there will be problems with the budget...and there are problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Tax revenues totalled a low 2.2 trillion roubles in cash in the first nine days of October. Overall tax receipts are about 40 percent below targeted levels.</p>
<p>The IMF had delayed payment of one of the summer tranches of the loan because of tax shortfall worries but later released that $300 million tranche.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russian government has undertaken a series of extraordinary measures to collect taxes but unfortunately there are no results yet,&quot; Yasin said.</p>
<p>Yasin said it was too early to predict the outcome of the IMF deliberations or to say what measures would be taken to change the 1997 draft budget which has been rejected by the Duma lower house of parliament.</p>
<p>The 1997 draft budget provides for a 3.3 percent deficit of GDP compared with 3.85 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The Russian budget deficit was 9.2 trillion roubles in September, or 3.8 percent of GDP under the methods the IMF uses to calculate the gap, finance ministry data showed.</p>
<p>The September figure compares with a 5.3 percent deficit IMF target for the whole of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;This budget deficit will not grow,&quot; Yasin said.</p>
<p>He said last week that stepping up borrowing would disrupt the entire process of resuming economic growth and restoring Russia's economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
