<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134878" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Focus-Ciba, Sandoz Jan-Sept sales up.</title>
<headline>Focus-Ciba, Sandoz Jan-Sept sales up.</headline>
<byline>Greg Calhoun</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ciba-Geigy AG and Sandoz AG posted higher nine month sales and predicted good full-year earnings, but Ciba's growth fell below expectations as sales lagged for its flagship drug Voltaren.</p>
<p>The two Swiss pharmaceuticals giants are planning to merge, forming a new company called Novartis.</p>
<p>Both companies also said in separate statements that, excluding merger-related special factors and barring any unforeseen developments, they should report higher net income for the full year.</p>
<p>Sandoz today reported an eight percent sales rise to 11.3 billion Swiss francs for the first three quarters of 1996.</p>
<p>Sandoz chief financial officer Raymund Breu said he expected the growth trend seen thus far in pharmaceuticals and agri-business to continue into the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no reason to think that the strong growth trend of the first three quarters should not continue into the fourth quarter,&quot; Breu told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>But Ciba said its sales rose by two percent to 16.26 billion, below market expectations of an increase of between about five and seven percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Sandoz was in line with out expectations. Ciba on the other hand has figures which are slightly disappointing, but were due to special factors in the pharma area,&quot; Union Bank of Switzerland pharmaceuticals analyst Birgit Kulhoff said. Ciba said in its statement that healthcare sector sales rose by three percent in both local currencies and in Swiss francs.</p>
<p>Pharma division sales increased in Europe and Japan with the successful introduction of new products.</p>
<p>Excluding the effects of this sales erosion in the U.S.A. the worldwide pharma business grew approximately in line with the market, Ciba also said.</p>
<p>However, total sales growth was limited by the impact of generic competition in the U.S. for the anti-rheumatic drug Voltaren and the anti-hypertension medication Lopresor, Ciba said.</p>
<p>&quot;This means that generic competition is rising...it had been a positive surprise that they could hold sales volume at high levels, but the momentum is falling,&quot; said Gerd Ramsperger, head of Brokerage Research at Zurich Kantonalbank.</p>
<p>Ramsperger noted that Ciba's pharma sales growth has dropped to the current three percent from the seven percent reported in the first six months of 1996.</p>
<p>Voltaren is Ciba's most successful drug. But it began facing generic competition when exclusive rights in the U.S. expired in September 1995.</p>
<p>Since then, market share erosion accelerated during in the third quarter this year, a Ciba spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>The numbers from the two companies reinforced the opinion held by some analysts that pharma rival Roche Holding AG is the more attractive of the three, at least from a short-term point of view.</p>
<p>Roche last week reported a 10 percent rise in nine month sales to 11.73 billion francs. Sales in the pharmaceuticals sector rose by 12 percent to 7.64 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Longer-term Sandoz has a better pharma pipeline than Roche,&quot; Ramsperger said. But in the short-term he expected the Novartis partners to come under pressure as market favour turned toward Roche.</p>
<p>&quot;The long-term outlook for Novartis continues to be better than for Roche,&quot; Ramsperger said.</p>
<p>Sandoz share price was down 12 francs to 1,480 at midday. Ciba was also off 12 to 1,576 while Roche certificates were up 40 francs to 9,680. -- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
