<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134881" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Steel firms braced for lightweight car challenge.</title>
<headline>Steel firms braced for lightweight car challenge.</headline>
<byline>Christian Gutlederer</byline>
<dateline>LINZ, Austria 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>When the first aluminium car, the Audi A8, rolled off the production line in 1994 it sent shock waves through the steel industry. Now steel firms are fighting back with their own lightweight car.</p>
<p>&quot;We have found an answer to the aluminium car body&quot;, said Horst Haider of Stahl Linz, a unit of Austria's VA Stahl AG.</p>
<p>He said plans for the new ultralight steel auto body (ULSAB) began to take shape in 1994 when 32 steel firms, including Stahl Linz, contracted Porsche Engineering Services of Germany to design a lightweight steel car.</p>
<p>Porsche came up with a car body that is lighter, more rigid and cheaper than today's typical five passenger car by using high strength steel and laser-welded sheets.</p>
<p>&quot;We were well under the target of 250 kilogramm&quot;, Haider said, adding that that the new ULSAB car body weighs just 205 kilogrammes, compared with 273 kilogrammes for an average car.</p>
<p>Within the next few months Porsche plans to build prototypes and check performance in a series of crash tests.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had excellent feedback from the motor industry&quot;, said Haider, adding that the new car body would be $150 cheaper than a typical five passenger car today.</p>
<p>&quot;The aluminium car body will not prevail&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>The European car industry uses six millon tonnes of steel a year, making it a major customer for a steel industry wary of competition from aluminium and plastics.</p>
<p>Haider says Stahl Linz, which has a European market share of ten percent, is well prepared for changes in the automobile industry.</p>
<p>In 1997 a new sheet plant is scheduled to start operations. Steel of different thickness and quality will be welded by laser and pressed into sheets then transformed by Germany's BMW AG into car doors.</p>
<p>Stahl Linz said the planned concentration of its cold rolling mill activities will represent another big step forward. &quot;This sector is the key for producing high strength steel of the best achievable quality&quot;, Haider said.</p>
<p>The company is confident that ultralight steel auto bodies have a bright future.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend is positive and by the year 2000 we should be using our full capacity&quot;, Haider said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LINZ, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
