<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134851" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Dini urges Israel to make peace gesture.</title>
<headline>Italy's Dini urges Israel to make peace gesture.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini made a fresh call on Tuesday for a unilateral gesture from Israel to help push forward the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>Dini, who will visit Israel on Sunday for talks with Foreign Minister David Levy, said Italy had no doubt about the right-wing government's desire for peace though Arab countries were starting to question Israel's commitment.</p>
<p>He told a joint sesson of the foreign affairs commissions of Italy's two houses of parliament that a &quot;precise signal&quot; was needed from Israel &quot;about one of the issues on the table&quot;.</p>
<p>Though Dini said it was not up to Italy to identify the issue on which Israel should act, he referred to the delay in an Israeli troop pullback from the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>&quot;The precise, firm declarations by the Israeli government that it wants peace have not been matched so far by corresponding initiatives that could secure progress. Those are facts, not criticisms,&quot; Dini said.</p>
<p>Israel and the PLO have been trying to hammer out a deal on a long-promised troop pullback from Hebron, the last and most sensitive of seven West Bank cities due to be handed over to Palestinian rule under a 1995 accord.</p>
<p>The Hebron pullout has been frozen since March by Islamic suicide bombings and Israeli fears for the safety of 400 Jews living and studying among the city's 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
<p>Dini said it was legitimate for Israel to be concerned about its security but he added that security could never be guaranteed 100 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There is always a margin of risk which has to be measured against the risks of a complete stall in the peace process which could lead to a resumption of a conflict which would be devastating,&quot; Dini said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
