<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134864" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy govt plans confidence vote on Banco di Napoli.</title>
<headline>Italy govt plans confidence vote on Banco di Napoli.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's centre-left government intends to seek a vote of confidence in the lower house of parliament to enable passage into law of a cabinet decree on a rescue plan for Banco di Napoli, a senior member of parliament for the governing alliance said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lanfranco Turci, economic affairs expert of the Democratic Party of the Left, said the decision to seek a confidence vote was likely to be taken by a cabinet meeting due to start at 1700 GMT.</p>
<p>Passage of the decree is being threatened by 1,000 amendments submitted by the separatist Northern League party.</p>
<p>The decree is due to expire on November 24 unless it has been passed into law by then and could not be resubmitted as a result of a Constitutional Court ruling banning the practice of successive cabinets of re-issuing expiring decrees.</p>
<p>Turci said the government could inform parliament that it was presenting a confidence vote later on Tuesday or on Wednesday, meaning it would be debated later this week.</p>
<p>Passage of a confidence vote has the effect of sweeping away amendments to a bill. Defeat on the vote would bring down the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
