<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134814" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy cabinet meeting brought forward to 1700 GMT.</title>
<headline>Italy cabinet meeting brought forward to 1700 GMT.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian cabinet meeting due later on Tuesday will start at 1700 GMT and not the originally planned 1800 GMT, the prime minister's office said in a statement.</p>
<p>The cabinet is expected to discuss all government decree laws due to expire before November 8.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Italy's high court ruled unconstitutional the practice by which cabinets have renewed decrees.</p>
<p>The ruling has yet to come into force and the government is racing to renew decrees which are about to expire, to win themselves breathing space.</p>
<p>Decrees take immediate effect but lapse unless they are ratified by parliament and passed into law within 60 days.</p>
<p>They were originally meant to be applied in extraordinary circumstances, but successive cabinets, faced with the slow pace of law-making in parliament, have in the past simply re-issued them with little or no change, renewing their life.</p>
<p>Deputy prime minister Walter Veltroni said earlier this month that while the ruling was justified, Italy could face paralysis unless parliament made a mammoth effort to enact more than 50 outstanding &quot;repeat&quot; decrees into law. -- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
