<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134808" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS - EU's anti-Helms-Burton plans in turmoil.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - EU's anti-Helms-Burton plans in turmoil.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union efforts to combat Washington's anti-Cuba trade laws were thrown into turmoil on Tuesday when Denmark said it would veto proposed retaliatory measures.</p>
<p>European Commission officials had hoped EU foreign ministers meeting in Luxembourg next week would approve a series of blocking tactics to counter the threat of Washington's Helms-Burton Act, an amalgamation of years of anti-Cuba policy.</p>
<p>But diplomats said on Tuesday that Copenhagen would veto the proposals because they compromised its national sovereignty.</p>
<p>&quot;Proposals for EU blocking tactics will not go through because Denmark will veto them,&quot; one diplomat told Reuters. &quot;The laws against Helms-Burton will not go through.&quot;</p>
<p>The Danish decision will not affect a case brought by the Commission, the EU's executive, against the United States at the World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Geneva.</p>
<p>A WTO panel is due to convene on November 20 to rule on EU complaints that the act -- and similar laws which seek to quash trade with Iran and Libya -- is extra-territorial.</p>
<p>The Danish government is currently embroiled in a court case brought by a citizens' group that accuses it of handing too much sovereignty to the EU.</p>
<p>Diplomats said neither the Commission nor Denmark's 14 EU partners could convince Copenhagen that proposed retaliation to Helms-Burton did not interfere with Danish sovereignty and would not affect the court case.</p>
<p>Peter Guilford, spokesman for EU Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan, said the Commission had not given up hope of persuading Denmark to approve the proposals when foreign ministers meet next Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We and the majority of member states are convinced of the validity of EU competence in this matter,&quot; Guilford said. &quot;We understand that Denmark has some legal difficulties in accepting the proposals, but we will try and sort the problem out.&quot;</p>
<p>The foreign ministers were due to discuss proposals that would allow countersuits to be brought anywhere in Europe against litigants who sue European companies or individuals for contravening the Helms-Burton Act.</p>
<p>Among other things the act allows naturalised Americans to take action in U.S. courts against &quot;traffickers&quot; -- foreign companies or individuals accused of gaining from investments made in property confiscated in Cuba since the 1959 Communist revolution.</p>
<p>The practical implications of the act have been suspended until January, ostensibly to give U.S. special envoy Stuart Eizenstat the opportunity to encourage Washington's allies to join efforts to isolate Havana but also to postpone the issue until after the U.S. presidential elections on November 5.</p>
<p>Although President Bill Clinton is known to privately oppose parts of the act, he was pressured into agreeing its passage in March after Cuba shot down two U.S. private light aircraft it said had repeatedly strayed into Cuban airspace.</p>
<p>Following outrage from the EU, Mexico and Canada, Clinton suspended part of the act, although he passed another section which bars executives of &quot;traffickers&quot; from entering the U.S.</p>
<p>Executives from Canadian mining conglomerate Sherritt International, among them EU nationals, have been barred from entering the United States. Washington is expected to name more companies it accuses of trafficking later this year.</p>
<p>The European Union is still studying proposals to bar U.S executives involved in litigation from the 15-nation bloc and has already begun compiling a &quot;watchlist&quot; of potential litigants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
