<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134855" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish govt seeks moderate wages and low inflation.</title>
<headline>Irish govt seeks moderate wages and low inflation.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Irish government said on Tuesday that it hopes to maintain a stable, moderate wage and low inflation environment, on the eve of negotiations for a new Programme for Competitiveness and Work (PCW).</p>
<p>In a statement accompanying the 1996 labour force survey, the government said that over the life of the PCW, 130,000 jobs were created -- more than in the preceding 20 years.</p>
<p>The PCW, agreed in 1993, included a wage agreement reached through a consensus approach by government, employers and unions to the management of the economy, known as social partership.  </p>
<p>That agreement is due to expire at the end of 1996 and negotiations on a new agreement begin on October 23. &quot;In the forthcoming discussions ... the government will be seeking to maintain, in conjunction with the social partners, a stable, moderate wage and low inflation environment to promote further job creation,&quot; the government said.</p>
<p>A labour force survey, published on Tuesday, showed an increase of 45,000 in employment in the year to mid-April which the government said was largely due to adhering to a prudent Programme for Competitiveness and Work (PCW) over the last three years.  </p>
<p>Apart from Scandinavia, Ireland has the highest level of trade union membership among EU countries at more than 50 percent of the workforce.</p>
<p>Trade union penetration of the private sector stands at around 35 percent as against 90 percent in the public sector.</p>
<p>It is expected that unions and employers will adopt a tougher stance in the forthcoming negotiations, demanding significant tax cuts and tight control of public spending before they sign up for any new agreement.</p>
<p>The government said the favourable macro-economic conditions currently enjoyed by Ireland was also a boost to increasing the numbers employed.</p>
<p>Ireland's gross domestic product is expected to grow by six percent in 1996. It grew at 10 percent in 1995 and is deemed the fastest growing economy within the European Union.</p>
<p>-- Carmel Linnane Dublin Newsroom + 353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
