<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134875" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Car production boosts French manufacturing.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Car production boosts French manufacturing.</headline>
<byline>David Clarke</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surprise surge in French manufacturing output in July and August was driven by demand for cars as people rushed to cash in on a government sales incentive which expired last month, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>National statistics institute INSEE said industrial output excluding energy, agri-food business and construction rose 2.9 percent in the two-month period from June after rising 0.3 percent in June compared to May.</p>
<p>Economists polled by Reuters had only expected a 0.3 percent increase during the period.</p>
<p>They said car production would have continued to support manufacturing output in September but the short-term nature of the demand, combined with a relatively downbeat outlook from French industrialists suggested the boost would be shortlived.</p>
<p>&quot;Production was strongly boosted by the expiry of the (incentive scheme), which was visible in car production and in intermediate goods production,&quot; said Patrick Mange, economist at Deutsche Bank in Paris. &quot;But what was surprising was that we had a good boost to consumer goods.&quot;</p>
<p>Mange said the 3.3 percent rise in consumer goods production was &quot;partly a catch-up&quot; after three months of declining output in the sector although it could also be a sign companies are beginning to rebuild levels of stocks.</p>
<p>INSEE said most of the overall rise was due to a leap in car production, which rose 8.1 percent in July/August after a 4.4 percent rise in June.</p>
<p>INSEE said the 2.5 percent rise in semi-manufactured goods was mainly due to the production of metal and electrical goods, up 6.5 and 3.8 percent respectively, destined for the car industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to know how seriously to take the numbers and it's hard to take them as a sign of underlying strength,&quot; said Sean Shepley, international economist at CS First Boston. &quot;There's an erratic element in this and we know the car sector will come down with a bump.&quot;</p>
<p>Shepley said, however, the strong headline number might help the government, which has come under fire because of record unemployment, in its attempts to persuade the public that the economic situation is improving.</p>
<p>INSEE said the increase in consumer goods was driven by a 9.5 percent rise in output by the publishing industry, reversing a decline of a similar magnitude in May and a 5.4 percent rise in household goods, which also reversed a recent drop.</p>
<p>Eric Chaney, economist at Morgan Stanley in Paris, who had predicted a 2.3 percent rise in manufacturing production in July and August, was altogether more upbeat about the message from the French production figures.</p>
<p>He said the increase in output of consumer goods and semi-manufactured goods was &quot;confirmation that there is a rebound in core Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Survey evidence is showing a strong pickup in foreign demand and that September is going to be a good month for manufacturing. The story is not finished,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A futures trader at a large French bank remained unconvinced. &quot;It's one number. I'd prefer to see a trend.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
