<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134893" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Hong Kong democrats urge UN watch after handover.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong democrats urge UN watch after handover.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong legislators and non- governmental groups said on Tuesday they wanted the United Nations to ensure some supervision of human rights in the British colony after its handover to Chinese rule next year.</p>
<p>They were speaking at a news conference before hearings by the U.N.'s Human Rights Committee of a report by the Hong Kong government on the situation in the colony in advance of the transfer of sovereignty on July 1, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite pessimistic about the fate of human rights in Hong Kong after the transfer,&quot; said Emily Lau, a member of the colony's current Legislative Council.</p>
<p>She is a member of a delegation representing critics of the terms on which the handover from British to Chinese rule is being made which came to Geneva to discuss the issue with the 18-member Committee, made up of independent human rights experts.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong government itself will also be appearing before the Committee over the next two days to answer questions on a report it submitted earlier this year on observance of the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights.</p>
<p>The government team, headed by Solicitor-General Daniel Fung, will form part of the official British team for the two-day Committee hearing.</p>
<p>Lau, supported by fellow legislators Andrew Cheng and James To as well as Paul Harris of the Hong Kong Bar Association, told the news conference a key area of concern was the Chinese attitude to reporting to the Committee after next July.</p>
<p>China has argued it has no obligation to make reports on Hong Kong after the transfer as it is not a signatory to the Covenant, which the U.N. body monitors.</p>
<p>&quot;If China continues to refuse to make reports, or does not sign the Covenant itself, we hope the Committee will be agreeable to receiving reports from non-governmental groups to decide whether a full hearing should be held,&quot; said Lau.</p>
<p>The Committee, set up in 1976, studies reports by governments on the human rights situation in territory under their jurisdiction and also accepts comments from unofficial organisations in states which have signed the Covenant.</p>
<p>But it has not tried in the past to hold hearings on problems in countries which are not signatories, nor has it accepted unofficial reports from such states.</p>
<p>Lau said Hong Kong was a unique case because it was being transferred from a state which had signed the Covenant to one which had not. &quot;We hope some way can be found for the Committee to continue to receive reports,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Members of her delegation said they were especially concerned at growing signs from China that it would not allow Hong Kong's present degree of political and media freedom to continue after it takes over.</p>
<p>In a recent interview, Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen made clear the new authorities would not permit a continuation of the annual Hong Kong demonstrations against the 1991 crackdown on the &quot;democracy movement&quot; in Bejing.</p>
<p>He also warned that the freewheeling Hong Kong media would be barred from publishing &quot;rumours or lies&quot; or personal attacks on Chinese leaders.</p>
<p>The unofficial Hong Kong delegation is also protesting at Beijing's plans to replace the existing elected legislature with a provisional one whose members will be nominated by China on July 1 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We were elected freely. Why should we be compelled to give up our mandates?&quot; said Cheng.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
