<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134839" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Lagardere profit jumps in first-half.</title>
<headline>Lagardere profit jumps in first-half.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Lagardere magazines-to-missiles conglomerate reported on Tuesday that its half-year profit jumped 38 percent to 409 million francs ($78.9 million), propelled by gains in its defence activities and a big improvement in its finances.</p>
<p>Operating profit slipped, however, to 976 million francs from 1.08 billion due to weakness in its automotive and audiovisual businesses, the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>Lagardere said its high-tech activities -- set to expand greatly with the acquisition of state electronics group Thomson SA -- showed a 55 percent profit increase as it began billing for several major contracts.</p>
<p>The French government last week said it preferred Lagardere's offer for Thomson SA over a rival bid from Alcatel Alsthom.</p>
<p>Lagardere will focus on Thomson's defence electronics unit Thomson-CSF, merging it with its Matra missiles business, and sell the consumer electronics division -- Thomson Multimedia -- to South Korea's Daewoo Electronics.</p>
<p>The government plans to recapitalise Thomson to the tune of 11 billion francs before selling it to Lagardere for the symbolic sum of one franc after a procedural review by the privatisation commission.</p>
<p>Lagardere said its automotive activities were hit by the weakness in the French car industry and the phase-out of the Espace minivan, which it builds with Renault, ahead of the model replacement.</p>
<p>Lagardere's financial results swung to a gain of 103 million francs in the first half from a charge of 54 million in the first half of 1995 due to lower interest rates and the sale of assets for which provisions had been set aside.</p>
<p>&quot;A study of forecasts for 1996 allows us to confirm the objective of a net attributable profit of one billion francs, given an improvement seen in operating profits in the second half,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Lagardere reported a 630 million franc profit for 1995.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
<p>($ = 5.183 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
