<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134882" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares close bourse lower, consolidating.</title>
<headline>German shares close bourse lower, consolidating.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares closed bourse trade lower on Tuesday, weighed down by a weaker dollar and losses on Wall Street overnight and Japan's Nikkei index.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 leading shares ended floor trade down 10.05 points, or 0.37 percent, at 2,718.98. Dealers said they expected the index to consolidate for the rest of the week and said it was well-supported above the 2,700 point level.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect a little consolidation over the next few days and there's support around 2,700 points,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>In the absence of any significant data, dealers said the focus for the rest of the week would come from specific company news.</p>
<p>Utility firm RWE AG reported a 10 percent increase in group net profits, excluding minority interests, to 1.2 billion marks in the year ending June 1996. But RWE shares ended bourse trade down 64 pfennigs at 63.31.</p>
<p>Results were also expected later on Tuesday from business software firm SAP AG.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, shares in Dresdner Bank raced ahead, adding nearly two and a half percent, or 98 pfennigs, to 40.93 marks, after investment bank Goldman Sachs raised its recommendation on the firm to &quot;market outpeformer.&quot;</p>
<p>The rest of the banking sector was also buoyed by Dresdner's gains.</p>
<p>The chemical sector was weaker than the rest of the market, with dealers saying setiment was hurt after Swiss Ciba-Geigy said its pharmaceutical sales growth was hurt by U.S. competition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
