<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134810" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German CDU backs tax cuts, Waigel for more economies.</title>
<headline>German CDU backs tax cuts, Waigel for more economies.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Christian Democrats (CDU) backed a radical tax cut plan on Tuesday after Finance Minister Theo Waigel warned they must also have the courage to impose unpopular spending cuts to finance it.</p>
<p>The annual congress of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's party passed a resolution calling for top tax rates to drop from 53 to around 35 percent while lowest rates should fall from 25.9 to under 20 percent.  Kohl wants the reform to start in 1999.</p>
<p>Waigel, chairman of the CDU's Bavarian sister party, hailed the reform plan as &quot;just the right thing&quot; to assure Germany remains internationally competitive.</p>
<p>But he also warned he would not continue to take all the heat for unpopular tax decisions like he did last week in a bitter feud with the third party in Kohl's shaken 14-year coalition, the liberal Free Democrats (FDP).</p>
<p>&quot;These are dammed tough times and we have to tackle them together,&quot; he declared.  &quot;There can't be two different roles in the coalition, with one side doing the dirty work in the quarry while the other side sells the marble.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl's centre-right coalition flirted with collapse last week when Waigel and the FDP bitterly locked horns over ways to find a few billion marks more for the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>That uproar was just a foretaste of the problems Kohl could face when Bonn starts hacking through a jungle of long-standing state subsidies and tax breaks to help finance the tax reform expected to reduce Bonn's revenues by 30 billion marks.</p>
<p>Waigel said his Christian Social Union (CSU) wanted Kohl to run for reelection in 1998.  Kohl, 66, has been CDU leader for 23 years and set a record as postwar Germany's longest-serving chancellor at the end of this month.</p>
<p>Under the planned reform, many of the myriad exemptions in Germany's confusing tax laws are to be cut out to help expand the tax base and make up for part of the revenue shortfall.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, the CDU parliamentary leader and Kohl's unofficial crown prince, also warned the 1,000 delegates at the congress about the rough road ahead once they went from talking tax reform to actually working out the details.</p>
<p>&quot;Every tax break we cut will provoke an outcry from those who are effected,&quot; he said.  &quot;Vested interests will pull out all the stops to keep their exemptions.  Some allies who at first patted us on the shoulder will quietly steal away.&quot;</p>
<p>The resolution is not binding on Kohl's coalition but the broad support for it and Schaeuble's sponsorship meant most of it would appear in the government's tax reform bill next year.</p>
<p>Like Kohl on Monday, both Waigel and Schaeuble attacked the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) for using their majority in the parliament's upper house last week to block Bonn's plan to delay a promised increase in child benefit payments that Waigel said he could not finance.</p>
<p>That led to the showdown with the liberal FDP, which had to cave in and let Waigel put off a planned cut in the hated solidarity tax levied to help rebuild eastern Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;In the lower house they complain about high debt and in the upper house they prevent budget consolidation,&quot; Waigel said of SPD parliamentarians. &quot;That is politically phoney.&quot;</p>
<p>But neither speaker ventured an opinion about exactly which subsidies or loopholes would have to go.</p>
<p>In the tax reform resolution due to be passed later on Tuesday, the CDU said: &quot;German tax law is too complicated and has thus become injust.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the lower tax rates could be levied in a few stages or progressively and proposed to treat all income equally, including the many extra payments -- now tax-free -- that workers get for working nights, on Sundays or on holidays.</p>
<p>&quot;With such low tax rates, we can do without most exemptions and tax breaks,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
