<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134842" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: U.N. plans for feared E.Slavonia Serb exodus-paper.</title>
<headline>U.N. plans for feared E.Slavonia Serb exodus-paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations has drawn up a secret plan to cope with a mass exodus of Serbs it fears will start when Eastern Slavonia, Croatia's last Serb-held enclave, reverts to Croatian rule, a French newspaper said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Croatian authorities are due to take over in Eastern Slavonia by next April 15 at the latest, and U.N. officials there fear this will cause a flight of the region's 130,000 Serbs, the daily Le Monde reported.</p>
<p>The paper said the United Nations, wary of a repeat of the panic exodus of Serbs from parts of Sarajevo when it reverted to Bosnian Moslem rule earlier this year, hopes to prepare an orderly departure which it opposes but sees itself as being unable to prevent.</p>
<p>Le Monde said it had seen a secret U.N. document calling for the channelling of Serb refugees towards Danube River bridges leading to Serbia proper.</p>
<p>U.N. officials on the spot were trying to encourage Serbs to stay butthey  believed Serb and Croat authorities had reached a secret agreement favouring ethnic separation which would be politically beneficial to both sides as they sought to consolidate post-war borders, the paper said.</p>
<p>The U.N. Transitional Authority in Eastern Slavonia (UNTAES) had drawn up plans for huge refugee camps in case there was an exodus, Le Monde added.</p>
<p>The newspaper said many Serbs, especially that half of the Serb population which lived in the area before civil war broke out over four years ago, wished to remain even under Croat rule.</p>
<p>But they feared scenes of revenge when the area's Croat inhabitants, expelled by Serbs earlier in the war, returned, the paper added.</p>
<p>Croat refugees threatened earlier this month to force their way back into the region unless U.N. peace troops left by January and local elections were held by mid-December.</p>
<p>UNTAES, backed by 5,000 peace troops, moved into Eastern Slavonia last January with the task of gradually reinstating Croatian government rule there in one year, with the option of up to a year's extension if needed.</p>
<p>Croatia's nationalist government said recently it would reluctantly accept a three-month extension to April 15, 1997, recommended by the U.N. administrator of the region.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council will decide the issue next month.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
