<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134954" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: RWE confident of continuing earnings growth.</title>
<headline>RWE confident of continuing earnings growth.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German diversified utility RWE AG said on Tuesday that it was confident of continuing its run of improved earnings growth in 1996/97, but said its fledgling telecoms business would make further losses.</p>
<p>Group sales rose eight percent to 16.5 billion marks ($10.72 billion) in the three months to September 30 from 15.2 billion in the year-earlier period, with telecoms sales doubling to 200 million marks, the company said.</p>
<p>The group said that it had seen a &quot;slight increase&quot; in earnings in the first quarter of 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that we can again increase earnings in 1996/97 following the measures we have taken,&quot; Dietmar Kuhnt, management board chairman of RWE AG, said at the group's annual results conference.</p>
<p>Should RWE realise this goal, it would make 1996/97 the eighth year in a row that RWE has reported higher earnings.</p>
<p>Kuhnt said that its proposed 10 pfennig increase to 1.50 marks in dividends was further evidence of its stated aim of boosting earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that the strategic direction of the group shows signs of long-term continuity,&quot; said Kuhnt.</p>
<p>While group net profit rose 10 percent in 1995/96, the increase in turnover was much less marked at 65.43 billion marks, up from 63.58 billion marks in the previous year.</p>
<p>In the group's telecoms business, start-up losses had been factored in to the group's strategy and would be higher this year, RWE said.</p>
<p>Last year the group saw turnover in its telecoms business of around 500 million marks, with losses of 75 million marks in the period.</p>
<p>RWE took the markets by surprise earlier this month when it said it was pulling out of a German telecoms alliance with British Telecom and fellow diversified utility Viag AG due to differences over market strategy.</p>
<p>The group said it would instead join an alliance between the British group Cable &amp; Wireless and the third of the big German utility groups Veba AG.</p>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless announced on Tuesday it was merging its British operations with those of NYNEX, of the U.S. and Bell Canada International into one company providing integrated telecommunications, information and entertainment services.</p>
<p>RWE's energy business contributed 564 million marks to group net profits in 1995/96, up from 516 million marks the previous year, while its mining and raw materials business added 271 million marks, up from 246 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Group net profit contributions from RWE's petroleum and chemicals business were almost unchanged in 1995/96 at 249 million, compared to 246 million the previous year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the group's waste disposal business came back into the black, reporting a profit of 12 million marks compared in 1995/96, bouncing back from a loss of 94 million marks in 1995/95.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($1=1.5386 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
