<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134993" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cable &amp; Wireless chief Brown rules nothing out.</title>
<headline>Cable &amp; Wireless chief Brown rules nothing out.</headline>
<byline>David Holmes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable &amp; Wireless chief executive Richard Brown said on Tuesday he did not rule out further international alliances in the wake of the plan to merge C&amp;W's British unit with three other cable firms in a new operator in which his company will have a controlling stake.</p>
<p>&quot;We never rule anything out,&quot; Brown said in a Reuters interview after the announcement that C&amp;W had reached agreement to merge its British unit Mercury with the U.S.-controlled NYNEX CableComms, Bell Cablemedia and Videotron Holdings.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a solid foundation,&quot; he said. The merger will create a new company called Cable &amp; Wireless Communications, to be listed separately in London and New York, in which C&amp;W will have a 52.6 percent stake.</p>
<p>The plan comes five months after C&amp;W named Brown as its chief executive following last year's boardroom bust-up in which the top two executives, chairman Lord Young and chief executive James Ross, left the company following a dispute over strategy.</p>
<p>Brown was previously in charge of accounting services group H&amp;R Block Inc and prior to that was vice-chairman of U.S. telecoms group Ameritech Corp.</p>
<p>Tuesday's announcement also follows the abandonment earlier this year of C&amp;W's merger talks with British Telecommunications (BT), and comes after months of bid speculation around C&amp;W centred on its valuable controlling stake in Hong Kong Telecoms.</p>
<p>C&amp;W last month replaced the giant BT in a major German alliance with diversified utility RWE that is seen as the main competitor to the dominant Deutsche Telekom as the German market is being liberalised.</p>
<p>At a time when other telecommunication groups were trying to expand their international operations, Brown said C&amp;W was already &quot;the most global telecom company on earth&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the speedy agreement on the new merger demonstrated what C&amp;W could achieve. &quot;Any of the banks involved will tell you this was the impossible achieved in record time,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a common vision of what could be done and we have done it with speed and nimbleness,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you put your hearts and minds to something, you can finish it in five weeks, whereas we were speaking to BT for five months.&quot;</p>
<p>C&amp;W's deputy group chief executive Rod Olsen said the merger would result in a wide range of benefits to C&amp;W and to its new cable partners.</p>
<p>&quot;Quite clearly something of this scale offers significant opportunities for cost savings, a significant strengthening of purchasing power and significant capital expenditure efficiencies,&quot; Olsen said.</p>
<p>It would also offer economies of scale on programming costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Cable companies are debt-laden and with this deal we have opportunities to reduce the cost of debt and to open up new opportunities to enhance revenue,&quot; Olsen said.</p>
<p>Brown said the merged company would give C&amp;W's Mercury unit access to six million homes in addition to its existing mainly business customers, giving access to 18 million consumers in total. &quot;It is very exciting for consumers and good for our shareholders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yet Brown said he was constrained in the detail he could give on the financial aspects of the merger because of the planned public listing of C&amp;W Communications.</p>
<p>As with any initial public offering, stock exchange authorities impose rules on what can be said about a company coming to market and when.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
