<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134911" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish employment up 45,000 in yr to mid-April - CSO.</title>
<headline>Irish employment up 45,000 in yr to mid-April - CSO.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish employment rose by 45,000 in the year to mid-April when a total of 1,284,000 people were in work, Ireland's annual Labour Force Survey showed.</p>
<p>The survey, published on Tuesday by the Central Statistics Office (CSO), also showed that the number of unemployed &quot;changed only slightly&quot; and stood at 190,000. The number of unemployed men fell by 5,000 but female joblessness rose by 4,000, it said.</p>
<p>Ireland's total labour force, which includes both those at work or unemployed, increased by 44,000 to 1,474,000.</p>
<p>A total of 46,000 households representing 145,000 people were interviewed in the survey.  </p>
<p>The survey results, which are subject to revision, showed that women accounted for 33,000 of the 45,000 increase in the numbers at work.</p>
<p>There was an increase of 47,000 in those employed in services but a fall of 6,000 in those working in agriculture.</p>
<p>The numbers working in industry grew by 4,000 with building and construction mainly accounting for the increase.  </p>
<p>The total number of unemployed persons dropped by 1,000 while those employed in the manufacturing sector increased by 1,000.</p>
<p>A change in the sectoral classification system in 1995 resulted in the transfer of about 4,000 people from professional services into commerce, insurance and finance.</p>
<p>The labour force survey estimated the Republic of Ireland's total population at 3.62 million, an increase of 23,000 over the 1995 figure while the number of students not in the labour force rose by 17,000 on the previous year to 358,000,</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
