<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134958" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: S-E-Banken says to probe own U.S. deals.</title>
<headline>S-E-Banken says to probe own U.S. deals.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish commercial bank S-E-Banken said on Tuesday it was investigating a number of unauthorised transactions at its New York office in 1992 and 1993 involving the allocation of profits in time and between units.  </p>
<p>&quot;In response to inquiries, S-E-Banken confirmed that it is reviewing certain transactions related to its New York operation in 1992 and 1993 which involved inappropriate deferral or transfer of trading income between different units of the group,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>The scope of the transactions were not of a material nature, S-E-Banken said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has not incurred any direct losses on these transactions, no customers were involved and no employees appear to have recognised any financial benefit,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>It said a number of employees involved in the transactions had been reassigned and were now at the disposal of the bank for its review.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has informed the appropriate U.S. and Swedish regulatory authorities about this matter and is cooperating fully with them,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Wikman pointed out that the bank had not suffered any direct losses through the affair as the transactions were not of a material nature.</p>
<p>&quot;That is our assessment. What happened is that someone rolled over taxes on profits, something which is not allowed under tax rules or our own internal rules,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It could turn out to be a matter of interest payments on the tax that has been deferred,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The bank said it had informed the appropriate U.S. and Swedish regulatory authorities about the matter and is cooperating fully with them.</p>
<p>Wikman said the U.S. Securities and Exchanges Commission was not directly involved in the affair as S-E-Banken is not registered in New York. She declined to make any further comment on the investigation.</p>
<p>S-E-Banken shares were a little weaker in Tuesday morning trade despite strength in the rest of the market, slipping 0.5 to 57 crowns.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
