<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134941" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French firms hope to cash on exotic meat craze.</title>
<headline>French firms hope to cash on exotic meat craze.</headline>
<byline>Dominique Vidalon</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small French companies hoping to cash on the latest craze for exotic but healthy food gathered at an international food fair here on Tuesday to promote their latest offers of ostrich and kangaroo meats.</p>
<p>France Autruches, a firm based in the western town of Chateaubriant, was offering consumers who have turned away from beef as a result of the scare over mad cow disease its latest low-fat alternative to red meat -- ostrich meat smoked with beech.</p>
<p>Gibieroy, from the eastern town of Neuvillers-Sur-Fave, was introducing a range of ready-to-cook kangaroo meat only 10 days after getting the green light from French authorities to sell kangaroo meat for human consumption.</p>
<p>Although ostrich meat costs 15-20 percent more than beef, France Autruches has been doing a brisk business selling a meat that tastes like beef but is more tender, high in protein and low in cholesterol, spokeswoman Corinne Roul told Reuters.</p>
<p>France Autruches started operations in 1993 and has gained experience in every aspect of the industry from local breeding of ostriches and emus to hatching and distribution.</p>
<p>With a livestock of almost 15,000 birds it has diversified into four sectors of activity, rearing, meat, fine leathers and cosmetics.</p>
<p>Sales have jumped to 37 million french francs ($7.12 million) in 1996 from 22.7 million in 1995 and meat volume has taken off from an initial 50 tonnes to reach 300 tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Producers said the scare over the mad cow disease that erupted in March after Britain admitted a possible link between the Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy (BSE) and its deadly equivalent in humans helped boost sales.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw a significant increase in sales at the start of the mad cow scare. But since then sales have kept growing. Consumers tasted ostrich meat during the crisis and found they liked it,&quot; Roul said</p>
<p>France Autruches generates 60 percent of its sales from exports, mostly to Spain, Italy, and Britain.</p>
<p>But it is also eying promising demand from the Middle East and China.</p>
<p>Last April the firm sent 500 ostriches and emus to Saudi Arabia to be raised for breeding and consumption.</p>
<p>It is currently working on a similar venture in China.</p>
<p>Consumers seaching for an exotic alternative to beef have also turned to game such as deer and bison.</p>
<p>Now Gibieroy is proposing to bring kangaroo meat to the French dinner table, said Jose Pereniguez, marketing manager for Gibieroy.</p>
<p>The company is hoping kangaroo meat will be a success with consumers during the Christmas season.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure kangaroo meat costs more than beef but it will appeal to consumers who want to give themselves a special treat once in a while,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=5.199 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
