<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134943" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Privatised Cimpor seeks acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Privatised Cimpor seeks acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal's largest cement producer Cimpor-Cimentos de Portugal, fresh from partial privatisation last week, can look forward to strong profit and sales growth as it prowls for foreign acquisitions, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Cimpor wants to grow in markets where it feels it will have a competitive advantage,&quot; said Mark Howard of Lloyds Bank Fund Managers in Cascais near Lisbon.</p>
<p>The Portuguese government earned some 115.3 billion escudos ($743.9 million) from the privatisation of a 45 percent stake of Cimpor a week ago. Sixty five percent of the company has now been floated, while the rest remains in state hands.</p>
<p>Analysts said they believed Cimpor would use its cash mountain to seek foreign acquisitions to stimulate growth and its stock market value.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the share price to increase by some 18 percent by the beginning of 1997 and a further 18 percent by the end of 1997,&quot; said James Harrison, analyst with Lisbon broker Midas.</p>
<p>Cimpor has the potential to invest up to 250 billion escudos in foreign acquisitions up to 2001, a company source said recently.</p>
<p>The investment plan depended on Cimpor's ability to maintain its cash flow and not to allow debt to reach 30 percent of total assets, the source said. Cimpor currently has low debt.</p>
<p>The company is considering Spain, South America, and northern and southern Africa as potential areas to acquire cement manufacturers, the source said.</p>
<p>In August Cimpor bought Moroccan cement firm Asment Temara for 11.8 billion escudos.</p>
<p>Lisbon newspaper Diario Economico reported last month that Cimpor was also studying a possible purchase of Brazilian cement producer Companhia de Materiais Sulfurosos -- Matisulfur.</p>
<p>The paper quoted a Brazilian press report as saying Matisulfur, located in Grande Belo Horizonte, was valued at $100 million and had a productive capacity of one million tonnes.</p>
<p>Cimpor already owns a subsidiary in Spain, Corporacion Noroeste, and in Mozambique, Empresa de Cimentos de Mocambique.</p>
<p>It is hunting for foreign cement producers to boost its production capacity because returns on its cash pile are limited in a climate of falling interest rates in Portugal.</p>
<p>The company's growth prospects would benefit from house- and road-building programmes and construction for the 1998 Expo World Fair in Lisbon, analysts said.</p>
<p>Cimpor said last month that full 1996 net profit would be at least double the 11.6 billion escudos earned in the first six months of the year.</p>
<p>Harrison forecast a price earnings ratio (PE) before extraordinaries of 14.9 for end-1996 and 12.3 for end-1997, at the present share price.</p>
<p>He expected the shares to rise to 3,865 escudos by early 1997 and 4,535 by end-1997. Cimpor closed at 3,260 on Monday, up from its its privatisation at a fixed 3,170 escudos a share.</p>
<p>Lloyds's Howard projected a PE with extraordinaries of 10.7 for end-1996 and 13.5 for end-1997, at the present share price. He expected Cimpor's share price to stand at 3,500 escudos by end-1996 and 4,500 escudos by end-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The share was priced attractively in the privatisation,&quot; Harrison said. &quot;This has resulted in a good post-privatisation market for the shares.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254 ($1=155.0 Escudo)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
