<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134973" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India markets sparkle in wake of credit easing.</title>
<headline>India markets sparkle in wake of credit easing.</headline>
<byline>Simon Cameron-Moore</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian markets reopened on Tuesday with some much-needed fizz injected by the central bank's announcement over the long weekend of a looser credit policy for the next six months.</p>
<p>&quot;The phones are ringing again. People are asking positive questions. We're feeling good,&quot; Ramesh Damani, a member broker at the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE), told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shares, gilts and the rupee all showed strength, but while the markets burst into life analysts said they were not issuing invites for a bulls' party.</p>
<p>The BSE top-30 index rose 98.75 points from Friday's close to close at a provisional 3,228.96, or 3.15 percent higher.</p>
<p>The rupee was quoted at 35.62 to the dollar late Tuesday, after closing on Friday at 35.67. But the strength was more evident in the forward market, where the six-month dollar premia fell to 1.30/1.32 rupees from 1.57/1.60 on Friday.</p>
<p>Gilts continued the uptrend begun in anticipation of the central bank's moves. The 13.50 percent 1997 issue yield was quoted at 12.18 percent on Tuesday, versus 12.72 on Friday.</p>
<p>The one-year T-bill yield was quoted at 12.00-12.25 percent on Tuesday versus 12.40-12.50 on Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts were not getting over-excited, however.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very cautious. It's a bit of a bear rally (on equities),&quot; said one director of a foreign brokerage based here.</p>
<p>&quot;It could go up to 3,300 in the current phase, thereafter it should react (downwards),&quot; said Girish Desai, head of research at brokerage Prabhudas Lilladher.</p>
<p>&quot;The market needs to find out whether the economic slowdown is temporary or rooted,&quot; Desai said.</p>
<p>October production figures for core industries, expected out sometime in mid-November, may provide some clues.</p>
<p>Analysts remained unconvinced by the Reserve Bank of India's decision to boost market liquidity by cutting banks' cash reserve requirement by a possible two percent to 10 percent in four stages over the next four months. However, they all described the measures as positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall just because of the credit poilicy I don't see the fundamental situation changing, although it has improved the investment climate,&quot; Devesh Kumar, strategist at W.I. Carr said.</p>
<p>The market's expectations of corporate earnings, in the middle of the reporting season, remain weak.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this rally will be sustained. We have to wait for the (half-year) results. These are not going to be very good,&quot; said Amish Choksi, a dealer at brokerage Amit Nalinkant.</p>
<p>The RBI's staggered approach to loosening credit means money supply remains fairly tight. The final two half-point cuts in January are contingent on monetary and price conditions at the time -- leaving some doubt whether they will happen.</p>
<p>In a note to clients R. Balakrishnan of Dil Vikas Finance Ltd wrote: &quot;For the stock markets the credit policy provides a temporary salve. The economic fundamentals remain fluid and infrastructure bottlenecks remain.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he expected the BSE index to stay in a 2,900 to 3,400 zone for the next couple of months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
