<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134905" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Scientology Church attacks Kohl party resolution.</title>
<headline>Scientology Church attacks Kohl party resolution.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Fleck</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Church of Scientology on Tuesday accused Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) of undemocratic behaviour after the party pledged to put it under official surveillance and bar its members from public service.</p>
<p>Stepping up its row with Germany, the U.S.-based group compared a tough resolution, passed at the CDU's annual congress on Monday, to the Nazis' notorious Nuremberg Decrees stripping Jews of basic rights.</p>
<p>&quot;With the passage of this hateful resolution, the CDU issued what amounts to a manifesto that declares that freedom, democracy, and human rights have been cut from the CDU's agenda,&quot; the group said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's CDU resolution is essentially a reprise of the (Nazi) law...which banned non-Aryans from public service and teaching positions,&quot; said the statement by Church of Scientology international president Reverend Heber Jentzsch.</p>
<p>The CDU resolution called for a country-wide information network to track the group's activities and warn Germans from joining it.</p>
<p>It also called for more help for would-be Scientology dropouts who, it said, came under &quot;massive psychic, economic and legal pressure&quot; to keep them in the group.</p>
<p>The resolution, though non-binding on Kohl, reflected popular feeling in the centre-right party, which forms the backbone of Germany's ruling coalition.</p>
<p>The U.S.-based church has been at loggerheads with German authorities who have refused to register it as a religion. Some German officials portray it as a totalitarian group using manipulative practices for profit.</p>
<p>Because of its own Nazi past, Germany tends to take a tough stand on groups which it thinks threaten its postwar democracy.</p>
<p>The Church of Scientology last week took out an advertisement in the New York Times in which it accused Bonn of using Nazi-style tactics to limit its activities.</p>
<p>Bonn rejected that charge as absurd and said the U.S.-based group had insulted the millions of Jewish victims of the Nazi Holocaust.</p>
<p>The Church of Scientology, founded in 1954 by American science fiction writer L. Ron Hubbard, gives would-be members personality tests and then offers courses and literature to help them realise what the church sees as their full potential.</p>
<p>In its resolution, the CDU called on the Office for the Protection of the Constitution -- Bonn's agency for counter-intelligence and anti-extremist investigations -- to monitor the group's activities.</p>
<p>The CDU's youth wing called earlier this year for a boycott of the Hollywood blockbuster &quot;Mission:Impossible&quot; because it stars Tom Cruise -- one of several high-profile Scientologists.</p>
<p>Fellow film stars Nicole Kidman, who is also Cruise's wife, and John Travolta are also members of the church.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
