<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134949" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: U.S. presidential race loses its worldwide sparkle.</title>
<headline>U.S. presidential race loses its worldwide sparkle.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As the presidential race between Bill Clinton and Bob Dole hots up in the United States with just two weeks to go, the dual has so far stirred remarkably little interest outside America.</p>
<p>The Cold War's conclusion is one of the main reasons for this muted international reaction to the 1996 race. Clinton versus Dole just doesn't whip up the same enthusiasm in a world without NATO versus the Warsaw Pact.</p>
<p>Nuclear-tipped American missiles that caused such controversy in Western Europe became obsolete with the fall of the Berlin Wall and the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Unlike in past races, there has been little talk in London pubs, Berlin beerhalls or Viennese coffeehouses about Star Wars defence systems, Pershing missiles, or reducing strategic forces -- issues that filled newspaper columns a decade ago.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no longer a sense that the Americans have a very important role to play in Germany or in Europe,&quot; said Richard Wagner, foreign editor of the influential Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung newspaper.</p>
<p>&quot;People are following the race, but only at a distance,&quot; said Wagner. &quot;There is no longer a big threat. When Ronald Reagan was running against Walter Mondale or Jimmy Carter, there was a profound interest in who these men were. People knew those elections were decisive for their lives. That's not the case anymore,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Another factor behind overseas apathy to the 1996 campaign is the big lead the Democratic incumbent Clinton has held over his Republican challenger Dole.</p>
<p>Unlike four years ago, when Clinton the outsider came roaring from behind to defeat the incumbent George Bush and become the first Democrat to win since 1976, this year's race has offered more yawns than yarns.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton is heading for victory because the Republicans have chosen such a weak candidate in Dole,&quot; said Tom Lodge of Johannesburg's Witswatersrand University. &quot;The whole campaign has turned out to be pretty boring for most South Africans.&quot;</p>
<p>Government officials in London, Paris, Bonn, Rome, Lisbon, Moscow and Tokyo have been quietly assuming Clinton would win re-election on November 5.</p>
<p>&quot;Though surprises are always possible, all the polls show a strong lead for Clinton,&quot; said one senior French official. &quot;If Clinton wins, we expect no major changes in foreign policy. But a fair number of international matters have been affected by the elections. This has slowed things down in many cases.&quot;</p>
<p>French officials have privately grumbled that in efforts to unblock Middle East peace talks, Washington could not be expected to put much pressure on Israel ahead of the elections, for fear of alienating Jewish voters in the United States.</p>
<p>Although refraining from official comments on the race, governments seem to look forward to a second Clinton Administration.</p>
<p>Even conservative leaders like German Chancellor Helmut Kohl and French President Jacque Chirac have developed fairly close personal relationships with Clinton in the White House over the past four years. Russian leader Boris Yeltsin is also on a first-name basis with Clinton.</p>
<p>The one exception may be Britain's Prime Minister John Major, whose relations with Clinton have been frosty since Major's Conservative party sent advisers to Washington to offer the Bush campaign hints on how to beat Clinton in 1992.</p>
<p>Reports that British government files had been searched allegedly to dig up dirt on Clinton's time at Oxford University in the 1960s also caused friction.</p>
<p>Clinton was recently criticised by Britain's former Northern Ireland minister, Michael Mates. He accused Clinton of exploiting the Northern Ireland peace process and putting votes before lives.</p>
<p>Mates said Clinton was pandering to 40 million Americans of Irish descent clustered in key U.S. voting areas and said the U.S. position was &quot;arrogance combined with ignorance&quot;.</p>
<p>Clinton and Dole have both tripped over each other to prove who was the best friend to another nation that carries a large influence over America's foreign policies -- Israel.</p>
<p>Dole recently warned Clinton not to pressure &quot;our friend Israel&quot; into concessions to Palestinians. Netanyahu responded with a wry remark taken to be a jestful swipe at Clinton, who overtly supported former Israeli Prime Minister Shimon Peres.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't get involved in domestic disputes,&quot; Netanyahu said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
