<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134947" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's BBV surges on good results.</title>
<headline>Spain's BBV surges on good results.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spain's Banco Bilbao Vizcaya rallied in mid-morning trade on Tuesday as traders focussed on the quality of the bank's nine-month results.</p>
<p>AT 0935 GMT, BBV was up 60 pesetas to 6,110, while the Ibex-35 index of leading stocks was down 5.26 points, 0.12 percent to 4,397.35.</p>
<p>&quot;The net (profit) figure was in line with expectations, but the quality of (BBV's) results was really impressive, much better than forecast. They've hit their year-end non-performing loans ratio already,&quot; said a trader at a European bank in Madrid.</p>
<p>Another trader forecast BBV could hit 6,500 pesetas in the short term.</p>
<p>On Monday BBV announced net attributable profit of 70.5 billion pesetas in the first nine months of the year, up 26.5 percent versus the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>BBV's provisions for doubtful debts increased to 100.9 percent, and the bank said it expects profits after minorities to grow 20 percent by year-end.</p>
<p>Dealers said other banks were higher in sympathy, ahead of their results. Banco Central Hispano was up 85 pesetas to 3,005, and Santander added 60 pesetas to 5,250.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of talk about narrower margins in Spain, but from these results you can tell that that's not true,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>A second trader at a Spanish brokerage said there had been switching out of electric utilities into banks after a strong run in the former sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors have no-where to go after the rise in electricals. People are now looking at what other sectors to get into, and they're taking a bit of money out of electricals and putting it into banks.&quot;</p>
<p>He highlighted strong results expected from Banco Santander, due to report on October 28.</p>
<p>BBV's business both at home and abroad was going very well, despite strong competition in Spain, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;They've done really well in South America where there's potential, but also on the domestic side,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
