<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134977" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BRITAIN'S LOTUS INSPIRED GENERATION OF RACE FANS.</title>
<headline>BRITAIN'S LOTUS INSPIRED GENERATION OF RACE FANS.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lotus, the troubled British car company at the centre of new speculation about its future, has inspired a generation of enthusiasts with its beautifully engineered but fragile sports models.</p>
<p>Malaysian car maker Proton on Tuesday refused to comment on reports that it was the leading contender to take over the firm engineering genius Colin Chapman founded in north London in 1952 with money borrowed from his future wife.</p>
<p>Lotus itself said it was looking for a partner not a buyer and while confirming it was working on technical collaboration with Proton, declined to say whether the Malaysian firm had bought an 80 percent share in the sportscar maker.</p>
<p>Chapman made his early reputation by producing sports cars that owners could go racing with -- all they had to do was drive to the circuit, stick on race numbers and take their place on the grid.</p>
<p>Lotus went into Grand Prix racing in 1958 and soon established a reputation as one of the most inventive and successful teams, winning the constructors' championship seven times between 1963 and 1978.</p>
<p>With its distinctive black and gold liveried cars, the team pioneered tobacco sponsorship.</p>
<p>The team, which was forced to disband in 1995 after the tobacco money dried up, was home to some of the best known drivers in Formula One.</p>
<p>Stirling Moss gave the company its first Grand Prix victory when he won at Monaco in 1960 driving a Lotus not for the factory but for the team of private entrant Rob Walker.</p>
<p>But Britons Jim Clark and Graham Hill, Austrian Jochen Rindt, Brazilian Emerson Fittipaldi and American Mario Andretti were all world champions with Lotus while Ronnie Petersen of Sweden and Brazilian Ayrton Senna also raced for the team.</p>
<p>Clark set a record of 25 Grand Prix wins, all with Lotus, in the 1960s. He took the drivers' title in 1965 and 1967 before he died during a Formula Two race at Germany's Hockenheim circuit.</p>
<p>The team was already in decline in 1987, when Senna delivered their final victory in the United States Grand Prix at Detroit, three years after Chapman died of a heart attack at the age of 54.</p>
<p>In parallel with his racing activities, Chapman produced a series of stunning sports models such as the minimalist Lotus Seven, the beautiful Elan and the innovative Elite.</p>
<p>The cars, which could also be supplied in kit form for home-build enthusiasts, established a reputation for being fast, light and beautfully designed. They also had a tendency to break down, leading owners to suggest cruelly that the brand name stood for Lots Of Trouble, Usually Serious.</p>
<p>The new lightweight Elise roadster is a typical Lotus in that it is agile and innovative and produced at a time when the company is facing major financial problems.</p>
<p>Lotus was taken over by General Motors in 1986, and then piled up losses of 50 million pounds ($75 million) in the five years before its sale in 1993 to Luxembourg-based Bugatti International, run by Italian entrepreneur Romano Artioli. Uncertainty has hung over Lotus' ownership since last year, when Italian car company Bugatti Automobili, part of Artioli's empire, went into receivership.</p>
<p>Apart from Proton, Korean industrial group Daewoo has been cited as a potential partner in the trade press, as has a British group led by former racing driver Brian Henton.</p>
<p>Despite the Lotus heritage, buyers are not so much interested in the car-making business. They want the profitable engineering division, whose clients include General Motors, Chrysler and Toyota.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
