<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134912" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Yeltsin's surgery at end of November - surgeon.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin's surgery at end of November - surgeon.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading U.S. heart surgeon who will advise Russian doctors during Boris Yeltin's heart surgery told an Italian newspaper on Tuesday that the operation would take place in Moscow during the last two weeks of November.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are no complications -- and I repeat, there are none right now -- the operation will take place at the end of November, during the last two weeks of the month,&quot; Michael DeBakey told the daily Corriere della Sera.</p>
<p>DeBakey, one of the world's foremost heart surgeons and the man who pioneered the coronary bypass procedure, examined the 65-year-old Russian president last month in Moscow. He said at the time that he expected Yeltsin to make a full recovery from the operation.</p>
<p>He told Corriere della Sera that the surgery would not be delayed or cancelled. The article said the newspaper's Moscow correspondent interviewed DeBakey by telephone, but it did not make clear where DeBakey was speaking from.</p>
<p>&quot;The preparations are continuing as planned,&quot; he said. &quot;Yeltsin's condition is improving all the time.&quot;</p>
<p>DeBakey said doctors had cured a blood problem which had raised questions about whether the operation could take place as scheduled.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's Russian doctors had said he suffered &quot;elements of anaemia&quot; -- a shortage of red blood cells, which play a key role in carrying oxygen around the body.</p>
<p>DeBakey said the problem had been caused by &quot;intestinal haemorrhages&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The patient had been taking aspirin to prevent congealing, he said. &quot;The aspirin was stopped and the bleeding stopped.&quot;</p>
<p>The doctor said Yeltin's liver, kidneys and lungs were normal, adding that the main risk of the operation was posed by the left ventricle.</p>
<p>He quoted an &quot;index of emptying of the ventricle&quot; which he said for Yeltsin was 20 percent a month and a half ago compared to 50 to 60 percent for a healthy patient.</p>
<p>&quot;It has already increased to 35 percent and we hope to arrive at 40 percent before the operation,&quot; DeBakey said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin had two heart attacks last year and some doctors say he may have had a third one between the two rounds of the Russian presidential election. He was elected for a new four-year term on July 3.</p>
<p>He is currently resting in the Barvikha sanatorium outside Moscow while doctors get him ready for the operation, which will improve the blood supply to his heart.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
