<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134916" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: RWE expects telecoms break-even around 2000.</title>
<headline>RWE expects telecoms break-even around 2000.</headline>
<dateline>ESSEN, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German diversified utility RWE AG expects its telecommunications business to break-even around the year 2000, the group said at its annual results conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We reckon that we will see break-even around the year 2000,&quot; management board chairman Dietmar Kuhnt told journalists.</p>
<p>The company said earlier it expected higher losses in its fledgling telecommunications business in the current business year.</p>
<p>Start-up losses had been factored in to the group's strategy and would be higher in the 1996/1997 year, RWE said in a statement prepared for delivery at a news conference.</p>
<p>In the 1995/96 business year, the group saw turnover in its telecoms business of around 500 million marks, with losses of 75 million marks in the period.</p>
<p>Kuhnt said that contracts for the planned telecoms joint venture with German utility Veba AG and the British telecoms company Cable &amp; Wireless would be signed this year, although a date for the signing was yet to be set.</p>
<p>RWE took the markets by surprise earlier this month when it said it was pulling out of a German telecoms alliance with British Telecom and fellow diversified utility Viag AG due to differences over market strategy.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ESSEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
