<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134990" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Japan's ad industry recovers from recession.</title>
<headline>Japan's ad industry recovers from recession.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Advertising expenditure in Japan, the world's second biggest advertising market, has resumed steady growth after getting hammered by recession a few years ago, according to a report released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The report by Zenith Media said $43 billion was spent on advertising last year in Japan, which is the second largest market after the U.S. and about twice as big as the world's fourth largest advertising market, Germany.</p>
<p>About $18.7 billion was spent on television advertising in Japan last year.</p>
<p>The figure was expected to rise to $19.7 billion this year and to reach $22.6 billion by 2001, at current 1995 prices, Zenith said in its report &quot;Television in Asia Pacific to 2001&quot;.</p>
<p>Zenith said Japan and Singapore were the only two countries in Asia-Pacific with televisions in 100 percent of homes, compared to China with 73 percent, Indonesia with 40 percent and India with 31 percent.</p>
<p>It said 20 percent of all homes in Japan had pay-TV last year and the percentage was forecast to increase to 27 percent by 2001.</p>
<p>Zenith, whose report covered the 14 largest countries in the Asia-Pacific region, said &quot;deregulation is in the air&quot; for Japan's broadcast industry.</p>
<p>NHK has a statutory monopoly as Japan's sole national broadcaster and takes no advertising, while commercial television is divided up among five large networks that use local affiliates.</p>
<p>The Japanese government said in January it would relax cross-ownership rules restricting holdings to one television channel and one radio station, and which forbid newspaper proprietors from owning a television channel.</p>
<p>Until April 1996 foreign broadcasters were required to have local Japanese partners as a condition for market entry.</p>
<p>&quot;Pay-TV deregulation is expected by the end of 1996, and cable companies were given permission to carry phone calls in October,&quot; said Zenith, the media-planning and -buying arm of Cordiant Plc, which also owns Saatchi &amp; Saatchi Advertising.</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
