<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134963" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Deutsche Telekom starts hard-sell roadshow.</title>
<headline>Deutsche Telekom starts hard-sell roadshow.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The roadshow aimed at wooing institutional investors to buy shares in the German telecoms giant Deutsche Telekom kicked off on Tuesday, with less than a month to go before Europe's biggest-ever flotation.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom board members will spend the next three and a half weeks travelling in three teams to 30 cities in 17 different countries. Their mission is to convince around 3,700 fund managers to buy shares in the telecoms monopoly.</p>
<p>&quot;The massive response from private investors, combined with the interest shown by institutional investors, convinces me that the flotation of Deutsche Telekom will be a genuine success,&quot; Ron Sommer, management board chairman of Deutsche Telekom AG said at the launch of the roadshow.</p>
<p>Over three million private investors have already signed up with Telekom to buy its stock when the flotation starts in Europe and the U.S. on November 18 and in Tokyo a day later.</p>
<p>Sommer said that the &quot;hot phase&quot; of the sell-off had begun in earnest, with the opening of book-building and subscription period for the shares, which runs until November 14.</p>
<p>Telekom is floating 500 million shares as part of the global flotation and banks have the option to exercise a &quot;greenshoe&quot;, or over-allotment, offering of 75 million additional shares.</p>
<p>After the first tranche, Telekom will be worth up to an estimated 75 billion marks ($48.95 billion), based on a price range for the share, which has been put at between 25 and 30 marks per share.</p>
<p>The German government will remain Telekom's majority holder until the end of the century.</p>
<p>Global coordinators for the flotation -- Deutsche Bank, Dresdner Bank and Goldman Sachs -- as well as other banks in the syndicate have met with international investors, and the feedback has been positive, Telekom said.</p>
<p>Summer said that many experts reckoned the flotation could be oversubscribed, given the interest from the institutions, combined with the enthusiastic reaction of private investors.</p>
<p>Around 50 percent of those registered to buy Telekom shares currently have no equity holdings. Around half are between the ages of 35 and 59 years-of-age, while 85 percent of those signed up are male.</p>
<p>Private investors must buy a minimum of 100 shares and Telekom's discounts will apply to up to 300 shares.</p>
<p>Accountants Price Waterhouse will monitor the flotation to ensure that individual investors do not get more than their allowed allocation of shares.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom's chief financial officer, Joachim Kroeske, said he thought two-thirds of the total demand for Telekom shares would come from Germany, with 13-18 percent coming from North and South America.</p>
<p>Kroeske said he thought eight to 12 percent would come from Britain, five to eight percent from the rest of Europe and the same percentage from Asia and the rest of the world.</p>
<p>($1=1.5323 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
