<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134913" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FOCUS-Dim note from Enso as profit falls.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Dim note from Enso as profit falls.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland's second-largest forestry group Enso Oy on Tuesday said full-year earnings would be satisfactory after profit fell sharply in January-August, but sounded a fairly glum note overall.</p>
<p>Enso reported profit after financial items down to 1.16 billion markka ($252.9 million) from 2.68 billion a year-ago on slightly lower net sales at 17.20 billion against 18.92 billion, and said it expected to make a profit in the last four months.</p>
<p>The result was fractionally below analysts' forecasts for a profit around 1.17 billion, and in line with retreating profits reported by Enso's rivals last week as demand has been hit by a combination of high customer stocks and slower growth.</p>
<p>Markets will pick up in the long term, but the recovery will be slow and the risk of setbacks exists, said Enso chief executive Jukka Harmala.</p>
<p>&quot;For a number of products, it is very difficult to see any rapid and steady improvement,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Europe's biggest forestry firm UPM-Kymmene Oy, which last week reported a 41 percent slide in profits, was last week equally hesitant in its outlook, after forestry firms last year were helped by economic recovery to record profits.</p>
<p>&quot;Entering the autumn, the market has not improved in line with expectations,&quot; Enso said. &quot;Although economic growth has started to pick up in Western Europe, the impact on the forest industry is being felt more slowly than anticipated.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Uncertainty over the prices for market pulp and newsprint could make the market difficult. Because of new production capacity, some of which is already in use, it is taking longer to restore the market to balance,&quot; the company added.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospects for the financial result for the rest of the year are not as bright as they appeared to be in the spring,&quot; said the company, echoing its own earlier warnings and uncertainty on prospects from its rivals.</p>
<p>Enso did say it expected market pulp prices -- the raw material for some paper grades and a leading indicator in the forestry cycle -- to firm in the last few months of the year.</p>
<p>Pulp prices nudged ahead earlier this year after slumping from last year's record levels, but gains have been tentative.</p>
<p>But even there, Harmala sounded an uncertain note.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot rule out the possibility that the market could take another turn lower,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Enso said its sales of market pulp fell 31 percent in the period to 1.15 billion markka, and its two units made operating losses although prices strengthened in June and July.</p>
<p>The outlook for publication papers was uncertain due to European imports of cheaper North American newsprint, he said. Analysts expect newsprint prices to fall next year.</p>
<p>The fine paper market was growing quite well and Enso was hoping to implement another price hike later this year after an increase of about 10 percent earlier this autumn, he said.</p>
<p>Yet there too, he warned of the possible negative impact of capacity increases due to come on stream.</p>
<p>($ = 4.586 Finnish Markka)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
