<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134909" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek equities rebound, end with mild gains.</title>
<headline>Greek equities rebound, end with mild gains.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities rebounded following Monday's sharp fall and closed with mild gains, off the session's high of 920.6 points. Turnover picked up to 8.34 billion drachmas, boosted by block trades in Ergobank.</p>
<p>On Monday brokers attributed the fall to a bearish market climate because of an uninspiring macro-environment, lack of cash inflows and feared tax measures with the 1997 budget next month which may hit investor pockets.</p>
<p>&quot;On the macroeconomic front, it is quite likely to see inflation stuck above 8.0 percent until year end. This strengthens an outlook of stable interest rates and is not boosting market psychology,&quot; said analyst Emmanuel Varsos at Investment Analysis.</p>
<p>&quot;Also the mandatory revaluation of fixed assets for listed firms could turn out an unpleasant surprise if tax rates on the capital gains rise to 5-8 percent from 1.0 percent previously,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This could have an impact on the liquidity of banks and heavy industrials and has not been discounted by the market Investment Analysis noted in its weekly outlook.  </p>
<p>Varsos also attributed the market's recent slide to law 2396/96 which outlines the general framework governing the activities of firms offering investment services in Greece, harmonising Greek law with European Union legislation.</p>
<p>It has sparked selling as players were forced to close out long margin positions, he said.</p>
<p>The market was waiting to see how National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou would shape the 1997 draft budget, due by end-November. He meets Prime Minister Costas Simitis on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index closed up 0.49 percent, or 4.48 points higher at 918.46 from Monday's 913.98 close after opening at 914.33 points.</p>
<p>Turnover rose to 8.34 billion drachmas from 6.04 billion on Monday on volume of 4.4 million shares boosted by block trades in Ergo Bank.</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 115 to 96 with 28 issues unchanged on 239 traded. Banks gained 0.88 percent, industrials firmed 0.39 percent with construction rising 0.59 percent after plunging 4.43 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>Small-caps regained composure closing with gains of 0.11 percent after tumbling 4.02 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas closed lower at 538-556. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, ended down 10 drachmas at 4,050.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares ended higher at 162.40-170.90 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It closed in-the- money at 1005.1</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six bank stocks was quoted higher at $9.07-$10.07. The strike price is set at $99.6 and the warrants expire October 8 1997.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted higher at 3,899-4,144 drachmas at the close. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
