<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134994" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada auto union and GM to continue talking.</title>
<headline>Canada auto union and GM to continue talking.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Auto Workers union president Buzz Hargrove told reporters on Tuesday that no deal was imminent to end the strike of 26,000 auto workers, but he vowed to keep on trying to reach a pact.</p>
<p>Hargrove said talks were to continue, but he maintained no deal could be reached until the union executive met with local union representatives at 0800 EDT/1200 EDT on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're just going to keep pushing it and I told them to be back here for eight o'clock,&quot; Hargrove said.</p>
<p>After a weekend of bargaining, the two sides had hoped to reach a new deal on Monday to end the nearly three-week-old strike that has shutdown plants in Canada as well as the United States and Mexico.</p>
<p>Hargrove said they made good progress on a number of issues, including the major stumbling block of contracting out.</p>
<p>But the two sides hit a snag over mandatory overtime at two car assembly plants in Oshawa, Ontario which employ about 6,500 members.</p>
<p>Oshawa local 222 officials said earlier their members wanted mandatory overtime abolished but the world's largest automaker was insistent that it be allowed to expand the scope of mandatory overtime.</p>
<p>In the previous collective agreement, the company had the right to require workers to work an extra hour, two days a week and six hours on a Saturday. The company was not allowed to exceed a 48-hour work week, however.</p>
<p>--Reuters Toronto bureau 416-941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
