<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134969" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares dive 2.2 pct in major profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares dive 2.2 pct in major profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares fell sharply in consolidation on Tuesday following the recent sharp gains, but recovered slightly on fresh support, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 ended at 81,504.41, down 1,796.55 points, or 2.16 percent from Monday's all-time high close of 83,300.96. Trade volume plunged to 17.30 trillion lira ($181.5 million) from Monday's record high 28.83 trillion ($302.5 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Today's profit-taking was a normal technical development and it may continue tomorrow. If the index falls some more, it may touch 78,000 levels before turning up again,&quot; said Murat Emrali from Eczacibasi securities.</p>
<p>Brokers expect selective demand to be fuelled by nine-month profit prospects in coming days. Companies have to release their nine-month financial reports by October 25 the latest and banks by November 8.</p>
<p>The index had surged 28.6 percent from September 13 to Monday, breaking nine record closes in the strong medium-term uptrend which began with the breaching of 65,000 barrier.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
