<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134946" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel says Germany recovering, on course for Euro.</title>
<headline>Waigel says Germany recovering, on course for Euro.</headline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel said on Tuesday that Germany's economy was recovering and, despite a setback over tax policy, Bonn would still qualify for European monetary union.</p>
<p>Confirming latest government forecasts, Waigel said the German economy would grow by &quot;somewhat over one percent&quot; this year and by over two percent in 1998.</p>
<p>Speaking at the annual party conference of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), Waigel also confirmed that Germany's budget deficit would shrink to 2.5 percent of gross domestic product next year and two percent in 1998.</p>
<p>Waigel, who heads the CDU's Bavarian sister-party the Christian Social Union (CSU), made a fighting speech after his tax policies were blocked last week by the opposition Social Democrats (SPD). The three-party Kohl coalition flirted with collapse on finding ways to shore up 1997 finances.</p>
<p>He singled out the SPD -- which can veto tax legislation through its majority in the Bundesrat upper house of parliament -- for pursuing wrecking tactics without offering any of their own policies.</p>
<p>&quot;In the Bundestag (lower house) they complain about high debt and in the Bundesrat they prevent budget consolidation,&quot; Waigel said. &quot;That is politically phoney.&quot;</p>
<p>Waigel's wide-ranging speech gave few clues as to how the Kohl coalition would handle the question of a major tax reform planned for 1999 beyond repeating a call for cuts in income tax rates, to be partly offset by scrapping tax breaks.</p>
<p>Waigel said he supported a cut in the top rate of income tax to 35 percent from 53 percent, while the entry rate should fall to around 20 percent.</p>
<p>But he warned that the tax cuts would have to keep Germany within the Maastricht deficit limits. Maastricht sets a reference level of three percent of gross domestic product for deficits.</p>
<p>He said that he could not demand consolidation from other European countries -- which Waigel wants enforced through a so-called stability pact -- if Germany did not control its own borrowing.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't go to Europe and demand that others observe the stability pact if I can't stick to it myself,&quot; Waigel said.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-2609750</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
