<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134944" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Enso CEO sees slow forestry recovery.</title>
<headline>Enso CEO sees slow forestry recovery.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The markets for forest industry products will pick up in the long term, but the recovery will be slow and the risk of setbacks exists, Finnish forestry group Enso Oy chief executive Jukka Harmala said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;For a number of products, it is very difficult to see any rapid and steady improvement,&quot; Harmala told Reuters.</p>
<p>Prospects for pulp, a leading indicator in the forestry cycle, were expected to remain volatile, although pulp prices were expected to turn higher in the long term, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot rule out the possibility that the market could take another turn lower,&quot; Harmala told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;(Pulp) inventories are still high worldwide ... capacity utilisation will determine what will happen,&quot; he said, putting the current softwood pulp market price at some $580 per tonne.</p>
<p>Fine paper volumes had increased favourably since summer and Enso was hoping to implement another price hike later this year after an increase of about 10 percent earlier this autumn, Harmala said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market itself (for fine paper) is growing quite well, but capacity increases ... will come on stream,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Of Enso's other main products, the liquid packaging board market was expected to remain good, but the outlook for publication papers was uncertain due to imports to Europe of cheaper North American newsprint, Harmala said.</p>
<p>Enso earlier published its January-August report showing a 1.16 billion markka profit after financial items, down from 2.68 billion in the first eight months of 1995.</p>
<p>--Ilkka Virtanen, Helsinki newsroom +358-9-6805 0248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
