<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134940" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Daimler to decide restructuring in early 97.</title>
<headline>Daimler to decide restructuring in early 97.</headline>
<dateline>STUTTGART 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German industrial group Daimler-Benz AG plans to decide on a massive restructuring plan at a supervisory board meeting in early 1997, the company said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The board wants to consider the management structure more intensively over the next few weeks,&quot; Daimler said.</p>
<p>Daimler-Benz, Germany's largest industrial company, has been considering a reorganisation for some months as part of its efforts to make individual operating units more profitable.  </p>
<p>The reorganisation has caused turmoil within the Daimler group. According to local media, Mercedes-Benz AG chairman Helmut Werner had threatened to resign if his car and truck unit were more closely integrated in the new structure.</p>
<p>Industry sources said on Monday that Daimler chairman Juergen Schrempp had gone as far as to offer Werner the post of chairman of a restructured Daimler in order to keep the Mercedes chief within the group.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody wants to keep Werner in the company,&quot; one source said on Monday.</p>
<p>Werner's contract as management board member of Daimler, which expires at the end of 1997, is up for renewal at a supervisory board meeting on November 6. His contract at Mercedes runs until 1999.</p>
<p>But Daimler said on Tuesday that it would not decide any personnel moves on November 6.</p>
<p>According to newspaper reports over the weekend, Schrempp planed to integrate Mercedes with the parent company as part of his plans to return Daimler to its transportation roots.</p>
<p>Mercedes, which now makes up around three-quarters of Daimler's group revenues, has predicted its 1996 profits will be &quot;clearly&quot; higher than last year's 2.275 billion marks ($1.5 billion) profit. ($ = 1.533 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
