<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134904" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Waigel won't take all the heat in German tax rows.</title>
<headline>Waigel won't take all the heat in German tax rows.</headline>
<byline>Tom Heneghan</byline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel on Tuesday hailed radical tax reform plans proposed by Germany's Christian Democrats (CDU) but warned he would not fight alone for the spending cuts needed to finance them.</p>
<p>Waigel, chairman of the CDU's Bavarian sister party, told the CDU annual congress the plan to slash top tax rates from 53 to 35 percent was &quot;just the right thing&quot; to help assure Germany remained internationally competitive in future.</p>
<p>But Waigel, who took the heat last week in a tax feud with Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Free Democrat (FDP) coalition partners, reminded the CDU rank and file they must now be as keen about slashing popular subsidies and tax loopholes.</p>
<p>&quot;These are damned tough times and we have to tackle them together,&quot; he said before the congress began debating the resolution on tax reform Bonn plans to pass next year.</p>
<p>&quot;There can't be two different roles in the coalition, with one side doing the dirty work in the quarry while the other side sells the marble,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>Kohl's centre-right coalition flirted with collapse last week when Waigel and the FDP bitterly locked horns over ways to find a few billion marks more for the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>That uproar was just a foretaste of the problems Kohl could face when Bonn starts hacking through a jungle of long-standing state subsidies and tax breaks to help finance the tax reform expected to reduce Bonn's revenues by 30 billion marks ($19.50 billion).</p>
<p>Under the reform planned to take effect in 1999, top rates would drop from 53 to around 35 percent while the starting rate would fall from 25.9 to under 20 percent.  Cutting out many of the myriad exemptions in Germany's confusing tax laws would expand the base and make up for part of the revenue shortfall.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, the CDU parliamentary leader and Kohl's unofficial crown prince, also warned the 1,000 delegates at the congress about the rough road ahead once they went from talking tax reform to actually working out the details.</p>
<p>&quot;Every tax break we cut will provoke an outcry from those who are affected,&quot; he said. &quot;Vested interests will pull out all the stops to keep their exemptions. Some allies who at first patted us on the shoulder will quietly steal away.&quot;</p>
<p>Like Kohl on Monday, both Waigel and Schaeuble attacked the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) for using their majority in the parliament's upper house last week to block Bonn's plan to delay a promised increase in child benefit payments that Waigel said he could not finance.</p>
<p>That led to the showdown with the liberal FDP, which had to cave in and let Waigel put off a planned cut in the hated solidarity tax levied to help rebuild eastern Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;In the lower house they complain about high debt and in the upper house they prevent budget consolidation,&quot; Waigel said of SPD parliamentarians. &quot;That is politically phoney.&quot;</p>
<p>But neither speaker ventured an opinion about exactly which subsidies or loopholes would have to go.</p>
<p>In the tax reform resolution due to be passed later on Tuesday, the CDU said: &quot;German tax law is too complicated and has thus become injust.&quot;</p>
<p>It said the lower tax rates could be levied in a few stages or progressively and proposed to treat all income equally, including the many extra payments -- now tax-free -- that workers get for working nights, on Sundays or on holidays.</p>
<p>&quot;With such low tax rates, we can do without most exemptions and tax breaks,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
