<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134968" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Weak figures cast doubt on Japan economic strength.</title>
<headline>Weak figures cast doubt on Japan economic strength.</headline>
<byline>Tsukasa Maekawa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weak economic data released Tuesday cast doubt on the strength of the Japanese economy and pointed to a need for the new government to come up with tonic to energise a feeble recovery, analysts said.</p>
<p>The government's Economic Planning Agency said its closely watched diffusion index of leading economic indicators for August fell below the so-called &quot;boom or bust&quot; 50 mark for the first time in five months.</p>
<p>The index is closely watched as a barometer of economic trends and compiled from a host of indicators that include job figures and money supply. A figure below 50 is generally taken as suggesting the economy could contract in the coming six months, while a figure above 50 suggests it will expand.</p>
<p>&quot;The leading indicators suggest we have little confidence in the economy overall. The government and the Bank of Japan have to think about something new to stimulate the economy,&quot; said Yuichi Matsushita, a senior strategist at Nikko Research Centre.</p>
<p>A senior EPA official said the drop was caused by temporary factors such as sluggish consumption in the summer and fewer workdays in August, adding: &quot;The index is likely to regain a level of above 50 in September.&quot;</p>
<p>The official said a temporary cut in output of cars and personal computers and production adjustment in semiconductors pushed down production-related indices, which are components of the leading index.</p>
<p>Just two days after Sunday's general election, which had put government debate on economic polices on hold, Japan's Trade Minister Shunpei Tsukahara called for additional fiscal measures to stimulate the economy in the form of increased public works spending.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally want the government to consider a large-scale supplementary budget to stimulate Japan's economy,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's Liberal Democratic Party secured 239 seats in Sunday's voting, 12 short of the 251 it needed to govern alone in the 500-seat Lower House.</p>
<p>A new government led by Hashimoto is expected to be formed in early November after the LDP succeeds in luring other parties to join a coalition government.</p>
<p>Hashimoto has been cautious about increasing fiscal spending, given a snowballing state budget deficit that has become one of the worst in major nations.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm afraid that given the fiscal state at the moment, it is unlikely that we will get a large boost for the economy from the public sector,&quot; said Yasushi Okuda, an economist at BZW Securities (Japan) Ltd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
