<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="134986" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Punters, local funds drive Bombay shares higher.</title>
<headline>Punters, local funds drive Bombay shares higher.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices held smart gains at close on Tuesday as sentiment improved after the weekend's new credit policy which released impounded bank funds, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sentiment got a shot in the arm,&quot; said Bharat Dhanki at broking firm Vrajlal Dhanki. &quot;The credit policy was very good.&quot;</p>
<p>As part of its monetary policy for the second half of 1996/97 (April-March), the central bank on Saturday cut reserve requirements for banks and reduced the interest cap on short-term deposits which sparked cuts in prime lending rates.</p>
<p>The 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index rose 98.75 points, or 3.15 percent, to a provisional 3,228.96.</p>
<p>The 50-stock National Stock Exchange (NSE) ended 28.32 points, or 3.16 percent, higher at a provisional 923.32.</p>
<p>The bourses were closed on Monday for a national holiday.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was driven up by local punters and mutual funds. Foreign institutions booked profit in some stocks but bought into state-run firms and other blue-chip stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;There was heavy buying in index-linked stocks,&quot; Dhanki said. &quot;It was a trader's market.&quot;</p>
<p>He said investment demand was largely limited to purchases by domestic funds.</p>
<p>SBI and Reliance rallied 10 rupees each, to 228.75 and 206.75 respectively. Bajaj Auto rose 32.50 rupees to 971.50, Indian Hotels 27.75 to 631.25, L&amp;T 19.0 to 234, Grasim 16.5 to 432.25, TELCO 8.0 to 430 and TISCO 2.75 to 175.25 at the BSE.</p>
<p>Analysts expect the upsurge to push the BSE index up by another 100 points but see resistance building up.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this (the rally) will be sustained,&quot; Amish Choksi at broker Nalinkant Dalal said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to wait for the (half-year company) results. These are not going to be very good.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
