<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135070" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>CLAIMS JOBS COMMITTEE WILL REDUCE UNEMPLOYMENT</p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello says the government's creation of a Cabinet committee on jobs will provide a strategy for economic and employment growth.</p>
<p>Mr Costello says it's a matter of applying good economics which will provide good job prospects.</p>
<p>He says once there's sustainable growth in the economy, sustainable increased employment will follow.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Mr Costello is predicting an unemployment rate at the budget forecast of eight-and-a-quarter per cent by the end of the financial year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WESTPAC SHARES SOAR AFTER BUY UP</p>
<p>A large buy up of preference shares has seen a soaring in the value of shares in the Westpac Bank.</p>
<p>There's speculation about the strategic manoeuvering on the Westpac share register, with large volumes of preferential shares being purchased by an unidentified buyer yesterday and today.</p>
<p>It's thought the buy up could be to acquire a blocking stake in the event of Westpac and another major bank striking up a scheme of arrangement.</p>
<p>Prudential-Bache Securities says a scheme would depend on a change of government policy following the recommendations of the Wallis Inquiry into the financial system.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ACID WATER LEADS TO STOP WORK ORDER</p>
<p>Conservationists claim a stop-work order has been issued on the site of Keith Williams' Port Hinchinbrook development after the detection of dangerous acid levels in the water.</p>
<p>The North Queensland Conservation Council says tests conducted by it and the Environment Department found acid contamination in waters near the site reached a PH of 4.5.</p>
<p>The Council's Margaret Moorhouse, says a Site Supervisor appointed by the Department of Environment has ordered work to stop until the developer addresses the problem.</p>
<p>Ms Moorhouse says the developer is now supposed to present an acid sulphate management plan, which requires the acid water be contained and not just released into the channel.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>DOWNER CONGRATULATES WINNERS IN UN SECURITY COUNCIL</p>
<p>Australia's UN Ambassador Richard Butler says Australia had good faith commitments for 40 per cent more votes than it received for membership of the United Nations Security Council. Australia lost to Portugal and Sweden in the contest for the two vacancies on the Security Council.</p>
<p>Mr Butler says the good faith commitments were meant at the time, but some competitors made promises or threats of withdrawal of co-operation to countries in parts of the world where Australia has less influence.</p>
<p>He says there've been allegations of vote-buying, including reports in the London Financial Times that Portugal paid U-N dues for some countries which would otherwise have been unable to vote.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Foreign Minister Alexander Downer has congratulated Sweden and Portugal, but says he doesn't believe the campaign could have been run better.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MEAT INSEPCTORS WALK OFF</p>
<p>Meat inspectors across the nation walked off the job this morning to discuss Federal Government plans to push towards company-based meat inspection.</p>
<p>Claire Moore from the Community and Public Sector Union, says the national reform agenda is talking about self regulation of the industry which she says will mean massive loss of jobs.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>NCA &quot;PLOT&quot; QUESTIONING</p>
<p>The National Crime Authority Chairman, John Broome, has faced intense questioning at a parliamentary hearing into the crime body.</p>
<p>Mr Broome was asked numerous times if, as suggested in a newspaper article, he believed there was a plot to abolish the NCA.</p>
<p>Western Australian Independent, Paul Filing, who's on the committee, said it was more than coincidental that the article appeared in yesterday's Age newspaper, ahead of today's hearing. But Mr Broome told the hearing he never used the word &quot;plot&quot;, blaming newspaper subbing for the headline.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CONFLICTING TESTIMONY IN BLACKHAWK INQUIRY</p>
<p>The Military Board of Inquiry hearing evidence in Townsville on the blackhawk helicopter disaster has heard from a corporal who was on one of the helicopters the night of the accident.</p>
<p>Corporal Karl Schmid was a loadmaster on Blackhawk three, and says soldiers had practiced the counter-terrorist exercise on the day of the crash.</p>
<p>But he said after the trial run the SAS had requested if the approach could be changed.</p>
<p>In his statement Corporal Schmid said that had been agreed to and later ordered, conflicting with the testimony yesterday of a co-pilot on the same aircraft who said the changes had been rejected.</p>
<p>Corporal Schmid was unsure about the fact when questioned.</p>
<p>He also said aircrew had not flown that kind of formation previously, and had not practiced flying three helicopters abreast.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WOMAN SEEKING DAMAGES FOR BEING REFUSED FERTILITY HELP</p>
<p>A woman who claims she was refused help at a fertility clinic because she was a lesbian, is seeking damages from the Queensland Government and doctors at the clinic.</p>
<p>The hearing at the Queensland Anti-Discrimination Tribunal is believed to be the first such case in Australia.</p>
<p>The Tribunal has been told there are no specific guidelines in Australia dealing with donor artificial insemination.</p>
<p>The woman later became pregnant through private donor insemination with the help of her partner.</p>
<p>In the witness box, the state's chief health officer, Doctor Dianna Lange, said doctors use ethical guidelines to treat infertility, but the guidelines had no legal standing.</p>
<p>Doctor Lange said new guidelines dealing with the issue should be released in 18 months to two years.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FOREIGN DOCTORS PLAN CRITICISED</p>
<p>Ethnic groups have slammed a proposal to impose quotas on foreign doctors, describing it as an ill-thought-out plan to save money.</p>
<p>Federal Cabinet is to be asked to further reduce the number of foreign doctors allowed to practice in Australia, on top of limiting the number of general practitioners by reducing access to Medicare provider numbers.</p>
<p>The New South Wales Ethnic Communities Council says there are better ways of dealing with the perceived oversupply of doctors in urban areas, including restricting the 14-hundred temporary visas handed out each year.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SUICIDE UP, BUT SLOWING</p>
<p>New figures on suicide reveal that although suicide rates have risen, the increase is slowing.</p>
<p>The Health and Welfare Institute figures show that seven percent more people killed themselves in 1994 that in the previous year.</p>
<p>Suicide rates were highest for men aged 20 to 29 years, and highest for women aged 35 to 39.</p>
<p>Overall, men were four times more likely to commit suicide than women.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
