<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135068" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ yields end lower again as rally keeps momentum.</title>
<headline>NZ yields end lower again as rally keeps momentum.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Market has little present fear of Reserve Bank</p>
<p>New Zealand debt market yields fell sharply again on Tuesday, underpinned by a currency which broke through 71 U.S. cents for the first time in over eight years.</p>
<p>The 90-day bank bills gapped down at the start of trade after the currency swung higher overnight and they ended 22 basis points lower at 9.26 percent.</p>
<p>They are now well below the 9.45 percent level they were at when the Reserve Bank made its comment last week that there was no scope for further easing.  </p>
<p>But dealers figured that since then inflation-related data -- new dwellings, unemployment and retail sales -- had all been weak and the currency had jumped over 120 basis points, so there was little to fear from the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The Reserve Bank will be very reluctant to say anything because they screwed up last week,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>He noted that any move to slow the slide in yields by the Reserve Bank would only further underpin the currency and encourage exporters to scream about their pain more loudly than at present.  </p>
<p>One chief dealer said there was no mood to fight the trend and he sees no immediate prospect of a correction.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the 90-days could go another 40-50 basis points,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Continued interest in euro and samurai issues was also showing no sign of slowing, dealers said.</p>
<p>There was further strong interest today from offshore in the mid part of the curve.  </p>
<p>Spreads against North American and Australian bonds narrowed dramatically and a continued narrowing of the spread is likely to be one dampening factor in the local rally.</p>
<p>---------------------------(SPREADS)----------------------------</p>
<p>NZD VS	  3 YR	 10 YR	  * NZD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p>USD	   119 (-18)    77 (-23)     * FUTURES   -15 (-11)</p>
<p>CAD	   241 (-17)    83 (-13)     * PHYSICALS -7   (+5)</p>
<p>AUD	    36 (-21)   -25 (-14)</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Simon Louisson 64 4 4714 276</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
