<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135087" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia enterprise bargains moderate - ACIRRT.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia enterprise bargains moderate - ACIRRT.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pace of growth in Australian enterprise bargainig agreements, identified last week as a key concern of the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA), has moderated in the June quarter, a study has found.</p>
<p>The average annual wage increase for enterprise bargaining agreements registered in the June quarter was 6.1 percent, down from 6.5 percent for agreements in the March quarter, the Australian Centre for Industrial Relations Research and Training (ACCIRT) said in a report released on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Given that agreements-based wage increase only affect above a third of the workforce this development highlights the importance of not placing too much blame on the collective bargaining sector for wage pressure,&quot; ACIRRT said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Other sectors are contributing just as much, if not more, pressure on inflation.&quot;</p>
<p>The average annual wage increase in all current agreements on ACIRRT's database was 5.7 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Mining and construction continue to contain the highest wage increases, 8.3 percent, and recreational services the lowest increases, 3.3 percent,&quot; ACIRRT said.</p>
<p>Last week, the RBA said the pace of growth in new enterprise agreements was not reflecting the moderation in wages or the low inflation enviroment.</p>
<p>&quot;The moderation in economy-wide wages growth is not yet evident in new enterprise bargains, raising concerns that wages growth might accelerate when labour market conditions begin to tighten,&quot; the RBA said in its quarterly report on the economy contained in the October Bulletin.  </p>
<p>The RBA also said enterprise bargains, a forward-looking indicator of wages growth, &quot;are running at over five percent, with no signs of deceleration&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Sustaining low inflation as employment gathers strength will require moderation in wage demands, especially in new enterprise agreements,&quot; the RBA said in the Bulletin.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
