<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135066" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian bonds stay on short leash pre-CPI.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian bonds stay on short leash pre-CPI.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------(Snapshot at 4.31 P.M./0635 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (DEC) 93.41  (- 0.01)    6.79    (UNCH)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (DEC) 93.10  (UNCH)	6.86    (UNCH)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (DEC) 92.485 (+0.010)    7.53    (- 0.01)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7955 (PREV 0.7970) US 30-YR  6.81   (6.81 NY)</p>
<p>---------------------(Oct 22)-------------------------------</p>
<p>*The Australian 10-year bond yield continued to buffet against 7.50 percent as tension mounted ahead of Wednesday's CPI, the first of the big data releases in the next two days.</p>
<p>*Thursday's wages data needs to be weak to sustain rally.  </p>
<p>The Australian 10-year bond yield continued to buffet against 7.50 percent with the market held to a fairly short leash ahead of Wednesday's CPI, the first of the big data releases in the next two days.</p>
<p>However, turnover was relatively light as tension mounted before what is generally expected to be market friendly news, although a sustained rally at current low yield levels is likely to hinge on the the outcome of Thursday's wages data.</p>
<p>Forecasts centre on a quarterly headline CPI rise of just 0.3 percent, bringing the year-on-year rate of 2.5 percent, according to a Reuters survey of economists.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the policy-sensitive underlying inflation rate is forecast at 0.6 percent up on the quarter for an annual rate of 2.5 percent and back within the RBA's 2.0-3.0 percent target.</p>
<p>Both annual rates were at 3.1 percent in the June quarter.</p>
<p>But unless inflation proves even weaker the market could hold fire until average weekly ordinary time earnings (AWOTE), given the emphasis that the RBA has put back on wages growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The tolerance levels on average weekly earnings is pretty specific...0.9 to 1.0 percent is just about on the boundary of being OK. Buy 1.1 to 1.2 and you get into difficult territory,&quot; said Stephen Roberts, chief economist at UBS Australia.  </p>
<p>Median forecasts centre on a 1.0 percent rise in quarterly AWOTE for an annual growth rate of 3.7 percent and below the RBA's perceived comfort zone of around 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>The local market got off on a softer footing following an easier close in U.S. Treasuries, but comments by Treasurer Peter Costello, and later reiterated by Prime Minister John Howard, that the government was sticking to its unemployment projections returned the bid tone.</p>
<p>In the August budget the government forecast unemployment at an average 8.5 percent for the fiscal year, a level seen by the market as providing scope for a monetary policy easing.  </p>
<p>------------------------(SPREADS)-------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 83 (- 01)   103 (- 01) * FUTURES   61.5 (- 01.5)</p>
<p> CAD	204 (+ 09)   108 (+ 07) * CASH	67   (UNCH)</p>
<p> NZD	-36 (+ 19)   +24 (+ 15) *</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Yield spreads to the U.S. narrowed slightly but continued to find resistance at 100 basis points on the 10-year differential. Rate cut speculation in Canada ahead of its CPI today saw margins widen, and local bonds also underperformed N.Z. bonds again, which charged ahead as the N.Z. dollar remained robust.  </p>
<p>----------------------(TECHNICALS)---------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*DAY'S HILO  *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (DEC)*92.49-92.45 *92.44-92.50 *65 PCT *92.40 *92.34</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (DEC)*93.12-93.07 *93.07-93.16 *62 PCT *93.08 *93.03</p>
<p>90-DAY  (DEC)*93.42-93.39 *93.40-93.43 *53 PCT *93.44 *93.43</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The 10-year bond contract continues to find resistance at 92.500, but weak data in the next couple of days could see this and the 92.560 30-month high seen in SYCOM on October 4 taken out, traders added.</p>
<p>--Colin Brinsden 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
