<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135078" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-INTERVIEW-Australian insurers set for growth.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INTERVIEW-Australian insurers set for growth.</headline>
<byline>Graeme James</byline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's insurance industry is set for further international growth in the next decade as local groups set their sights on expanding Asian markets, the National Insurance Brokers Association (NIBA) said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our industry is in good shape. We've come of age and Australia is poised in the next decade for Asian expansion,&quot; NIBA executive director Noel Pettersen said in an interview.  </p>
<p>Pettersen, who is also chairman of the council of International Insurance Broker Associations, said the global insurance industry now regards Australia as an efficient growth market.</p>
<p>&quot;It will also attract a lot of global players,&quot; he said at the close of a NIBA convention on Queensland's Gold Coast.</p>
<p>The NIBA convention, which was attended by senior insurance executives from the United States, United Kingdom, Hong Kong, Singapore, India, Malaysia, New Zealand and Fiji, expressed positive views on the global industry's long-term outlook, Pettersen said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Globally, the insurance market at present is soft with rates coming down and the competition tough,&quot; Pettersen said.</p>
<p>Australia's industry had been rationalised and would see further rationalisation, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a regulated industry and downsizing has seen six thousand brokers nationally in 1985 now numbering one thousand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Pettersen said it was hard to predict the outcome of the government's Wallis enquiry into financial regulation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to say how the Wallis enquiry will turn out (for insurers),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our submission has been to seek the status quo,&quot; Pettersen said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't need more regulation foisted on us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both the National Australia Bank Ltd and Colonial Mutual Holdings Ltd have submitted recommendations to the Wallis enquiry for a consolidation of all financial system supervisors under a mega-supervisor.</p>
<p>This would comprise three units including the Reserve Bank of Australia on monetary policy, the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission and a separate board for prudential supervision.  </p>
<p>Pettersen's outlook for the local industry also comes amidst massive reorganisation and demutualisation of the top insurers in the country.</p>
<p>Australia's second-biggest insurer National Mutual Holdings Ltd listed successfully this month while Colonial Mutual is planning a listing on Australian and New Zealand exchanges in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>AMP, the biggest life insurer has reported it would consider demutualisation as part of a review of its organisation. A decision is planned by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
