<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135084" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Porgera gold output down in 3rd quarter.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Porgera gold output down in 3rd quarter.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Papua New Guinea's Porgera gold mine production was 213,560 ounces for the quarter and 604,314 ounces for the nine months ended September 30, 25 percent partner Placer Pacific Ltd  said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>This compares with 263,737 ounces and 669,301 ounces in the respective corresponding periods a year ago, Placer Pacific said in a statement.</p>
<p>In March, the Porgera partners forecast calendar 1996 production at about 940,000 ounces, against 848,870 ounces in 1995.  </p>
<p>Underground ore grades averaged 11.1 grams of gold per tonne compared to 15.9 grams for the second quarter. The Porgera joint venture partners said in July they expected underground ore grades to increase in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Open pit ore grades delivered to the mill averaged 5.6 g/t, up 0.3 g/t on the second quarter.</p>
<p>A total of 13,323,182 tonnes of material were mined during the quarter, up significantly on the June quarter's 12,388,476 tonnes.</p>
<p>Mill head grade for the September quarter averaged 7.0 g/t compared to 6.2 g/t for the three months to June.</p>
<p>Mill throughput improved slightly to 1,214,373 tonnes in September from 1,204,299 in the June quarter. This was below joint venture goals and due mainly to a higher sulphur grade in the mill feed.</p>
<p>The statement said sulphur treatment capacity should increase with the arrival of custom-made feed pumps in the second quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Cash operating costs were down to $279 per ounce compared to $335 per ounce for the previous quarter, with the decrease largely due to increased gold production.</p>
<p>Exploration during the September quarter identified mineralisation in the eastern extension of the Roamane Fault Zone and in the Eastern deeps area.</p>
<p>In August the joint venture partners estimated they had increased reserves by about 35 percent.</p>
<p>They said total proved and probable reserves were estimated to be 78.7 million tonnes of ore at 4.8 g/t gold containing an estimated 11.5 million ounces of gold.</p>
<p>Porgera is owned equally by Placer Pacific, the Papua New Guinea government, Highlands Gold Ltd and Goldfields Ltd, a listed offshoot of Renison Goldfields Consolidated Ltd.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
