<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135061" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: MacMillan sees weakness extended in Q4.</title>
<headline>MacMillan sees weakness extended in Q4.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian forest products giant MacMillan Bloedel Ltd, which reported a sharp drop in profits in the third quarter, said on Monday it expected little improvement in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>MacMillan earlier said it earned C$1 million in the third quarter which translated into a loss per share of C$0.01. That compared to earnings of C$74 million, or C$0.55 a share, for the same period last year.</p>
<p>The company said it did not expect to see much improvement in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Japanese lumber markets have strengthened, seasonal weakness is anticipated in building materials demand in North America&quot;, it said.</p>
<p>Moreover, MacMillan &quot;anticipates further price deterioration in the paper sector due to continuing excess supply and weak markets&quot;.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the company said U.S. and overseas markets for linerboard had tightened, supporting the price increase of US$30 per ton announced for October 1.</p>
<p>&quot;Market conditions in the third quarter remained difficult for most of our products,&quot; said Bob Findlay, the company's chief executive officer. &quot;Our solid wood business continued to suffer from reduced sales revenues from pulp logs and chips and the lower Japanese yen has reduced profit margins from lumber operations in the Japanese market.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Paper prices declined further and containerboard markets did not improve sufficiently to turn prices around. The good news is that demand for building materials in North America remained strong ...,&quot; MacMillan said.</p>
<p>MacMillan's solid wood division saw earnings fall C$53 million in the third quarter from the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>It attributed the drop to lower sales prices for pulp logs and chips and the impact of a weaker yen on hemlock lumber sales revenues in Japan. Margins were also reduced by the costs of recently introduced provincial regulations and higher royalties.</p>
<p>MacMillan said earnings from paper fell C$19 million in the third quarter from the same period of 1995 while its packaging profits dropped C$46 million over the same time.</p>
<p>In the third quarter, &quot;prices for newsprint, groundwood specialties and lightweight coated grades continued to deteriorate due to reduced consumption and surplus inventories. Prices for standard newsprint have dropped 26 percent since the beginning of the year. Market downtime removed 32,000 tonnes from paper production in the quarter, for a total of 74,000 tonnes lost year to date&quot;, the company said.</p>
<p>MacMillan said linerboard prices, which have fallen 28 percent so far this year, stabilised during the third quarter as a result of stronger export markets and improving demand in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>Market downtime has removed 26,000 tonnes of containerboard production year to date, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
