<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135095" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Perpetual says sees profit increase.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Perpetual says sees profit increase.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Perpetual Trustees Australia Ltd is on target to live up to forecasts of a profit incrase for the current financial year, chairman John Lamble told the annual meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have budgeted for an increase in profit for this year compared to last year and I am happy to say that the results for the first three months are ahead of budget,&quot; Lamble said.</p>
<p>&quot;But there are still nine months to go and it is too early to predict the final result. Again, one can only say 'so far so good',&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Perpetual Trustees, Australia's largest trustee operation, reported a net profit of A$14.56 million for the year to June 30, up 29.4 percent on the previous year.</p>
<p>Lamble said a change of emphasis in the company's investment portfolio had resulted in realised gains of A$1.8 million and unrealised gains of A$2.5 million in the three months to September 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The results for the three months need to be qualified by the fact that our portfolio does not set out to track the All Ordinaries index, so variations, both up and down, will arise because some industries come into favour and others go out of  </p>
<p>favour,&quot; Lamble said.</p>
<p>Managing director Graham Bradley said the company's three main strategies for future growth would be to &quot;retain and strengthen each of Perpetual's three major businesses; create new business building on core competencies; and improve the value of the company&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We have also integrated our private client superannuation area with our corporsate superannuation division into one function to achieve efficiency, better coordinated market development and focussed compliance management for our total superannuation business,&quot; Bradley said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Revenues have continued to grow in our corporate and institutional services division, driven by growth in unit trust and property trust assets under management, growth in mortgage securitisation and our strong market position in both areas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Perpetual Funds Management has experienced stronger net funds inflow during the first quarter of the year than in any quarter during 1995/96,&quot; Bradley said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
