<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135099" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INP exchangeable shares to list in NZ.</title>
<headline>INP exchangeable shares to list in NZ.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Independent Press Communications Ltd (IPCL) on Tuesday declared its takeover offer for newspaper group Wilson and Horton Ltd unconditional after the New Zealand Stock Exchange approved the listing of exchangeable shares offered by IPCL as part of the bid.</p>
<p>The stock exchange board approved the listing and quotation subject to IPCL satisfying normal procedural requirements which IPCL said were reasonable.</p>
<p>IPCL chairman Michael Walls said shareholders accepting the exchangeable shares would receive certificates within seven days of valid acceptances being received.  </p>
<p>&quot;We now expect the exchangeable shares to be listed and quoted on the Stock Exchange at the latest shortly after our offfer's closing date of November 8, 1996,&quot; Walls said.</p>
<p>At close of business on Monday IPCL, a subsidiary of Independent Newspapers Plc, had acquired 15 percent of Wilson and Horton's capital, lifting the combined shareholding of IPCL and three other Independent Press companies to 60 percent.</p>
<p>IPCL is bidding for all of Wilson and Horton, offering NZ$11 or 1.375 exchangeable INP shares for each W&amp;H share.  </p>
<p>IPCL said 75 percent of acceptances were for exchangeable shares, with 15.25 of the 40 million shares available assigned to date on a &quot;first come, first served&quot; basis.</p>
<p>The stock exchange has agreed to the listing and quotation of Independent Newspapers Plc as an overseas listed issuer, IPCL said. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
