<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135092" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia sees improving Japanese wool demand.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia sees improving Japanese wool demand.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wool demand was showing signs of improvement and the Japanese market in particular was expected to be much stronger over the next year, Michael Chaney, managing director of rural group Wesfarmers Ltd, told the Australia-Japan Business Cooperation Committees meeting.</p>
<p>Wool prices had been on a downtrend for more than 12 months, with Australia's eastern market indicator dropping 35 percent to 544 Australian cents per kg in May 1996 from its peak of 843 cents in March 1995, he said.  </p>
<p>Japan, Australia's third-largest market taking nine percent of Australian wool exports (after 21 percent by China and 15 percent by Italy), was showing signs of a turnaround this year, he said.</p>
<p>Japanese retail sales were three percent higher in June compared with the previous year, while total Japanese raw wool imports in July were twice the level of the previous year, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook is for continuerd growth in demand,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The total volume of Australian wool potentially available (production, grower stocks and Wool International stockpile sales) was forecast to be 880 million kg against 827 million kg in 1995/96, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Improving demand conditions and reduced overseas stocks suggest that average wool prices will increase in the next two years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply in Australia is, however, expected to remain relatively high, restricting any significant market improvement,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Keiji Oda, senior adviser at Japanese trading group Kanematsu Corp, said Japanese wool purchases in 1995/96 were down by 23 percent to 678,000 bales on a global basis, with 437,000 bales bought from Australia.</p>
<p>Australia's share of the Japanese market contracted to 64.4 percent from 65.6 percent in 1994/95 because of structural change in the Japanese industry, he said.</p>
<p>It was not expected that Japanese wool purchases would increase significantly, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
