<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135016" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Oct 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- TELEKOM SHARES SURGE IN UNOFFICIAL MARKET</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom, the German state-owned telecommunications company which is being partially privatised in Europe's largest initial public offering, has published an official price range of between DM25 and DM30. Following publication of the range, the price of shares on the unofficial &quot;grey' market surged to DM39, and closed the day being quoted at around DM35.</p>
<p>-- CHAIRMAN OF EMAP IN STORM OVER RULE CHANGE</p>
<p>The media group Emap is facing a boardroom split over a rule change governing the removal of directors. A meeting called for Wednesday will discuss the conflict which could lead to the dismissal of chairman Sir John Hoskyns. The row centres on undertakings given by Sir John to shareholders over new procedures for removing directors.</p>
<p>-- HOUSING SHORTAGE GIVES &quot;FALSE PICTURE OF PROPERTY BOOM'</p>
<p>A survey of over 100 estate agents has revealed a dearth of available housing, with the number of homes for sale at its lowest for eight years. The shortages are worst in southern England, where some of the largest house price increases have occurred in the south-east region. The Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors, which carried out the survey, said that some homeowners are delaying putting their properties on the market because they have unrealistic expectations of further price rises.</p>
<p>-- CLARKE SEEKS TO IMPROVE PRIVATE FINANCE INITIATIVE</p>
<p>Chancellor Kenneth Clarke has signalled the Government's determination to back the private finance initiative (PFI) with a pledge to &quot;forge an alliance for progress' between the Treasury and the Confederation of British Industry. Under the PFI the private sector builds, finances and operates projects, but this year it is set to fall short of the 1.9bn stg target the government had hoped for.</p>
<p>-- BRITONS &quot;UNABLE TO ACCESS NEW TECHNOLOGIES'</p>
<p>A Mori survey commissioned by the electronics group Motorola has revealed that people in Britain are eager to incorporate new technologies such as smartcards and on-line services into their everyday lives, but that lack of access is holding them back. The survey found that while 36 per cent of the 1,037 people sampled have a personal computer at home, 56 per cent said they expect to own one by the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- MEDICINES R&amp;D &quot;SET FOR 2BN STERLING RECORD'</p>
<p>A survey from the Surrey-based Centre for Medicines Research claims that spending on research and development in the UK by pharmaceuticals companies is set to reach a record 2 billion stg this year. The survey claims that the greatest growth in R&amp;D has come from companies like SmithKline Beecham  and Zeneca which have not been involved in mergers or takeovers in the past few years.</p>
<p>-- BA SCRAPS PLAN FOR MID EAST FRANCHISE</p>
<p>British Airways has dropped plans to franchise out the running of loss-making flights to Beirut, Amman and Damascus to the independent carrier British Mediterranean. Under the proposed franchise, British Mediterranean, which already runs its own flights to cities, would operate former BA services still using BA's livery.</p>
<p>-- VIDEOTRON BID BATTLE NEARS CLIMAX</p>
<p>A number of telecoms companies are understood to still be vying to take over Videotron, the UK's seventh-largest cable television company. Deutsche Telekom and the US cable group CableTel are understood to be interested, but British telecoms group Cable and Wireless remains favourite to take control in a deal expected to be worth about 700m stg.</p>
<p>-- IBM MATCHES TOP FORECASTS WITH $1.28bn EARNINGS</p>
<p>Computer group IBM has reported an 8 per cent rise in revenues for the third quarter, up to $18.1bn from $16.7bn for the same period last year. Announcing the strong third-quarter growth, IBM also revealed a global initiative to expand it sales to businesses with less than 1000 employees. Three quarters of IBM's business is accounted for by about 1000 large customers. For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742 END</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
