<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135089" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Mosaic to take 100 pct of PNG permit.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Mosaic to take 100 pct of PNG permit.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mosaic Oil NL said on Tuesday it had elected to take up a 100 percent stake in Papua New Guinea (PNG) oil exploration permit PPL 163 following the withdrawal of Kerr McGee Corp and Phillips Petroleum Co.</p>
<p>&quot;Directors advise that there is significant interest in this most prospective permit from major oil companies wishing to farm in to PPL 163 and will now work diligently to ensure drilling in the licence,&quot; Mosaic told the Australian Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>&quot;Mosaic Oil NL will initiate as soon as possible discussions with interested parties on potentially drillable prospects such as Kimu which covers up to 25,000 acres and has the potential (if it is oil bearing) to hold 60 to 450 million barrels of recoverable oil,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>Mosaic said PPL 163 covered the area known as the Bosavi Arch which it said was regarded as a focal point for possible upward migration of oil in the foreland area of PNG.</p>
<p>PPL 163 covers an area of 7,238 sq km and is due for renewal on September 29, 1999.  </p>
<p>Permit conditions include commitment to a well prior to September 29, 1997 and another well prior to September 29 1999.</p>
<p>Mosaic shares were trading at 10 cents near the close of trading, up from Monday's close of 9.8 cents.</p>
<p>Phillips had held 58 percent, Kerr McGee 34.3 percent and Mosaic 7.7 percent of PPL 163 before Phillips announced its withdrawal earlier this month.</p>
<p>The split had then become Kerr McGee 80 percent and Mosaic 20 percent.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
