<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135098" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FOCUS - Pasminco sees another tough year.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FOCUS - Pasminco sees another tough year.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base-metals producer Pasminco Ltd forecast on Tuesday another tough year of cost-cutting, warning that a weak zinc market and a strong Australian dollar would make its last annual profit hard to beat.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to have a difficult year,&quot; chief executive David Stewart told reporters after delivering a subdued earnings outlook to shareholders at the group's annual meeting here.</p>
<p>Pasminco surprised financial markets markets in August by reporting a tripling of net profit to A$41 million for the year to June 30, despite weak prices for its major product, zinc.  </p>
<p>World zinc prices have not moved dramatically since then, but a stronger Australian dollar has made a major impact, dragging first quarter profit for 1996/97 lower, Stewart said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first quarter, our result...is below last year because of the impact of the (Australian) dollar,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For every one-cent rise in the value of the Australian dollar against the greenback, Pasminco suffers a A$7.5 million fall in after-tax profit, Stewart said.</p>
<p>The local dollar on average was five cents stronger in the first quarter than its average throughout 1995/96, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
