<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135053" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reckitt &amp; Colman to pay special dividend.</title>
<headline>Reckitt &amp; Colman to pay special dividend.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.K. foods and household products group Reckitt &amp; Colman Plc said on Tuesday it planned to pay a special foreign income dividend of 35.65 pence per share.</p>
<p>It said the payout will total 152 million stg.</p>
<p>The company will also ask shareholders to approve a share consolidation which will reduce the number of ordinary shares in issue by 5 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;The proposal is expected to enhance earnings per share and will not have any effect on the level of future dividends per share,&quot; Reckitt said in a statement.</p>
<p>The group said it did not believe its special dividend would be affected by Chancellor Kenneth Clarke's recent move to restrict repayment of tax credits available on distributions linked to share capital conslidation.</p>
<p>As a foreign income dividend (FID), which reflects earnings made outside Britain, its payout does not entitle shareholders to any tax credit, it said.  </p>
<p>Reckittt said the payout and share consolidation would be funded from cash deposits, and reflected the company's expectation that it would generate strong cash flow.</p>
<p>The group's 1994 acquisition of the U.S. household products group L&amp;P Household, maker of the Lysol disinfectant brand, for 1.0 billion stg was financed by a 230 million stg rights issue and various loans.</p>
<p>Reckitt said that by the end of 1996 it expected to have reduced net debt by more than 450 million stg, largely from the sale of non-core businesses totalling 430 million stg, including the famous Colman's mustard brand.  </p>
<p>The group will also have paid one-off reorganisation costs of 95 million stg and financed some small acquistions from its cash flow by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The group will continue to amke fill-in acquistions to strengthen its positions in developing markets, but expects that future free cash flow will exceed its financing requirements for such acquisitions,&quot; the statment said.</p>
<p>It added that the plan would &quot;not inhibit the group from pursuing more significant strategic acquisitions if an appropriate opportunity is identified.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
