<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135004" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: MONETARY POLICY UNCHANGED IN 97 - SIMITIS, PAPADEMOS.</title>
<headline>MONETARY POLICY UNCHANGED IN 97 - SIMITIS, PAPADEMOS.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A stricter 1997 fiscal budget will support the government's monetary policy and bring about a speedier de-escalation of inflation, Prime Minister Costas Simitis and Bank of Greece Governor Lucas Papademos decided yesterday, financial daily Imerisia reports.</p>
<p>Latest central bank estimates show the fall of inflation slowing, and expected to close at between 8.1-8.2 percent this year, overshooting initial targets of 7.9 percent.</p>
<p>Papademos said monetary policies had been the major factor in reducing inflation over recent years and that the policy aimed to support government efforts to achieve a 6.2-6.5 percent annualised inflation rate in 1997.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange policies will stick to the convergence programme, with the aim of keeping the drachma on an even keel with the ECU and to lay the ground for the drachma's inclusion in the new exchange rate mechanism.</p>
<p>Forex policy will be supported by selective flexibility in the course of the year to protect the drachma from possible speculative pressures, despite criticism by the EU's monetary commission that the drachma is overpriced, Imerisia said.</p>
<p>However, the central bank and the government claim that monetary policy for 1997 is based on a strict programme of fiscal discipline which will be positive for the drachma. --Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
