<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135086" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dlr climb pauses as data daunts.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dlr climb pauses as data daunts.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar's climb faltered Tuesday as bulls were daunted by stiff chart resistance and the danger of a sudden shift in interest rate sentiment.</p>
<p>The underlying mood remained upbeat thanks to a worldwide switch toward high yielding investments and an improving technical picture following the break of the US$0.7965 barrier, which had capped the currency for more than five weeks.</p>
<p>But there was also much talk a couple of key pieces of data on consumer prices and wages Wednesday and Thursday would show inflation subdued enough for the Reserve Bank to safely ease monetary policy in the next month or so.  </p>
<p>By 4.45 pm (0645 GMT) the local dollar had retreated to US$0.7955/60 from an early US$0.7962/67 and US$0.7970/75 Monday.</p>
<p>Caution prompted several tests lower but all faltered in the face of US$0.7950 support, which was variously attributed to dual currency samurai demand and local exporters taking cover.</p>
<p>Further chart support was expected at US$0.7940 and US$0.7870 at the outside, while resistance was thick between 80 cents and US$0.8020.</p>
<p>On the crosses, the dollar relaxed to 89.50/60 yen from Monday's lofty four year peak of 89.92/02, in line with the U.S. dollar which eased to 112.60 from a 33-month high of 112.90.  </p>
<p>In trade weighted terms it ended at 58.9, just off from Monday's five year high of 59.1.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market remained keen to capitalise on the local currency's yield advantage over the yen, and there were rumours of up to A$600 million of A$ dual currency samurais in the pipeline for this week.</p>
<p>But it needed to see the upcoming prices and wages data so as to better gauge the risk of a near term rate cut.</p>
<p>The RBA gave dollar bulls hope last week by warning that private wage settlements were running too high for comfort and a policy easing might store up problems for the future.  </p>
<p>However, the consumer price and wages figures are expected to show a marked improvment in the current inflation picture.</p>
<p>The underlying inflation measure, out Wednesday, is expected to show a modest rise of 0.6 percent in the third quarter after a 0.8 percent gain in Q2.</p>
<p>And because a big jump in Q3 last year will drop out, annual growth should slow to 2.5 percent from 3.1 percent in Q2, well within the RBA's 2-3 percent target range.</p>
<p>The headline measure of consumer prices is seen rising only 0.3 percent, taking year on year growth to 2.2 percent in the September quarter from 3.1 percent.  </p>
<p>Falling interest rate charges, the impact of the firm Australian dollar on import prices and cut throat discounting by retailers, will all play a part in subduing inflation.</p>
<p>Average weekly ordinary time earnings (AWOTE), out Thursday, are expected to rise 1.0 percent in Q3, but that would still see annual growth slow to 3.7 percent from 3.9 percent in Q2. This would be well below the RBA's danger level of 4.5 percent but crucially is seen as a lagging indicator by the RBA.</p>
<p>If the data match forecasts the money market would bay for a cut and unsettle the dollar, although analysts emphasised that all depended on the RBA's assessment of future wage risks.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bank is expecting Q3 inflation to be low, so a good inflation result should not by itself trigger an easing,&quot; said Andrew Pease, an economist at Nomura Research.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank is also more concerned with foreward looking indicators of wages growth...it would take a surprisingly low AWOTE result to trigger a cut,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>It was this sort of reasoning that was supporting the dollar and could help it weather even a fairly weak set of figures.</p>
<p>There were no local data today but Reserve Bank governor Ian Macfarlane was addressing a banking dinner tonight.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
