<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135085" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ jury out in British surgeon manslaughter trial.</title>
<headline>NZ jury out in British surgeon manslaughter trial.</headline>
<byline>Victoria Batchelor</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A New Zealand jury was unable to reach a verdict on Tuesday in the trial of a British surgeon accused of manslaughter over the deaths of three patients, a court official said.</p>
<p>A registrar at Wellington High Court said the jury of six men and six women was still out after five hours of deliberation on Tuesday in the case of 44-year-old Keith Douglas Ramstead.</p>
<p>They would resume their deliberations on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The British heart and lung surgeon had pleaded not guilty to the manslaughter of three patients on whom he performed lung removal operations while working as a cardio-thoracic surgeon in New Zealand in 1991/92.</p>
<p>He also denied two charges of making false statements about two of the deaths.</p>
<p>During the four-week trial, the prosecution said Ramstead failed to use the reasonable standard of knowledge, skill and care of a competent thoracic surgeon and so was criminally negligent in the deaths of two men, aged 50 and 74, and an elderly woman at a Christchurch hospital.</p>
<p>Using diagrams to illustrate what he said were Ramstead's mistakes, prosecutor Brent Stanaway said in his closing address on Monday that Ramstead's defence was built on his own evidence about what happened, and this had been shown to be both unreliable and dishonest.</p>
<p>He said the defence had attempted to arouse compassion for Ramstead, who told the court that not being able to work as a surgeon since the charges were filed had destroyed his life.</p>
<p>&quot;A verdict based on sympathy is not justice,&quot; Stanaway said.</p>
<p>However, the defence told the court there was no evidence that the Liverpool doctor was incompetent. In his closing address on Tuesday, defence laywer David Collins said the prosecution's case was &quot;fundamentally flawed&quot; because its theories ignored the facts.</p>
<p>&quot;During the course of this trial (we have) seen a number of experts... change their minds on very fundamental points,&quot; Collins said.</p>
<p>Collins finished by emphasising to the jury a statement made by Leonie van Dijk, the wife of one of the men who died during surgery.</p>
<p>&quot;I still believe that Mr Ramstead became a surgeon to save people's lives and not to kill them. That things can go wrong is normal but very sad,&quot; her statement said.</p>
<p>Ramstead returned to New Zealand to stand trial after an extradition battle lasting 2-1/2 years.</p>
<p>The trial involved detailed testimony of numerous medical professionals for both the prosecution and defence, with often conflicting views on crucial details of the operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Rarely has a case of such complexity been put before New Zealand juries,&quot; Collins told the court.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
