<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135013" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - OCT 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - OCT 22.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--The winds of worry blow through the Athens Stock Market. Although listed firms have shown significant profits in first half 1996, shares show a downward trend. Positive developments - political stability, profits, low interest rates - appear to be having little effect on the climate in the market.</p>
<p>--Margins for further falls in interest rates in state titles the conclusion from yesterday's auction of seven-year bonds. Demand exceeds supply three-fold. </p>
<p>--Government ignores social and internal party reactions in order to take the final 'nationally imperative' decisions for its economic policy. Prime Minister Costas Simitis determined to proceed.</p>
<p>--Thessaloniki court rules in favour of Goodyear, following its appeal for security measures to remove laid-off workers from the closed plant's premises.</p>
<p>--Petrol station owners ask development minister to withdraw legislation that further protects the heating fuel market, saying that petrol firms are making excessive profits.</p>
<p>--Intracom gets 600 million drachma telecommunications organisation (OTE) contract to upgrade and expand Hellas Com network. </p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--A continual and sudden fall in the general price index has been the norm over the past few days, despite the excellent climate, and is attributed to the 'indifference' of stock exchange authorities. </p>
<p>--Government reveals radical changes in procedures to auction public works projects in new bill. </p>
<p>--Prime minister has repeated meetings with senior economic official to crystallise economic targets for the new budget. --Dutch ABN AMRO and Deloitte appointed financial consultants to the sale of Agricultural Bank's shares in state-run Bank of Central Greece.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--Search for new sources of revenues as traditional solutions do not cover the government's needs for the 1997 budget. Senior government economic official says that the government has not ruled out taxing financial products. &quot;The money and capital markets, from a taxation viewpoint, are something we should look into,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>--Simitis mediates an internal party consensus on taxation and incomes policy, in meetings with government and party officials.</p>
<p>--OTE refrains from high increases for phone tariffs, influenced by the government's battle against inflation. Rise to be 4.62 percent.</p>
<p>--Government delegation achieves temporary solution to TVX-local residents stand-off on gold processing plant. Blockade on the road will be called off until an environmental study can be completed.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--Finance ministry considers increasing the threshold for a number of the objective tax criteria. </p>
<p>--The 1997 budget becoming a Gordian knot as the government seeks to balance pragmatism with its 'social' profile.</p>
<p>--Monetary and exchange policies this year and next the topic of discussion at yesterday's meeting between Simitis and central bank governor Lucas Papademas.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--Latest estimates put inflation at 8.5 percent for 1996 and 6.2 percent for 1997. Simitis to decide on 'intensity' of measures today.</p>
<p>--Ergo Bank to proceed with share capital increase of 27 billion drachmas in January.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
