<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135096" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian beef exports set to increase - AMLC.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian beef exports set to increase - AMLC.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian beef exports are projected to increase after a difficult year in 1996, John Penn, group marketing manager of the Australian Meat and Livestock Corp (AMLC), told the Australia-Japan Business Cooperation Committees meeting.</p>
<p>But continued competition from the U.S. for at least two years was expected to restrain significant growth, he said.</p>
<p>After a five-percent dip in Australian beef exports in calendar 1995 to 749,000 tonnes, largely a result of the U.S. 'overhang' of beef in Australia's export markets, exports in January-September 1996 fell by eight percent, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have some catching up to do in the final quarter to reach the 1996 forecast of 752,000 tonnes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Penn presented figures which showed the AMLC was currently forecasting exports of 792,000 tonnes in 1997 and 862,000 tonnes in 1998.</p>
<p>On a year-to-year basis, Australian beef exports to Japan, its largest market, were down by 10 percent to September after the 'mad cow' scare and the outbreak of E. coli infections.</p>
<p>Exports to Japan were starting to pick up again this month, Penn said.  </p>
<p>It was becoming clear that the setbacks of the past few months have been only temporary and renewed consumer confidence would settle the market, returning it to a more normal pattern, he said.</p>
<p>Japan was likely to remain Australia's major market for beef in the forseeable future.</p>
<p>Shipments to Japan were projected to increase in 1997 to 325,000 tonnes from the forecast level of 310,000 tonnes in 1996. This compared with the peak of 320,000 tonnes exported in 1995.  </p>
<p>By the turn of the century it was expected that Japan would be consuming 250,000 tonnes to 350,000 tonnes a year more than at present, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;While the early 1990s growth levels are unlikely to be sustained for the rest of the decade, falling tariffs and vigorous promotion... will continue to drive an expanding market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Japanese market would continue to offer significant opportunities over the next five years, he added.  </p>
<p>Teruchika Okoso, vice-chaiman of the big Japanese group Nippon Meat Packers, Inc, discussing the current meat market in Japan, said 57.2 percent of Japanese consumers bought their meat in supermarkets.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
