<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135044" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bell Cablemedia to buy Videotron's UK co.</title>
<headline>Bell Cablemedia to buy Videotron's UK co.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bell Cablemedia said on Tuesday it had conditionally agreed to buy 56 percent of Videotron Groupe's UK company, Videotron Holdings Plc, in addition to the 26 percent it already owns.  </p>
<p>After buying the Canadian company's stake in Videotron Holdings, Bell Cablemedia said it would make an unconditional offer to buy all of the UK unit's public and employee shares for $19.75 cash per Videotron American Depositary Share.</p>
<p>The company said the offer represented a premium of 12.9 percent to the closing price of $17.50 per Videotron share and would value Videotron at $1.09 billion.</p>
<p>Bell Cablemedia also said that on completion of the deal, Cable and Wireless Plc would subscribe $338 million in cash for about 91.1 million Bell Cablemedia ordinary shares at the equivalent of $18.55 per Bell Cablemedia ADS.  </p>
<p>Following the subscription, Cable and Wireless and Bell Canada International will each hold some 32.5 percent of Bell Cablemedia.</p>
<p>Jones Intercable Inc and certain affiliates will hold some 10.4 percent. Public shareholders of Bell Cablemedia will hold the balance of about 24.6 percent, the company said in its statement.</p>
<p>Cable and Wireless had undertaken not to exercise voting rights in Bell Cablemedia in excess of 29.9 percent, it said.  </p>
<p>Bell Cablemedia said it would finance the proposed acquisition of Videotron Holdings, a UK television cable network operator, with proceeds from the subscription and a short-term bridge facility amounting to $425 million.</p>
<p>The balance would be paid with existing resources, the company said.</p>
<p>Bell Cablemedia said it would pay $607 million in cash for Videotron Groupe's 56 percent stake in Videotron Holdings.</p>
<p>The company said it was being advised on the proposed acquisition of Videotron by Salomon Brothers and NatWest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
