<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135069" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining: Good ship Moonstone.</title>
<headline>RTRS-OPINION - Louthean on Australian Mining: Good ship Moonstone.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Ross Louthean*</p>
<p>The good ship Moonstar got a blessing from a minister of religion in keeping with the importance of this ceremony for even the most hardened mariner for a ship being prepared for sea.</p>
<p>Moonstar is no newcomer to the ocean for, in her former life after being built in Troon, Scotland, she plied the British coastal trade.</p>
<p>She has been fitted out for a cost of about US$10 million for a joint Australian-South African marine diamond search programme.</p>
<p>The ship is not for the Australian scene, where there are aspirations rather than clear proof of offshore diamonds.</p>
<p>Moonstar is destined for the cold, unpredictable waters of the west coast of South Africa so it's easy to see why seafarers at the Capetown Wharf for the official ceremony took seriously the blessings bestowed by the Reverend Thornley.</p>
<p>The affair was given a touch of panache when local identity Baron Achim von Arnim used a cutlass to break open a magnum of champagne for a toast.</p>
<p>One of the near shore marine licences to be tapped by Moonstar is next to the Namibian border which in the old days was the notorius Skeleton Coast which consumed so many of the early ships on the African run.</p>
<p>Partners in the quest on concessions 2B and 3B are Perth-based Moonstone Diamond Corporation NL, and the Johannesburg-listed and Capetown administered Benguela Concessions Ltd managed by John Gurney, rated as one of the best academic and practical geologists on alluvial and marine diamonds.</p>
<p>Monstone's chairman, Yannic Mercier, told the Capetown gathering that conservatively the completion of fitting out, the commissioning trials could go through to the end of the year.</p>
<p>SERIOUS PRODUCTION SEEN IN NEW YEAR</p>
<p>John Gurney told a press briefing that Benguela would expect to be getting into serious production at least by the beginning of the new calendar year.</p>
<p>Production is expected at the rate of 65,000 carats per annum on a resource estimated at this stage at 325,000 carats and representing identified diamond-bearing gravels covering only one percent of the areas.</p>
<p>The 85 metre long Moonstar, weighing 2,330 tonnes, has four point moorings to cope with rough seas and two airlift heads to recover the diamond-bearing gravels. The technological-age gear includes a position-fixing system to give the most comprehensive sea floor clearing capabilities, as well as an on-board 50 tonnes/hour concentrating plant.</p>
<p>Transfer of crews and major deliveries will be made at sea via helicopter utilising Moonstar's helipad.</p>
<p>Moonstone, which footed the refurbishing bills as its leg-in-the-door contribution to the joint venture, will represent Australia's first marine diamond producer and the second Aussie diamond producer in Africa.  (Already operating is Auridiam Consolidated NL, 50 percent owner and manager of the River Ranch mine in Zimbabwe).</p>
<p>The deal on mining Concessions 2B and 3B, south of the Orange River and adjacent to Namaqualand, is expected to produce annually for the first five years an annual gross income of about US$13 million. Mercier predicted that with operating costs and contingencies the joint venture could expect a first year full profit of above US$4 million.</p>
<p>This 50/50 deal sees Moonstone take a royalty starting at seven percent but sliding progressively down to 2.5 percent once costs of the ship refit are covered, while Benguela will take a four percent royalty for its management commitments.  </p>
<p>Still in the background in Benguela's original partner on these and other African marine concessions, the Big Australian, The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd which, with Benguela had spent about $A35 million on geological mapping and sampling using a fully rigged ship.</p>
<p>BHP's backstage role is undoubtedly coloured by its huge commitment to developing the Lac de Gras diamond project in Canada's NorthWest Territories.</p>
<p>BHP MAY OPT NOT TO COME BACK  </p>
<p>Gurney told me that in all probability BHP may not opt to come back on this &quot;mid-water&quot; operation.</p>
<p>Bengeula has been selling its existing diamond flow after inviting tenderers to &quot;sights&quot; at its secure Capetown office and then to tender their offers by facsimile.</p>
<p>The Central Selling Organisation has been a tenderer but Gurney said this De Beers diamond marketing arm had regularly come in lower than other tenders.</p>
<p>He said the stones have a good average value of US$200/carat and are predominantly white, some good yellows and a few browns and 95 percent gem stones, ranging in average size from 0.3-0.4 carat.</p>
<p>Full scale mining is expected to produce stones as big as 20 carats.</p>
<p>Moonstone's progression from explorer to miner emanates from a decision by the company to get into advanced projects, and this prospector which moved from private company to an Australian Stock Exchange listing in the mid 1990s has cut back its profile in the Kimberleys of Western Australia, though it still has a prime block down strike from Striker Resources NL's significant Bulgurri leases.</p>
<p>As well as the marine quest with Benguela, Moonstone has 75 percent in licences covering 17 farms in the South African side of the Limpopo diamond belt with South African gold miner Randgold &amp; Exploration Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Some of these blocks were sampled by De Beers but its focus shifted quickly to its big Venetia discovery.  </p>
<p>In the same region Moonstone has purchased 47 percent interest in the Madimbu alluvial project from Madimbu Mining Corporation and invited in alluvial diamond special Robin Baxter-Brown -- a key igure in Moonstone's pre-listing genesis - to take up 13 percent equity.</p>
<p>&quot;Baxter&quot;, who is also a director of Redaurum Mining, Auridiam's River Ranch partner, has four years had a watchful eye on the Madimbu Corridor.  </p>
<p>The Madimbu Corridor partners plan to delineate sampling sites for the ancient river system found on this licence is considered to have an association with drainage of primary and alluvial diamond source regions in South Africa, Botswana, Zimbabwe, Zambia and Angola.</p>
<p>* Ross Louthean is editor of Paydirt and publisher of Gold Mining Journal, The Australian Mines Handbook and Mineral Resources of New Zealand.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
