<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135199" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B shares edge down on speculative selling.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B shares edge down on speculative selling.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's B share index closed slightly lower on Tuesday on light speculative selling with most investors sidelined due to the absence of trading incentives, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B share index shed 0.71 points, or 0.79 percent, to close at 88.87 on turnover of HK$12.31 million, compared with HK$8.61 million on Friday.</p>
<p>There was no trading in the B share market on Monday in line with the closure of the Hong Kong bourse due to a public holiday.</p>
<p>Sustained profit-taking in recently-listed Dadonghai by institutions also weighed on the index, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Dadonghai traded the most on trade of 954,600 shares and sank HK$0.03 to HK$1.29 compared with an offer price of HK$1.22 per share.</p>
<p>Retailer Shenzhen International Enterprise put in the worst performance on speculative selling, brokers said. The counter dived HK$0.50, or 16.67 percent, to HK$2.50, with only 16,400 shares traded.</p>
<p>Great Ocean ebbed HK$0.30, or 14.15 percent, to HK$1.82 on volume of 4,000 shares and Tsann Kuen slumped HK$0.25, or 10.42 percent, to HK$2.15 also on trade of 4,000 shares.  </p>
<p>Guangdong Power was the second-most active counter and closed unchanged at HK$5.29 after 649,900 shares changed hands.</p>
<p>Speculative buying pushed Zhonghao up HK$0.12, or 7.59 percent, to HK$1.70 on light volume of 3,400 shares.</p>
<p>The A share market tumbled on Tuesday on heavy profit-taking triggered by an official report on the China Securities Regulatory Commission's reiteration of a ban on stock trading on credit, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Shenzhen-based Securities Times quoted CSRC officials as saying they had found that some brokerages were still providing credit for their clients for stock trading, which is banned.  </p>
<p>Brokers said there had been rumours that the CSRC was drafting detailed measures aimed to crack down on the illicit pratice.</p>
<p>The A share index plunged 18.30 points, or 4.83 percent, to end at 360.82 on turnover of 11.81 billion yuan, compared with Monday's 14.11 billion yuan. The composite index dipped 16.43 points, or 4.66 percent, to finish at 336.54.</p>
<p>Jilin Chemical, which had seen steep rises in previous sessions, dived 2.95 yuan, or 13.66 percent, to 18.65 yuan. Northeast Electric was the focus of profit-taking, brokers said. The counter plunged 1.44 yuan, or 12.54 percent, to 10.04 yuan.  </p>
<p>Northeast Pharmaceutical tumbled 1.20 yuan, or 10.67 percent, to 10.05 yuan. Jinan Diesel Engine Co Ltd, which listed 22.50 million A shares in Shenzhen on Tuesday, ended the session at 14.11 yuan per share on volume of 20.04 millinn shares compared with a recent offer price of 4.18 yuan per share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
