<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135169" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia rupiah firms, swaps fall in late trading.</title>
<headline>Indonesia rupiah firms, swaps fall in late trading.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah firmed against the dollar in sleepy late trading on Tuesday but swaps trading was active, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a sleepy day. The rate has moved in a narrow range of 30 cents since the morning,&quot; one U.S. bank dealer said. &quot;There is no fresh factor. Overall sentiment on the rupiah remains bullish,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was quoted at 2,324.25/24.50 at 0845 GMT against an opening of 2,324.25/24.50.</p>
<p>Tomorrow and today rupiah closed at 2,323.80/23.90 and 2,323.00/23.25, respectively.  </p>
<p>Dealers said, however, the relatively active swap market had helped provide some life.</p>
<p>One dealer said overnight money fell to 10.0/11.0 percent late in the afternoon from 16 percent at the opening.</p>
<p>He said short-dated swaps also declined on expectation of an easing in money market conditions following fresh inflows of civil servants' salaries transferred by the government.</p>
<p>He said state banks were seen unloading short-term swaps which might indicate the beginning of fresh transfers.</p>
<p>Overnight swap was at 0.65/0.70. Tom/next swap declined to 0.46/0.47 points from 0.57/0.60 points.  </p>
<p>Another reason was the expectation of some fresh rupiah supply following central bank's dollar buying on Monday.</p>
<p>One state bank dealer said Bank Indonesia was estimated to have absorbed about $200 million from the market after the spot rate fell out of the band.</p>
<p>Dealers said the amount sold to the central bank was not significant because of a relative lack of trading activity.</p>
<p>The U.S. bank dealer said declines in short-term swaps had helped drag down longer-term swap premiums.  </p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment on longer-term swaps was bearish. Some players seemed to anticipate narrowing interest rate differentials between the two currencies,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>He said they were expecting possible higher U.S. interest rates in the short-term while more downside was anticipated for the rupiah, narrowing the differential.</p>
<p>One-month swap was quoted at 17.3/17.75, two at 32.5/33.25, three at 49.50/50.25 and six at 98.0/98.75 points.</p>
<p>One foreign bank dealer said operators were uncertain over the short-term trend because they could not push the dollar further down due to the central bank floor rate for dollars.  </p>
<p>However, there was no incentive to buy dollars, keeping the market hovering around the band in lethargic trade, he said.</p>
<p>He said a firm stand by the central bank to defend the band seemed to have discouraged further speculation for now.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its intervention rate unchanged at 2,324/2,516 and the conversion rate at 2,324/2,372 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
