<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135145" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FIJI: FEATURE - Traders skirt the issues at tiny Fiji bourse.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Traders skirt the issues at tiny Fiji bourse.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SUVA, Fiji 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's 10 minutes before the opening of trading at the Suva Stock Exchange and you could cut the tension in the humid atmosphere with a swaying palm leaf.</p>
<p>Part-time dealers in traditional sulu skirts line up opposite a trading board, while a &quot;chalkie&quot; in an orange and blue sari gets ready to register the trades in shares for the exchange's four listed companies on a whiteboard.</p>
<p>Exchange manager Mesake Nawari, a jolly Fijian in crisp white shirt and tie and grey sulu, smiles in anticipation -- his exchange only trades once a week on Monday morning and for 30 minutes.</p>
<p>There are no stock brokers in Fiji, so in an attempt to stimulate trading, an open call system has just been introduced.</p>
<p>Australian Tony Cooper, local media manager for Australia's Westpac Banking Corp, has volunteered to be the caller.</p>
<p>&quot;I just help them out on Monday mornings for a bit of fun,&quot; says Cooper. &quot;I call all the stocks and we also have government bonds, quasi bonds and government securities.&quot;</p>
<p>Cooper rings a small, golden bell and the exchange is, well, if not quite abuzz, open for business.</p>
<p>Cooper invites interest in the first listed company, Burns Philip Toyota (South Seas) Ltd, but buyer and seller can't agree on a price and there is no trade.</p>
<p>The next company, Flour Mills of Fiji Ltd, sees a nerve wracking trade between buyer and seller, who exchange 13 prices, mostly quoting in one cent lots until they finally agree and 2,000 shares trade at F$2.03 (US$1.58).</p>
<p>Unfortunately the remaining two companies, Fiji Sugar Corporation and South Pacific Distilleries Ltd, fail to trade.</p>
<p>Traders here know the real action is on the secondary bond market. This morning Housing Authority (Short Term) Bonds with a face value of F$100,000 and coupon of 7.82 percent, maturing December 31, 1998, are sold at F$101.85.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonds are the growth area,&quot; says a confident Lionel Yee, stock exchange chairman and head of the Fiji National Provident Fund, currently the main source of domestic investment in Fiji.</p>
<p>&quot;The bonds are quite a lucrative market in terms of fixed interest. But people are not used to buying and selling bonds,&quot; Yee told Reuters, adding he hoped that once word spread, bonds would challenge local banks for depositors' savings.</p>
<p>The Fiji government last month started trading debt from its bankrupt National Bank of Fiji on the exchange and plans to convert some F$160-200 million in debt, says Yee.</p>
<p>He declines to disclose when the next bond will be released.</p>
<p>In a town where everybody knows everybody, such sensitive information could move the market -- anyway its against the exchange rules adopted from the Australian Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Yee says two trades is a healthy morning at the exchange, although he recalls proudly a record F$5-6 million turnover one morning. &quot;It's not New York or Sydney,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Increased bond trading and the possible partial float next year of Fiji Post &amp; Telecom, which posted a F$18.8 million profit in calendar 1995, will hopefully provide enough liquidity for a screen-based trading system, says Yee.</p>
<p>By the end of 1996 he hopes to have an overseas trading facility for Fijians to trade out of Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>The government has exempted residents from a five percent tax on dividends for listed companies and abolished stamp duties on trades in an attempt to attract investors.</p>
<p>But the exchange needs at least 30 companies for long-term viability, says Nawari.</p>
<p>The Suva Stock Exchange was formed in 1979, but prior to July this year, it operated as a trading post where trading of securities by both buyer and seller was handled by the exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;This was largely due to the absence of a trading floor and broker community,&quot; says Nawari in his modern, but small, exchange on Victoria Parade along Suva Harbour. An electronic tickerboard at the entrance diplays the latest trades.</p>
<p>Exchange chairman Lionel Yee says the choice was either to close the exchange or open a trading floor and hope it encouraged activity.</p>
<p>In 1995, the volume of shares and bonds traded was 66,023 and F$155.5 million respectively. Since July, 120,533 shares have changed hands and F$21.8 million worth of bonds.</p>
<p>Nawari said most trades are by institutional dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no stockbrokers, but we hope that the 24 part-time dealers with the stock exchange will encourage a brokerage community,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>But despite its small size, trading on the Suva Stock Exchange is a tough game for dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;You missed a trade,&quot; barks Yee to a young female dealer after the close of the Monday morning session. &quot;You have to attract the buyer. You only get a split second to get on and you have to put the highest price on the board.&quot;</p>
<p>(F$1=US$0.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIJI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUVA, Fiji"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FIJI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
