<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135119" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-News Corp outraged by Israel tax raid.</title>
<headline>RTRS-News Corp outraged by Israel tax raid.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rupert Murdoch's News Corp said on Tuesday it was outraged that the Israeli tax authority had raided the offices of its subsidiary News Datacom Research Ltd, describing it as an intrusion against the firm and employees.</p>
<p>&quot;We are outraged that despite giving full co-operation to the Israeli Income Tax Authority...they have taken this large and intrusive action against the company and its employees,&quot; News said in a statement issued in London and received here.  </p>
<p>&quot;The unilateral action undertaken by the tax authorities last Sunday puts into question Israel's approach and commitment to foreign investment in order to expand its high-tech infra-structure,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>News Corp said it had been told three weeks ago by the Israeli tax authority that News Datacom was not being investigated.</p>
<p>Israeli tax authorities said on Sunday they had raided the offices of the Jerusalem-based News Datacom and removed documents.  </p>
<p>&quot;The company is suspected of concealing income in the years 1989-1996 of some 150 million dollars,&quot; the tax authority said in a statement, adding it had been investigating News Datacom undercover for the past year and was launching an open inquiry.</p>
<p>News Datacom said in an unsigned statement on Sunday: &quot;Allegations of tax evasion are entirely without merit&quot;.</p>
<p>News Corp said it had been &quot;assured as recently as three weeks ago by these same authorities that News Datacom Research Limited was not under investigation&quot;.  </p>
<p>&quot;At no point has the company been approached by the tax authorities on this question or to engage in any discussion on the subject&quot;,&quot; the News Corp statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Given our full co-operation with the authorities, it is hard to understand the reason for the public and extreme action undertaken on the 20th October 1996,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>News Datacom develops and sells encryption systems mainly for pay-television broadcasters, like Murdoch's BSkyB television.  </p>
<p>News Corp said that prior to the fiscal year ending June 30, 1996, neither News Datacom Research nor News Datacom Ltd UK, the British-based parent company, had cumulative operating profits.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, the question of tax evasion in any one country regardless of the manner in which the accounting between the companies is done, is irrelevant,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>News Corp said it believed the Israeli tax investigation was being driven by a former employee who is being sued in Britian by News Corp for allegedly defrauding the company out of millions of dollars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
