<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135118" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-MIM says 1996/97 will be difficult.</title>
<headline>RTRS-MIM says 1996/97 will be difficult.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mining house MIM Holdings Ltd said on Tuesday its current financial year will be difficult, especially due to the current level of copper prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking into account economic and market conditions and the volatility of prices and exchange rates, it is very hard to forecast the financial result for 1996/97,&quot; the company said in the outlook section of its 1995/96 annual report.</p>
<p>&quot;However, given the present level of copper prices in particular, a difficult year is in prospect,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>MIM also said its gearing will increase due to funding requirements for new local and overseas projects.  </p>
<p>MIM said its new projects under construction, the Alumbrera copper mine in Argentina, the Ernest Henry copper/gold project in Queensland, and the Enterprise base metals mine near Mount Isa in Queensland, will not contribute to 1996/97 earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;While MIM is well placed to fund these projects, gearing will increase during the year,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>It said metal markets were still feeling the effects of a substantial fall in the price of copper, MIM's single most important product, due to the market manipulation scandal late last financial year.  </p>
<p>&quot;Continuing low world stock levels provide some underpinning of the price although this could change as new production outstrips consumption in the next 12 months,&quot; MIM said.</p>
<p>&quot;The aftermath of the copper market revelations continues to exert a depressing influence on the market for other metals,&quot; MIM said.</p>
<p>It said zinc prices were not likely to rise substantially, lead prices can be expected to hold, and there were no strong guides to the future price of gold and silver.</p>
<p>&quot;Fluctuations in currency exchange rates will also directly affect returns to the company.&quot;  </p>
<p>MIM achieved a net profit of A$170.6 million in 1995/96 compared with a net loss of A$216.1 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company said it was now entering a new phase which had the objectives of higher profits and greater shareholder wealth.</p>
<p>&quot;But of course, much will depend on commodity prices and currency fluctuations but at least the controllable issues are understood.&quot;</p>
<p>It said this phase, which includes the opening of new projects, could span two years and coincided with the three year investment plan for its core Mount Isa operations.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
