<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135127" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Ashton says September 1996 quarter diamond sales on target. [CORRECTED 02:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>RTRS-Ashton says September 1996 quarter diamond sales on target. [CORRECTED 02:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>(Corrects headline from &quot;Q1 diamond sales&quot;)</p>
<p>Argyle diamond mine partner Ashton Mining Ltd said sales in the September 1996 quarter (corrects from 1996/97 first quarter) through the key Antwerp market were in line with forecasts and progress had been made in establishing a direct market presence.</p>
<p>The Argylye partners, which consist of 40 percent-owner Ashton and CRA Ltd/RTZ Plc with the remainder, split from the Central Selling Organisation (CSO) in June, challenging its global market dominance. CSO is operated by De Beers Consolidated Mines Ltd of South Africa.</p>
<p>Ashton also said earlier concerns in the Indian market about a price war with CSO had eased.  </p>
<p>&quot;As mentioned in the June quarterly report, Argyle has now commenced selling of all its diamonds directly into the Antwerp market following the decision not to renew a sales contract with the Central Selling Organisation,&quot; Ashton said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sales for the first three months have been in line with forecasts and substantial progress has been made during the last three months in establishing an expanded direct market presence.&quot;</p>
<p>Ashton said the retail diamond market remainded strong, particularly in the United States which accounts for 34 percent of diamond jewellery sales.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
