<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135166" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Nichiei Finance Co Ltd, a Yokohama-based medium-sized non-bank institution, plans to apply for liquidation as early as on Tuesday. Nichiei has liabilities of about 170 billion yen. Nichiei's main creditor banks -- Asahi Bank Ltd, Dai-Ichi Kangyo Bank Ltd and Yokohama Bank -- have agreed to renounce claims on their loans to the firm.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Honda Motor Co Ltd plans to increase its annual dividend by one yen to 15 yen for the business year ending March 31, 1997, which would mean a rise in its dividend for the first time in seven years. The planned increase is due to strong sales of recreational vehicles in Japan and the weaker yen. Honda is expected to increase its parent current profit for the current business year by 2.5 times from a year earlier to 120 billion yen.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>NEC Corp plans to cut investment in its semiconductor production business for the business year ending March 31, 1997, by 20 billion yen from its original plan to 190 billion due to a sharp decline in memory chip prices. Other leading chip makers, including Toshiba Corp, Hitachi Ltd and Mitsubishi Electric Corp, are also expected to cut their chip investment.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Nippon Cargo Airlines and U.S. aircargo company United Parcel Service of America Inc plan to reach agreement on Friday on air cargo service cooperation between Japan and the United States.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Toshiba Corp plans to set up its first plant in Vietnam to manufacture colour televisions, in cooperation with a Vietnamese state-run company. The firm aims to manufacture 88,000 televisions annually from July 1997, and to boost production to 200,000 by 1999. The company is owned 64 percent by Toshiba's Singapore affiliate and 36 percent by the Vietnamese company.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Sumitomo Corp plans to set up a joint venture in late November to provide transport services in Vietnam, in cooperation with Shizuoka-based transport company Suzuyo Co Ltd and two Vietnamese state-run firms. Sumitomo and the partners have already received investment permission from Vietnam's government. The company, capitalised at $4 million, will be owned 27 percent by Sumitomo, 25 percent by Suzuyo, and 48 percent by two Vietnam-state run companies.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
