<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135138" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ dollar largely immune to easing - Aust analyst.</title>
<headline>NZ dollar largely immune to easing - Aust analyst.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Any easing in New Zealand monetary conditions is unlikely to have a significant negative impact on the high-flying kiwi dollar, an Australian analyst said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Steve Shuster, Citibank Australia's head of foreign exchange, told Reuters Financial Television that while it seemed likely the Reserve Bank would ease policy, it was questionable whether this would have a significantly downward impact on the currency.  </p>
<p>&quot;The export sector is hurting. So the RBNZ is probably in a position where it can ease. But the question is whether this would actually affect the spot market.</p>
<p>&quot;Should we get a one percent easing in the December monetary policy statement, we'll still have short rates at nine percent. That's still attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>The currency touched 71.46 U.S. cents in early Tuesday trade and hit 68.08 on the Trade Weighted Index, its highest levels since mid-1988.</p>
<p>Shuster said he did not think the RBNZ would have to release a statement before December to cool the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;For the time being, we've probably seen the larger extent of the kiwi's upward move. And I think the RBNZ feels that as well, so there's probably no panic on their behalf. We'll now just wait and see what unfolds on the political front.&quot;</p>
<p>Shuster said while yield-driven buying would continue, this would be offset by profit-taking as investors, faced with a heavy funding cost, sold Kiwi bonds.</p>
<p>He forecast a short-term range of 70.00 to 72.00 U.S. cents for the kiwi, with the currency unlikely to breach 69.80 on the downside.  </p>
<p>Clifford Bennett, technical analyst at Creative Currencies in Sydney, told RFTV that the kiwi's breach of resistance at 71.25 U.S. cents had set the currency up for a try at 72 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;The nature of the price action suggests that the currency hasn't expired - there's some some energy there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
