<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135151" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: By Caroline Allen.</title>
<headline>By Caroline Allen.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's fund management industry, controlling huge investments in Europe, will find the way it does business radically altered with a single currency but plans for change are still in their infancy, analysts say.</p>
<p>They warn that many fund managers at the heart of the global industry are betting -- wrongly -- that European economic and monetary union (EMU) will not have an immediate impact on their investments.</p>
<p>&quot;They hope they will be able to convert slowly, to think about all the ramifications,&quot;  Nigel Morgan, economic strategist at Old Mutual International Asset Managers said.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will be like reunification of East and West Germany -- people found there was no interim. They had to make the leap and clear up the mess afterwards.&quot;</p>
<p>EMU is due to start on January 1, 1999. Although doubts about the political will to see it through are dissipating, few see Britain in the first round.</p>
<p>This worries many London-based investment houses because they know that Britain if was outside the system, their influence on a growing and potentially lucrative European investment market would dry up. But views differ widely.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be much impact to start with. In 30 years time it will all be pan-European, sure, but things move very slowly,&quot; said a European fund manager who declined to be named. &quot;Besides, London differs from European markets in everything from accounting standards to management styles.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the questions concerned funds are asking are how strictly the criteria for first-round EMU membership will be applied, whether Britain will join at all and what the long term consquences for European capital markets will be. PAN-EUROPEAN OUTLOOK</p>
<p>A single currency would accelerate a process already underway whereby institutional investors have an increasingly pan-European outlook, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;There are already tremendous opportunities. Pricing anomalies will disappear -- if you want to buy a chemical company you'll look for the cheapest in Europe, never mind where it is based,&quot; Stephen Cohen, director at Mercury Asset Management (MAM) said.</p>
<p>&quot;A single currency will promote cross border flows which conventional economics tells us is a good thing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Cohen believes that if distinctions among key European currencies go, then accountancy and corporate governance differences will also be reduced.</p>
<p>But previous attempts to free up cross-border capital flows in Europe have met with little success. Many countries still have restrictions on how much may be invested internationally and demand a minimum holding in domestic bonds or equities. Strategically, EMU will force fund managers to either build a pan-European presence or specialise and serve niche markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who can't do either will wither or get caught in between...so there will be more international mergers building on the national activity recently,&quot; said Morgan at Old Mutual.</p>
<p>Some analysts say the introduction of the euro will at a stroke wipe out huge swathes of capital markets like foreign exchange dealing, arbitrage and any currency based instrument.</p>
<p>Morgan agrees. &quot;The currency game will fade away, and I suspect potential participants will arrange to devalue a lot in the run-up to EMU so that when they freeze they have an ultra-competitive currency,&quot; he said. SKEPTICISM REMAINS</p>
<p>There is still a widespread scepticism about the benefits of the process, which many believe is being forced ahead before economies have had a chance to converge properly.</p>
<p>At Lichenstein Global Trust (LGT), senior economist Tim Lee said that contrary to common belief, the EMU process will be inflationary, with especially peripheral countries being misled into cutting their interest rates too quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;It's being pushed through too quickly. It is the peripheral countries which will pay for this in the end,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He expects member governments to try to enhance demand for the euro in the three-year transitional phase to 2002 by using it for official transactions and by also perhaps taking tax and social security payments in the new currency.</p>
<p>Lee also predicts some &quot;massaging of expectations in the run-up to EMU so the markets come to the right conclusions&quot;. INTERIM PORTFOLIOS</p>
<p>In an interim period after 1999, fund groups would have to run euro portfolios alongside home currency portfolios, taking account of the base currency of their investor and measuring it against newly produced Euro-denominated indices.</p>
<p>If Britain does not participate initially, there will be little operational change for British fund managers. Portfolios will remain sterling-based and London-listed stocks will still be quoted in sterling. But as EMU develops, currency-specific portfolios would be abolished for the euro.</p>
<p>MAM's Cohen noted there was already an informal class of &quot;European&quot; stocks. &quot;It's sometimes difficult to distinguish between a French or German company and a European one. Soon there will be euro-denominated shares and a centralised European stock exchange, perhaps cross listing on several exchanges.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the biggest implications of EMU will be for information systems. &quot;It is going to be systems-intensive as the euro is going to have all the component currencies running alongside it for at least three years,&quot; noted one fund manager.</p>
<p>But he admitted his company had &quot;not scrutinised the operational side&quot;. &quot;We are frankly more concerned about what the year 2000 will do to our computer systems,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cohen said that theoretically there should be no problem adding a new currency -- the euro -- to any adequate system.</p>
<p>&quot;But you'd have to evaluate how to convert say a mark portfolio into euros and how to recalculate all the book costs. Everyone is going to have to do some work. The better existing systems will need less.&quot; -- London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
