<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135147" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Goodman not distracted by resignation.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Goodman not distracted by resignation.</headline>
<byline>Ian Pemberton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food group Goodman Fielder Ltd said it would not be distracted by the surprise resignation of its finance director after only seven months with the company.</p>
<p>Chief executive David Hearn, announcing the resignation of Les Cullen, also said he believed there was no longer a compelling reason to regard Goodman Fielder as a takeover stock.</p>
<p>Hearn said Cullen had helped the company towards its twin objectives of building a team of executives and developing a direction and clarity for the operations, which are mostly based in Australia and New Zealand.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the departure of Cullen, who handed his resignation to Hearns last night, was a surprise because his appointment had been lauded by Hearns in February this year.</p>
<p>At the time, Hearns said Cullen's appointment &quot;represents a building block in our senior management team for the future&quot;. At a joint press conference on Tuesday, Cullen said he had resigned to pursure a job with wider responsibilities while Hearns said Goodman Fielder could not provide these new horizons in the timeframe sought by Cullen.</p>
<p>Goodman shares bucked the overall market trend at the open to be six cents lower at A$1.47 at 10.15 a.m. (0015 GMT).  </p>
<p>Hearn, who was appointed chief executive in September 1995, said Goodman was on the road to improvement after a number of years of little direction and poor results.</p>
<p>&quot;We have clearly done, I think, a reasonable starting job of putting the blocks in place for the future,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are nowhere near finished that yet, and there is more peformance to come out of the business. So yes it should be a recovery stock.&quot;.</p>
<p>Hearns said media reports that Goodman Fielder was a takeover target were incorrect and &quot;esterday's story&quot;, with institutions snapping up large holdings sold in July and August.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't see there is any compelling reason why we should be a takeover target at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no overt signs on the share register of people building a stake.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Brierley Investments Ltd had virtually sold its entire holding while the AMP Society had more recently reduced its stake to meet new index weighting measures on the New Zealand Stock Exchange, where Goodman Fielder is also listed.</p>
<p>The Brierley and AMP holdings were bought by a large number of local and overseas institutions, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
