<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135104" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Wattyl sees 10-15 pct profit rise.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Wattyl sees 10-15 pct profit rise.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paint manufacturer Wattyl Ltd said on Tuesday it expected a 10 to 15 percent increase in profit for the first six months of the current year to June 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The first two months sales in July and August showed a significant improvement over 1995/96 with a corresponding lift in profits,&quot; chairman Murray Anderson told the annual meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;September sales, however, were disappointing and took away some of the July-August improvement, but are still 13 percent above last year,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;As a result, I would forecast a profit increase for the first six months of 10-15 percent with the ultimate result being very much dependent upon the next three months,&quot; Anderson said.</p>
<p>Wattyl reported a net profit of A$21.2 million for the year to June 30, down from A$33.78 million a year earlier.  </p>
<p>&quot;The 1995/96 year has certainly been the toughest year in the company's history,&quot; Anderson said, attributing much of the problem to a run-up in sales in 1995 to beat proposed taxes and a fall-off in the housing industry.</p>
<p>&quot;It is probably true to say that we did not start on a cost cutting programme early enough and it did not begin to bite until the last quarter,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Anderson said Wattyl's prospects in 1996/97 would very much depend on its Australian operations.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has already taken steps to actively improve our situation and this is on-going,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are very soundly based to take advantage of the general market conditions and will be doing so in the months ahead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
