<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135153" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Banned Nobel winner says he would not disrupt APEC.</title>
<headline>Banned Nobel winner says he would not disrupt APEC.</headline>
<byline>Ruben Alabastro</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nobel peace prize laureate Jose Ramos-Horta said on Tuesday Manila's decision to ban him from the Philippines during the forthcoming APEC summit meeting was like banning a mouse from a party of elephants.</p>
<p>&quot;Who am I to be able to disrupt a summit of mighty states?&quot; the East Timorese resistance leader said from his Sydney home in an interview with reporters in Manila.</p>
<p>&quot;I am bit like Mickey Mouse, (they're) accusing me, a Mickey Mouse, of trying to disrupt a party of elephants.&quot;</p>
<p>The Philippine government said on Monday it would not allow Ramos-Horta to enter the country next month because his presence might disrupt a summit of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum in Subic free port.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta, in an interview earlier on Tuesday with Reuters in Sydney, dismissed the Philippine ban as &quot;silly&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I am always amazed that an individual like me, without an army and navy behind me, can be considered a potential disturbance,&quot; Ramos-Horta said.</p>
<p>Co-winner of the 1996 Nobel Peace Prize with East Timor Catholic bishop Carlos Belo, Ramos-Horta has been invited by Filipino peace activists to address a parallel summit in Manila of non-governmental organisations.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded the former Portuguese colony of East Timor in 1975, just after Portugal pulled out, and annexed the territory the following year in a move never recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta said he wanted to go to Manila &quot;to engage in public forums to discuss a peace process (for East Timor), with possible Philippines mediation&quot;.</p>
<p>He spoke to reporters in Manila in a phone interview arranged by organisers of the planned NGO summit.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish to state that I have no intention to be disruptive...I would not use Philippine hospitality to attack one of its neighbours,&quot; he said. &quot;If the Philippines starts to curtail freedom of speech, we ask, what is APEC for?&quot;</p>
<p>Both the Philippines and Indonesia are members of APEC.</p>
<p>The NGO summit organisers said they would challenge the ban in the Supreme Court and appeal to NGOs in APEC member economies to pressure their heads of state to boycott the APEC summit if Manila refused to lift the ban.</p>
<p>Filipino academic Walden Bello, chairman of the international convening committee of the Manila People's Forum on APEC, told a news conference: &quot;We will use all possible legal means, moving this up even to the Supreme Court, to get Mr Horta in.&quot;</p>
<p>He said court action would be taken once Manila implements the ban by denying Ramos-Horta a visa.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta said he planned to apply for a visa at the Philippine consulate in Sydney on Wednesday.</p>
<p>President Fidel Ramos defended the government ban and said he was confident the courts would uphold it.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not violating the democratic rights of Filipinos,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;They can talk...meet anywhere they want as long as there is no disturbance of peace and order.</p>
<p>&quot;But foreigners must not get involved in the internal politics of the Philippines...that is prohibited in our constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta said East Timor believed in regional cooperation and hoped to join APEC and the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) when it was free from Jakarta rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
