<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135156" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai soybean ends mixed in slow trading.</title>
<headline>Shanghai soybean ends mixed in slow trading.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai soybean futures ended mixed in slow trading on Tuesday due to an uncertain short-term market trend, traders said.</p>
<p>The key November 1996 contract ended at 3,296 yuan ($396) per tonne, rising seven yuan. It opened at an intra-day high of 3,297 and hit a low of 3,276. January fell nine to 3,240 yuan per tonne, March 20 to 3,270 and May rose 18 to 3,310.</p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 8,400 tonnes from 18,700.</p>
<p>Traders said many investors were wary about the short-term market trend with poor long-term fundamentals limiting the potential for technical rebounds in the short term.  </p>
<p>&quot;Short-covering pushed the prices up but they met resistance at high levels due to weak market sentiment,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Slow trading indicated that long position holders lacked confidence,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Traders said the November contract will rise further if it breaches the key 3,300 yuan resistance, but the long-term pessimistic view will remain.</p>
<p>&quot;Over-supply of domestic spot soybeans makes many investors hesitate to build long positions at current levels,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>($1=8.3000 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
