<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135126" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - Australian inflation to stay modest.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - Australian inflation to stay modest.</headline>
<byline>John Mair</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's inflation rate is seen falling to its lowest level in two years in the September quarter and analysts also expect the key underlying rate to be back inside the Reserve Bank of Australia's (RBA) target band.</p>
<p>Wednesday's data is seen confirming the favourable near-term outlook for inflation, with both inflation rates seen falling further in the December quarter, economists said.</p>
<p>The median forecast of the 32 economists surveyed by Reuters was for a 0.6-percent rise in the underlying rate. Forecasts ranged from 0.3 to 0.7 percent.  </p>
<p>In annual terms, the underlying rate was seen at 2.5 percent, which would be its lowest level since the June 1995 quarter and also the first time since then that the underlying rate has been below 3.0 percent. Forecasts for the annual rate ranged from 2.2 to 2.7 percent,</p>
<p>The underlying rate excludes seasonal and volatile items in the consumer price index (CPI) and is the inflation focus of the RBA, which aims to keep it to an average of between two and three percent over a run of years.  </p>
<p>Last week, the RBA said &quot;underlying inflation should fall into the two to three percent range , and possibly into the lower half of the target band during 1996/97&quot; (July/June), and economists agree the near-term outlook is favourable.</p>
<p>&quot;The factors that helped to support low inflation in the first half of the year are all still at work,&quot; Bankers Trust Australia senior economist Peter Munckton said.</p>
<p>&quot;These include: excessive stock levels, strong competition in the retail sector in the face of modest consumer demand, a strong exchange rate, subdued inflation expectations and a sluggish labour market,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The CPI, or headline rate, is seen falling below the underlying rate for the first time since September 1994.</p>
<p>Forecasts for the quarter centre on a 0.3-percent rise, and range from 0.2 to 0.5 percent. In annual terms, the CPI is seen at 2.2 percent, with forecasts ranging from 2.1 to 2.4 percent.</p>
<p>Of the categories that make up the CPI, economists expect increases in food, household equipment, tobacco and alcohol, health and personal care, and recreation and education.</p>
<p>Housing is expected to be a detraction, while clothing and transport are expected to show falls, but not by all economists.  </p>
<p>The two rounds of cuts in mortgage rates -- the first in June as a result of competition in the mortgage market and the second followed the July 31 rate reduction -- are expected to start impacting this quarter, but economists said their impact on the CPI will be more obvious in the December quarter.</p>
<p>While the markets attention is on the underlying rate, because that in turn is the RBA's focus, the improvement in the CPI is nevertheless important.  </p>
<p>Economists said that as it is the CPI that is used as a yardstick for wage negotiations, and for indexation of some levies and transport fares, the falling headline rate should help the underlying rate down the track.</p>
<p>Recent inflation data and forecasts are detailed below:  </p>
<p>CPI	Q1 95   Q2 95   Q3 95   Q4 95   Q1 96   Q2 96   Q396(f)</p>
<p>Index    114.7   116.2   117.6   118.5   119.0   119.8    120.2</p>
<p>q/q pct   +1.7    +1.3    +1.2    +0.8    +0.4    +0.7     +0.3</p>
<p>y/y pct   +3.9    +4.5    +5.1    +5.1    +3.7    +3.1     +2.2</p>
<p>--------</p>
<p>Underly  Q1 95   Q2 95   Q3 95   Q4 95   Q1 96   Q2 96   Q396(f)</p>
<p>Index    115.2   116.3   117.7   118.5   119.0   119.9    120.6</p>
<p>q/q pct   +0.3    +1.0    +1.2    +0.7    +0.4    +0.8     +0.6</p>
<p>y/y pct   +1.9    +2.5    +3.1    +3.2    +3.3    +3.1     +2.5</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
