<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135110" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-W.Australia lupin disease seen under control.</title>
<headline>RTRS-W.Australia lupin disease seen under control.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An outbreak of anthracnose disease in albus (white) lupin crops in Western Australia was now considered to be under control although 54 properties were reported to have been infected, the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>ABARE said in its Crop Report yields in albus lupin crops in Western Australia were expected to be well down on last year. So far 3,000 hectares (ha) of albus lupins had been ploughed in in the Geraldton region, where the disease seemed to be centred, while a further 3,000 ha had been found to be infected, it said.  </p>
<p>To prevent further outbreaks, a moratorium on albus production in most locations was likely until 1998, it said.</p>
<p>ABARE forecast total Australian lupin production in 1996/97 would fall by 14 percent to slightly more than 1.2 million tonnes. The reduction was mainly the result of lower production in Western Australia, which accounts for 85 percent of Australia's lupin production.</p>
<p>Lupin production in Western Australia was forecast to be almost 1.1 million tonnes, down 12 percent on 1995/96, because of a combination of reduced plantings and yields, it said. While harvesting was yet to commence because of the late start  </p>
<p>to the season, lupins appeared to be podding well, it said.</p>
<p>Lupins are used mainly as stock feed in Australia, with the industry in Western Australia estimated to be worth A$200 million a year.</p>
<p>Until mid-September, when lupin-killing anthracnose disease was discovered in the Western Australia albus lupin crop, only Australia and South Africa were thought to be anthracnose-free.</p>
<p>Albus (white) lupins cover about three percent of the WA lupin area of a total 1.08 million ha.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
