<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135113" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Wisconsin wants other Asia-Pacific deals.</title>
<headline>Wisconsin wants other Asia-Pacific deals.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wisconsin Central Transportation Corp President and Chief Executive Edward Burkhardt said on Tuesday the U.S. railroad company was looking for more opportunities in the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p>&quot;We are always interested in growth opportunities,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Wisconsin purchased a major stake in New Zealand Rail, now Tranz Rail, in 1993 when it was privatisated.  </p>
<p>&quot;I see that (privatisation) as coming on strong in Asia-Pacific, but not only there, it's a worldwide phenomena,&quot; Burkhardt said. &quot;Our purchase in Britain was part of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Wisconsin recently purchased four of five rail freight companies that were privatised in Britain and is interested in acquiring the sixth.</p>
<p>Burkhardt said Wisconsin was particularly interested in Australia and Malaysia, where it expects rail to privatisated.</p>
<p>&quot;We certainly would be looking at that. The change of commonwealth government in Australia is going to make all types of privatisations much more likely.&quot;  </p>
<p>However, he noted most of Australia's railways are owned by the states in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;I see more opportunities today in the operations the Federal Government is involved in there -- Australia National and National Rail,&quot; he said. &quot;We would look at them or if any state operations were put on the market there.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Malaysia had taken taken a few tentative steps towards rail privatisation and Wisconsin was following developments closely.  </p>
<p>Burkhardt said Wisconsin had been pleased with its New Zealand purchase, a much cleaner buy than in Britain. The latter was complicated because the rail infrastructure was spun off into a different company to the passenger and freight companies.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Britain) set up a regime that is very costly in assessing charges against the operators to support the infrastructure company.</p>
<p>&quot;All of this is totally foreign to the way railway companies operate in North America and New Zealand. It has taken some getting used.&quot;  </p>
<p>Wisconsin is in the process of cutting the staff in the British companies by half from 75,000.</p>
<p>&quot;The New Zealand system was much better run and had a much more successful history up till the date of privatisation than the British system had.&quot;</p>
<p>Burkhardt said any fresh purchase would be funded from a combination of debt and equity.</p>
<p>There were opportunities for Tranz Rail to work in a joint venture with Wisconsin.  </p>
<p>There were limits to Wisconsin's ability to manage dispersed railway companies and Tranz Rail with its history of successful transformation from state-owned company to commercial operation could use its experience.</p>
<p>&quot;Between the two of us, we can magnify our management resources in looking at these bigger transactions,&quot; Burkhardt said. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
