<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135183" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks close down, investors take profits.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close down, investors take profits.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks closed lower on Tuesday after a late afternoon slide which brokers described as a short bout of overdue profit-taking.</p>
<p>&quot;This market was long overdue for a short-term correction, said Francis Wong, head of regional sales at DBS Securities.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index shed 65.39 points to 12,444.66 after trending sideways on robust volume during the morning session.</p>
<p>Trading was active all day, bringing turnover to HK$7.30 billion, greater than Friday's HK$6.67 billion.</p>
<p>Brokers said they thought selling would be limited.</p>
<p>&quot;While we saw some lock in profits today, locally based funds are not selling because the property market outlook is improving,&quot; said Patrick Ho, sales director at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;They will continue to hold onto their (equity market) positions if they think the property market improvements are going to flow back to the market, Ho said.</p>
<p>Technical analysts are cautious on the short-term outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term we are running into resistance at 12,600. The market is very overbought and we are likely to see limited upside for the remainder of the week,&quot; said Ted Chen, technical analyst at Technical Data Inc.</p>
<p>Chen put minor support at 12,300 points and major support at 11,900.</p>
<p>The property sector managed to fare the best in the afternoon sell-off, while the commercial and industrial sector suffered the heaviest profit-taking.</p>
<p>Swire Pacific dropped HK$1.50 to HK$70.25 and CITIC Pacific lost HK$0.70 to HK$37.00. Both shares were among the most actively traded on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cathay Pacific eased HK$0.40 to HK$12.20.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong led the property sector, putting on HK$0.25 to HK$62.25. Hopewell added HK$0.15 to HK$5.45.</p>
<p>Banking giant HSBC Holdings put on just HK$0.50 to close at HK$155.50, after trading up to a new record high of HK$156.50.</p>
<p>Subsidiary Hang Seng Bank, hit by profit-taking, declined HK$2.00 to HK$91.00.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
