<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135139" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: OPINION - From the Beehive - Maori issues the key.</title>
<headline>OPINION - From the Beehive - Maori issues the key.</headline>
<byline>Ian Templeton</byline>
<text>
<p>WELLINGTON, Oct 22 - On the campaign trail, pressed to indicate whether he favoured Labour or National as a coalition partner, Winston Peters used his famous side-step to stay: &quot;You can't begin to play until the cards have been dealt.&quot;</p>
<p>Now, post-election, Peters holds at least one ace, but is not letting on what other cards he has been dealt. The balance of power in parliament, in effect, represents the ace.</p>
<p>The question Peters has yet to resolve is how to play it. It could make a winning hand, but he could end up holding a busted flush.  </p>
<p>That depends on the way he works the dual negotiations (read bidding war) that began on Monday with National, and continues on Wednesday with both National and Labour.</p>
<p>Both National and Labour have set up negotiating teams which spent the weekend studying NZ First's election manifesto. Already, though, both parties are indicating, in recognition of the tidal wave that swept the Maori seats out of Labour control into the hands of NZ First, they could each mount aggressive programmes to lift health, education and living standards in the Maori population.  </p>
<p>Most voters, especially NZ First voters, have assumed the party would do a deal with Labour. But the difficulty is NZ First's electoral success is founded heavily on the disenchantment of Maori with Labour.</p>
<p>Maori having rejected Labour so thoroughly, NZ First's concern is that it cannot lightly donate its considerable Maori support straight back to Labour. Maori want something more than they have been offered this last 60 years.</p>
<p>That's where Maori demands touch on the more sensitive issues of sovereignty or separatism, and here there are paradoxes on which Peters will have to tread carefully.  </p>
<p>He himself may have been forgiven by his more fervent acolytes for the Maori-bashing that helped thrust him into the political spotlight. Clearly that identified him as a conservative. In contrast, his deputy Tau Henare is a radical.</p>
<p>Similarly, Tukoroirangi Morgan is a radical -- but Rana Waitai is a conservative.</p>
<p>The same kind of split is also apparent on, for example, how the assets of the Treaty of Waitangi Fisheries Commission should be distributed.  </p>
<p>Tau Henare is a strong advocate for urban Maori getting some of the assets; Tu Wyllie, the as-yet-unconfirmed MP for Te Tai Tonga, has been a vigorous lobbyist, (particularly on behalf of Ngai Tahu) for distributing the assets on a coastal population basis.</p>
<p>It may be that the first clue on how power will be exercised inside NZ First may come from the Treaty of Waitangi Fisheries Commission. Sir Graham Latimer, a long time National Party stalwart, may not last long as chairman.</p>
<p>If Sir Tipene O Regan, currently deputy chairman, succeeds him, it could mean that the conservatives are winning.  </p>
<p>That pointer could also have implications for economic policy.</p>
<p>Winston Peters may have clashed with National on the social implication of the 1991 budget, with its cuts to benefits, but he recognises that economic growth is the base on which to build better living standards.</p>
<p>NZ First's priority may be to lift employment rates for Maori, using some of the ideas employment spokesman Peter McCardle wanted to introduce when he was a National MP, and implementing its concept of workfare, where those on the dole would be paid about $10 an hour for part-time community work.</p>
<p>If these turn out to be NZ First's priorities, it should be relatively simple to share out portfolios, with NZ First taking Maori Affairs, Labour, Employment and Immigration and possibly Social Welfare.</p>
<p>Peters would be deputy prime minister, and might also expect a role in making economic policy, either (in Labour) as Minister of Economic Development, or (in National) as deputy Minister of Finance.  </p>
<p>The tough call, for whoever will be prime minister, is to drop current front-benchers in either Labour or National to make way for the new ministers nominated by Mr Thirteen Percent.</p>
<p>(Note - the opinions expressed in the above article are those of the writer and are not attributable to Reuters).</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
