<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135108" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Cochlear sees A$1 mln off 96/97 net.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Cochlear sees A$1 mln off 96/97 net.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bionic ear maker Cochlear Ltd said on Tuesday after tax profit for the year to June 30, 1996 is expected to be reduced by A$1 million due to the change in Australia's research and development (R&amp;D) tax concession rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Our after-tax profit for the current financial year is expected to be reduced by an estimated A$1 million as a result of the R&amp;D tax concession change,&quot; chairman David Penington told shareholders at the company's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Cochlear reported a net profit of A$10.86 million for the 1995/96 year. Penington said sales for the first half of 1996/97 will be lower than the same period a year earlier.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although the first half will be below the level of sales of the corresponding period of last year, the new products are expected to enable us to meet the challenging target of maintaining our profitability for this financial year,&quot; Penington said.</p>
<p>Penington said if the Australian dollar rises above current levels it could impact on 1996/97 profits.</p>
<p>&quot;The increased relative value of the Australian dollar over the past several months will, if it further strengthens, impact on profits,&quot; Penington said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The company has, however, taken forward cover to protect a substantial part of our earnings through the current financial year against any further rise in the value of the dollar,&quot; Penington said.</p>
<p>Penington said the group has adequate cash flow to meet all obligations and respond to short term changes in its businesses.</p>
<p>He said the company would not lower its current R&amp;D investment. &quot;...but it may be necessary to slow investments in any new areas of research,&quot; he said. In August, the Australian government announced in its 1996/97 budget the R&amp;D tax concession would fall to 125 percent from 150 percent.  </p>
<p>For the current financial year, Penington said sales in the European market are lower, partly attributable to anticipation of imminent availability of new products.</p>
<p>He said sales continue at a very satisfactory level in the United States and Asia.</p>
<p>At 2.50 p.m. (0450 GMT), Cochlear shares were 10 cents lower at A$3.20.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
