<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135137" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Final NZ election results expected Weds/Thurs.</title>
<headline>Final NZ election results expected Weds/Thurs.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The final outcome of New Zealand's October 12 general election should be known by Wednesday or Thursday, subject to any recounts sought by candidates or parties, chief electoral officer Phil Whelan said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Whelan said he had urged electorate returning officers to declare their official results as soon as possible after 7 p.m. Tuesday -- the cut-off deadline for receiving special results in the mail.  </p>
<p>&quot;A couple have said they still haven't got a few specials from overseas and may get them in the mail tonight,&quot; Whelan told the New Zealand Press Association.</p>
<p>More than 250,000 special votes had been cast and all of them must be checked by registrars to determine whether they qualified by being on electoral rolls, he said.</p>
<p>Election night counting gave the ruling National Party 44 seats, the main opposition Labour Party 37, the left wing Alliance 13 seats and nationalist New Zealand First 17 seats. New Zealand First is negotiating with both National and Labour over the formation of a new government.  </p>
<p>Whelan said the checking of special votes would continue on Wednesday, and possibly into Thursday, for one or two electorates -- &quot;if they are unable to complete the count of their large volume of paper on Wednesday&quot;.</p>
<p>Candidates and parties have three working days in which to apply for recount in a district court. Such an application would delay the final election outcome until next Tuesday or Wednesday, after the Labour Weekend holiday on Monday.</p>
<p>There were recounts for two electorates after the 1993 general election. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
