<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135175" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Top metal trader Hamanaka seen as quiet family man.</title>
<headline>Top metal trader Hamanaka seen as quiet family man.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>To the financial world, Yasuo Hamanaka was a feared player in the world copper market who became the key figure in the biggest financial scandal in history.</p>
<p>But to neighbours and friends he was a quiet family man whose demeanour belied the huge funds he once controlled as a top trader.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Tokyo prosecutors arrested Hamanaka, who is 48, on charges that he forged documents to create secret trading accounts for manipulation of the world copper market.</p>
<p>Sumitomo, a financial powerhouse, rocked world markets on June 13 when it announced it had fired Hamanaka, saying he had run up record losses of $1.8 billion on unauthorised trades that went on for more than a decade.</p>
<p>As copper prices collapsed after the scandal was announced, the company said in September that the losses had grown to $2.6 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Sumitomo is currently placing the blame only on him, but I can't believe their story at face value,&quot; a source close to the family said as the affair unfolded last summer.</p>
<p>While high-rolling traders were common in the financial world, especially during the boom years of the 1980s, Hamanaka did not fit the image.</p>
<p>His two-storey house in the city of Kawasaki, on the outskirts of Tokyo, has nothing to distinguish it in a neighbourhood populated by mid-level office workers rather than financial superstars.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Hamanaka would sometimes walk his dog around the neighbourhood during the weekend. He looked just like any other quiet salaried worker,&quot; a neighbour said.</p>
<p>&quot;I never realised he was such a world famous metal trader.&quot;</p>
<p>Neighbours say he drove a mid-range Nissan, eschewing the flashy BMWs beloved by high-profile traders worldwide. To commute, he crowded on to packed railway trains each morning like millions of other Japanese workers.</p>
<p>And in common with many Japanese workers, Hamanaka spent his entire career with one company.</p>
<p>Unusually, though, he spent 21 of his 26 years there trading in copper. Traders are usually shifted regularly from one section to another to keep them fresh.</p>
<p>&quot;He sometimes took weekend drives with his family and was a real family man. I'm so worried about his family after the copper scandal,&quot; the neighbour said.</p>
<p>Hamanaka once berated a Reuters reporter for calling him at home with a question about the copper market. &quot;It's OK to press me for any comment on the market in the office, but never get my family involved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hamanaka began his career in 1970 after graduating from Tokyo's Seikei University, a private university that is popular but not especially prestigious.</p>
<p>He and his wife have two children, a high-school-age son and a daughter who has just started work after graduating from university.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
