<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135106" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ dollar ends lower after touching eight-yr high.</title>
<headline>NZ dollar ends lower after touching eight-yr high.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar closed lower on Tuesday after selling out of Hong Kong and calls from Labour Party finance spokesman Michael Cullen for an easing in monetary policy brought it down from fresh eight-year highs.</p>
<p>The kiwi ended at US$0.7120/27 and 67.90 on its Trade-Weighted Index after trading a 0.7110-46 range on the day.</p>
<p>A chief dealer said the currency ran up strongly after the market opened short. &quot;There was further buying but (in later trading) there has been heavy selling out of Hong Kong that has really pushed it back and we are closing on the support around this 0.7110 level.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said a statement by Labour's Cullen that the Reserve Bank should ease added to the selling sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market was already squarish at the time but it was another factor that pushed it down. People have got to see that there is a possibility he could be finance minister in a few weeks. But he is only stating the obvious.&quot;</p>
<p>After the general election on October 12 the nationalist New Zealand First Party, which holds the balance of power, is entering negotiations with Labour and the caretaker National Party government over possible coalition agreements.  </p>
<p>&quot;(New Zealand First leader) Winston Peters is the key to it. Everyone seems to think he is not going to get any of his economic policies -- I can't imagine Winston going into coalition with anyone if they are not going to adopt any of his economic policies,&quot; the chief dealer said.</p>
<p>He said the Reserve Bank should not be influenced by politics, but if it says interest rates have gone too low and pushes the dollar higher while the coalition negotiations are on, it would make Peters' case for a change to the Reserve Bank framework stronger.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Reserve Bank should be aware that while they have higher rates they will never have a lower dollar.&quot;</p>
<p>In a commentary on Tuesday, Bankers Trust New Zealand said it did not expect the RBNZ to comment on the rising kiwi as long as interest rates moved lower in response.</p>
<p>The chief dealer said one U.S. dealer had said the combination of a AA+ economy and 10 percent short term interest rates was &quot;the sort of stuff you get in Cuba&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole world is sitting here -- telling New Zealand 'your rates are too high'. They are saying: 'If you don't push your rates down, we will push the dollar even higher'.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dealers said the selling out of Hong Kong was strong, so if the kiwi stayed below 0.7120 it could test back to 0.7080 overnight. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
