<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135146" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ Labour's Cullen calls for RBNZ easing.</title>
<headline>NZ Labour's Cullen calls for RBNZ easing.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Labour Party finance spokesman Michael Cullen said on Tuesday it was time for the Reserve Bank to allow an easing in monetary conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The currency has quite clearly been pushed up by our high interest rates. The combination is putting enormous pressure on the export sector and there has to be serious concern about the downstream effects in terms of jobs and investment if monetary conditions are not allowed to ease,&quot; Cullen said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Cullen was commenting on the rise of the New Zealand dollar, which hit a fresh eight-year high of US$0.7146 and 68.08 on its Trade-Weighted Index early on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cullen noted the Reserve Bank's last economic forecasts in September assumed a TWI of 65 and 90-day bank bill rates around 10 percent. Ninety-day rates were around 9.28 percent at the time his statement was released.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clearly important that monetary conditions are allowed to ease, that the dollar and interest rates are allowed to fall back,&quot; Cullen said.  </p>
<p>Labour is to start negotiations with nationalist New Zealand First on Wednesday on forming a coalition after an inconclusive general election 10 days ago, and has said it sees Cullen as the sole choice for finance minister.</p>
<p>NZ First is also negotiating with the caretaker National Party government. Its leader Winston Peters has repeatedly said he wants to drive the New Zealand dollar lower, but his office on Tuesday declined comment on the currency's latest highs.  </p>
<p>Cullen said last week's lower-than-expected September quarter inflation figures had been achieved at the cost of punitively high interest rates over the last two years.</p>
<p>He called for a more balanced approach to economic policy rather than sole reliance on the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
