<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135200" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Suharto urges non-oil exports boost.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Suharto urges non-oil exports boost.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's President Suharto on Tuesday urged local businessmen to boost non-oil exports in a bid to trim a widening current account deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;The challenges that we face include limited job opportunities, education and training and widening of the current account deficit,&quot; Suharto said in a speech while inaugurating an export products exhibition.</p>
<p>&quot;In recent years we all have worked hard to increase non-oil exports....In the years to come, our task will be more difficult as the deficit is widening,&quot; Suharto said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have said that the increase of non-oil exports must be a goal for the entire nation,&quot; Suharto said.</p>
<p>Industry and Trade Minister Tunky Ariwibowo, also speaking at the ceremony, said non-oil exports rose by 15.13 percent in 1995, compared with growth of 12.12 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth is below target. Imports of capital goods and consumption goods grew at 27.36 percent and 12.91 percent respectively in 1995. This caused a balance of payments deficit because total export values were lower than import values,&quot; Ariwibowo said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the effort to increase exports to the government target of 19.2 percent growth a year, cooperation between government and private sectors is needed. The government will continue deregulation measures in all sectors, including cuts in levies,&quot; Ariwibowo said.</p>
<p>He said the government would also seek new markets for Indonesian goods.</p>
<p>Indonesia has estimated its current account deficit would widen to $8.7 billion in fiscal 1996/97 (April-March) or about four percent of gross domestic product (GDP), from $7.0 billion or about 3.2 percent of GDP in 1995/96.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
