<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135208" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan dollar ends sharply down to T$27.550.</title>
<headline>Taiwan dollar ends sharply down to T$27.550.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Taiwan dollar closed sharply lower against its U.S. counterpart on Tuesday as late, active U.S. dollar buying pushed down the local unit to the lowest level since late July, dealers said.</p>
<p>The local unit ended at an intraday low of T$27.550 against Monday's T$27.500 close. Turnover was an active US$249 million.  </p>
<p>Dealers reported a sudden burst of U.S. dollar buying in the last 15 minutes by serveral foreign banks. Once the Taiwan dollar broke T$27.51, it immediately hit T$27.550.</p>
<p>&quot;We can say the Taiwan dollar is now back to fundamentals,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;In the past few weeks, the Taiwan dollar resisted to follow the overseas trend of a firming U.S. dollar because foreign funds had actively entered the domestic stock market,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, foreign funds have been net sellers in recent sessions in the stock market, giving chance for the Taiwan dollar to depreciate,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Dealers said weakness in the Taiwan dollar also reflected recent interest rate cuts by several major Taiwan commercial banks which have cast a bearish tone over the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Rising U.S. dollar demand nearing the end of the month and especially the year was also a factor behind the Taiwan dollar depreciation,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the trading range to expand after Tuesday. The range had been stuck in narrow T$27.48-50 band in the past several weeks.</p>
<p>For Wednesday, a T$27.52-58 range was seen.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
