<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135215" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Associated Kaolin in Gabon timber deal.</title>
<headline>Associated Kaolin in Gabon timber deal.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Associated Kaolin Industries Bhd said on Tuesday that it had agreed to buy Gabon timber concession holder Winnerpac Sdn Bhd for 36 million ringgit.</p>
<p>In a statement, the kaolin and timber products maker said it had made the pact with Landzen Development Sdn Bhd to buy 800,000 shares of Winnerpac for 45 ringgit a share, representing the entire share capital of Winnerpac.</p>
<p>Associated Kaolin's stock was suspended on Monday pending an announcement. Its stock closed at 13.10 ringgit on Friday.</p>
<p>Under an agreement with Societe Forestiere De Makokou, a company incorporated in Gabon, West Africa, Winnerpac has the right to downstream timber processing and related activities on three lands totalling 104,758 hectares (258,752 acres) for tenures of up to 20 years, the statement said.</p>
<p>Based on an average annual harvest of 300,000 cubic metres from Gabon concessions and a projected average profit margin of $30 per cubic metre, Associated Kaolin said the operations could yield profit before tax of about 22.5 million ringgit per year.</p>
<p>Winnerpac's share of profit is 90 percent, with Societe Forestiere getting 10 percent. Under that ratio, Winnerpac's average profit before tax per year would be 20.25 million ringgit, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
