<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135216" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai bourse seeks gains from off-floor trading.</title>
<headline>Shanghai bourse seeks gains from off-floor trading.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Shanghai Stock Exchange is hoping that large-scale, off-floor trading started last week will help it catch up with its Shenzhen counterpart, which has been using the method since 1993, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The exchange launched the computerised off-floor trading after a two-month trial period, and more than 100 domestic brokerages and securities branches around China have begun to use it to trade on the exchange, they said.</p>
<p>The exchange has ruled that securities offices in Shanghai only have to retain one trading seat on the bourse's floor and can do the bulk of their trading through remote terminals.</p>
<p>Exchange officials decline to say what percentage of current trading volume is off-floor trading, but the exchange has said that it wants off-floor trading to eventually take up the lion's share of its business.</p>
<p>In Shenzhen, off-floor trading started in July 1993, and accounts for more than 99 percent of trading volume, an exchange official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Shanghai exchange has come under increasing pressure from brokers in recent months to take measures to improve business and liquidity in the face of a growing challenge from Shenzhen, analysts said.</p>
<p>Trading volume on the Shenzhen stock exchange is now regularly double that of the Shanghai exchange, a dramatic turn-around from a year ago when people in the markets were asking whether Shenzhen had a future at all.</p>
<p>In the first nine months of this year, Shenzhen's stock turnover hit 574 billion yuan ($69.16 billion) against Shanghai's 483 billion yuan, exchange figures show.</p>
<p>&quot;The recent surging volume in Shenzhen is partly due to convenience derived from mature off-floor trading,&quot; said a senior stock analyst with a major Chinese brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;Off-floor trading is one of the measures Shanghai is taking to compete with Shenzhen,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Chinese brokers who have used the system said off-floor trading had already improved the Shanghai exchange's capacity, speeding up trading and helping to reduce costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Off-floor trading will help the Shanghai exchange to multiply its trading capacity,&quot; said Xu Zhiling, deputy general manager of the securities trading department of China Guotai Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;We use the system and find it much convenient for the company and for investors,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But brokers said reliability of the remote computer system for off-floor trading in Shanghai had yet to be fully tested due to the current relatively low trading volumes.</p>
<p>Overseas brokers, who can only trade foreign currency B shares and not the domestic A shares which make up most of the trading volume, said there was little value in off-floor trading for them.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign brokers are not concerned about off-floor trading because most of their customers are foreigners and fund managers and institutional investors,&quot; said Bruce Richardson, HG Asia's chief representative in Shanghai.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
