<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135242" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL overnight drops to 6.2/3 pct vs 8.0 on maturity.</title>
<headline>KL overnight drops to 6.2/3 pct vs 8.0 on maturity.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The overnight interbank rate dropped to 6.2/3 percent against 8.0 percent previously due to the maturity of a central bank deposit, dealers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the maturity gave the system fresh liquidity, which is expected to leave the system on Wednesday after payment for a Bank Negara bill issue.  </p>
<p>The dealers said there were two issues of Bank Negara bills totalling one billion ringgit. While 500 million ringgit will come from a maturing bill issue, a large part of the rest would come from the central bank maturity.</p>
<p>The maturing deposit was raised by Bank Negara as part of its open market intervention operations last month.</p>
<p>It regularly intervenes in the money market to control liquidity and set interest rates, but it does not disclose the amount it has raised.</p>
<p>Earlier, other interbank rates were mostly steady as banks held back funds for the Bank Negara bill issue, dealers said.  </p>
<p>One-week money was at 7.00/10 percent against 7.05/15, while two-week at 7.10/20 and one-month at 7.15/20 were unchanged.</p>
<p>Two-month at 7.15/18, three-month at 7.16/19 and six-month at 7.20/23 were three to five basis points lower.</p>
<p>Interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange were marginally higher though volumes shrank due to a steady trend in the cash market, futures dealers said.</p>
<p>At 0730 GMT, the Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate December contract was up one point at 92.85. Volumes for all contracts was just 74 lots.</p>
<p>- Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
