<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135241" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai fixed-income funds grow as stocks languish.</title>
<headline>Thai fixed-income funds grow as stocks languish.</headline>
<byline>Anuchit Nguyen</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai fixed-income funds are growing substantially this year as a prolonged slump in the stock market prompts local retail investors to seek sanctuary elsewhere, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very bullish about fixed-income funds. The size of fixed-income funds has grown substantially to about...90 billion baht now,&quot; said Teera Phutrakul, president of Thai Asia Mutual Fund Co Ltd.</p>
<p>According to data from Thai Farmers Asset Management Co Ltd, the outstanding amount in fixed-income funds at the end of September rose by 334 percent to 92.18 billion baht ($3.69 billion) from a mere 21.23 billion baht at the end of last year.</p>
<p>A fixed-income fund is a mutual fund that invests mainly in fixed-yield financial instruments such as short-term notes and bonds.</p>
<p>Teera said that when the mutual-fund industry was liberalised in 1992, only about one percent of the funds targeted fixed-income investments, whereas investors today can now choose between a roughly equal number of fixed-income and equity funds.</p>
<p>He blames the stock market's prolonged slump -- which has led to poor performances by most equity mutual funds -- for the increased interest in fixed-income funds by retail investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock market has been bearish for more than three years with little possibility of any recovery in the near term,&quot; Vichate Tantiwanich, first senior vice president at Thai Farmers Asset Management, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There were large amounts of funds shifting into fixed-income funds from equity investment, reflecting the substantial growth of the funds in the first nine months,&quot; Vichate said.</p>
<p>The key SET index is presently trading at three-year lows on decelerating economic growth and concern over Thailand's political uncertainty.</p>
<p>The popularity of fixed-income funds can also be attributed to their returns, which are higher than those offered by bank deposits due to tax incentives, said Vivan Tharahiranchote, the president of One Investment Management Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Teera said the growing amount of money being poured into fixed-income funds had also helped Thai bond markets develop by creating demand for bonds in primary and second markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The fixed-income funds are now the major players in primary and secondary bond markets. There are several bond issues where the funds snapped up 50 percent of the initial placement,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
