<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135212" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia's Mahathir urges self-censorship.</title>
<headline>Malaysia's Mahathir urges self-censorship.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said information technology had grown too fast for his government to control properly and called for self-censorship by consumers and providers.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the information explosion era caused by sophisticated telecommunications equipment,&quot; Mahathir said at the opening of a new broadcast centre for Malaysia's commercial television station TV3 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Previously, the government could control broadcast media by outright ownership of stations or by licensing them.</p>
<p>But today Malaysians can receive foreign information through the Internet and satellite television easily and cheaply and the information can be transferred to tape or hard disc for further dissemination, all outside the control of governments.</p>
<p>&quot;What is happening is that advanced telecommunications technology is moving too fast for governments to make laws, policies or mechanisms to control it,&quot; Mahathir said.</p>
<p>Foreign propaganda, deviant teachings and pornography can be disseminated through advanced telecommunications as easily as dangerous drugs, despite stringent laws and enforcement, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Censorship of information must be done by users of the telecommunications systems themselves. They must know what is good for them and what needs to be rejected..,&quot; Mahathir said.</p>
<p>Television and radio stations &quot;which soon will have hundreds of channels, play a key role in the efforts to stem the flow of negative materials that we face&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;They must not only censor the programmes and materials they broadcast, but must also make an effort to choose programmes that can form good behaviour as well as give entertainment.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We must not be fanatics who reject everything, but we also do not need people who are too liberal or not responsible as censors at our broadcast stations,&quot; Mahathir added.</p>
<p>Mahathir, who in August launched an information technology zone aimed at attracting world-class multi-media companies, has of late de-emphasised the role of government in controlling information.</p>
<p>His government has promised there would be no censorship or controls in the so-called &quot;multi-media super corridor&quot; except on distribution within Malaysia of material deemed offensive.</p>
<p>Malaysia has so far declined to follow neighbouring Singapore in curbing local access to &quot;undesireable&quot; internet sites.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
