<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135219" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Jinhai applies to issue 21.50 million A shares.</title>
<headline>Jinhai applies to issue 21.50 million A shares.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hainan Jinhai Co Ltd has filed an application with the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) to make an offer of 21.50 million A shares and list the equity in Shenzhen, a company spokeswoman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jinhai has also applied to the CSRC to float 7.80 million staff shares, issued at one yuan per share, along with the A shares, the spokeswoman told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin.</p>
<p>Jinhai, based in Haikou, the capital of Hainan province, is chiefly engaged in processing nonferrous metals, the official said.</p>
<p>She said Jinhai's share offer application is being supported by the China National Nonferrous Metals Industry Corporation.</p>
<p>Jinhai aims to inject the proceeds from the offer into its main business, she said.</p>
<p>The official said Jinhai is forecasting net earnings of 18.53 million yuan for 1996. She did not provide any comparative figures.</p>
<p>Jinhai now has total share capital of 65 million shares, comprising 39.315 million founder shares, 12.685 million legal person shares and 13 million internal staff shares.  </p>
<p>The official said Shanghai Guotai Securities has been named the chief underwriter for the offer and Jinhai's listing promoter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
