<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135211" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures end down but off lows.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures end down but off lows.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei futures ended weak but off their lows on Tuesday, as uncertainty about the direction of Japanese government policy after Sunday's election continued to weigh on the market.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei 225 December contract recovered from a low of 21,060 to end at 21,195 against a previous settlement at 21,245.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as it stays above 21,125, it should consolidate to head higher,&quot; said a trader with a local institution, adding that the December Nikkei would need to close above 21,360 to signal a clearer uptrend.  </p>
<p>Dealers said players were awaiting the formation of a ruling coalition after the Liberal Democratic Party's failure to gain a majority in Sunday's general election.</p>
<p>The trader players were also concerned about how Japanese manufacturers would be affected by the current high levels of crude oil prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan is a net importer of energy and crude oil prices have been buoyant, which is the reason the Nikkei can't go higher, faster,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
