<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135243" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs surge toward close, rise to new high.</title>
<headline>JGBs surge toward close, rise to new high.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key December Japanese government bond futures ended sharply higher and set a new high in late afternoon trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Traders said the December's advance was led by purchases related to hedge demand by banks which paid fixed interest rates in the swap market.</p>
<p>&quot;Purchases to fulfil hedging needs were first seen yesterday,&quot; said a brokerage trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The swap market lacks liquidity, so once things start moving there seems to be a tendency to shift to Euroyen futures and JGB futures to satisfy hedging needs,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The December reached a new high of 123.96, and ended at 123.90, up sharply from Monday's 123.58. Turnover was 41,128 contracts.</p>
<p>Regarding the December's surge in the afternoon, a city bank trader said: &quot;Those who bought stock index futures and sold bond futures before the elections are unwinding their positions now.&quot;</p>
<p>Expectations of a money flow from investment funds, set up under a government scheme to clear up the bad loan mess at failed mortgage firms, into the JGB market may also be supporting the market, the city bank trader said.  </p>
<p>There was talk that agricultural financial institutions and the New Financial Stabilisation Fund may buy the soon-to-be issued 10-year JGBs, the brokerage trader said.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance said on Tuesday, its auction of 2.9 percent 10-year JGBs produced a lowest price of 100.35 yen. MOF said the average price was 100.40.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to have been some demand from regional investors and some city banks,&quot; the brokerage trader said.</p>
<p>Since there was some concern earlier about how the auction would turn out, the results may have reassured the market, and contributed to the bullish sentiment, he added.  </p>
<p>Traders said they are watching to see whether government-guaranteed and municipal bonds will be offered at a coupon rate of 2.9 percent or three percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The terms are to be set tomorrow, and it's hard to tell at this point which coupon rate will be adopted,&quot; a trader for a city bank's securities affiliate said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Wataru Kubo said on Tuesday the three parties in the outgoing coalition have not made a decision on forming an extra stimulative budget for this year. Traders said few market participants believe a large supplementary budget is a viable option. -- Masayuki Kitano, Tokyo Treasury Desk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
