<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135220" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo gold futures firm, tracking strong bullion.</title>
<headline>Tokyo gold futures firm, tracking strong bullion.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yen-denominated gold futures ended firmer across the board on Tuesday, buoyed by firmer spot gold prices and the yen's slip, traders said.</p>
<p>Gold prices ranged from four to six yen per gram higher, with benchmark August finishing up six yen at 1,367 yen.</p>
<p>Traders said they tended to take a slightly bullish view of the gold futures market, after the benchmark August contract finally broke out of range trade between 1,330 and 1,360 yen.</p>
<p>Spot gold was a tad stronger at $381.90/382.20 per ounce at the Tokyo close, against $381.75/382.25 in New York on Monday.  </p>
<p>Private investors were tending to liquidate their longs, especially in the December contract, while building fresh longs in distant months, based on views that the yen has more room to dip against the dollar, the traders said.</p>
<p>In the bullion market, selling by Japanese trade houses earlier in the day was overwhelmed by buying interest from overseas investors, the traders said.</p>
<p>One trader said spot gold prices were likely to probe upper resistance at $383 per ounce in the near term, as technical sentiment in the Tokyo gold futures market has improved slightly.  </p>
<p>Other precious metals futures settled firmer on the heels of gold.</p>
<p>Platinum futures were off early highs as profit-taking selling above 1,380 yen for distant months put a lid on further gains. TOCOM benchmark August platinum ended two yen higher at 1,382 yen per gram, while other months were two to four yen higher.</p>
<p>TOCOM August palladium settled three yen firmer at 425 yen per gram. Other futures ranged from three to seven yen better.</p>
<p>August silver ended up 1.1 yen at 181.1 yen per 10 grams.</p>
<p>--Tokyo Commodity Desk, (81-3-3432-7431)--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
