<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135206" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HSBC Americas Q3 net income up 25 pct.</title>
<headline>HSBC Americas Q3 net income up 25 pct.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>HSBC Americas Inc, whose principal subsidiary is Marine Midland Bank, said on Tuesday net income for the third quarter of 1996 increased to US$101 million from $81 million a year earlier.  </p>
<p>The bank said in a statement received in Hong Kong that return on common equity rose to 22.09 percent from 18.64 percent a year earlier and total assets increased to US$22.2 billion from $19.9 billion over the same period.</p>
<p>It said the higher net income reflected improved net interest income resulting from purchases and growth in Marine Midland's core business lines.  </p>
<p>It specifically cited Marine Midland's retail businesses, higher investment and money market assets, and the acquisition in the second quarter of Hang Seng Bank Ltd's two New York City branches and East River Savings Bank's 11 branches in the New York metropolitan area.</p>
<p>Hong Kong-based Hang Seng Bank is 61.51 percent held by HSBC Holdings Plc.</p>
<p>&quot;Third quarter earnings were strong, core business was good, and acquisitions completed earlier in the year have enhanced our revenue stream without a corresponding increase in the expense base,&quot; said James Cleave, chief executive officer of HSBC Americas.</p>
<p>&quot;During the quarter we also announced the acquisitions of First Federal Savings Bank and J.P. Morgan's U.S. dollar clearing business, which position the institution for future growth.&quot;</p>
<p>In the nine months ended September 30, 1996, net income rose 26 percent to US$276 million from US$219 million in the first nine months of 1995.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
