<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135313" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: FOCUS-Singapore GDP growth seen at 6.4 pct in 1996.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Singapore GDP growth seen at 6.4 pct in 1996.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore's economy is likely to grow by only 6.4 percent this year, compared with 8.8 percent in 1995 and 10.2 percent in 1994, a Reuters' poll of leading financial institutions suggested on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The poll of 11 economists, carried out after Monday's announcement of a surprise 6.2 percent fall in the island's non-oil exports in September, shows estimates are still being cut to reflect the current slump in global electronics demand.  </p>
<p>Electronics, computers and related products account for about 50 percent of Singapore's total industrial production and almost 60 percent of its non-oil exports.</p>
<p>A similar Reuters poll last week forecast Singapore's gross domestic product (GDP) would grow by 6.5 percent this year. A poll in September forecast 1996 growth at 7.1 percent.</p>
<p>But Monday's non-oil export figures were at the bottom of expectations and encouraged several economists to cut their forecasts for 1996 growth by as much as 0.5 percentage point.  </p>
<p>&quot;The trade numbers were worse than I thought,&quot; said Liew Yin Sze, economist at local brokerage J.M. Sassoon. &quot;The electronics sector was bad and almost every other sector was also weaker.&quot;</p>
<p>Monday's figures showed a 23.7 percent year-on-year fall in Singapore's exports of telecommunication equipment and a 16.2 percent fall in exports of electrical machinery.</p>
<p>But it also showed a 20 percent year-on-year decline in exports of crude materials and a 10.8 percent fall in drinks and tobacco products.  </p>
<p>The result of the latest Reuters poll contrasts with Singapore's most recent official forecast, restated by Trade and Industry Minister Yeo Cheow Tong as recently as September 24, of &quot;seven to eight percent&quot; growth for 1996.</p>
<p>One economist said he expected the government to cut its official growth forecast for the year sometime over the next few weeks, probably at its quarterly economic briefing in mid-November.</p>
<p>The poll left the average forecast for Singapore's GDP in 1997 unchanged at 7.0 percent year-on-year.  </p>
<p>Many economists said they had not had time to readjust fully their quarterly growth estimates in light of the recent trade data, but several shaved their forecasts by a few tenths of a percentage point.</p>
<p>Most now expect Singapore's GDP growth in the third quarter to average slightly over 3.0 percent year-on-year. Growth in the fourth quarter was expected to average around 4.9 percent.</p>
<p>Eddie Lee, economist at brokerage Vickers Ballas, said he had adjusted downwards his forecast for Singapore's growth this year, but still expected a strong rebound in 1997 when the current electronics downturn was over.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am looking for a full recovery next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
