<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135395" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan bureaucrats battle on Euroyen bond tax break.</title>
<headline>Japan bureaucrats battle on Euroyen bond tax break.</headline>
<byline>Chikafumi Hodo</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Ministry of Finance (MOF) says it may drop plans to kill off a law designed to encourage Euroyen bond purchases by foreigners -- but only if the Trade Ministry can prove it is not providing a tax loophole.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Ministry of International Trade and Industry (MITI) can come up with up a decent scheme that could confirm non-Japanese residents are the main buyers of Euroyen bonds, then we may consider retaining the law,&quot; a senior official at MOF's International Tax Affairs Division told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>The law was originally designed to encourage Euroyen bond purchases by overseas investors and to boost the global use of the Japanese currency by providing a withholding tax break on bond purchases by foreigners.</p>
<p>But MOF said the main buyers of Euroyen bonds have been Japanese, and it wants to repeal the law to close a tax loophole. Japanese firms are able to buy the bonds through overseas subsidiaries.</p>
<p>Meanwhile MITI, along with a group of leading domestic firms, fiercely opposes the finance ministry's plan to scrap the tax exemption, saying it would be detrimental to fund-raising by Japanese companies.</p>
<p>The Euroyen bond market is one of the main fund-raising places for Japanese firms, which issued a total of 528 billion yen ($4.71 billion) worth of yen bonds in the five months to August, traders said.</p>
<p>Broking and underwriting business in the lucrative Euroyen bond market is also the main source of profit for foreign brokers, they added.</p>
<p>After protests by MITI and companies, MOF is now showing willingness to retain the law -- on condition that MITI can demonstrate that it is not being abused.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very difficult to prove the law is benefiting only foreign buyers, but we will submit research on the Euroyen market to MOF,&quot; a MITI official said.</p>
<p>But the Finance Ministry's own study shows that the tax exemption goes beyond the original intended beneficiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we know, about 80 percent (of the bonds) are held by Japanese. In this situation, we cannot simply leave tax exemption privileges as they are,&quot; the MOF official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyhow, we will see what MITI comes up with,&quot; said the official.</p>
<p>The legislation, which requires a review every two years, was first passed in 1985. The law could expire as early as next April if the Finance Ministry decides to scrap it.</p>
<p>MOF had said it was intending to abolish the exemption rule altogether by April 1998, when it is also expected to abolish the current 40-day lock-up rule on domestic sales of Euroyen bonds issued by Japanese borrowers.</p>
<p>The rule bans brokers from selling Euroyen bonds to Japanese residents for 40 days after the launch of the bond. It is aimed at protecting the domestic corporate bond market, which offers fewer price advantages than Euro markets, traders said. ($1=112 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
