<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135362" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: More Japan firms tapping bond market for funds.</title>
<headline>More Japan firms tapping bond market for funds.</headline>
<byline>Hiroko Nakata</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese companies, which have depended heavily on bank loans for funds in the past, are tapping bond markets at a record-setting pace this year.</p>
<p>Analysts say firms are likely to issue a record amount of domestic corporate bonds in the current financial year to next March, aiming to save on costs and take advantage of recent deregulation.</p>
<p>&quot;Blue-chip companies can get cheaper money by raising funds by themselves (in the capital market), as credit ratings on banks are lower than their (the firms') ratings now,&quot; said Yasuhiro Matsumoto, senior associate director for financial advisory services at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Credit rating agencies have lowered their ratings for banks due to bad loans afflicting the industry, making it more expensive for them to raise money. That in turn has forced banks to set higher rates on loans to firms, analysts said.</p>
<p>Hajime Miwa, an economist at Fuji Securities Co, said a structural change was occurring in corporate fund-raising.</p>
<p>&quot;Borrowers can choose banks now, rather than customers being selected by banks,&quot; Miwa said. &quot;Banks' bad loan problems ended up lowering their credibility,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many banks are suffering from bad loans as a result of a sharp drop in land prices following the bursting of the &quot;bubble economy&quot; of inflated asset and stock prices in the early 1990s. Many loans were backed by real estate as collateral.</p>
<p>Miwa added that the trend of greater bond issuance is supported by deregulation in the capital market, allowing companies to issue domestic bonds more easily.</p>
<p>The total amount of domestic corporate bonds -- straight bonds, convertibles and samurais -- reached 8.8377 trillion yen ($78.9 billion) in the 1995/96 financial year, the Bond Underwriters' Association of Japan said. That is almost double the 4.73 trillion yen ($42.2 billion) in 1990/91. Samurai bonds are yen-denominated debt issued in Japan by foreign entities.</p>
<p>The issued amount of bonds hit 6.8465 trillion yen ($61.1 billion) in the first half of 1996/97 and is on track to set a record. Fuji Securities Co sees it hitting a record high of about 13 trillion yen ($116 billion) this business year.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the Ministry of Finance (MOF) abolished a requirement that firms needed to have a certain minimum rating to issue corporate bonds. It also deregulated the bonds' shelf registration system, in which companies register securities they plan to issue in the future, when market conditions are more favourable.</p>
<p>Previously, Japanese firms needed at least a BBB rating to issue unsecured bonds.</p>
<p>In Japan, firms that need funds traditionally depend on a so-called &quot;main bank&quot; to guarantee their interest-rate payments in case of default or delays in payments, said Hideki Goto, an analyst at debt rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's Corp.</p>
<p>This makes banks loans relatively more expensive than direct fund-raising in the capital market, such as by issuing shares or corporate bonds, he said.</p>
<p>Analysts say there have been several recent cases of companies turning away from the traditional system.</p>
<p>Computer software firm Softbank Corp has been an aggressive player in tapping capital markets, even at the cost of alienating a shareholder bank, the Industrial Bank of Japan Ltd (IBJ).</p>
<p>The long-term credit bank, a major lender of funds to Softbank in the past, said earlier this month that it had sold part of its stake in the firm.</p>
<p>A Japanese business daily said the reason for the sale was that Softbank had been relying more on the capital market and short-term bank loans to fund its expansion than on the IBJ.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Softbank said the firm's long-term demand has been covered by funds raised from the capital market, while its short-term demand had been covered by bank loans.</p>
<p>&quot;The top priority of Softbank is to raise funds on more preferable terms, and it does not have a very traditional Japanese relationship with banks,&quot; Morgan Grenfell's Matsumoto said.</p>
<p>But he warned that it would be better for firms looking for venture capital, such as Softbank, which needs a huge amount of capital to build up its business, to raise funds in the stock market instead of the bond market, which carefully monitors the ratings of companies in making investment decisions.</p>
<p>But Matsumoto also said the traditional ties between Japanese firms and their main banks are unlikely to break overnight.</p>
<p>($1=112 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
