<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135300" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Proton declines comment on Lotus deal.</title>
<headline>Proton declines comment on Lotus deal.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Perusahaan Otomobil Nasional Bhd (Proton) declined to comment on Tuesday on a report that is acquiring an 80 percent stake in British luxury sports car maker Lotus Group.</p>
<p>Tengku Mahaleel Tengku Ariff, Vice Chairman of Strategy and Operations at car manufacturer Proton, said through his secretary that he could not comment about the reports on the proposed deal.</p>
<p>Proton chairman Yahaya Ahmad could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The Asian Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday that Proton was proposing to acquire the stake for 210 million ringgit in cash, and assumption of Lotus' 51 million ringgit in debt.  </p>
<p>The Journal quoted auto industry executives close to the proposed deal as saying Proton reached a preliminary agreement late last week to buy the stake.</p>
<p>In striking the deal, Proton's Yahaya appeared to have outbid international rivals, including Daewoo Motor Co  DWGR.CN of South Korea for Lotus, an automotive engineering firm and maker of luxury sports cars, the article said.</p>
<p>An announcement was expected in the coming week. Proton's stock was up 10 Malaysian cents to 15.10 ringgit at midday on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lotus chairman Romano Artioli said on September 19 Lotus would announce a new partner for the company &quot;within days&quot;. Lotus is currently owned by Artioli-controlled, Luxembourg-registered Bugatti International SA.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
