<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135376" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan stocks end lower on late profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Taiwan stocks end lower on late profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed lower on Tuesday as investors' lack of confidence in the market's upside triggered late profit-taking and erased earlier gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index, which stayed higher for most of the session, suffered heavy selling in the last hour to close 14.85 points or 0.23 percent lower at 6,426.30.</p>
<p>Turnover was a modest T$38.05 billion.</p>
<p>The market had opened higher as some investors sought to lift the index out of a recent slump, which caused it to drop nearly 200 points since October 14.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market showed signs of life early, but the late selling made it obvious that confidence on the maket was still very weak,&quot; said Wang Jieh of Foremost Investment.</p>
<p>Profit-taking spread across most sectors, with electronic shares losing 0 56 percent and textiles and plastics both falling by 0.70 percent. Opto Tech plunged by the daily seven-percent limit or T$2.40 to T$32.90, and Systex lost 6.37 percent or T$2.60 to T$38.20.</p>
<p>The heavily-weighted financial shares fought off late selling to close 0.25 percent higher, giving the overall market some support, brokers said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Financials had already fallen plenty in the past week, so the sector found a better support today,&quot; Wang said.</p>
<p>Brokers expected the market to continue languishing in a consolidation on Wednesday. A 6,400-6,450 range was seen.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Chen (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
