<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135383" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Tongdu Copper to offer A shares for Shenzhen list.</title>
<headline>Tongdu Copper to offer A shares for Shenzhen list.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anhui Tongdu Copper Co Ltd said on Tuesday it has been given the green light by the China Securities Regulatory Commission to launch an offer of 31 million A shares and list the stock on the Shenzhen bourse.</p>
<p>The offer, priced at 5.25 yuan per share, is due to be launched in Hefei, the capital of eastern China's Anhui province, on October 24 and completed on October 31, Tongdu said in a prospectus published in the official Securities Times.</p>
<p>Anhui Provincial International Trust and Investment Co has been named as the main underwriter for the offer and Tongdu's listing promoter, the prospectus said.</p>
<p>Tongdu, based in the city of Tonglin in Anhui province, said it has also received the approval of the CSRC to list four million staff shares, offered at face value of one yuan per share in 1992, along with the A stock.</p>
<p>Tongdu said it plans to use the bulk of the proceeds from the offer to upgrade copper processing technology.</p>
<p>Tongdu, set up in 1992 with registered capital of 40 million yuan, said it forecast net earnings of 45.22 million yuan for 1997 and 44.07 million yuan for this year, compared with 33.95 million yuan in 1995 and 5.57 million yuan the previous year.</p>
<p>It did not give a reason for its earnings surge last year.  </p>
<p>It said it racked up 17.99 million yuan in net profits in the January-June period of this year. It did not give a comparative figure.</p>
<p>Tongdu specialises in processing copper, gold and silver, and its core products include electrolytic copper, sulphuric acid, gold and silver, the prospectus said.</p>
<p>The firm said it currently has the capacity to turn out 45,000 tonnes of electrolytic copper, 128,000 tonnes of sulphuric acid, 1,600 kg of gold and 30,000 kg of silver a year.</p>
<p>Tongdu said electrolytic copper accounted for 76.82 percent of its sales in 1995, gold 10.57 percent, sulphuric acid 4.10 percent and silver 2.42 percent.</p>
<p>Tongdu said it had sales of 1.33 billion yuan last year, compared with only 31.86 million yuan in 1994.</p>
<p>It said some of its electrolytic copper and sulphuric acid was exported via its biggest shareholder, Tonglin Nonferrous Metals (Group) Co, to Europe, the U.S. and Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>Tongdu said it currently has total share capital of 109 million shares, including 99.90 million state shares, 1.10 million legal person shares and eight million employee shares.</p>
<p>Tonglin Nonferrous holds 96.60 million state shares, or 88.62 percent of Tongdu's oustanding shares outstanding.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
