<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135363" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Church denies HK cardinal to retire upon handover.</title>
<headline>Church denies HK cardinal to retire upon handover.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Roman Catholic bishop of Hong Kong, Cardinal John Baptist Wu Cheng-chung, will not retire at the British colony's handover to China next year, a church spokeswoman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;No, he is not retiring,&quot; said Mary Seung, director of the Hong Kong Catholic Communications Office, in response to media reports that the cardinal would step down on July 1, 1997, the day China resumes sovereignty of the British colony of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Pope John Paul II has announced the appointment of Shanghai-born Joseph Zeng, 64, as coadjutor bishop and John Tong as auxiliary bishop of Hong Kong.</p>
<p>But Seung said the papal appointments did not signal the departure of Wu, 71, who has not reached retirement age.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is helpful for a peaceful transition that the Holy Father appoints an auxillary bishop and coadjutor,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said that under canon law, he is required to retire at the age of 75.</p>
<p>&quot;He has to serve the diocese for 3-1/2 more years and that goes beyond the handover.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1988 Wu became the first Hong Kong priest to be elevated to the position of cardinal.</p>
<p>The Beijing government does not recognise the ultimate authority of the Vatican in religious affairs and insists that Chinese Catholics worshipping openly do so under the auspices of the state-sponsored Catholic Patriotic Association.</p>
<p>Hong Kong has about 270,000 Roman Catholics, the diocese said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
