<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135302" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends up on LME gains.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends up on LME gains.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended up on Tuesday due to overnight gains on the London Metal Exchange, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active February 1997 contract ended at 19,180 yuan ($2,310) per tonne, rising 270 yuan. It opened at 19,000 yuan, hitting and intra-day low of 18,950 and a high of 19,190.</p>
<p>November rose 180 to 18,860 yuan, December 260 to 18,880, January 270 to 19,100, March 200 to 19,200 and April 100 to 19,200.</p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 63,880 tonnes from 65,400.  </p>
<p>Copper opened higher and rose further before most contracts closed near their intra-day highs.</p>
<p>Traders said LME gains encouraged long position holders and short-covering pushed copper up for most of the session.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of the short-covering came from retail investors who are wary about the future trend in the short term,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;LME copper did not breach the $1,970 resistance level despite declines of stockpiles, which indicates the long- and mid-term downward trend may not change,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Traders said rebounds over the past two days had not changed the short-term weak market sentiment in Shanghai based on the over-supply of domestic spot copper.</p>
<p>&quot;The thin volume indicates investors lack confidence in the future trend,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>Analysts expect copper to meet strong resistance at the 19,500 yuan level in the next few days.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended down. November fell 110 to 13,380 yuan per tonne, December 200 to 13,200 and January 200 to 13,200.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 1,350 tonnes from 620.</p>
<p>($1=8.3000 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
