<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135336" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan leading indicator to top 50 mark in Sept - EPA.</title>
<headline>Japan leading indicator to top 50 mark in Sept - EPA.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's diffusion index of leading economic indicators is likely to rise above the so-called &quot;boom or bust&quot; mark of 50 in September after falling below that critical mark in August for the first time in five months, a senior official for the Economic Planning Agency (EPA) said on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>The official said the index of coincident indicators was also expected to rise above the 50 mark in September.</p>
<p>The EPA had announced previously that the index of leading economic indicators stood at 33.3 on a scale of 100 in August, while that of coincident indicators was 30.0.</p>
<p>&quot;The falls below the 50 mark in August were temporary, and the indices are likely to regain a level of above 50 in September,&quot; the official said. A temporary cut in output of cars and personal computers and production adjustment in semiconductors pushed down production-related indices which are components of the leading indicators, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
