<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135399" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Yuan closes unchanged against US dollar.</title>
<headline>Yuan closes unchanged against US dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan closed flat at 8.3000 against the U.S. dollar on Tuesday from Monday's close on the Shanghai-based interbank foreign exchange market.</p>
<p>The yuan opened up slightly at 8.2995 and hit an intra-day high of 8.2990 early in the session but then fell to consolidate below 8.3000 for most of the session, hitting a low of 8.3008.</p>
<p>Trading was active with most done around 8.3000, traders said.</p>
<p>Dealers said consistent selling prevented the yuan from bouncing back above the 8.3000 level as it did in the past two days.  </p>
<p>&quot;The yuan seems to have some difficulty standing above 8.30 because buying has decreased in the wake of intervention from the central bank over the past two days,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>But a second dealer said that strong pro-yuan sentiment will push the yuan back above 8.3000.</p>
<p>Dealers expect the yuan to consolidate around the key 8.3000 level on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The yuan closed down at 7.3605 from 7.3501 against 100 Japanese yen and ended up at an intra-day high of 1.0728 from 1.0738 against the Hong Kong dollar.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
