<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135353" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nippon Life says to launch joint venture in China.</title>
<headline>Nippon Life says to launch joint venture in China.</headline>
<dateline>OSAKA, Japan 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nippon Life Insurance Co will launch an insurance joint venture in China, Nippon Life president Josei Itoh told reporters on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>Itoh said that the company and China's biggest insurer, the People's Insurance Co of China (PICC), would decide later on the specifics of the joint venture in China.</p>
<p>Nippon Life would be the first foreign company to specialise in providing life insurance coverage in China, Itoh said.</p>
<p>Among Japanese non-life insurers, only Tokio Marine &amp; Fire Insurance Co Ltd currently operates in China, he said.</p>
<p>Nippon Life said on Monday that it plans to set up a joint venture in the Philippines. It would become the first Japanese company to sell life insurance policies abroad, it said.  </p>
<p>The company said it and the Yuchengco Group of the Philippines would sign a contract by the year-end to establish a joint venture by next March.</p>
<p>Nippon Life will own 50 percent of the joint venture, which will be based in Manila. The rest will be owned by two Yuchengco Group firms -- 30 percent by Great Pacific Life Assurance Corp and 20 percent by Rizal Commercial Banking Corp.</p>
<p>Itoh said it also plans to buy a stake of up to nine percent in Thai life insurer Bangkok Life Assurance Ltd before the end of March next year.</p>
<p>Nippon Life is the largest Japanese insurer as well as one of the world's top providers of life cover. It has assets of about 39 trillion yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSAKA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
