<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135396" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Thailand IOT in 5-year plan to renew tanker fleet.</title>
<headline>Thailand IOT in 5-year plan to renew tanker fleet.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's private oil trading firm International Oil Tanking Pte Ltd (IOT) is planning to renew its medium-range tanker fleet over the next five years, a company source said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>IOT has informed shipping brokers of its intention to sell all six of its 30,000-tonne tankers over the next few years and to replace them with younger vessels, the source said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to reduce the overall age of our fleet to around 15 years,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>But the company has no plans to commission the building of new tankers. &quot;We are not building new ships,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Currently, IOT's 17-vessel fleet age, including one 320,000-tonne ultra large crude carrier (ULCC) and two very large crude carriers (VLCC), are about 20 years old.</p>
<p>The average age of IOT's medium-range fleet is between 21 and 22 years and the company is looking to buy newer tankers of between 12 and 15 years, he said.</p>
<p>IOT uses its fleet of medium and long range vessels to transport mainly middle distillates from the Middle East to Thailand, China and other Southeast Asian countries.  </p>
<p>It has also been using its large carriers as floating storage off Singapore or Fujairah in the United Arab Emirates to augment its trading positions.</p>
<p>The company recently expanded its trading activities to include fuel oil but this is still a small part of its total business, the source said.</p>
<p>Of the 17-vessels, one VLCC and two long-range vessels are dedicated as dirty tankers, he said.</p>
<p>-- Raj Rajendran, Singapore Newsroom (65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
