<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135347" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: GE-P&amp;W says close to Airbus superjumbo engine deal.</title>
<headline>GE-P&amp;W says close to Airbus superjumbo engine deal.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president of U.S. aero-engine joint venture GE-P&amp;W Engine Alliance said on Tuesday the group was close to a memorandum of understanding with the European Airbus Industrie consortium to supply superjumbo engines.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the final stages of an MOU with Airbus and expect it within days or weeks, and certainly before the end of the year,&quot; Larry Scott told reporters at the Seoul Air Show.</p>
<p>GE Aircraft Engines, a unit of General Electric, and United Technologies Corp unit Pratt and Whitney teamed up to build an engine for Boeing Co's 747-500X and 600X planes, which are bigger versions of the 747 jumbo.</p>
<p>GE Aircraft Engines said last month it would offer European Airbus Industrie the engine if the consortium builds its 3XX superjumbo, which would seat more than 500 passengers.</p>
<p>Scott said the engine to be offered to European Airbus, a GP7277 with 78,000 pounds of thrust, was in the final design stages. It would begin the certification process in January 1997, and start testing in 1998.</p>
<p>Certification was expected by the end of 1999, and the engines could be supplied before 2000.</p>
<p>The engine was part of the new GP7000 family of powerplants, Scott said.  </p>
<p>Scott forecast the global superjumbo market at between 500 and 1,200 planes. He did not give a timeframe.</p>
<p>&quot;Seventy percent of those will be delivered to the Asia/Pacific market. These planes haul large numbers of people long distances and this is an opportunity market for this type of aircraft,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom 822 -727 5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
