<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135444" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Kubo says no coalition decision on extra budget.</title>
<headline>Kubo says no coalition decision on extra budget.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Finance Minister Wataru Kubo told a news conference on Tuesday that the three parties in the outgoing coalition have not made a decision on forming an extra stimulative budget for this year.  </p>
<p>During the campaign for Sunday's Lower House election, officials from the Liberal Democratic Party called for a supplementary budget, featuring economic stimulative steps, worth about five trillion yen.</p>
<p>&quot;This is something that each party has called for during their election campaign. We have not made a decision, as coalition parties, to form a supplementary budget,&quot; Kubo said.</p>
<p>There are mixed views within business circles as to whether a large-scale stimulus package centering on public works spending would have a decisive impact on the economy, Kubo said.</p>
<p>He added there are misunderstandings among the public that public works spending would fall off in coming months and have a negative impact on the economy unless the government forms an extra budget.  </p>
<p>&quot;The budget for public works investment in the latter half of this fiscal year is enough to rival the amount implemented in the second half of the last fiscal year. The important thing now is to steadily implement the budget for 1996/97,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the same time Kubo expressed caution about forming an extra budget this year because it may delay the formation of next year's budget.</p>
<p>Japan's Finance Ministry usually comes up with a draft of the next year's budget by end-December, and it is debated in parliament from January.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to consider what effect the delay in the formation of next fiscal year's budget would have on the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that it was up to the next government to decide whether there was a need for a supplementary budget.</p>
<p>Separately, Kubo said he was not in a position to comment on Nichiei Finance Co Ltd's liquidation plans.</p>
<p>The financing firm on Tuesday filed for liquidation with the Yokohama district court and said it would work out a restructuring programme under court guidance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
