<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135484" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nichiei Fin to apply for liquidation, restructuring.</title>
<headline>Nichiei Fin to apply for liquidation, restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nichiei Finance Co Ltd said on Tuesday that it would apply for liquidation on Tuesday with the Yokohama District Court and work out a restructuring programme under court guidance.  </p>
<p>Nichiei Finance, which is a credit guarantee and financing company, said in a statement that its borrowing totalled 170.89 billion yen at the end of September 1996 and that the debts it guarantees totalled 820.65 billion yen on that same date.  </p>
<p>Nichiei Finance, a unit of lumber firm Nichiei Co Ltd, was hit hard by the bursting of Japan's bubble economy of inflated asset prices in the early 1990s. The company said it formed a restructuring plan in 1994 but its business continued declining.</p>
<p>&quot;We were considering revisions of the restructuring plan from April, but our unrealised asset losses were far larger than our estimate and we could not expect a recovery in our business environment. So we had to give up reviewing the plan,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering our characteristics as a credit guarantee company and seeking to maintain fairness to creditors, we have chosen to liquidate the company based on the commercial law and we will apply (for liquidation) at Yokohama District Court,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
