<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135428" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- Jeepney, bus and taxi operators filed separate petitions for fare increases yesterday as the Land Transportation Franchising and Regulatory Board failed to dissuade them from delaying their applications. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- President Fidel Ramos issued an executive order creating the Southern Philippines Council for Peace and Development which is expected to guarantee peace and progress in Mindanao (The Philippine Journal)</p>
<p>- President Fidel Ramos gave indications on Monday he would be shuffling his Cabinet soon. (MANILA CHRONICLE)</p>
<p>-The Catholic Bishops Conference of the Philippines, invoking democracy and human rights, yesterday urged President Fidel Ramos to allow Nobel Peace Prize winner Jose Ramos Horta into the country next month. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- Protest rallies and strikes against recent oil price increases paralysed transport and business operations in Mindanao on Monday but had almost no impact in Metro Manila. (MANILA BULLETIN)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- The government maintained its inflation targets in the fourth quarter of the year despite the combined effects of the oil and power rates. Government sources said inflation  targets for October have been maintained at 5.0 percent, 5.5 and 6.0, respectively. (PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>- President Fidel Ramos said on Monday he expected the country's gross national product to grow by 7.1 percent year-on-year in 1996. (PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>	  - Manila newsroom (632) 841 8938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
