<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135427" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Sampoerna to sell Astra stake --paper.</title>
<headline>Sampoerna to sell Astra stake --paper.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's largest cigarette company PT Hanjaya Mandala Sampoerna will sell its 2.85 percent stake in vehicle manufacturer Astra International, the Bisnis Indonesia newspaper reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sampoerna financial director Eka Dharmajanto Kasih was quoted as saying that Sampoerna Investment, the wholly-owned subsidiary which bought the stake last month, would sell the holding.</p>
<p>&quot;We will release our stake soon. One of the reasons to establish Sampoerna Investment was for short-term investment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sampoerna officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Kasih declined to say when the stake would be sold but added it could be as soon as the company received a good offer price.</p>
<p>Kasih also told Bisnis Indonesia that Sampoerna president director Putera Sampoerna was likely to hold on to the 9.81 percent stake in Astra that he bought on his own account and could even raise his holding.</p>
<p>He gave no further details.  </p>
<p>Sampoerna shares fell last month after the company announced its purchase in Astra. Brokers said the move appeared to signal that Sampoerna was moving away from its core business.</p>
<p>The shares rose on Monday after a weekend announcement that Sampoerna had cancelled a shareholders' meeting scheduled for November 2, which sources in the company said was likely to have considered a proposal to raise the stake in Astra.</p>
<p>On Monday Sampoerna closed at 20,250 rupiah, up 1,350.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
