<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135406" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila says new taxes to be finalised by year-end.</title>
<headline>Manila says new taxes to be finalised by year-end.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine government was optimistic its new tax package aimed at replacing a complicated system that has been widely abused would be finalised by year-end, a senior official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are optimistic that the comprehensive tax reform package will pass, the final version should come through by end of the year,&quot; finance secretary Roberto de Ocampo told reporters late on Monday.</p>
<p>The new tax package is crucial to the government's economic reform programme because it is designed to ensure a sustainable source of revenue.</p>
<p>But its implementation has been delayed in the legislature because of differing opinions over how beer and cigarettes should be taxed.</p>
<p>De Ocampo told reporters the tax reform package was one of the most important tasks before the government to ensure the benefits of economic reforms were sustained.</p>
<p>It was important because the Philippines had the lowest tax collection rate among East Asian countries, he said.</p>
<p>Philippine revenue from taxes amount to just about 16 percent of gross national product compared to over 20 percent for some other countries in the region.  </p>
<p>A Department of Finance official said national statistics showed at least seven million people should have been paying income tax but actually only some 2.6 million people pay.</p>
<p>About 200,000 firms are registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission of which only 70,000 file returns and of these an even smaller segment pays tax.</p>
<p>The tax reform package includes three parts. The first, on oil products, has already been approved. The second, on beer and cigarette taxes, is still pending in the legislature.</p>
<p>The third part of the package is individual taxes which the government hopes to finalise next year.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
