<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135472" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Philippine stocks on Tuesday:</p>
<p>* On Monday, the Dow Jones slipped by 3.36 points to 6,090.87. PLDT's ADR fell by $ 1/8 to $60 1/8.</p>
<p>* The peso closed unchanged at 26.273 to a U.S.dollar.</p>
<p>* The Philippine Stock Exchange index closed at 3,092.34, down 7.39 points.</p>
<p>* The Philippine interbank call loan rate jumped to 11.34375 percent from 11.0625.  </p>
<p>* The Solid Group Inc told the Philippine Stock Exchange on Monday it was confident of achieving its 1996 net income target of 834 million pesos.</p>
<p>* Empire East Land Holdings Inc told the Philippine Securities and Exchange Commission its net income jumped by 179 percent in the first nine months of the year to 1.006 billion pesos from the year-ago 360 million pesos.</p>
<p>* The Philippines' benchmark 91-day treasury bill rate rose to an average of 11.531 percent at Monday's regular weekly auction from last week's 11.526 percent, the Bureau of Treasury said.</p>
<p>* The government maintained its average 5.5 percent monthly inflation target for the fourth quarter of 1996 despite the combined effects of the rise in oil and power rates. (PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>* Manila Electric Co president Manuel Lopez told Reuters on Monday the company expects an 11 percent rise in sales for full-year 1996. Lopez also said the company's net income for the first nine months would be &quot;around&quot; the 3.9 billion pesos forecast in a recent Reuter poll.</p>
<p>* Metropolitan Bank and Trust Co is expected to report on Wednesday a net profit &quot;close to 3.2 billion pesos,&quot; in the first nine months of the year, a senior bank official told Reuters on Monday.</p>
<p>The bank posted net income of 2.287 billion pesos in the same period last year. &quot;We're on target to meet our 5.0 billion-peso full-year net,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>* Brokerage Dharmala Securities Phils Inc said positioning ahead of the release of third quarter corporate earnings this week should provide trading opportunities in the market.</p>
<p>The brokerage firm advised its clients to buy Fil-Estate Land Inc and accumulate Davao Union.</p>
<p>				   -----------</p>
<p>To contribute to this page, please fax your comments on the stock market to Reuters newsroom on fax (632) 817 6267. For details, please phone the newsroom on (632) 841 8934.</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632)841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
