<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135490" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Rashid Hussain seen in Kwong Yik bid.</title>
<headline>Rashid Hussain seen in Kwong Yik bid.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock broker Rashid Hussain Bhd (RHB) has received Malaysia's central bank clearance to proceed with acquisition talks for Kwong Yik Bank Bhd, The Star newspaper reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Quoting banking sources, the daily said Rashid Hussain, who heads the firm, discussed the proposal on Saturday with Malayan Banking Bhd (Maybank) managing director Amirsham Abdul Aziz. Maybank owns 75 percent of Kwong Yik.</p>
<p>Earlier on Saturday, Amirsham told reporters after Maybank's annual general meeting that the company had no immediate plans to sell all or part of its stake in Kwong Yik.</p>
<p>The newspaper said it was unclear which unit of the RHB group would be directly involved in the takeover. The company owns a controlling 20 percent stake in DCB Holdings Bhd, which is the parent of DCB Bank.</p>
<p>Shares of RHB, DCB, Kwong Yik and Maybank were all suspended on Monday pending announcements. Officials at the companies could not immediately be reached for comment on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Rumours about a restructuring involving Rashid Hussein being taken over by DCB Bank have been circulating in the market for weeks. Rashid said recently the company is open to merger proposals with other banks or a tie-up with a foreign bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
