<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135409" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hengli set to make A share offer.</title>
<headline>Hengli set to make A share offer.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yueyang Hengli Air-conditioner Co Ltd said on Tuesday it was set to launch an offer of 10 million A shares via the Shenzhen bourse's automated quotation system at 5.98 yuan per share on October 24.</p>
<p>The offer, approved by the China Securities Regulatory Commission, reflects a P/E ratio of 15.7 times based on a forecast per-share net of 0.38 yuan for 1996, the company said in a prospectus published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>Hengli said it has also been given approval by the CSRC to list three million staff shares, issued at one yuan per share in 1993, along with the A shares in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Shanghai Shenyin &amp; Wanguo Securities has been appointed the lead underwriter for the issue, Hengli said.</p>
<p>Hengli, which specialises in making air-conditioners for buses and cars, said it would use the proceeds from the offer to expand its core operations and revamp production facilities and technology.</p>
<p>Hengli, based in the city of Yueyang in central China's Hunan province, said it has forecast net earnings of 19.79 million yuan for this year, compared with 7.45 million yuan in 1995 and 3.79 million yuan a year earlier.  </p>
<p>It said it had after-tax profits of 8.00 million yuan in the first half of this year but did not give a comparative figure.</p>
<p>Hengli said most of its products are sold domestically, with some exported to southeast Asia and Pakistan.</p>
<p>Hengli now has total share capital of 42 million shares, comprised of 30 million founder shares and 12 million staff shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
