<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135417" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Proton said to buy 80 pct of Lotus Cars.</title>
<headline>Proton said to buy 80 pct of Lotus Cars.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian national carmaker Perusahaan Otomobil Nasional Bhd (Proton) has agreed to buy an 80 percent stake in U.K. sportscar maker Lotus Cars Ltd, the Asian Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Quoting auto industry executives close to the proposed deal, the newspaper said Proton reached a preliminary agreement late last week to buy the stake for about 210 million ringgit in cash and the assumption of 51 million ringgit in debt.</p>
<p>Officials at Proton were not available for comment on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In striking the deal, Proton's head Yahaya Ahmad appeared to have outbid international rivals, including Daewoo Motors Co of South Korea for Lotus, an automotive engineering firm and maker of luxury sports cars, the article said.</p>
<p>An announcement is expected in the coming weeks, although Yayaya couldn't be reached for comment and a spokesman for Lotus declined to comment, the article said.</p>
<p>Proton's stock was unchanged on Tuesday morning at 15.00 ringgit after rising as high as 15.10 ringgit earlier.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
