<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135449" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Nobel winner an embarrassment to Manila - official.</title>
<headline>Nobel winner an embarrassment to Manila - official.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines' top security official confirmed on Monday that Nobel peace laureate Jose Ramos-Horta had been banned from entering the country, saying his presence would be an &quot;embarrassment&quot;.</p>
<p>Presidential national security adviser Jose Almonte said Ramos-Horta was in the category of foreigners who &quot;may cause disturbance&quot; during the November 25 summit of the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum in nearby Subic freeport.</p>
<p>&quot;Our assessment is it (Ramos-Horta's presence) will cause embarrassment to the nation,&quot; Almonte told reporters.</p>
<p>President Fidel Ramos said last weekend he had ordered the immigration bureau to bar the entry of anyone who might disrupt the summit meeting. Ramos did not specifically mention the East Timorese resistance leader.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta, who won this year's Nobel peace prize with East Timor's Roman Catholic bishop Carlos Belo, had accepted an invitation to speak at an international meeting of non-government organisations (NGOs) in Manila November 21-24.</p>
<p>Indonesian President Suharto is expected to attend the APEC summit.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in 1975 and annexed it the following year in a move never recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Almonte indicated the decision to keep out Ramos-Horta was taken in consultation with other governments in the 18-member APEC forum.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to look at the political security situation of each of the leaders of the APEC economies and this is not done by us alone,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is in coordination with other security agencies of the APEC economies so the evaluation is not necessarily unilateral. It is in coordination with our guests. &quot;</p>
<p>Jose de Venecia, speaker of the Philippine House of Representatives, said Manila could invite Ramos-Horta to visit at some future time.</p>
<p>His exclusion at this time is &quot;out of respect for President Suharto and in order to maintain the serenity within APEC,&quot; de Venecia said.</p>
<p>Manila barred Ramos-Horta and other East Timorese dissidents from entering the country in 1994 during an international human rights conference on East Timor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
