<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135493" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Iraq Kurdish leader set for U.S. ceasefire talks.</title>
<headline>Iraq Kurdish leader set for U.S. ceasefire talks.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Bell</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kurdish militia leader Jalal Talabani arrived in Turkey for talks with a U.S. mediator on Tuesday on ending infighting in northern Iraq that has hurt Washington's anti-Baghdad efforts.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources said U.S. peace envoy Robert Pelletreau would try to convince Talabani to accept a ceasefire proposal that was also put to rival Iraqi Kurd chieftain Massoud Barzani.</p>
<p>&quot;(Talabani) arrived in Istanbul from Tehran last night,&quot; said Shazad Saib, Turkey representative of Talabani's Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>Washington, which has kept Iraqi President Saddam Hussein out of north Iraq for most of the last five years, fears Baghdad or Tehran might fill a power vacuum caused by the Kurdish feud.</p>
<p>Pelletreau laid out the ceasefire plan at a meeting with Barzani in the Turkish border town of Silopi on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;(Barzani) was positive on the ceasefire. Very positive,&quot; a source close to the talks told Reuters.</p>
<p>But the U.S. bid has yet to produce a let up in fighting. Neither side has gained a clear advantage in the latest clashes which broke out 10 days ago.</p>
<p>Turkish officials said Talabani would meet Turkey's Foreign Minister Tansu Ciller around 4 p.m. (1600 GMT) and then hold talks with Pelletreau.</p>
<p>The PUK on Monday halted a push by Barzani's fighters on Talabani's stronghold Sulaimaniya, near the Iranian border.</p>
<p>Witnesses said forces loyal to Talabani retook the town of Ranya and repelled a KDP assault on the strategic Dukan Dam.</p>
<p>&quot;PUK forces are continuing their victorious counter-attack against Barzani mercenaries,&quot; the group said in a statement. It said the PUK had also taken the towns of Sangasar and Zharawa.</p>
<p>Kurdish fighting in August gave Saddam the chance to flex his muscles in the north, under nominal protection of a U.S.-led allied air force since after the end of the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Barzani called in support from Iraqi armoured troops to overwhelm Talabani's forces in Arbil, the region's capital.</p>
<p>The United States launched missiles at military targets in south Iraq in reprisal but still lost much of its aid, intelligence and military capability in the north.</p>
<p>Barzani has since threatened to call on Iraqi help again if the fighting does not go his way.</p>
<p>Pelletreau cautioned against any more Iraqi involvement and warned neighbouring Iran to stay out of the Kurds' fight.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States would regard that as a negative development that could have very negative consequences,&quot; he said after meeting Barzani on Monday.</p>
<p>The KDP accuses Talabani of receiving men and munitions from Tehran, raising the spectre of a Iran-Iraq conflict. Talabani and Tehran deny military cooperation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
