<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135467" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - October 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - October 22.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Indonesia President Suharto says Indonesia's religious diversity not a barrier to national unity.</p>
<p>- Japan's Liberal Democratic Party works on forming new coalition government but finding other parties having mixed feelings about roles in next ruling coalition.</p>
<p>- Singapore and Australia sign three agreements giving further boost to defence links between two countries.</p>
<p>- New listings Delifrance Asia and Labroy Marine hog spotlight in stock market.</p>
<p>- Singapore Technologies Industrial Corp and NTUC Club Investments' joint venture for family entertainment centres will have 15 outlets by end of year.</p>
<p>- Singapore non-oil domestic exports for the third quarter shrinks 2.4 percent year-on-year in nominal terms.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Eu Yan Sang plans comeback to the Singapore stock market within three years under bigger group embracing its namesake in Hongkong which would be delisted from Hongkong's exchange.</p>
<p>- Two Indonesian tycoons, Mohammad 'Bob' Hasan and Putera Sampoerna, in head-on fight for biggest block of shares in PT Astra International.</p>
<p>- Indonesian conglomerate Sinar Mas secures licence to build huge palm oil refinery in Ningbo.</p>
<p>- Malaysian tycoon Yahaya Ahmad's Hicom group secures Tekka Corner for Singapore $84 million.</p>
<p>- Tony Tan, managing director of Parkway Holdings Ltd, says it may sell non-healthcare assets within a year.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
