<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135494" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO negotiators storm out of talks with Israel.</title>
<headline>PLO negotiators storm out of talks with Israel.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Burston</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>PLO negotiators stormed out of talks with Israel after revolving-door diplomacy by the United States and France failed to help break a deadlock over a troop pullout in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>As U.S. President Bill Clinton's peace envoy headed for home emptyhanded late on Monday after 15 days of nearly non-stop mediation, French President Jacques Chirac poured fuel on hardline Israeli ire by calling for a Palestinian state.</p>
<p>Angry Palestine Liberation Organisation peace negotiators said they had walked out of talks on Monday night in protest at Israeli delegates' attitudes, which they described as that of &quot;occupiers toward the occupied&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately the head of the Israeli delegation treats the Palestinian negotiators as if he is a military leader, and not as a negotiator,&quot; said senior PLO security official Mohammed Dahlan of Dan Shomron, a former Israeli army chief.</p>
<p>One PLO official said the Palestinian delegates had now gone to Bethlehem to brief Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on the talks, which cover security issues. He said talks on civilian affairs, which are being held at a separate venue with different teams of negotiators, would continue.</p>
<p>Both sides have accused the other of foot-dragging in the marathon talks over a long-pledged Israeli withdrawal from much of Hebron, the last and most sensitive of seven West Bank towns due to be handed over to PLO rule, and the only one with a Jewish settler population.</p>
<p>Last week the sides said they were close to agreement. But the long face of U.S. envoy Dennis Ross said otherwise.</p>
<p>&quot;Would I have liked to see more achieved? You bet,&quot; said said Ross, dispatched by Clinton after Israeli-Palestinian gun battles that left 75 dead last month threatened to deal the fragile peace process a mortal blow.</p>
<p>Clinton had made Middle East peace talks a centrepiece of his foreign policy, and administration officials had hoped for a breakthrough with U.S. elections only two weeks away.</p>
<p>Chirac, ending the first of three days in Israel and the Palestinian lands, urged Israel to abide by the Hebron accord reached between the PLO and the previous Israeli governments of Shimon Peres and his slain predecessor Yitzhak Rabin.</p>
<p>&quot;Time is working against peace and working for its adversaries,&quot; Chirac said at a dinner hosted by Israeli President Ezer Weizman.</p>
<p>&quot;Any calling into question of agreed arrangements ends up weakening what has been accomplished,&quot; he said, adding in reference to the Palestinians: &quot;It would be an error and a crime to make them lose hope.&quot;</p>
<p>Chirac earlier nettled Israeli hardliners by telling university students in the northern city of Haifa that only a Palestinian state &quot;will be capable of making, and adhering to the commitments that are necessary for the security of Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>Just before the Chirac dinner, a parliamentary defeat put a damper on the appetite of right-wing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who lost a no-confidence vote over economic issues.</p>
<p>The 45-43 vote against Netanyahu bore only symbolic significance, however, under a new law that requires a majority of 61 votes in the 120-member house to topple a government.</p>
<p>Netanyahu edged out Peres in May elections vowing to hold to a tough, go-slow stance in peace talks. He rejects any further territorial concessions to the Arabs in exchange for peace, and brands a Palestinian state a mortal danger to Israel.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's foreign minister David Levy said a Hebron accord could have been signed last week, but for Palestinian stalling.</p>
<p>PLO officials countered that Israel was trying to pin the blame for the failure of the Ross mission on the Palestinians.</p>
<p>They said delegates walked out of talks on security arrangements in Hebron because Shomron maintained a &quot;take it or leave it&quot; position on Israeli proposals for altering the Hebron accord -- proposals already rejected by the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Dahlan said there was still no agreement on such major security issues as Israel's demand for a right of hot pursuit into areas due to be handed over to Palestinian police.</p>
<p>The Hebron pullout has been frozen since March by Islamic suicide bombings and Israeli fears for the safety of 400 Jews living among the city's 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
