<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135445" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- The spectre of the Phuket land reform issue could return to haunt the Democrats after the prime minister has ordered the public prosecutor to speed up the case. The Supreme Attorney-General's Office will today give the cabinet a progress report on the case, a day after the opening of candidate registration set the November 17 election campaign in motion. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- A total of 1,610 candidates have registered for the November 17 general election on Monday, the first day of registration. The first day of registration saw a carnival-like atmosphere at most provincial halls around the country. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Eight in every 1,000 babies born in Thailand, or 24 newborns of the 3,000 births nationwide each day, are diagnosed with the life-threatening congenital heart disease. A senior public health ministry says the situation is further deteriorating due to insufficient specialists and lack of equipment. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The Bank of Thailand is prepared to help financial institutions that have liquidity problem to the extent that they may face bankruptcy. The central bank's chief concern is the effect that a run on a failing financial institution can have on the system. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa has rejected a request for promotional privileges by Thai-Asahi Chemical Co for its sodium chloride expansion project, saying the venture is profitable and needs no help. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- The Transport and Communications Ministry has split a highly-sweetened deal for Don Muang Tollway Co (DMT) into five separate contracts, with Cabinet today set to consider a proposed increase in toll rates. Cabinet will consider DMT's request for higher toll rates while contracts covering government commitments on a soft loan, equity investment, tollway extension and its connection with the expressway, will be discussed in the near future. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
