<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135419" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Honda says no plans yet to raise dividend.</title>
<headline>Honda says no plans yet to raise dividend.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honda Motor Co Ltd said on Tuesday it has not decided whether to raise its dividend payment for the 1996/97 business year ending March.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun financial daily said on Tuesday that Honda is likely to increase its annual dividend payment to 15 yen in 1996/97 from 14 yen the year before, which would be the first increase in seven years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not decided yet whether to raise the dividend payment for 1996/97,&quot; a Honda spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Honda has been paying an annual dividend of 14 yen since 1989/90.</p>
<p>Last August, Honda revised upward its forecast for parent current profit to 120 billion yen in 1996/97, up from 47.18 billion yen a year earlier, mainly helped by robust demand for its recreational vehicle. This would surpass the previous record current profit of 90.5 billion yen set in 1989/90.</p>
<p>&quot;Nikkei's story has had no impact on the stock market today because it's not fresh news. Investors have believed for a long time that Honda would raise its dividend to 15 yen this business year,&quot; said Nomura Research analyst Seiji Sugiura.</p>
<p>Honda shares were down 20 yen at 2,710 yen at 0237 GMT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
