<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135587" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish Enso's Jan-Aug profit slides.</title>
<headline>Finnish Enso's Jan-Aug profit slides.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland's second-largest forestry group Enso Oy said on Tuesday its profit in January-August fell sharply, but full-year earnings would be satisfactory.</p>
<p>Reporting profit after financial items down to 1.16 billion markka ($252.9 million) from 2.68 billion a year-ago on slightly lower net sales at 17.20 billion against 18.92 billion, Enso said it expected to make a profit in the last four months of the year.</p>
<p>The result was fractionally below analysts' forecasts for a profit around 1.17 billion, and in line with retreating profits reported by Enso's rivals last week as demand has been hit by a combination of high customer stocks and slower growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Entering the autumn, the market has not improved in line with expectations. Although economic growth has started to pick up in Western Europe, the impact on the forest industry is being felt more slowly than anticipated,&quot; Enso said in the report.</p>
<p>&quot;Uncertainty over the prices for market pulp and newsprint could make the market difficult. Because of new production capacity, some of which is already in use, it is taking longer to restore the market to balance,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>&quot;The prospects for the financial result for the rest of the year are not as bright as they appeared to be in the spring,&quot; said the company, echoing its own earlier warnings and uncertainty on prospects from its rivals.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene Oy, which last week reported a 41 percent slide in profit, had been equally hesitant in its outlook after forestry firms last year were helped by economic recovery to record profits.</p>
<p>But Enso did say it expected market pulp prices -- the raw material for some paper grades and a leading indicator in the forestry cycle -- to firm in the last few months of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Pulp prices are expected to strengthen further during the last few months of the year,&quot; Enso said. &quot;There will be less need to curtail production than earlier in the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Pulp prices nudged ahead earlier this year after slumping from last year's record levels, but gains have been tentative.</p>
<p>Enso said its sales of market pulp fell 31 percent in the period to 1.15 billion markka, and its two units made operating losses although prices strengthened in June and July. ($ = 4.586 Finnish Markka)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
