<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135584" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden cuts repo rate to 4.85 percent.</title>
<headline>Sweden cuts repo rate to 4.85 percent.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's central bank, the Riskbank, on Tuesday cut its key repo interest rate by 10 basis points to 4.85 percent, in line with expectations on the financial markets.</p>
<p>It was the 22nd cut in the repo rate so far this year as the bank pursues an active monetary policy in a low inflation environment.  </p>
<p>The repo rate, which began the year at 8.91 percent, is the bank's key tool for controlling money market liquidity and is the central rate of its three tier system. The latest cut follows the bank's pattern of trimming the rate every second week.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of 11 analysts found most expected a cut of 10 basis points at the Riksbank's weekly repo tender.The new reverse repurchase operation will run from October 23 to October 30.</p>
<p>Most analysts were also expecting the bank to lower its interest rate corridor when the board meets on Thursday.</p>
<p>The corridor is marked by the floor, the deposit rate which currently stands at 4.75 percent, and the ceiling rate, the lending rate, that is now 6.25 percent. The interest rate corridor was last lowered on August 15.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
