<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135572" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Metro sticks to profit goal, but sales weak.</title>
<headline>Metro sticks to profit goal, but sales weak.</headline>
<dateline>COLOGNE, Germany 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss-controlled German retail giant Metro AG said on Tuesday it would hold to its goal of pre-tax profits of 1.0-1.1 billion marks this year despite continued weak consumer demand in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Metro, born recently out of a merger of leading German store chains, said in a statement group turnover was 43.263 billion marks in the first nine months of the year. It gave no comparative figure.  </p>
<p>&quot;The development reflects the slackness in turnover which continued unabated in the third quarter,&quot; board spokesman Klaus Wiegandt said.</p>
<p>The company said that the profit goal -- which has been shaved downwards once since Metro's listing in the summer -- assumed Christmas sales in line with last year.</p>
<p>Metro has revised its sales forecast down to 62 billion marks, but gave no new figure in the statement, which was published after a meeting with German analysts.</p>
<p>The company also said it expected no improvement in the consumer climate next year and would lower its medium-term sales forecasts accordingly.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment it is too early to estimate how big the impact on earnings will be. With our wideranging measures to improve basic earnings and cut costs we will strongly act against that,&quot; Wiegandt said.</p>
<p>It was also too early to say impact longer shop opening hours would have in 1997, Metro said.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
