<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135583" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: PRESS DIGEST - Italy - October 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Italy - October 22.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the top headlines in leading Italian newspapers.</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP POLITICAL STORIES</p>
<p>* Shopkeepers announce &quot;tax obstructionism&quot; against the 1997 budget. &quot;We'll create all the obstacles permitted by the law&quot;(all).</p>
<p>* Rightwing National Alliance party leader Gianfranco Fini might table a parliamentary motion of no-confidence against Finance minister Vincenzo Visco. But centre-right Freedom Alliance leader Silvio Berlusconi says: &quot;We are opposed to motions of no-confidence against individual ministers. Our no-confidence in reality regards the entire government&quot; (all).</p>
<p>*Milan magistrates are split over a law proposal on the double function of Italian magistrates about whether they can be state prosecutors and magistrates at the same time. The law would make it more difficult for magistrates to move from one role to another (all).</p>
<p>----------</p>
<p>TOP BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>* In an interview Prime minister Romano Prodi says talks with European partners over the re-entry of the lira in the ERM will start after the Lower House of Parliament has approved the 1997 budget. Italy seeks to get the lira back in the ERM by the end of the year. (Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>*Consumer prices index in three sample cities (Milan, Turin, Trieste) showed inflation is heading further down. Analysts now expect an October year on year rate at 3.1 percent (all).</p>
<p>*Giorgio Fossa, chairman of employers association Confindustria, says the government should stay out of the dispute over metalworkers' contracts (Corriere, Stampa).</p>
<p>* Fossa also says if Italy wants to join the EMU there must be additional deficit-cutting measures in 1997.</p>
<p>* An agreement is near between the government and Communist Refoundation party over tax modifications in the 1997 budget. The government proposes to raise the minimum personal tax rate to 20 percent from the present 10 percent and reduce the top tax rate to 46 percent from 51 percent. But the rise won't hit low incomes, prime minister Romano Prodi said (Sole 24 Ore).</p>
<p>*Good start for the second-tranche sale of energy giant Eni: in the first day of offer, demand exceeded 250 milion of shares, the minimum level required for the whole operation (Sole 24 Ore, Corriere, Stampa).</p>
<p>* Insurer Generali is said to be &quot;in pole position&quot; in the bid for Prime, Fiat's financial group for fund and savings management (Sole 24 Ore, Corriere).</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39266129450</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
