<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135575" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- Portugal and four other countries were elected on Monday to the powerful 15-member U.N. Security Council for a two-year term beginning on January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>- International markets expect Portugal to take part in Economic and Monetary Union in 1999, Prime Minister Antonio Guterres said at a banking seminar.</p>
<p>- British firm Avon Automotive has opened a car components factory in the industrial park of Tondela in northern Portugal. The 800 million escudos investment will produce rubber tubing for the car industry.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>- A proposal by centre-right Social Democratic Party (PSD) leader Marcelo Rebelo de Sousa for a referendum on abortion divides the ruling Socialist Party (PS).</p>
<p>- Former Prime Minister Anibal Cavaco Silva believes there will be currency turbulence in Europe in 1998 ahead of the launch date for a single European currency on January 1 1999.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>- The directorate-general of the health ministry wants the abortion law to be changed to permit voluntary termination of pregnancy up to the 24th week in the case of congenital problems or malformation of the foetus.</p>
<p>- Under-Secretary for Finance Teixeira dos Santos will receive today the final report in the privatisation of tobacco company Tabaqueira. The choice of the winner could be a political decision, the paper says.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon bureau 3511-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
