<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135504" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Ruffled Chirac elbows past Israeli security.</title>
<headline>Ruffled Chirac elbows past Israeli security.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Using his elbows, French President Jacques Chirac forced his way through a forest of Israeli security men and police on a tour through the Old City of Jerusalem on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a provocation. Stop this now. Do you want me to go back to my plane and go home to France?&quot; Chirac protested in English to the head of security, his teeth clenched in anger, after more polite words failed to ease the situation.</p>
<p>The French president went on with the tour but was visibly angered by the heavy security which wrestled journalists away from his party and by armed border guards standing guard outside each Palestinian shop.</p>
<p>Security men forced away brown-robed priests and photographers and moved Chirac along each time he tried to stop at a shop.</p>
<p>Chirac turned down an Old City tour with the Israeli mayor of Jerusalem, Ehud Olmert, assserting France's view that the international community does not recognise Israeli sovereignty over Arab East Jerusalem, including the Old City, annexed after the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Dozens of Israeli security guards surrounded Chirac as he entered the Church of the Holy Sepulchre, traditional burial place of Jesus.</p>
<p>Two small throngs of Palestinians applauded him from street corners.</p>
<p>More than 80 journalists accompanied Chirac along with Israeli reporters and there were scuffles from time to time with police. Police shouted in Hebrew at a French press corps bemused by the experience.</p>
<p>&quot;Security, security&quot; was the response police gave whenever asked about the measures. Security lapses were blamed for a right-wing Jewish gunman's assassination almost a year ago of Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin in Tel Aviv.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
