<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135514" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- French President Jacques Chirac: Only a Palestinian state will bring security to Israel.</p>
<p>- U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross leaves as Hebron talks stall.</p>
<p>- Syria: We're ready for war if Israeli provocations continue.</p>
<p>- Government in tact despite successful vote of no confidence.</p>
<p>- Report: Israel Air Force scrambled jets on Syrian front 11 days ago.</p>
<p>- Dead Sea Works may be split up.</p>
<p>- National Infrastructure Minister Ariel Sharon to explore plan for Israel Lands to sell government real estate.</p>
<p>- Shekel depreciates to 3.27 against dollar.</p>
<p>- Cairo summit will host ministers, but not prime ministers.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Dan Meridor seeks fiscal restraint mechanism.</p>
<p>- Labour and Social Affairs Minister Eli Yishai intends to restrict the number of permits for people who want to work on the Jewish sabbath.</p>
<p>- Vishay Intertechnology cancels plans for Ofakim plant, citing government red tape.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Meridor: In 1997 a method for coordinating budget spending to tax income.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Palestinian's body found in car near Ramallah; circumstances of his death unclear.</p>
<p>- Increasing fear in Israel of a military confrontation with Syria, after U.S. elections.</p>
<p>- Government submits to Knesset &quot;Norwegian law&quot; on cabinet ministers leaving parliament; vote next week.</p>
<p>- Opposition victory in no-confidence vote doesn't topple government because new law requires simple majority of 61-59.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Meridor expects another budget cut will be required in 1997 budget.</p>
<p>- Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's secret reports, faxed by his security chiefs, reach settler by mistake: &quot;French president's visit should be exploited to put European pressure on Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>- Ross's departure for Washington brings about a breakthrough in negotiations.</p>
<p>- Rupert Murdoch tells Yedioth Ahronoth: &quot;I am ready to answer any question of the investigators from Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>- 56 percent of Israelis have a headache at least once every three months.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Israel: Arafat is purposely delaying completion of the negotiations on Hebron.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
