<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135502" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar emir names third son as heir.</title>
<headline>Qatar emir names third son as heir.</headline>
<dateline>DOHA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's emir on Tuesday appointed his third son as heir apparent in the oil and gas-rich Gulf Arab state, a decree published by the official Qatar news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;His Royal Highness Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani... issued today an emiri decree appointing Sheikh Jassim bin Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani as Crown Prince,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>The decree took effect immediately.</p>
<p>Officials and diplomats expected the appointment to be the first of many in a cabinet reshuffle that was also likely to include the appointment of a new prime minister.</p>
<p>Sheikh Jassim, 18, a second lieutenant in the Qatari army, is one of four sons of the emir. He graduated from the British military academy Sandhurst in August.</p>
<p>The post of heir apparent has been vacant since Sheikh Hamad toppled his father Sheikh Khalifa bin Hamad al-Thani in a bloodless palace coup last year.</p>
<p>Officials said the emir was set to appoint his younger brother Abdullah bin Khalifa al-Thani as prime minister, a post the emir currently holds.</p>
<p>Western-educated Sheikh Abdullah, who played a key role in the ouster of his father, is interior minister and deputy prime minister.</p>
<p>Among the other changes expected was a new oil minister to replace Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah. The emir was expected to head a new supreme council of energy.</p>
<p>The present Foreign Minister, Sheikh Hamad bin Jassim bin Jabr al-Thani, may be named deputy prime minister. The Minister of State for Defence, Sheikh Hamad bin Abdullah al-Thani may be moved to the Interior Ministry with the same rank.</p>
<p>Qatar's ruling family said on Sunday it had ended a row over billions of dollars missing from the treasury since the former emir was overthrown while he was on holiday in Geneva.</p>
<p>Officials said the deposed emir was expected to return to Qatar soon as part of the settlement over the disputed accounts. Unofficial estimates say the sum controlled by the deposed emir ranged from $3 billion to $7 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
