<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135528" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>spain: PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Spain - Oct 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>Headlines from major national newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>EL PAIS</p>
<p>- Spain's government and Catalan president Jordi Pujol agree to merge Catalan electricity companies Fecsa, ENHER and Hidruna.</p>
<p>- Spain's military intelligence chief Javier Calderon testifies before judge in case investigating death of two ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) suspects in 1980s &quot;dirty war&quot; against Basque separatists.</p>
<p>EL MUNDO</p>
<p>- Bilbao's bishop offers to mediate peace talks with ETA and asks for repatriation of ETA prisoners to Basque country.</p>
<p>- Government will sell its whole 21 percent stake in Telefonica at the end of January 1997.</p>
<p>DIARIO 16</p>
<p>- Diario 16 celebrates 20 years of publication.</p>
<p>- Basque Nationalist Party says it is continuing contact with ETA to try to end violence.</p>
<p>ABC</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar has reduced number of his advisors to 27 while his predecessor Felipe Gonzalez had 43.</p>
<p>CINCO DIAS</p>
<p>- Spain's electricity group Endesa denies it plans to sell off its 80 percent stake in Viesgo.</p>
<p>- Stock market indices reach highs despite suspension of five electricity stocks.</p>
<p>- Bank of Spain governor Luis Angel Rojo warns against euphoric expectations that Spain will be among first members of European monetary union in 1999.</p>
<p>- Spain's transport companies will pass rise in gas prices onto customer.</p>
<p>EXPANSION</p>
<p>- Stock market value of main electricity companies has risen 400 billion pesetas in 12 days since talk emerged that Endesa would launch an offer for Sevillana and Fecsa.</p>
<p>- Economy ministry has launched investigation into profitability of pensions' collective savings schemes.</p>
<p>GACETA DE LOS NEGOCIOS</p>
<p>- Stock market value of electricity companies rises 225 billion pesetas in two days.</p>
<p>- Economy Minister Rodrigo Rato says budget adjustments will last two more years.</p>
<p>- BBV posts 20 percent increase in its group profit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
