<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135527" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE: World market for October 21, 1996</p>
<p>Robusta futures in London closed lower with the key November/January spread, a barometer of nearby availability, attracting most market attention in heavy trading volumes. The November/January switch widened to $113 a tonne at the close but traders said further gains are unlikely as the spread will now draw in fresh coffee. November shed $6 to close at $1,500, while January was down $12 at $1,387. In New York arabica futures closed sharply higher rallying on speculative and trade buying in reaction to five consecutive sessions of losses. Bullish crop news from Central America where hurricane Lili has pounded many farm lands aided sentiment, although it is not yet clear what the actual damage is. Agricultural sources said that the rains may delay the crop but that this should not be a major factor. The unexpected steep decline in US certified coffee stocks should boost prices Tuesday in a market already unnerved by low levels of consumer stocks.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - US certified coffee stocks plummeted 24,391 60-kg bags, or more than 80 per cent, in the week ended October 18, to 5,583 bags (29,974 bags). Stocks in New York declined by 750 bags (zero) to 4,061 bags (4,811 bags), while stocks in New Orleans fell by a massive 17,391 bags (0) to 1,253 bags (18,644 bags). Stocks in San Francisco fell by 5,750 bags (0) to 250 bags (6,000 bags), while stocks in Miami fell by 500 bags (-750 bags) to 19 bags (519 bags). The sharp drawdown came as a shock to traders which had anticipated a slight fall in line with the small drawdowns seen in recent weeks. With concerns about near-term supplies mounting, the nearby switch will benefit the most by the fall. December's premium to March ballooned to 8.95 cents/lb on Monday compared with 7.55 cents/lb on Friday. The latest drawdown in coffee stocks comes at a time when US consumer stocks, comprising both exchange-deliverable and non-exchange coffee, are hovering at the lowest levels in almost a decade. Supplies of green coffee housed in US warehouses were reported at 1.6 million bags in September, the lowest level since the Green Coffee Association began tracking inventories in 1988.</p>
<p>MEXICO - Mexico exported 4.578 million 60-kg bags of coffee in 1995/96 (October/September) up from 3.258 million bags exported the previous year. The export figures indicate, that total production in 1995/96 was probably above 5.2 million 60-kg bags, significantly up on earlier projections.</p>
<p>UGANDA - According to the Ugandan Coffee Development Authority (UCDA) coffee exports in September 1996 reached 371,324 60-kg bags up from the 338,614 bags exported in August and 284,650 bags exported the same month the previous year. That brought total exports in crop year 1995/96 (October/September) up to 4.149 million bags up from 2.760 million bags exported the previous year. Export earnings in 1995/96 were $388.9 million down from $433.0 million the previous year. The higher exports were ascribed to generally good weather in coffee growing areas, that helped the crop to respond to good husbandry practices and made it possible for the crop to be picked all the year around.</p>
<p>SWEDEN - According to official sources Swedish coffee imports dropped to 1.565 million bags in calendar year 1995, 17 per cent less than was imported the previous year. Main suppliers of green coffee in 1995 were Brazil (437,100 vs 685,900 bags) and Colombia (363,100 vs 493,600 bags). The country exported 203,900 bags of coffee in 1995 nearly 9 per cent less than was exported the previous year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
