<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135589" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- In Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) one third of party posts will go to women</p>
<p>- Deutsche Telekom shares cost between 25 and 30 marks</p>
<p>- Draft legislation aimed at protecting the environment is criticised</p>
<p>- Recession in the construction sector will last until 1998, according to the main German building industry federation</p>
<p>- Employers and workers in metal industry become more sceptical. Pay talks to be held until Wednesday</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- Chancellor Helmut Kohl fans flames of internal row in his coalition. Without mentioning the solidarity tax he tries to calm delegates at the CDU party congress</p>
<p>- Nuremberg Institute for the labour market and employment research says fewer jobs in 1997</p>
<p>- Chairman of the board of the Deutsche Telekom, Ron Sommer, speaks of shareholders' fever. Telekom shares will cost from 25 to 30 marks. Sommer said he was proud of foreign interest in flotation of the firm</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Chancellor Helmut Kohl warns that the welfare state may become drained of all resources. Kohl courts consensus between industry leaders and workers. He is confirmed in office as leader of the CDU at party congress</p>
<p>- Bonn presses for a compromise. Private banks should withdraw a complaint to Brussels</p>
<p>- Three managers from European Kings Club go on trial in Frankfurt for investment fraud</p>
<p>- Even after a compromise many ABM training places in east Germany look threatened</p>
<p>DIE WELT</p>
<p>- Chancellor Helmut Kohl moves away from his goal of more employment at CDU party congress. Congress votes in favour of women's quota in the party</p>
<p>- Three million Germans want to buy Telekom shares</p>
<p>- Metalworkers' union IG Metall and metal industry employers show willingness to compromise and propose pay talks in 1997 to discuss sick pay cuts</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 26097160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
