<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135524" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: FEATURE - Oman plans export-led growth.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Oman plans export-led growth.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Gulf Arab state more famous for its frankincense than industrial output is taking decisive steps towards privatisation and diversification, but analysts say dependence on oil remains a threat to Oman's development.</p>
<p>Sitting at the mouth of the Gulf, Oman is not as wealthy as its northern neighbours, but the average 850,000 barrels of oil it pumps every day still form the backbone of the economy.</p>
<p>The emphasis, however, is now on a private-sector export-oriented economy -- part of the &quot;Vision 2020&quot; that officials and citizens speak of with pride.</p>
<p>The law is being changed to streamline taxes on foreign and local firms and the Omani Centre for the Promotion of Investment and Development of Exports is being set up to &quot;cut down on red tape&quot;, as one official put it.</p>
<p>To lure foreign investment in minerals lying beneath the rugged coastal hills, the 1974 mining law is being updated.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investment, export-oriented investment and privatising all services, this is the trend,&quot; said Ministry of Commerce and Industry undersecretary Ali Masoud Al-Sunaidy, adding these were the &quot;three pillars for our next 25 years&quot;.</p>
<p>But the plans are peppered with caution from analysts who say high population growth and reliance on oil, which accounts for over 75 percent of state revenue, must be controlled.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth potential is slowing and Oman is still heavily dependent on oil. This dependency is still one of the fundamental threats to the economy,&quot; a Western diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic growth has to be substantial just to stand still, considering that population growth is 3.7 percent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The government's plan to the year 2000 forecasts annual growth in gross domestic product (GDP) of 4.6 percent. Official data show nominal GDP grew 6.5 percent in 1995 and 3.4 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>Inflation is not a problem for now. Thanks to a 1.8 percent drop in the housing index, overall inflation edged up only 0.3 percent in the first seven months of this year. But analysts warn that food prices are rising at around three percent.</p>
<p>Privatisation -- the Muscat buzzword -- is seen as the engine for growth in the next decade. In June, Sultan Qaboos decreed the setting up of a ministerial committee to handle the privatisation programme. The first step is infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has gone to the private sector to develop infrastructure. It is a learning curve,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>When the Manah power station came on stream in April, Oman became the first Gulf Arab state to use a build own operate transfer (BOOT) scheme for an infrastructure project. It also plans to use BOOT in Muscat and Salalah wastewater projects.</p>
<p>Under BOOT, the developer operates the plant and collects revenue for a fixed period before handing it back to the state.</p>
<p>A number of other private sector projects -- ranging from an aluminium smelter to a sugar refinery -- are also planned. Ports at Raysut and Sohar are set to be developed too.</p>
<p>The biggest project however, is a $6 billion partnership between the government and foreign firms to produce 6.6 million tonnes a year of liquefied natural gas from the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Manah and the other BOOT projects are a start, but a wider private sector role is needed, including the sale of existing state assets,&quot; the Western diplomat said, adding these included holdings in a number of banks, the General Telecommunication Organisation (GTO), Gulf Air and possibly the Oman Mining Co.</p>
<p>&quot;But the GTO is the second highest government revenue earner, so I don't think they will be all that anxious to privatise all profitable areas,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>If income is a worry, the government can probably heave a small sigh of relief for now. Higher-than-forecast oil revenues this year have boosted state coffers, run down by eight years of deficit financing amid weak oil prices.</p>
<p>By end-July the deficit was 24.5 million rials ($65 million) versus a forecast 218 million rials for the year. But analysts warn by year-end it will move back towards the budgeted level, as any oil income above the $15 a barrel budgeted for will be used to replenish the State General Reserve Fund.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been spending overruns in the past, but it looks like this year they will stick to budget. There has been severe pressure on the finance ministry to break budget, but it has withstood these, which is good news,&quot; said an analyst.</p>
<p>The Minister of Economy Ahmad bin Abdul-Nabi Mekki has said the government is committed to wipe out the deficit by 2000.</p>
<p>In the meantime, Oman will gather funds for its development plans through a debut Eurobond issue and a $400 million syndicated loan -- its biggest since the 1990 Gulf crisis. ($1=0.38 rial)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
