<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135581" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Sandoz sees growth continuing into Q4.</title>
<headline>Sandoz sees growth continuing into Q4.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong growth trends seen in Sandoz AG's pharmaceuticals and its agri-business segments during the first three quarters of 1996 should continue into the final quarter of the year, Sandoz chief financial officer Raymund Breu said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Pharma and agri-business look quite good. We have no reason to think that the strong growth trend of the first three quarters should not continue into the fourth quarter,&quot; Breu said in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>Breu also said the recent divestitures announced by the company should address the concerns of U.S. regulators with regard to the company's herbicide and animal health businesses.</p>
<p>The discussions with the regulators are now focused on Sandoz and Ciba-Geigy AG's genetic therapy operations, Breu said.</p>
<p>The two companies last March agreed to merge. The merger is pending U.S. Federal Trade Commission approval, which is expected in late fall.</p>
<p>When announcing first half results earlier this year the two companies said they were looking into the divestiture of some of their U.S. crop protection and animal health businesses with the aim of expediting the FTC approval process.</p>
<p>Late last month Sandoz announced the sale of a portion of its corn herbicide business in the United States and Canada to BASF AG for about $695 plus about $83 million in net working capital.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Sandoz sold its flea and tick business in the U.S. and Canada to Central Garden &amp; Pet Co for $41 million. -- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
