<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135598" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe calls on firms to take steps to create youth employment.</p>
<p>-- Government to sell state-owned shipping company Compagnie Generale Maritime (CGM) to Compagnie Maritime d'Affretement (CMA) through private placement.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE DESFOSSES</p>
<p>-- Daewoo Electronics may run into obstacles in offer on Thomson Multimedia, as Lagardere may decide to keep certain high-technology activities under French control.</p>
<p>-- TF1 TV channel chairman Patrick Le Lay says in an interview he is trying to block a merger plan between subscriber-TV channel Canal Plus and Dutch media group NetHold, on grounds that it would go against Canal's interests in Eurosport channel, in which TF1 and Canal hold shares.</p>
<p>-- Small and medium-sized firms leaders pessimistic about their economic future, survey shows.</p>
<p>L'AGEFI</p>
<p>-- Credit National chairman Emmanuel Rodocanachi says bank to pay dividends in 1996, expects return to profit this year.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- British Airways managing director Robert Ayling says in an interview the company's aim in bidding for insolvent Air Liberte is not only to gain landing slots at Orly airport, but to operate a network to complement its French TAT airline.</p>
<p>-- Retired people to demonstrate today to protest against erosion of purchasing power.</p>
<p>-- Financial factors helped the first-half profits posted by many listed companies this autumn, even though operations proved flat or loss-making.</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- Sagem electronics group may be interested in making an offer for Thomson Multimedia, following Daewoo Electronics' offer, itself a part of the Lagardere bid for Thomson SA.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- President Jacques Chirac during visit to Israel says that only a Palestinian state could guarantee security in the region.</p>
<p>-- Credit Lyonnais chairman Jean Peyrelevade is quoted as saying a privatisation plan for the ailing state-owned bank would be ready by the end of the year.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
