<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135563" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Handelsbanken says may redeem own shares.</title>
<headline>Handelsbanken says may redeem own shares.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish commercial bank Handelsbanken's president Arne Martensson said on Tuesday it may buy back some of its own shares in a move mirroring a recent redemption by state-owned rival Nordbanken.</p>
<p>&quot;I see a buy-back as an alternative. It's our policy to create a return on equity higher than that of the other (Swedish) banks,&quot; Martensson told business daily Dagens Industri.</p>
<p>Nordbanken recently bought back its own shares to the value of five billion crowns, and Handelsbanken's over-liquidity would allow it to at least double that amount in a buy-back transaction.</p>
<p>However, the bank would first need to be sure that the money could not be used in a better way, such as for acquisitions, Martensson said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aim is to become one of the three largest banks in (each of) Finland, Norway and Denmark. This we can do through small acquisitions and own establishment,&quot; Martensson said, adding that this policy had been successful in Finland and Norway, and now it was Denmark's turn.</p>
<p>Martensson repeated that a merger with Swedish rival S-E-Banken was not on the agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of investigations showing that advantages of scale cease to take effect at a size smaller than Handelsbanken is at present,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
