<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135526" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS - Danes to block EU's anti-Helms-Burton moves.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Danes to block EU's anti-Helms-Burton moves.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union's efforts to combat Washington's anti-Cuba trade laws were thrown into doubt on Tuesday when diplomats said Denmark would veto retaliatory proposals during a meeting of EU foreign ministers next week.</p>
<p>Diplomats said neither the European Commission -- the EU's executive -- nor the 14-other member states could persuade Denmark that proposed retaliation to Washington's Helms-Burton Act would not interfere with Danish sovereignty.</p>
<p>&quot;Proposals for EU blocking tactics will not go through (on Monday) because Denmark will veto them,&quot; one diplomat told Reuters. &quot;The law against Helms-Burton will not go through.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats said Denmark was opposed to the blocking tactics because it brought into question aspects of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>The Danish government is currently embroiled in a court case brought by a citizens group which accuses it of handing too much sovereignty to the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;Denmark has problems at home and so is very reluctant to accept new laws,&quot; a diplomat said. &quot;We hope that this will not spill over into other aspects of community law.&quot;</p>
<p>EU foreign ministers were due next Monday to discuss laws to block the Helms-Burton Act, an amalgamation of decades of anti-Cuba policy.</p>
<p>Among other things the act allows American citizens to sue in U.S. courts European companies or individuals accused of profiting from investments made in property confiscated in Cuba since the Communist revolution of 1959.</p>
<p>The European Commission, which has already launched a complaint against the Act at the World Trade Organisation, on Monday hoped to win acceptance for another retaliatory measure which would allow European companies or individuals to counter-sue in EU member state courts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
