<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135517" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE bank governor rebukes government over aliens.</title>
<headline>UAE bank governor rebukes government over aliens.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governor of the United Arab Emirates' Central Bank, in remarks published on Tuesday, delivered a rare rebuke to the country's policymakers over the economic impact of a crackdown on illegal aliens.</p>
<p>About 200,000 people -- nearly 10 percent of the 2.4 million population in which three out of four are foreigners -- have left the Gulf state in recent weeks to avoid tough new penalties for working illegally.</p>
<p>A three-month amnesty, which mostly affects labourers from the Indian subcontinent but also workers from southeast Asia, is due to expire at the end of this month. The UAE government says the illegal aliens are a threat to the country's security.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Sultan Nasser al-Suweidi urged senior policymakers to avoid future shocks to the economy by consulting business people before changing the law.</p>
<p>&quot;Friendly dialogue will help concerned authorities to explain their thoughts properly to the business community who will be able to give them feedback on the current market status,&quot; he said in an interview with Gulf News.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank is keeping an eye on the situation and anticipates that an indirect impact of the amnesty may lead to temporary slowdown in some labour-intensive businesses.&quot;</p>
<p>The newspaper said this meant the construction sector, booming as the UAE rushes to develop its infrastructure. The $6 billion construction industry contributes about 14 percent to the federation's gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Suweidi called on authorities to consider a system to bring temporary workers to the country because there was now a real need. &quot;Several systems can be introduced to ensure flexibility and eliminate the existing workforce black market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An economist said recently: &quot;Economic activity will be slowing in the last quarter of this year and (first quarter) next year. The exodus of workers will slow down construction and many contractors may have to postpone projects and prices will go up.&quot;</p>
<p>A Gulf-based diplomat told Reuters: &quot;People are looking everywhere for labour. A dhow that used to take a day to load on Dubai creek now takes five days. Traders are getting squeezed. There's bound to be a damper on growth.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
