<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135592" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Finland - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are some of the leading stories in Finnish papers this morning.</p>
<p>HELSINGIN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Centre Party and the ruling Social Democrats now neck-and- neck as two biggest parties after European parliament and local elections.</p>
<p>- Courts in different parts of the country hand down different punishments for similar criminal offences, polls show.</p>
<p>- A clear majority of Finns think alcohol should be on sale in ordinary supermarkets, but 20 per cent say strong spirits should not be avaliable, polls show. @</p>
<p>- Majority of adult education experts say job-seekers should be obliged to satisfy minimum proficiency criteria before being offered jobs.</p>
<p>- Insurance group Sampo gets court order to pay compensation for illegal dismissals.</p>
<p>- Over half of the world's spoken languages face risk of extinction in coming decades, says Australian professor.</p>
<p>- Overall performance of ruling Social Democrats in local and EU elections indicates the party's support is waning among voters - editorial. @</p>
<p>KAUPPALEHTI</p>
<p>- In the next few years more funds will flow into life insurance, expected to boost insurance companies' shares.</p>
<p>- Insurance group Sampo to derive huge benefits as overall value of sister company Kaleva is transferred to newly formed Henki-Sampo.</p>
<p>- Many business people made significant gains in local elections. More than 1,000 of total 2,500 elected candidates are business people. @</p>
<p>DEMARI</p>
<p>- Low election turnout in urban centres explains poor performance of ruling Social Democrats.</p>
<p>- Centre Party member of parliament Mikko Pesala emerges as strong favourite of vice-speaker of parliament to replace Sirkka-Liisa Antil who leaves for Brussels.</p>
<p>AAMULEHTI</p>
<p>- Famous BBC symphony orchestra finally makes an appearance in Tampere after 66 years of existence.</p>
<p>- Forest industry shows growing concern over diminishing forest reserves, even though wood cutting in Finland is far below forest growth rate. @</p>
<p>TURUN SANOMAT</p>
<p>- Low turnout of unemployed behind overall low showing for Europoll, statistics show.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 89 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
