<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135599" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Boxmore says confident looking forward.</title>
<headline>Boxmore says confident looking forward.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Ireland-based packaging firm Boxmore International said on Tuesday that it was encouraged by current progress and confident looking forward.</p>
<p>The company said while overall UK manufacturing growth remained sluggish, the markets in which it operated continued to improve.</p>
<p>Boxmore said major extensions to the Barrier and Other Containers division were nearing completion and would provide increased production capacity and warehousing facilities.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Boxmore announced a 39 percent rise in pre-tax profits for the six months to June 30 to 7.62 million stg.</p>
<p>The company said the impressive performance by the pharmaceutical and healthcare division was mostly due to its acquisition of GCM and the successful launch of Boxmore Healthcare Packaging earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Sales in the division for the six month period were 17.89 million stg which was an increase of 58.3 percent over the same period in 1995.  </p>
<p>Boxmore said Glaxo Print Services, which it had acquired for a consideration of 6.30 million stg on July 1, was not expected to make a contribution to the pharmaceutical and healthcare division during the first six months of ownership.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident it will make a significant impact on profits in future years and further strengthen our position as the leading supplier of packaging to this industry,&quot; Chairman Harold Ennis said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;A major re-organisation and investment in our labels and leaflets operations to provide faster set-ups and improved efficiency is now in progress,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Boxmore said its emphasis in the healthcare packaging sector over the short-term was to consolidate its position as the market leader in the UK and the Republic of Ireland.</p>
<p>The company said it intended to expand its activities in the sector over the medium and long term by acquisition or alliances in Europe and the U.S.</p>
<p>Boxmore said its food and drinks division had continued to show strong growth with sales for the six month period at 14.44 million stg, an increase of 37.5 percent compared with the same period in 1995.  </p>
<p>The company said its joint venture in South Africa for the manufacture of PET bottles as anticipated had shown a trading loss which reflected the normal off season demand as well as the writing off of start-up costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless, the company has already established a reputation for quality and service which we believe will soon be reflected in higher sales and improved financial results,&quot; Ennis said.</p>
<p>Boxmore said it would continue to exploit its technical leadership at home in the food and drink and the barrier container sector through organic growth and, where appropriate, through joint ventures overseas.</p>
<p>The company said sales in the barrier and other containers divsion had increased by four percent in value and 15 percent in volume, the difference reflecting reductions in selling prices arising from the fall in raw material prices compared with the first half of 1995 and increased competition.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
