<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135525" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: FEATURE - Suez Canal powerful symbol of defiance for Egypt.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Suez Canal powerful symbol of defiance for Egypt.</headline>
<byline>Mona Eltahawy</byline>
<dateline>PORT SAID, Egypt 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Egyptian socialist leader Gamal Abdel Nasser nationalised the Suez Canal in 1956 he transformed the vital waterway from a symbol of occupation to one of defiance of western imperialism.</p>
<p>Egyptians say say Nasser's daring action, aimed at obtaining funds to build the Aswan High Dam, reaped for Egypt the blood and sweat of the thousands of their countrymen who dug the waterway.</p>
<p>&quot;The Suez Canal is a very dear part of Egypt,&quot; said Mohammed Ezzat Adel, former head of the Suez Canal Authority and a veteran of the 1956 war.</p>
<p>Nasser took the world by surprise in July 1956 by announcing that Egypt would take over the Suez Canal, which had been a private company owned and run by British and French interests.</p>
<p>Taking advantage of nationalism unleashed by the coup he led in 1952 that also effectively ended British occupation, Nasser quickly became a symbol of empowerment for developing countries, many of which were taking their first post-colonial steps.</p>
<p>The waterway was a vital link between the Mediterranean and the Red Sea and the British and French colonial powers could ill afford to lose it, so the two countries, aided by Israel, invaded Egypt in October, 1956, in a bid to reclaim it.</p>
<p>&quot;Egypt lost over 100,000 people during the digging of the canal. They dug it in very hard circumstances, for very low wages, under very bad conditions that were almost slavery,&quot; said Adel, who was among the thousands of Egyptians who confronted British and French troops in Port Said during the fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;So Egypt paid a very high price for digging the Suez Canal but what did the Egyptian people get in return? British occupation. The Suez Canal is a very touchy issue and very emotional to all Egyptians,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But Egypt has changed since 1956.</p>
<p>Nasser's successor, Anwar Sadat, turned his back on socialism and implemented instead an &quot;open-door policy&quot; that encouraged foreign investment and led to a growing class of nouveaux riches.</p>
<p>Hosni Mubarak, who took over as president after Sadat's assassination by Moslem militant army officers in 1981, has struck a cautious balance between his predecessors' styles.</p>
<p>For those who still yearn for Nasser's policies, the state-owned canal represents a socialist way of business that some feel is losing favour as the present-day government implements a privatisation programme aimed at dismantling a centralised state economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The nationalisation of the Suez Canal was the first successful attempt of that sort in the third world,&quot; said political analyst Mohammed Sid Ahmed.</p>
<p>&quot;Nasser was the first to get away with it. It was the most important moment in the Nasser period. If it was not a military success then it was a diplomatic and political success.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it is a reminder of the importance that the state should own certain basic national assets. The logic of multinational corporates and the ideology of global markets tend to minimise the importance of certain institutions and the ability to deal with others on an equal footing,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The government has said repeatedly that it has no plans to sell the canal to businessmen, but privatisation has made inroads into sectors previously excluded, such as flour milling.</p>
<p>For Rifaat el-Said, secretary general of the National Progressive Unionist Party, the canal now represents a simple commodity -- cash. Egypt gets an average of $150 million a month in Canal-related revenues.</p>
<p>&quot;The Suez Canal as a symbol has changed from time to time. At one time it was a symbol of British occupation and represented an example of foreign betrayal of the Egyptian people,&quot; Said told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Then it became a symbol of foreign tyranny. At one time, Egyptians were prohibited from holding jobs in the company, even mid-level jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, the Suez Canal is a source of hard currency. The canal as a nationalist symbol is a thing of the past.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72603">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT SAID, Egypt"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
