<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135506" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Ministry of Social Development to complete talks, started by Jordanian economic team with the World Bank, on getting $125 million to implement a social safety net for Jordan's poor. Money would go towards health services and insurance, roads, water, sewage works and schools.</p>
<p>- Parliamentary speaker Srour says he opposes passing of temporary laws covering customs, companies and the stock exchange. Says temporary laws offer no reassurance to investors because they could be amended when parliament sits.</p>
<p>- Financial officials said to be considering a $60 million to $70 million emerging markets fund in Amman covering Jordan, the Palestinian territories and Oman.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kabariti stresses need to give private sector a major role in tourism. Says government will continue to provide supportive role and private sector involvement will not mean replacing one monopoly with another.</p>
<p>- Doctors' committee disagrees with union over understanding which union head Bassem al-Dajani reached with the government and demands doctors carry out planned strike on Saturday.</p>
<p>- King Hussein tells visiting U.S. Jews that Middle East peace process needs to be pushed forward.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Kabariti says won't pass any temporary law ahead of parliament's regular session next month.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Kabariti says French President Jacques Chirac's visit to Jordan on Wednesday reflects importance of France's continued support for Arab and Islamic affairs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
