<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135588" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Sagem eyes Thomson Multimedia - paper.</title>
<headline>Sagem eyes Thomson Multimedia - paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French electronics company Sagem is trying to gather a group of industrial and financial partners to bid for television maker Thomson Multimedia, to rival an offer from South Korea's Daewoo Electronics, daily newspaper Liberation reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Stricken by the government's choice of the Matra -Daewoo partnership, Pierre Faure, chairman of Sagem, seems to be putting together a group of industrial and financial companies capable of making an offer for Thomson,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>French paper La Tribune reported on Monday an unnamed French businessman was putting up a rival bid to Daewoo.  </p>
<p>Sagem later issued an emphatic denial of the newspaper report.</p>
<p>&quot;Following erroneous information published in the daily newspaper Liberation this morning, Sagem denies any interest, and what is more, any negotiations or any contact concerning Thomson Multimedia,&quot; Sagem said in a statement.</p>
<p>Liberation reported that Sagem had apparently been working with Thomson Multimedia's chairman Alain Prestat since last Wednesday to make an offer which would &quot;torpedo&quot; Daewoo's.</p>
<p>A finance ministry spokesman on Monday said the government had not received a third bid for Thomson Multimedia.</p>
<p>The government has chosen Lagardere's bid for the Thomson SA group and plans to sell the Multimedia unit to Daewoo while keeping the defence electronics arm, Thomson-CSF .</p>
<p>A rival bid from engineering giant Alcatel Alsthom was passed over.</p>
<p>Sagem is active in telecommunications and aerospace avionics.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452 pnt</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
