<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135540" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Most ABB segments boost earnings.</title>
<headline>Most ABB segments boost earnings.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABB Asea Brown Boveri AG said operating earnings at three of its five business segments had risen in the first nine months of the year from last year.</p>
<p>ABB said in its nine month report that operating earnings at the Power Generation segment &quot;were well below&quot; the level reported last year and &quot;are expected to remain so for the full year.&quot;</p>
<p>ABB said this reflected continuing competitive market conditions and lower imputed interest income on custumer advances.</p>
<p>Orders at power generation, however, were above last year's level while sales were about the same.</p>
<p>Operating earnings at Power Transmission and Distribution continued to be &quot;substantially above&quot; last year with most business areas contributing to this result.</p>
<p>Operating earnings at Industrial and Building Systems, ABB's largest segment, had improved &quot;substantially&quot; on continued productivity gains, cost-reduction programmes and increased volume, ABB said.</p>
<p>Orders at Industrial and Building Systems was also higher.</p>
<p>At Adtranz, the rail venture with Daimler-Benz AG, operating earnings were &quot;positive and in line with expectations,&quot; but still below that of ABB Transportation in the same period last year.</p>
<p>ABB added that the positive effects of restructuring and elimination of duplication will mainly come in 1997 and 1998.</p>
<p>Earnings at the Financial Services Segment continued to increase &quot;substantially&quot;, reflecting higher treasury centre earnings and a better result in insurance.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
