<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135637" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine state pension funds to be privatised.</title>
<headline>Philippine state pension funds to be privatised.</headline>
<byline>Uday Khandeparkar</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine government plans to privatise the country's two state-controlled pension funds which together have assets worth nearly $7 billion, Finance Secretary Roberto de Ocampo said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to be part of our third wave of privatisation,&quot; De Ocampo told reporters late on Monday.</p>
<p>The Philippines runs two pensions funds, the Government Service Insurance System (GSIS) for government employees which has assets of about 80 billion pesos ($3.05 billion).</p>
<p>The Social Security System (SSS) for private sector employees has assets worth about 100 billion pesos ($3.82 billion) and together the two funds cover about 20 million people, nearly a third of the nation's population of 68 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The pension system is being reviewed and we are taking note of various models to see if any are adaptable (to the Philippines),&quot; De Ocampo told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The other part of this privatisation is to see if other social services like hospitals and schools ... can benefit from privatisation,&quot; De Ocampo said.</p>
<p>He said the government had not yet worked out a time-frame for the pension fund privatisation plan.</p>
<p>The finance secretary said he described this as the third privatisation wave because the government's programme had begun with the divestment of stakes in firms which were originally in the private sector but later came under state control.</p>
<p>The second phase involves infrastructure firms like the National Power Corp (Napocor) and the Metropolitan Water Works and Sewerage System (MWSS).</p>
<p>The MWSS privatisation would be completed by the end of the year while Napocor would begin the process next year, he said.</p>
<p>Brokers welcomed the pension fund plan announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;This is good news for the market,&quot; Julie Villena, an analyst at Manila brokerage Dharmala Securities, said.</p>
<p>Both pension funds were likely to be more aggressive in their investments and increase market liquidity, she said.</p>
<p>Dharmala research director Fitz Aclan said SSS currently invested 10 to 20 percent of its funds in the Philippine stock market while the figure for GSIS was up to 30 percent.</p>
<p>Russel Ong, an analyst at Anscor Hagedorn Securities, said the privatisation would increase government revenues and contribute to an overall improvement in the business environment with a more efficient use of the pension funds.</p>
<p>De Ocampo said that linked to the privatisation was the government's objective of cutting the size of the bureaucracy.</p>
<p>With firms going out of state control &quot;we no longer need a bigger workforce, so we'll have a smaller bureacracy which hopefully will be better paid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Manila-based Asian Development Bank said in a recent report that the Philippines' privatisation programme launched in 1993 has helped it correct the growing public sector resource imbalance.</p>
<p>Privatisation brought in revenues worth $1.9 billion in 1994 and $1.7 billion last year, it said, but the ADB expressed concern that most big ticket privatisations were over while the government had not yet finalised sustainable alternative sources of revenue.</p>
<p>The government says it is working on this and is hoping a new tax package will be in place by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The implementation of the tax reform package has been delayed in the legislature because of differing opinions over how beer and cigarettes should be taxed. The present tax system is complicated and leaves scope for large-scale evasion. ($1 =26.20 pesos)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
