<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135681" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-MONTGOMERIE ALREADY LOOKING FORWARD TO RECORD FIFTH TITLE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-MONTGOMERIE ALREADY LOOKING FORWARD TO RECORD FIFTH TITLE.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colin Montgomerie, his fourth successive European Order of Merit title confirmed, is already looking forward to a record fifth.</p>
<p>&quot;I will play 18 tournaments, the same as this year,&quot; said Montgomerie as he prepared for the the Volvo Masters starting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be marvellous to win for a record fifth time -- then to be interviewed on TV by Peter Oosterhuis.&quot;</p>
<p>The only other four times champion, now a European Tour commentator, is unstinting in his praise for the 33-year-old Scot.</p>
<p>&quot;I admire the quality of player that he is because I think it is very much tougher now to come out on top every year,&quot; said Oosterhuis, who won his fourth title 22 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Look at the success of the European Ryder Cup team and the number of Europeans who have won major titles. In my time there was only Tony Jacklin.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength of Colin's game is that he is outstanding tee to green. And he is obviously a better putter than he thinks he is to shoot the scores he shoots.&quot;</p>
<p>Oosterhuis admires Montgomerie's rhythm. &quot;His control over it, no matter what the circumstances, is wonderful.&quot;</p>
<p>And he feels the Scot's only weakness &quot;is that he tends to get overstressed when he hits a good putt and the ball doesn't drop.&quot;</p>
<p>Montgomerie clinched the title when closest challenger Ian Woosnam missed the cut at the German Masters three weeks ago.</p>
<p>That resolved the issue in stark contrast to his stirring battle against fellow-Scot Sam Torrance last year, when Montgomerie had to hole a three-foot putt on the final green at Valderrama to win his third title.</p>
<p>Next year Montgomerie will start earlier but play only 18 European Tour events -- the same as this year -- while spending more time in the United States trying to win his first grand slam crown.</p>
<p>This year he delayed his start until March when his wife Eimear gave birth to their second child, using the time to embark on a fitness programme which saw him shed some 15 kgs.</p>
<p>Then, after the three-month break, he won his first event, the Dubai Desert Classic, with a magnificent second shot with his driver off the fairway at the final hole which led to a one-stroke victory over Spaniard Miguel Jimenez.</p>
<p>He had lost nothing by being away so long. &quot;Starting late as I did, losing weight and winning in Dubai -- that set me on my way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Since clinching the Order of Merit title, Montgomerie failed to help Scotland retain the Alfred Dunhill Cup and could not pick up the World Matchplay title, in which he was beaten in the second round last week by American Mark Brooks.</p>
<p>But the 40,000 pounds sterling ($64,000) he won for that boosted his lifetime earnings above five million pounds ($8.0 million), making him only the third European to do so after Bernhard Langer and Nick Faldo.</p>
<p>His incentive to capture this week's title -- he also won it in 1993 -- is that victory would bring a total 300,000 pounds ($480,000) in prize money and bonuses, making him the first person to win more than one million pounds ($1.6 million) in official earnings for the year on the European tour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
