<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135641" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: End to Indian sugar export monopoly hits prices.</title>
<headline>End to Indian sugar export monopoly hits prices.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's recent decision to end a trading agency's monopoly over sugar exports has helped push down prices and undercut export earnings, industry officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's cabinet decided in late August to end an export monopoly held by the Indian Sugar and General Industries Export Import Corp (ISIGEC), a private company set up by the sugar milling industry.</p>
<p>Exports will continue to be funnelled, or &quot;canalised&quot;, through ISIGEC until the Sugar Export Promotion Act (SEPA) of 1958 is amended, officials said.</p>
<p>Parliament is not scheduled to reconvene until next month. But the decision to end ISIGEC's monopoly could be implemented through a presidential ordinance.</p>
<p>&quot;The mere announcement of decanalisation has brought down prices because the big dealers know what the result is going to be,&quot; said Shivaji Rao Patil, president of the National Federation of Cooperative Sugar Factories (NFCSF).</p>
<p>Industry officials said world sugar prices had come down sharply since the government announcement, partly because of the change in Indian policy.</p>
<p>NFCSF managing director M.S. Marathe said that white sugar on the export market was quoted at about $370 per tonne on September 2. More recently it has fallen to about $330.</p>
<p>&quot;Decanalisation has precipitated the fall,&quot; Marathe said.</p>
<p>&quot;It (decanalisation) could have contributed to the price sentiment since India is the largest producer of sugar,&quot; said Sujay Mishra, an analyst with SSKI securities.</p>
<p>Industry experts said there was a self-fulfilling expectation that competition among exporters, once ISIGEC's control over foreign sales ends, would push down prices.</p>
<p>Domestic millers said they expected an increase in the number of exporters would hurt the quality of exports, put downward pressure on prices and hurt India's trade balance.</p>
<p>&quot;If everybody is allowed to export it would lead to undercutting and a fall in realisation, and quality will go down,&quot; Mishra said.</p>
<p>But Civil Supplies Minister Devendra Prasad Yadav recently told parliament that competition among exporters would lead to improved quality.</p>
<p>Surplus stocks and the prospect of greater traded supplies on world markets have also contributed to lower world prices, analysts said.</p>
<p>The International Sugar Organisation estimates that world production will outstrip supply for the third consecutive year in 1996/97 (October-September).</p>
<p>International trade house E D &amp; F Man said last week that world sugar prices could come under pressure later in 1996/97, with the possibility of raw sugar exports from India and the release of white sugar surpluses from Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>In its first estimate of the 1996/97 sugar balance, Man said an export buffer was building up in India, Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic, and a sizeable volume of sugar could be unleashed on the world market.</p>
<p>Indian sugar output in the 1995/96 season which ended on September 30 is forecast at about 16.4 million tonnes, up sharply from 14.6 million in the previous crop year, according to industry estimates. Annual domestic consumption is about 13 million tonnes.</p>
<p>India contracted for one million tonnes of sugar exports in the 1995/96 season. A similar quantity has been authorised for exports in 1996/97.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
