<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135600" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Oct 22.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's Austrian newspapers.</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Conservative coalition partner, the People's Party, has set an ultimatum for plans by Social Democrat Health Minister Christa Krammer for specialist doctors' call duty. The party will only back the plans if they are clearly profitable.</p>
<p>- Banking secrecy is to become more permeable. Security accounts will in future be opened without a court decision.</p>
<p>- Inflation went up to two percent in September due to rising prices in oil, rent and in the clothing sector.</p>
<p>- Some 500 jobs are to be lost at synthetic fibre maker Lenzing over the next two or three years.</p>
<p>- Austria has a 16 to 20 percent share of EU-investments in the emerging markets, making the country second only to Germany.</p>
<p>- German chancellor Helmut Kohl has praised Austria's tax system as a model for his country.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- The ministers' council will probably pass the plans of Health Minister Krammer for specialist doctors' duty in hospitals.</p>
<p>- Bidders for the governemnt's stake in Creditanstalt will have to place their offers by November 15, the Finance Ministry announced.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Conservative People's Party leader and vice-chancellor Wolfgang Schuessel has declared his party would not agree to change the course of the government. Chancellor Franz Vranitzky wants to introduce socialist reforms after his Social Democrat's defeat in recent European parliament polls.</p>
<p>- In the last run for the privatisation of Creditanstalt the buyer will not have to take over all of the government's stake.</p>
<p>- Austria's GDP per capita is higher than its neighbouring countries. Only Switzerland has a higher ratio.</p>
<p>- Floods due to heavy rainfall in northern Austria have killed three people.</p>
<p>WIRTSCHAFTSBLATT</p>
<p>- Vienna's city government is to exclude council home spending -- amounting to 12 billion schillings -- from its budget.</p>
<p>- German building material maker Raab Karcher is to start up business in Austria. Talks on taking over regional traders have begun.</p>
<p>- Austria's beer market has gone down by 2.3 percent in the period from January to September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
