<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135688" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHELSEA FUTURE ASSURED DESPITE HARDING DEATH, SAYS BATES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHELSEA FUTURE ASSURED DESPITE HARDING DEATH, SAYS BATES.</headline>
<byline>Andy Drinkwater</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chelsea chairman Ken Bates said on Wednesday the future of the club was assured despite the death of multi-millionaire backer and vice-chairman Matthew Harding in a helicopter crash.</p>
<p>Speaking at a press conference at the club's Stamford Bridge ground he said everyone connected with Chelsea had been stunned by his death.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all still shocked and trying to come to terms with what happened when only 20 hours ago we were laughing and joking,&quot; Bates said.</p>
<p>&quot;Matthew's death does not and will not affect our future plans. Such was his devotion he has insured that his present financial committment was in place.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue the next phase of delivering his and all Chelsea fans' dreams of having a world class team in a world class stadium.&quot;</p>
<p>As a mark of respect the club announced that the new North Stand would be named the Matthew Harding Stand.</p>
<p>There will be a minute's silence at all premier league matches on Saturday including the match between Chelsea and London rivals Tottenham which will go ahead as scheduled.</p>
<p>Harding was one of five people killed in a helicopter crash on Tuesday as they flew back after Chelsea's defeat in a third round English League Cup match at Bolton.</p>
<p>Manager Ruud Gullit said he was &quot;deeply depressed&quot; at the news of Harding's death.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew him for a short time but I will remember him, his laughs and happiness after a game. He was enthusiastic about the club. He was really a Chelsea fan, something we would like to treasure.&quot;</p>
<p>Estimates of Harding's personal investment in Chelsea vary enormously from 11 million pounds ($17.6 million) to as much as 26.5 million pounds ($42.4 million).</p>
<p>But it is clear the money from his personal fortune of 150 million sterling ($240 million) that he did put into the club was crucial to helping Chelsea's dream of a return to the club's halcyon days of the 60s and 70s.</p>
<p>Harding became Chelsea vice-chairman earlier this year following a much-publicised boardroom power struggle with Bates during which Harding was banned from the directors' box. Harding disagreed strongly about the direction his money should take the club, believing that a great team was the first priority, not a futuristic stadium that no-one wanted to visit.</p>
<p>Harding became the landlord at their Stamford Bridge ground when he bought the site in his capacity as boss of city insurance group Benfield for 16.5 million pounds ($26 million) in 1995 . Harding was also the prime mover behind the recruitment of Glen Hoddle, now England manager, and his successor, player-manager Ruud Gullit and backed with cash the high-profile signings of Italians Gianluca Vialli and Roberto Di Matteo and France's Frank Le Boeuf.</p>
<p>For the fans who gathered at the ground on Wednesday to lay floral tributes at the stadium gates the approachable and down-to-earth Harding was a hugely popular figure and his death may be a significant blow to the club's fortunes.</p>
<p>Chelsea are desperate for success. Only recently have they started to show signs of being able to compete with the premier league elite. In 1995 the club reached the European Cup Winners' Cup semifinals, having been beaten in the F.A. Cup final at Wembley in 1994 by league and cup double winners Manchester United.</p>
<p>Their only championship success came in 1955 and their only F.A Cup success in 1970. The only other major honours include the League Cup in 1965 and the European Cup Winners Cup in 1971.</p>
<p>Despite their size and their potential support, Chelsea are still considered to be London's &quot;third&quot; club after Arsenal and Tottenham and Harding's death must raise serious questions about the club's financial future.</p>
<p>Harding's money was a key element in the signing of many big-name players and Chelsea's ability to make any future acquisitions for a sustained tilt at the major honours must be seriously in question.</p>
<p>News of his death sent shares in Chelsea Village, the public company which owns Chelsea Football Club dived 9p to 80p.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
