<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135697" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: HORSE RACING-CIGAR AGAIN IS BREEDERS' CUP CLASSIC FAVORITE.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-CIGAR AGAIN IS BREEDERS' CUP CLASSIC FAVORITE.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cigar, last year's Horse of the Year and one of the best thoroughbreds of all time, drew post position 7 Wednesday and predictably was made the 4-5 early favourite for Saturday's $4 million Breeders' Cup Classic race.</p>
<p>The 1-1/4-mile Classic, one of seven races in the $11 million Breeders' Cup extravaganza, presents a rare chance for Cigar to avenge a defeat.</p>
<p>The second favourite at 6-1 was Dare and Go, who halted Cigar's streak of consecutive victories at 16 last August.</p>
<p>Dare and Go will break from the inside gate in the 13th running of the Breeders' Cup at Woodbine racetrack, the first time the event is being staged outside the United States.</p>
<p>Three-year-old filly Yanks Music -- third favourite in the early betting line -- was set at 10-1 and drew the 8th gate.</p>
<p>Cigar, who will be ridden by Jerry Bailey, has won 19 of 21 starts on dirt with an undefeated season last year, including victory in the Breeders' Cup Classic. Bailey is aiming for his fifth Classic win in the last six years.</p>
<p>The six-year-old Cigar, who could be making his last run for money Saturday, arrived Wednesday from Belmont in New York and trainer Bill Mott pronounced him fit after the horse rolled in the hay and ate a peppermint candy.</p>
<p>Dare and Go's trainer, Dick Mandella, said the post position is &quot;not a big advantage or disadvantage one way or the other. It's more important to get a good break at the start than have a good post.&quot;</p>
<p>Mandella said he had all his horses &quot;as good as I can have them.&quot; He indicated that to be in any better shape his horse would have &quot;to be Cigar.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It'll just have to be our day and not his. To be honest, I wouldn't wish him any bad luck, but I'm rooting for myself.&quot;</p>
<p>Preakness Stakes winner Louis Quatorze, with Pat Day riding, was set at 12-1 out of the 11th chute for the Classic. Belmont Stakes winner Editor's Note was seen by track oddsmaker Jim Bannon as a 15-1 shot.</p>
<p>Japan will have its first representative in the Breeders' Cup with Taiki Blizzard, sired by Seattle Slew, in the Classic.</p>
<p>Twelve European horses are expected to start in the turf races.</p>
<p>Singspiel, Swain, Shantou and Wall Street, owned by Godolphin racing and Sheikhh Mohammed bin Rashid al Maktoum, the minister of defence of the United Arab Emirates, were put at 9-5 favourites for the $2 million Turf over 1-1/2 miles.</p>
<p>The Godolphin entry of Mark of Esteem and Charnwood Forest are 8-5 favourites for the $1 million Mile on turf.</p>
<p>Providing a good deal of levity, if not outright scorn by the purists, for the very serious day of racing, is New Mexico-based Ricks Natural Star, who was pronounced a 99-1 shot to win the Turf. Ricks Natural Star has not raced in 14 months and last won in 1993 against $3,500 claimers.</p>
<p>Woodbine's racing stewards allowed the horse to be one of the maximum 14 entries in the Turf after a 15-minute inquiry Wednesday into the horse's fitness. The track starter could have scratched the horse if he determined his appearance could be detrimental to the race.</p>
<p>In the Juvenile over 1-1/16 miles, Ordway was set as the 2-1 favourite, breaking from post 6 with jockey John Velazquez. Boston Harbour is the strong second choice at 5-2 from post position 2.</p>
<p>As usual, the 1-1/8-miles Distaff will have the smallest Breeders' Cup field with just seven entries. Different is the 9-5 favourite in the morning line.</p>
<p>The favourite in the $1 million Sprint over six furlongs is Honour and Glory at 3-1.</p>
<p>The best of the 12-horse field for the 1-1/16-mile Juvenile Fillies race are suspected to be Storm Song at 5-2 and Sharp Cat at 7-2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
