<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135664" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-BARCELONA GO TOP IN SPAIN AS CHAMPIONS ATLETICO CRASH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BARCELONA GO TOP IN SPAIN AS CHAMPIONS ATLETICO CRASH.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Barcelona bumped arch-rivals Real Madrid off the top spot in Spain thanks to a late goal by Luis Enrique Martinez in a hard-fought 1-0 win at Sevilla on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the big news of a full first division programme was in the Vicente Calderon stadium where champions Atletico Madrid crashed 3-1 to lowly neighbours Rayo Vallecano.</p>
<p>Barcelona move two points ahead of Real, 2-1 winners at Zaragoza on Tuesday, while Atletico are a further 10 points back after just nine games.</p>
<p>Barcelona survived disallowed goals in each half but were kept afloat by keeper Vitor Baia and another Portuguese international, winger Luis Figo.</p>
<p>Just 12 minutes from time the game looked to be heading for a draw when Figo unleashed a fierce shot from outside the area which appeared to cross the line after bouncing off the bar. </p>
<p>Luis Enrique saved the referee the problem of consulting with his linesman by heading home the winner with Sevilla keeper Monchi Rodriguez stranded.</p>
<p>After the game Sevilla coach Jose Antonio Camacho accused the referee of &quot;being scared&quot; in calling offside on the disallowed goals.</p>
<p>Atletico Madrid's outspoken president Jesus Gil, who has blasted referees he believes favour Barcelona and Real Madrid over the past few days, was silenced by three goals by Rayo Vallecano.</p>
<p>Brazilian striker Guilherme, Croatian midfielder Stjepan Andrijasevic and Jesus Cota -- the first Spanish player to score for the side this season -- found the mark, before Juan Carlos Gomez snatched a late consolation goal for Atletico.</p>
<p>&quot;We were a caricature of a team, there's a lot of things we have to do,&quot; grumbled Atletico coach Radomir Antic, whose side lost their way after Argentine striker Juan Eduardo Esnaider missed a penalty.</p>
<p>Third-placed Deportivo Coruna managed only a 1-1 draw at Racing Santander and fall two points behind Real Madrid while fourth-placed Real Betis are a further point back after returning home from Oviedo with the same score.</p>
<p>Valladolid are a surprise fifth after winning 1-0 at Logrones while Valencia helped veteran keeper Andoni Zubizarreta celebrate his 35th birthday with a 2-1 victory over Sporting Gijon that moves them up to sixth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
