<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135669" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ZARAGOZA'S FERNANDEZ SEEKS JUSTICE AND POINTS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ZARAGOZA'S FERNANDEZ SEEKS JUSTICE AND POINTS.</headline>
<dateline>ZARAGOZA, Spain 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beleaguered Zaragoza coach Victor Fernandez is facing dismissal just 16 months after taking the club to its greatest-ever triumph.</p>
<p>With only one win in nine games this season, Fernandez's charges are unrecognisable from the sleek attacking side who snatched a last-gasp victory over Arsenal in Paris in the 1995 European Cup Winners' Cup final.</p>
<p>In the 1993-94 season Fernandez led Zaragoza to only their fourth-ever Spanish Cup win and third place in the league.</p>
<p>But fans with short memories carried banners reading `Adios Fernandez' during Tuesday's home match against Real Madrid, which Zaragoza lost 2-1.</p>
<p>The match typified the bad luck which has dogged Fernandez's side in recent months. A questionable penalty and a sending-off sealed the game for Real after Zaragoza had twice been denied by the woodwork.</p>
<p>Long-suffering Zaragoza fans must be wondering what they have done wrong.</p>
<p>Just four weeks ago, their team's 3-1 lead over Barcelona was transformed into a 5-3 defeat after another hotly-disputed penalty and a dismissal. On the opening day of the season a dubious sending-off also changed the course of their match against Valencia.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel powerless, as well as rage and desperation,&quot; Fernandez said after Tuesday's match. &quot;Let's hope some day we `suffer' some correct refereeing decisions.&quot;</p>
<p>Little has actually changed at Zaragoza since the Paris final, when Nayim's spectacular last-minute strike from the halfway line ballooned over the head of Arsenal 'keeper David Seaman and brought all of Spain to its feet.</p>
<p>The other Zaragoza scorer that night -- Argentine striker Juan Eduardo Esnaider -- has moved on, but most of the side's other heroes are still with the club.</p>
<p>It scarcely showed last weekend against newly-promoted Extremadura, who beat Zaragoza 2-1 to chalk up their first points at the top level after seven consecutive defeats.</p>
<p>The bad run of results has been too much for sections of the crowd at the Romareda stadium, who proclaimed their unhappiness with Spain's referees recently by greeting one of them with a chorus of 15,000 whistles.</p>
<p>But while much of the anger is directed against match officials, Fernandez knows that with his team fifth from bottom of the table, and with four teams facing automatic relegation this season, he has to start producing results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZARAGOZA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
