<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135651" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks drift lower in morning trade.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks drift lower in morning trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks drifted lower in Tuesday morning trad, shedding a quick 30-gain at the market consolidated recent gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;After having gained so much ground, we expect some consolidation,&quot; said Peter Lui in institutional sales at NAVA SC Securities. &quot;But any consolidation is likely to be short-lived, only two to three days.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index was down 19 points at 12,491. Turnover was HK$1.28 billion after the first 30 minutes of trade.</p>
<p>The blue chip index rose 73.25 points to hit a new record close of 12,510.25 on Friday.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said the market is looking very overbought and a healthy consolidation would be a good sign.</p>
<p>&quot;Short-term, we need to see a consolidation, even as much as 500 points would be good,&quot; said Alan Shum, research manager at New Century Securities. &quot;Medium-term, the index is still on course to hit 13,000.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders remained cautiously optimistic that market activity would remain robust enough to support further gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Turnover will be the key,&quot; said Ronald Lam.  &quot;We are not likely to reach 13,000 without turnover of HK$7 billion to HHK$8 billion.&quot;</p>
<p>NAVA's Lui said that the market is still in the process of a rerating, which would bring the index to a valuation of 17 times to 18 times prospective earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still seeing foreign investor interest in the Bank (HSBC) and other blue chips,&quot; said Lam.</p>
<p>All blue chip sectors were down in early trade with the exception of the utilities. The commercial and industrial sector came in for the heaviest profit-taking with CITIC Pacific down HK$0.70 at HK$37.00 and Swire Pacific off HK$0.75 at HK$71.00.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Telecom inched up HK$0.05 to HK$13.75, while China Light lost HK$0.20 to HK$37.00.</p>
<p>HSBC opened up HK$156.00, an all-time high, then eased to trade HK$0.50 up at HK$155.50. The share was the most active in early trade.</p>
<p>Subsidiary Hang Seng Bank led the losers with a net change of HK$0.75 to HK$92.25.</p>
<p>Hopewell also remained high on the most active list, gaining HK$0.10 to HK$5.40 on trade of HK$103.02 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
