<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135696" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - IRELAND'S OLDEST SOCCER CLUB FACES TOUGHEST TEST.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - IRELAND'S OLDEST SOCCER CLUB FACES TOUGHEST TEST.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>For 117 years Cliftonville Football Club has survived the rough and tumble of the soccer pitch. Now it faces an altogether more serious threat off the field.</p>
<p>One of Northern Ireland's 16 professional teams, the oldest club on the island of Ireland and the driving force behind the formation of the Irish Football Association in 1880, it has finally fallen victim to the sectarian strife that has plagued the British province for generations.</p>
<p>An attack by Protestant pro-British &quot;Loyalists&quot; on buses carrying Cliftonville fans, who are mainly pro-Irish Catholics, has sent shudders through the game in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>&quot;Mob attack puts soccer in crisis,&quot; said a headline in Belfast's Irish News after Protestant hardliners pelted two coaches from the north Belfast club with bricks and bottles as they arrived in Portadown on October 19 for a match with the local team.</p>
<p>The match was abandoned at half-time.</p>
<p>&quot;Cliftonville:...is this the end?&quot; asked Belfast's Sunday Life. It said the club's future was hanging in the balance &quot;after the politically-motivated campaign against their supporters took on a frightening new dimension.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's very, very sad and it doesn't augur well for the future of football,&quot; League president Morton McKnight told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Football has remained apart from the political scene and has provided a vehicle for both sections of the community to mingle on the terraces and enjoy the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;I am asking people now to stand back. It is very, very dangerous obviously for Cliftonville and spells great danger for the Irish League as well when people can determine who is going...to attend a football match.&quot;</p>
<p>The Portadown ambush has raised fears among Cliftonville fans that other hardline Loyalists will mount further attacks.</p>
<p>Some fear the violence might force Cliftonville to follow in the footsteps of two other Catholic-supported teams, which were forced out of Northern Irish football after trouble linked to the province's sectarian malaise.</p>
<p>&quot;Reds (Cliftonville) may be forced to quit the Irish League,&quot; the Irish News commented gloomily.</p>
<p>Belfast Celtic, arguably the most powerful club ever in Northern Ireland,  disbanded in 1949 after winning the League six times in the previous seven seasons.</p>
<p>Derry City withdrew from the League in 1972 as a direct result of the troubles and after a moribund decade they re-started and now play in the Republic of Ireland.</p>
<p>Some of the 200 troublemakers at the Portadown match held up placards with the message &quot;Republican scum not welcome in Ulster (Northern Ireland)&quot;.</p>
<p>According to media reports, they gathered after leaflets were circulated alleging that some Cliftonville fans had placed a wreath last August at an IRA memorial to dead guerrillas.</p>
<p>The Irish Republican Army, which draws support from a minority of the 40 percent Catholic population in Northern Ireland, resumed a bombing war against British rule in February after a 17-month truce.</p>
<p>Royal Ulster Constabularly assistant chief constable Bill McCreesh, who tried to hold the rioters back, denounced them as vicious thugs.</p>
<p>It was the second Loyalist protest against Cliftonville in a month.</p>
<p>In an earlier incident they blocked Cliftonville fans from attending a match in the staunchly pro-British stronghold of east Belfast in retaliation for Catholic nationalist protests against parades by Protestants during a volatile summer &quot;marching season&quot; in the province.</p>
<p>Sectarian tension grew into the worst street violence for years in several towns during July.</p>
<p>Two people died and many others were injured in clashes when Protestants were allowed to parade through Catholic areas in Belfast and Portadown.</p>
<p>The new violence was seen in some quarters as a spillover from those disturbances, undermining the pride felt by the senior soccer organising body, the Irish League, which despite years of conflict football had been a force for unity between Protestants and Catholics.</p>
<p>Cliftonville chairman Jim Boyce, who said he detested any display of sectarianism, warned that further violence against his club's followers would have grave repercussions. </p>
<p>&quot;The whole of (Northern) Irish League football is at stake,&quot; he said. &quot;I would fear for...football in this province if anything more happens.</p>
<p>&quot;It (would be) very, very easy to get rid of Cliftonville but the club is determined that it is going to continue in football for as long as it can,&quot; Boyce told Reuters.</p>
<p>Pledging full support for Cliftonville, McKnight said there was widespread sympathy for its plight.</p>
<p>&quot;They are the oldest club in Ireland and it would be very very sad if after battling through since 1879 they had to withdraw because of the actions of a few people.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
