<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135632" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks shed weight, Lagardere stars again.</title>
<headline>French stocks shed weight, Lagardere stars again.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks opened a touch weaker on Tuesday with a degree of consolidation paring leading shares after a good run last week and new highs reached on Friday.</p>
<p>After a lower start, the blue-chip CAC-40 index crept back a little and was down 1.24 points or 0.06 percent at 2178.98 at 0923 GMT while the CAC-40 futures contract was down one at 2186.0 from Monday's close.</p>
<p>Oil stocks Elf and Total bucked market trend, but the star once again was missile-to-magazines group Lagardere.</p>
<p>Lagardere's stock was up 4.36 percent at 184.3 francs at 0925 GMT, extending Monday's gains of more than six percent, on continued good feeling after it emerged as the government's preferred bidder in the privatisation of Thomson SA.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody cares about the results, it's the Thomson story that counts,&quot; said one trader, noting foreign investor interest.</p>
<p>Other action came on the television front, with news that TF1 broadcaster was crossing swords with rival Canal Plus over the latter's merger with Nethold.</p>
<p>TF1 chairman Patrick Le Lay said in a newspaper interview he had started legal proceedings to exclude Nethold sports coverage from the alliance, saying Canal Plus had pledged not to compete with another sports channel Eurosport, in which TF1 is involved.</p>
<p>Both Canal Plus and TF1 stocks were more than one percent weaker in morning trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
