<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135665" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE GETS 100TH CAP BUT AUSTRALIA FIND GOING HARD.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE GETS 100TH CAP BUT AUSTRALIA FIND GOING HARD.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>PADUA, Italy 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Winger David Campese collected his 100th international cap on Wednesday as Australia made hard work of getting the better of Italy 40-18.</p>
<p>The visitors celebrated at the whistle but it was more in relief than anything else after finding themselves lagging behind the hosts 18-13 in the second half.</p>
<p>Campese, 34 years old on Monday, came on to a roar and a banner declaring &quot;Some say God, we say Campo!&quot;</p>
<p>It was undoubtedly his night but Australia made heavy weather of the match and Campese, despite a few delightful touches, had a subdued first half.</p>
<p>Fullback Mathew Burke missed three penalty kicks in the first 10 minutes before flanker David Wilson put the visitors ahead with a try after Michael Brial made the run.</p>
<p>Stefano Bordon put Italy back in the game with a 22nd minute try and former Puma flyhalf Diego Dominguez delighted the crowd with a drop goal in the 25th as a confident Italy team took the lead for the first time.</p>
<p>Burke replied with a penalty in the 33rd minute and another on the stroke of half time.</p>
<p>Six minutes into the second half Dominguez deftly side-stepped limping flyhalf David Knox for Italy's second try and then converted for a 15-13 lead.</p>
<p>Knox was substituted by Jason Little as Australia went further behind to a Dominguez penalty.</p>
<p>Burke kicked two more penalties to put Australia 19-18 ahead before the American referee Ed Sorenson gave the visitors a helping hand with a call that incensed the locals.</p>
<p>He ruled Michael Foley had scored a pushover try despite Italian protests that he had not. The crowd shouted &quot;idiot, idiot&quot; and no Australian claimed the honours.</p>
<p>Italy scored no further points and faded badly, with Australian vice-captain Tim Horan scoring a beautiful try in the 75th and Wilson his second in the final minute.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PADUA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
