<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135668" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-MONTY BLASTS BONUS RULING FOR ALLENBY.</title>
<headline>GOLF-MONTY BLASTS BONUS RULING FOR ALLENBY.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number two Colin Montgomerie on Wednesday slammed European Tour officials for ruling Robert Allenby would be entitled to collect a bonus of up to 73,000 pounds ($117,00) for hitting just one shot in Thursday's Volvo Masters.</p>
<p>&quot;It is bringing the game into disrepute. It is a farce. We are holding ourselves up to ridicule,&quot; said Montgomerie, who is guaranteed a bonus of 150,000 pounds ($240,000) for starting the event.</p>
<p>The difference is that Montgomerie plans to play the entire tournament whereas Allenby, still recovering from injuries sustained in a car crash three weeks ago and taking part against doctor's orders, may not hit more than one shot.</p>
<p>Allenby, third on the money list, will be eligible for 73,000 pounds ($117,000) in bonus money if he maintains his place on the list and if he meets the requirement that he play in this event to be eligible for the payout.</p>
<p>The Australian, who sustained a broken breast bone in the accident, has been ordered not to play until late November.</p>
<p>He was due to be the first player to tee off at 0850 local time (0750 GMT).</p>
<p>European Tour officials have ruled Allenby will be eligible for the payout -- even if, as reports say, he does it with a putter off the tee.</p>
<p>Montgomerie, assured of being number one in Europe for the fourth successive year the minute he hits his first shot, does not agree.</p>
<p>&quot;The rule says he must compete to win the bonus. Assuming he putts once off the tee, is that competing? The Tour says yes, but common sense says something else. I wouldn't say that's competing in any tournament. That's not competing to me,&quot; Montgomerie said.</p>
<p>&quot;But you can't blame Robert Allenby at all. He's quite entitled to do what he's doing. All credit to him for flying back from Australia to do it, because the rule is there,&quot; Montgomerie said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I'm not sure he's actually competing.&quot;</p>
<p>Montgomerie said he felt the bonus pool of 600,000 pounds ($960,000), which is distributed to the top 15 on the money list after the tournament, should rather be added to the prize money.</p>
<p>&quot;Why not, as the U.S. Tour does, put it into the prize fund and have a far greater first prize?&quot; he suggested.</p>
<p>&quot;The bonus is offered to encourage players to play. But if it was in the prize fund, players would be encouraged the same way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In addition to the bonus, if Allenby remains in third place on the money list he will also gain exemptions to various U.S. tournaments including the Masters, at Augusta in April, and the World Series in Ohio in August.</p>
<p>&quot;Robert's looking to next year. Naturally he wants to play in the Masters,&quot; Montgomerie said.</p>
<p>Allenby's manager Andrew Ramsey said the golfer was &quot;still pretty hurt&quot; from his accident.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unlikely that Robert will hit more than one shot,&quot; said Ramsey, speaking by telephone from Malaga airport.</p>
<p>He added that they had booked a flight to leave Spain on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
