<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135691" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH OFFICIALS STAND FIRM OVER ITALY ENCOUNTER.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH OFFICIALS STAND FIRM OVER ITALY ENCOUNTER.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>England have confirmed next month's international against Italy will go ahead, despite the possibility of the home side fielding a third-choice side at Twickenham if their top clubs withdraw leading players.</p>
<p>The Rugby Football Union (RFU), whose talks with the clubs broke up amid acrimony on Tuesday, insist they are prepared to select an alternative team if the dispute goes on.</p>
<p>&quot;God forbid the best players should not be available. The players want to play for England and I hope they are not used as pawns,&quot; said RFU president John Richardson</p>
<p>&quot;But we have lots of good players in the country and we are not in the business of calling off internationals. The game against Italy will be played.&quot;</p>
<p>If the English Professional Rugby Union Clubs (EPRUC) go through with their threat to withdraw players contracted to them, former England captain Will Carling could be the only established player left in the national side.</p>
<p>Carling has declined to align himself with EPRUC, who are at odds with the RFU over television rights and control of competitions.</p>
<p>The RFU describe the proposals rejected by EPRUC as &quot;the most generous and liberal that any country has devised.&quot; They have offered the 24 league one and two clubs a deal worth 18 million pounds over the next two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
