<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135662" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SEC bars ex-Stratton Oakmont salesman for five years.</title>
<headline>SEC bars ex-Stratton Oakmont salesman for five years.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Regulators on Wednesday issued an order barring for five years a former Stratton Oakmont Inc. salesman for allegedly using high pressure and fraudulent sales tactics &quot;in utter disregard of his obligations to customers.&quot;</p>
<p>The order signed by SEC Chairman Arthur Levitt and three other SEC commissioners upheld a ruling by an administrative law judge against Richard Puccio, of Syossett, N.Y.</p>
<p>The SEC said Pucio engaged in &quot;boiler room&quot; sales practices and failed to tell customers the stocks he was selling were speculative and risky. The order bars Puccio from joining any broker or dealer, with a right to reapply after five years.</p>
<p>The SEC said Puccio's admissions at a hearing show that he engaged &quot;in knowing misconduct.&quot; He could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>The SEC alleged that Puccio made baseless price predictions, discouraged customers from selling, misrepresented Stratton's research capabilities and impersonated other salesmen.</p>
<p>The SEC said that Puccio's counsel admitted that the salesman's conduct at Stratton was &quot;egregious.&quot;</p>
<p>Puccio worked for Stratton, a penny-stock specialist, from March 1989 to June 1991.</p>
<p>Before working for the New York firm, he broke state securities sales rules in the sale of a security to an Oklahoma resident, the SEC said. He was fined $500 and promised not to repeat the violation.</p>
<p>After leaving Stratton, Puccio was employed at Josepthal Lyon &amp; Ross Inc. The SEC said he once again ignored his obligations to customers by failing to make an independent investigation of the securities he was recommending.</p>
<p>The SEC said Puccio had contended that the administrative law judge's sanction was excessive and unfair when compared with those meted out to a principal and to another salesman at Stratton.</p>
<p>Levitt and the other commissioners rejected this, saying the sanction against Puccio &quot;is fully merited.&quot;</p>
<p>The SEC charged Stratton Oakmont in 1992 with fraudulent sales practices and other violations. The firm settled two years later, without admitting or denying any wrongdoing by agreeing to return over $2 million to investors and pay a $500,000 fine.</p>
<p>In April (1996), the National Association of Securities Dealers fined the firm $325,000 for fraud and other violationss related to an initial public offering. It suspended for 45 days and fined the firm's head trader $50,000 in connection with those violations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
