<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135620" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Consumers urge WTO work for competition rules.</title>
<headline>Consumers urge WTO work for competition rules.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main global consumers grouping called on Monday for the World Trade Organisation to start work as soon as possible on a pact on competition rules to ensure big companies cannot carve up world markets and dictate prices.</p>
<p>The call was included in a list of recommendations issued by the London-based Consumers International (CI) for the WTO's first ministerial conference in Singapore in December and handed to the trade watchdog's Director-General Renato Ruggiero.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumers are already facing less choice and higher prices as transnational corporations (TNCs) dominate an ever-growing segment of national and regional economies,&quot; declared CI, a federation of over 200 bodies in 90 countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Without stricter legislation and enforcement of competition regulation, consumers and national economies suffer. With cross-border mergers and international cartels, competition on a global level is in jeopardy in many industries.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a need for an international competition policy that ensures both healthy competition between many players and benefits for consumers and domestic economies,&quot; a CI &quot;agenda&quot; for the Singapore meeting declared.</p>
<p>Representatives from CI member bodies in India, Argentina, Kenya and Britain told a news conference before meeting Ruggiero that any WTO discussion on global investment rules should also envisage tough regulations on business practices.</p>
<p>&quot;Without strong and binding rules on corporate practice, competition and consumer protection, a WTO agreement on investment rules could only increase the power of the TNCs,&quot; said Pradeep Mehta of India's Consumer Unity and Trust Society.</p>
<p>Major industrialised powers are pushing hard at the WTO, where the programme for Singapore is currently being discussed, for agreement by the ministers on setting up a working group to look at a possible investment accord.</p>
<p>The European Union is also arguing for a WTO agreement on competition rules which could be enforced through the trade body's dispute settlement procedure under which neutral panels review complaints and return their findings.</p>
<p>Several developing countries -- including India, Malaysia, Indonesia and Tanzania -- are strongly opposed to WTO discussions on investment rules, saying a binding accord could limit their ability to follow national industrial policies.</p>
<p>They are also wary of the EU framework for discussions on competition, arguing that it appears aimed at dismantling their national monopolies to clear the way for penetration by big global corporations.</p>
<p>Consumers International also indicated it felt the time had not yet come for investment negotiations in the WTO, saying current talks on an agreement in the Paris-based OECD &quot;rich man's club&quot; were not taking into account the interests of developing countries or of consumers around the world.</p>
<p>In its own &quot;agenda&quot; for Singapore, CI urged developed economies to focus more on the needs of the world's poorest states -- the 48 so-called least-developed countries or LDCs -- who were facing increased marginalisation.</p>
<p>It accused major powers of slowing down implementation of a 1994 accord to open up world markets for textiles and clothing, and urged them to agree on wider liberalisation of agricultural trade to open markets for LDC produce.</p>
<p>Many of the poorest countries, the consumer grouping said, faced ever growing food import bills as a result of the 1994 world trade treaty that set up the WTO, calling on the richer countries at Singapore to look at how the LDCs could be helped.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
