<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135636" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia's Indosat sets sights for 2005.</title>
<headline>Indonesia's Indosat sets sights for 2005.</headline>
<byline>Gde Anugrah Arka</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>PT Indonesian Satellite Corporation (Indosat) said on Tuesday its overseas ventures and local diversification were aimed at maintaining profits after the expected end of Indonesia's international telephone services duopoly.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a kind of preparation. When the duopoly ends, we will have businesses that would already be established and growing,&quot; president director Tjahjono Soerjodibroto told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Indonesian government had given state-controlled Indosat, also listed in New York, and PT Satelit Palapa Indonesia (Satelindo), exclusive rights to run international telephone services until 2005, Tjahjono said.</p>
<p>Satelindo, controlled by President Suharto's son Bambang Trihatmodjo, was given a licence to run basic international telecommunications services in January 1994, ending Indosat's monopoly.</p>
<p>Satelindo's shareholders, other than Trihatmodjo's Bimantara conglomerate, include Deutsche Telekom unit DeTe Mobil GmbH holding 25 percent, state-owned telecommunication firm Telkom with 23 percent and Indosat with 8.0 percent.</p>
<p>Indosat Public Relations Manager J.B. Basuki said Indosat expected to spend some 500 billion rupiah ($215.1 million) in 1997 to improve international telecommunications services and related businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know what the government will do when the duopoly ends. It may want to fully open the market and there could be other players as well, but whatever the case we have to be ready,&quot; Tjahjono said.</p>
<p>Indosat's overseas ventures include a 49 percent stake in Cambodian Indosat Telecommunication S.A, less than a one percent stake in Japan's Astel Tokyo Corporation and a 20 percent stake in telecommunications reseller Global Link of the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aim in venturing in developed countries is not so much to capturing market share, but more as a way of learning skills and technology from those countries,&quot; Tjahjono said.</p>
<p>He said the firm's ventures locally were aimed at broadening access to its international telecommunications services.</p>
<p>Indosat's local ventures include equity in fast growing cellular telephone firm PT Telekomunikasi Seluler (Telkomsel) and PT Mitra Global Telekomunikasi Indonesia.</p>
<p>Tjahjono said the firm expected Telkomsel to be among the largest sources of revenues due to the country's fast growing cellular telecommunication business. He did not give details.</p>
<p>Mitra plans to set up 400,000 telephone lines in Central Java in the coming years. Its shareholders include Australia's Telstra Global Limited, Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp and Japan's Itochu Corp.</p>
<p>Tjahjono said Indosat also expected to expand into businesses in the local markets which would complement the firm's core business.</p>
<p>Indosat was currently studying the possibilities of expanding its internet business and considering expanding into broadcasting, he said without giving details.</p>
<p>Indosat posted a net profit of 235 billion rupiah ($101.08 million) in the first six months of 1996 against 220.9 billion rupiah in the same period of last year.</p>
<p>($1=2,325 rupiah)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
