<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135621" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FEATURE - Melfi puts Fiat in Europe's driving seat.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Melfi puts Fiat in Europe's driving seat.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MELFI, Italy 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Melfi was the start of the story. Europe's most efficient integrated car plant built on a greenfield site in the heart of Italy's poor south was to mark the renaissance of the nation's giant car maker Fiat.</p>
<p>Melfi was to show that Europe could compete against the onslaught from the Far East's successful automotive groups, while re-establishing Fiat's pre-eminence in its traditionally strongest area, the European small car market.</p>
<p>In one bold leap, Fiat now has its biggest Italian car producing plant a whisker away from the world's most efficient with a build-to-order flexibility to leave the mind boggling.</p>
<p>The huge sprawling car plant 120 km (75 miles) east of Naples which took just two years to build is home to Fiat's best-selling Punto small car, top small car in Europe and second overall model to Volkswagen's perennial top seller, the Golf.</p>
<p>To match the best in the world, Fiat needed a greenfield site to design from scratch a 21st century car plant working three near-eight-hour shifts for six days with computer assisted maintenance to discover a fault before it fully materialised.</p>
<p>The first Punto rolled off the Melfi production line in January 1994 and when full capacity of 450,000 cars a year is reached next year Fiat will be producing 79 cars per man per year, set against a European average of 45 and the world's top-ranked plant, owned by Toyota in Kentucky, at 80.</p>
<p>Fiat sold 600,000 Puntos last year, nearly 300,000 from Melfi, out of global sales of 2.4 million. When Melfi hits full production next year Punto output will go up, while sharing the assembly line with 120,000 planned Punto-sized Lancia Y cars.</p>
<p>The Turin-based group had searched Spain, Portugal and Britain for a site for its new car plant, but decided on Melfi because of a supplier network already in place in Italy. Fiat now builds 60 percent of its Italian cars in the south.</p>
<p>Fiat spent 4.671 trillion lire ($3 billion) on Melfi of which 1.355 trillion came from soft loans and interest refunds from Rome and Brussels as finance for less developed areas of which southern Italy or the &quot;Mezzogiorno&quot; is high on the list.</p>
<p>RADICAL RETHINK NEEDED FOR MELFI</p>
<p>Fiat needed a radical rethink for Melfi. The isolated rural area had an untrained workforce and needed an infrastructure of roads and services before the plant could aim to turn out its target of 1,600 cars a year at full capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;Only 50 people came here with any car industry experience,&quot; explained the Melfi plant director Paolo Sandri. Now the workforce totals 5,900 with an average age of 27. About a fifth of the workforce are women.</p>
<p>Fiat's role in the world car industry had begun to falter in the late 1980's. It was still launching successful models but sales fell away disappointingly after the initial years.</p>
<p>What was needed was to refine its product towards a truly European car but still retaining the essential Italian style, while making a quantum productivity leap towards competing head on with the ultra-efficient Far Eastern producers.</p>
<p>The result was a massive seven-year 1991-97 investment plan to spend 40 trillion lire to build Melfi, launch 23 new models, create a new family of engines with a new dedicated engine plant and refurbish all of its existing car plants.</p>
<p>The key was Melfi. Fiat was to base its small car strategy around Melfi which started production of Puntos in January 1994 and added the upmarket Lancia Y in November 1995.</p>
<p>The new model range added the medium-sized Bravo/Brava in September 1995 and the medium-large Marea the following September to renew the Fiat marque, while Fiat-owned Lancia and Alfa Romeo are progressively renewing their models.</p>
<p>Melfi is a fully integrated car plant incorporating four distinct processes -- pressing, welding, painting and assembly. Cars are only built to order and before the first zinc-coated steel sheet is cut there is a customer's name on the car.</p>
<p>In the pressing room, four giant machines stamp out the 22 pieces need to construct a Punto with massive dies that can be changed in 100 seconds to switch from pressing out Punto side panels to Lancia Y bonnets and on to Punto doors sections.</p>
<p>Some pressed sheets are allocated to Fiat's Punto plants in Sicily and Fiat's spiritual home at Mirafiori in Turin, but most pass to the welding shop where the 22-piece jigsaw to make a Punto is assembled and crimped together before passing through a forest of robotic welders which bend and lean over the car shells applying some 3,000 weld points.</p>
<p>Through to the paint shop. Fiat came across one of the major problems of building cars in southern Europe or South America compared to northern Europe. High humidity is an anthema to water-based paints and Fiat has had to use several different levels of air conditioning in the paint shop to overcome it.</p>
<p>FLEXIBILITY IS THE WATCHWORD</p>
<p>Flexibility is again the watchword and batch production is a thing of the past as a red two-door Punto follows a mustard coloured four-door Punto then a yellow Lancia, with the robotic spray paint arms immediately adjusting to each individual car.</p>
<p>The sprayers can switch to 12 different colours for the Punto and Lancia Y without a hint of manual interference. To emphasise the plusher Lancia, a total of some 110 special colours shades or &quot;Kaleidoes&quot; are offered.</p>
<p>Into the assembly room, the painted shell is lifted on to the 4-wheel track already containing engine and gearbox before dashboard, windows, seats and trim are installed.</p>
<p>The Melfi complex covering 2.7 sq km (1.05 sq miles) includes an industrial park next door with 22 component suppliers building an array of headlights, dashboards and seats close to the assembly line and accounting for 42 percent of the finished car value.</p>
<p>Just in time ordering means most of the car parts arrive from the component factories next door and the engines from Fiat's Termoli plant on the Adriatic some 150 km (93 miles) away exactly when required, cutting down waiting and storage time.</p>
<p>Still with an eye on the future, Fiat's new car ranges will need to be updated each six years so the plant was designed to have in mind a new Punto which will roll out of the plant in 1999 -- just in time to mark Fiat's centenary. ($1=1,540 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELFI, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
