<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135607" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 22.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- The Russian beef ban affecting exports from counties Tipperary, Cork and Monaghan will be lifted as soon as BSE levels there fall, according to the Russian official who negotiated the deal with Ireland's Minister for Agriculture, Ivan Yates.</p>
<p>- The Northern Ireland peace talks can succeed without Sinn Fein, the chairman of the multi-party talks, George Mitchell, said on Monday.  </p>
<p>- The Irish police commissioner, Pat Byrne, has denied that there is &quot;widespread corruption&quot; in the force.</p>
<p>- One of the heaviest sentences for animal drug offences has been handed down at a special sitting of Athlone District Court, where a Tipperary farmer was given a six month prison sentence and fined 12,000 punts.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- A leading businessman, a pilot and three journalists narrowly escaped death on Monday when a helicopter crashed in a field near Enniskillen, Northern Ireland, while on a promotional flight for Guinness Ireland.</p>
<p>- Ireland's enterprise and employment minister Richard Bruton on Monday moved decisively to dampen expectations by workers and unions of an 850-million-punt tax bonanza.</p>
<p>- Ireland's enterprise and employment minister Richard Bruton on Monday hit out at &quot;unwarranted and uninformed cynicism&quot; of the track record in attracting jobs to Ireland of the state industrial development authority IDA Ireland.</p>
<p>- The four people who will be responsible for competition policy in Ireland were appointed on Monday by the minister for enterprise and employment Richard Bruton.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
