<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135645" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: U.S investment in Philippines seen at over $1 bln.</title>
<headline>U.S investment in Philippines seen at over $1 bln.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. investment worth more than $1 billion is expected to pour into the Philippines over the next few years, U.S. Ambassador Thomas Hubbard said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I can say that the United States is bullish on the Philippines ... American companies are now planning additional investments of more than $1 billion in the next three to five years,&quot; he told a group of top businessmen.</p>
<p>Americans are the largest foreign direct investors in the Philippines and its biggest trading partners. They bought $6 billion worth of Philippine products last year, while importing $5 billion worth of local goods, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to do even better in future years,&quot; Hubbard added.</p>
<p>Asian investors, especially Japanese and Taiwanese, have also started investing heavily in Philippine business in recent years, Hubbard said.</p>
<p>Often, foreign investors were not only those with existing businesses here, but those which are looking for possible sites for regional headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;The market-opening reforms the Philippine government has instituted have provided major, measurable benefits to the economy here, and both our nations are profiting from the removal of obstacles to investment and business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Since 1992, the government has opened up basic industries, such as the power, telecommunications and banking sectors, to foreign companies.</p>
<p>Hubbard said, however, that the government should now focus its attention on the infrastructure needs of a growing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;To sustain and expand today's promising economic growth, the Philippines needs more and better roads, ports and airports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;To compete successfully for the industrial investment that will create jobs, the Philippines needs dependable, low-cost sources of power and water.&quot;</p>
<p>Hubbard also urged the government to encourage a higher savings rate, to speed up its comprehensive tax reform package, do more to protect intellectual property rights, and to further liberalise the telecommunications market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
