<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135654" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: FEATURE - Norway's anguished face causes legal confusion.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Norway's anguished face causes legal confusion.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The harrowing creature shrieking in despair in Norway's most famous painting, &quot;The Scream&quot;, is at the centre of an international tangle over copyright.</p>
<p>Edvard Munch's 1893 masterpiece, depicting an embryonic figure screaming beneath a blood-red sky, has fallen into a 20-year time gap between copyright laws in the United States and Europe,</p>
<p>Fifty years after Munch's death, the United States has lifted any restrictions on the use of work by Norway's most famous artist, but Europe retains a 70-year ban on using an artist's work without approval from the copyright holder.</p>
<p>&quot;&quot;The Scream' is almost like an icon now and is used all over the world in advertising and cartoons,&quot; Per Boym, director of the Munch Museum in Oslo, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The curving body of the figure giving no hint of gender, very clearly represents the modern man, without a god, the lonely individual, and has become an expression of the 1990s.&quot;</p>
<p>But since copyright restrictions were lifted in America, the volume of adverts and products flooding into Europe featuring &quot;The Scream&quot; without copyright approval from licensees, the Munch Museum and Munch's family, has increased sharply.</p>
<p>Norway's Visual Artists' Copyright Society (BONO) and sister groups overseas have since 1994 clamped down on blow-up &quot;Scream&quot; figures, postcards of the screamer smoking a joint, and a range of &quot;Scream&quot; goods -- none with approval.</p>
<p>The latest battle is against a pillow featuring the screamer with a voice box which guarantees 3,000 screams.</p>
<p>&quot;We can stop the use, confiscate the goods and claim compensation for any damage or loss of moral rights,&quot; said BONO's chief executive Harald Holter.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that now &quot;The Scream' is the most widely used work of art after the &quot;Mona Lisa'. Its expression is very easy to use for advertising companies, but it can also be misused.&quot;</p>
<p>Formal approval for using &quot;The Scream&quot; commercially is given sparingly, with only some 1.6 million Norwegian crowns ($240,000) raised from its use each year.</p>
<p>Approaches by drug companies wanting to use the work in anti-depressant adverts have been refused, as have requests from political parties.</p>
<p>Holter said his group and other copyright groups internationally were seeking to harmonise the global laws on copyright, lobbying for the United States to fall in line with the EU, which set the 70-year restriction last year.</p>
<p>Until then, he said, action would have to continue to be taken against the increasing unapproved use of &quot;The Scream&quot;.</p>
<p>Holter said the 1994 theft of the painting, valued at 48 million pounds ($30 million), from the National Gallery in Oslo seemed to have fired even more interest in the work.</p>
<p>Thieves snatched the painting in the space of a minute on February 12, 1994, opening day of the Winter Olympic Games in Lillehammer, by climbing a ladder, smashing a ground floor window and cutting the painting from the wall.</p>
<p>The picture was recovered undamaged three months later and the thieves were caught after British agents from Scotland Yard's arts and antiques squad posed as potential buyers from the John Paul Getty Museum in California.</p>
<p>Four men were jailed for the theft earlier this year.</p>
<p>But it was a cheeky calling card left behind by the gang, saying &quot;thanks for the poor security&quot;, that left the National Gallery red-faced.</p>
<p>&quot;We have nothing more to say. Everything has been said in the press,&quot; said gallery spokeswoman Bodil Sorensen.</p>
<p>Security at the gallery has now tightened.</p>
<p>Guards with earpieces and walky-talkies patrol the gallery at all times with one permanently stationed by &quot;The Scream&quot;.</p>
<p>The heavy wooden entrance doors have been fitted with electronically-controlled security locks and all windows replaced with stronger glass.</p>
<p>&quot;We make no comment about our security,&quot; said Sorensen.</p>
<p>Although lauded in the 20th century, &quot;The Scream&quot; was not appreciated when it was first shown.</p>
<p>It was part of a series by Munch called &quot;The Frieze of Life&quot;, which was exhibited in Berlin in 1893 but caused a major scandal and labelled &quot;an insult to art&quot;.</p>
<p>After one week the exhibition was closed.</p>
<p>&quot;It was looked upon as uncivilised and pornography,&quot; Boym said. &quot;Munch was seen as a bad painter by the public and was laughed at, but in artists' circles he was much admired.&quot;</p>
<p>It was between 1902-1909, when working in Germany, that Munch became famous as an artist.</p>
<p>Made edgy by city life and drinking heavily, he suffered a nervous breakdown and, after treatment, returned to Norway where he spent the rest of his life living at Skoyen, just outside Kristiania, his childhood home.</p>
<p>Munch died from pneumonia in 1944 at the age of 80.</p>
<p>In his will Munch left his money to his family and to a foundation for needy artists, but bequeathed all his work to the City of Oslo.</p>
<p>The Munch Museum was opened in 1963 with a new wing added between 1992-94 and holds 1,150 of Munch's estimated 1,800 paintings, 17,000 prints, and up to 7,000 drawings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
