<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135684" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-HEARTS LINE UP CHANCE OF REVENGE AGAINST RANGERS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HEARTS LINE UP CHANCE OF REVENGE AGAINST RANGERS.</headline>
<dateline>GLASGOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hearts lined up a Scottish League Cup final against Rangers and the chance of a first trophy in 34 years when they swept aside first division leaders Dundee in their semifinal on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Goals from Darren Beckford, Colin Cameron and Stephane Paille had Hearts coasting before Scotland Under-21 striker Jim Hamilton grabbed a consolation for Dundee.</p>
<p>Victory clinched a November 24 final date at Celtic Park against Rangers who crushed Dunfermline in the other semifinal on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It gives Hearts the chance of avenging their 5-1 beating by Rangers in the Scottish Cup final last May.</p>
<p>Beckford, a substitute for the injured John Robertson, struck the opener before Colin Cameron, who won this trophy with Raith two years ago, scored a second from the penalty spot to have Hearts cruising at half-time.</p>
<p>Former French international Paille scored his first goal for the club after an hour to make sure of victory before Hamilton's 73rd-minute reply.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLASGOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
