<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135680" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL ICE HOCKEY-LIGHTNING MAKE IT FOUR IN A ROW WITH WIN OVER ISLANDERS.</title>
<headline>NHL ICE HOCKEY-LIGHTNING MAKE IT FOUR IN A ROW WITH WIN OVER ISLANDERS.</headline>
<dateline>UNIONDALE, New York 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The surprising Tampa Bay Lightning made it four wins in a row Tuesday and are are off to the best start in the club's five-year history.</p>
<p>John Cullen had a goal and three assists as the Lightning erupted for four first-period goals to down the New York Islanders 6-3 and raise their record to 5-1-0.</p>
<p>Alexander Selivanov, Patrick Poulin, Dino Ciccarelli and Cullen scored in the first period and Brian Bradley added two goals and an assist for Tampa Bay.</p>
<p>Corey Schwab, pressed into a starting role with Daren Puppa out with a groin injury, needed to make just 13 saves.</p>
<p>Zigmund Palffy scored twice for the Isles, losers of three in a row. New York (1-4-1) has only 16 goals in seven games.</p>
<p>Tampa Bay wasted little time in getting to goaltender Eric Fichaud as Selivanov swept a backhander past him 53 seconds into the game. Just 99 seconds later, Poulin's made it 2-0, firing home a one-timer off a pass from Cullen.</p>
<p>After Palffy cut the deficit in half, Cullen picked up the 500th point of his career, deflecting a pass from Poulin past Fichaud. Ciccarelli stuffed in a rebound of a Cullen shot for his fifth goal of the season and a 4-1 lead.</p>
<p>&quot;The first 10 minutes we played like a machine, then we fooled around a bit and gave up some soft goals,&quot; said Lightning coach Terry Crisp.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Ron Hextall needed to make just 12 saves to record his 15th career shutout and Eric Desjardins had a goal and an assist as the Flyers blanked the Mighty Ducks of Anaheim 3-0 for their third straight win.</p>
<p>Hextall was barely tested, stopping just one shot in the first period and four in the second. The 12 shots allowed by Philadelphia set a franchise low.</p>
<p>Desjardins set up Shjon Podein's goal 8:16 into the game and beat Guy Hebert on a power play 4:14 into the third. Rob Brind'Amour scored with a minute left in the second.</p>
<p>Both teams were missing their top players. Philadelphia's Eric Lindros and Anaheim's Paul Kariya are nursing severe groin injuries and have sat out all season.</p>
<p>In Calgary, Theoren Fleury completed his 11th career hat trick with a goal on a penalty shot as the Flames shocked the Colorado Avalanche 5-1.</p>
<p>Trevor Kidd came within 2:04 of a shutout, making 24 saves before Adam Deadmarsh snapped a rebound of his own shot between Kidd's pads to foil the shutout bid.</p>
<p>Fleury scored in the first and second periods as Calgary built a 3-0 lead. With the Flames up 4-0 late in the game, Fleury was on a breakaway and was pulled down from behind by Peter Forsberg. He beat Patrick Roy low on the glove side on the penalty shot.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Mats Sundin had two goals and an assist as the Maple Leafs ended a five-game losing streak with a 4-3 victory over the San Jose Sharks.</p>
<p>The Maple Leafs won for the first time since opening the season with a victory over Anaheim.</p>
<p>Sundin opened the scoring with his fourth goal 96 seconds into the game and added number five at 18:53 of the third for a 4-2 lead.</p>
<p>Sundin also set up Larry Murphy for a first-period powerplay tally. Doug Gilmour scored the other goal for Toronto, which never trailed.</p>
<p>In Edmonton, Ryan Smyth scored twice as the Oilers produced five unanswered goals in a 5-2 win over the struggling Pittsburgh Penguins.</p>
<p>Mario Lemieux notched his fifth goal midway through the second to put Pittsburgh up 2-0. But Oilers goaltender Curtis Joseph stopped 34 shots, including all 12 in the final period.</p>
<p>Jason Arnott, forced to miss several shifts after crashing heavily into the end boards early in the third, came back to snap a 2-2 tie at 8:37 as the Oilers victimised Ken Wregget five times over the last two periods.</p>
<p>Smyth, who picked up his sixth and seventh goals, and Andrei Kovalenko later beat Wregget 37 seconds apart.</p>
<p>In Phoenix, Jim Campbell scored with 13:26 left in the third period to snap a tie and Grant Fuhr made 26 saves to lift the St Louis Blues to a 2-1 victory over the Coyotes.</p>
<p>Geoff Courtnall took a pass at centre ice, crossed the blue line and passed to a streaking Campbell, who tipped it past goaltender Nikolai Khabibulin from the left doorstep for the game winner.</p>
<p>Norm Maciver's second-period goal had put Phoenix in front. But Brett Hull tied the game for St Louis with just 10 seconds left in the period, deflecting a Courtnall slap shot into the Phoenix goal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNIONDALE, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
