<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135682" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-LIVERPOOL HELD TO 1-1 BY CHARLTON IN LEAGUE CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-LIVERPOOL HELD TO 1-1 BY CHARLTON IN LEAGUE CUP.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>English premier league side Liverpool were forced into a third round League Cup replay on Wednesday after they were held to 1-1 draw by first division Charlton.</p>
<p>Arsenal, currently second in the league, were also held to a draw by another first division side, Stoke. Striker Mike Sheron's 11th goal of the season rocked the London side before Ian Wright snatched a late-equaliser to save Arsenal from an embarrassing exit.</p>
<p>League leaders Newcastle were pushed to the limit by bottom-of-the-first-division Oldham, relying on Peter Beardsley's 25th minute penalty to carry them through to fourth round.</p>
<p>Manchester United also had their anxious moments against Swindon, another first division outfit, with the score locked at 1-1 until Paul Scholes' 72nd minute winner. They now play Leicester in the fourth round.</p>
<p>Striker David Whyte stunned Liverpool with a cheekily-taken 18th minute goal to give first division strugglers Charlton the lead at The Valley.</p>
<p>Carl Leaburn nudged on a long through-ball and Whyte delicately lifted it over goalkeeper David James.</p>
<p>Manchester United made eight changes to the side who crashed 5-0 in the league at Newcastle on Sunday and were made to sweat in their 2-1 win over first division Swindon at Old Trafford.</p>
<p>One of the few players to keep his place was Czech winger Karel Poborsky, who gave United a 19th-minute lead.</p>
<p>Former Blackburn striker Peter Thorne hit back for Swindon before Scholes soothed United's worries.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough were by far the most impressive of the top flight sides crushing Huddersfield 5-1 thanks to two goals by Fabrizio Ravanelli and others from Danish international Mikkel Beck and Brazilians Juninho and Emerson. They now face Newcastle in mouth-watering fourth round tie.</p>
<p>In other results holders Aston Villa set up a showdown with either Wimbledon or Luton after coming from behind to beat Leeds 2-1.</p>
<p>Tottenham outplayed Sunderland 2-1 to set up a fourth round tie with Bolton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
