<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135619" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. Council wants cease-fire, talks in Afghanistan.</title>
<headline>U.N. Council wants cease-fire, talks in Afghanistan.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. Security Council intends to adopt a resolution on Tuesday calling for a ceasefire and political negotiations in Afghanistan where the radical Islamic Taleban has captured the capital, Kabul.</p>
<p>But still in dispute in the document, drafted by Russia, are objections to the Taleban's discrimination against women and girls who have been denied schooling and work.</p>
<p>China believes human rights concerns are not the province of the Security Council and Egypt is sensitive to possible criticism of Islamic practices, diplomats said. Consequently Russia may have to soften the language on women.</p>
<p>The resolution, careful not to take sides in the conflict, says the main responsibility for finding a political solution to the conflict lies with the Afghan parties.</p>
<p>The document calls for states to refrain from interfering in Afghanistan's internal affairs and stop supplying arms and ammunition in the country's civil war. But it does not impose an arms embargo as Pakistan had wanted, with members saying this would be nearly impossible to enforce.</p>
<p>It requests Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali and U.N. representatives to cooperate with interested states and organisations such as the Organisation of the Islamic Conference to promote a political dialogue.</p>
<p>Pakistan has offered to negotiate a ceasefire, overshadowing, at least temporarily, efforts of U.N. negotiator Norbert Holl of Germany.</p>
<p>In a news conference in Kabul on Monday, Holl, in an apparent reference to Pakistan, warned that no single country could bring peace to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>&quot;People may think in Kabul it is more important to follow the advice of other negotiators but in the long run help for reconstruction will only come from the international community,&quot; he said after talks with Taleban representatives.</p>
<p>The Organisation of Islamic Conference also proposed a truce and a conference in Saudi Arabia of the warring groups.</p>
<p>So far, however, the Taleban and troops supporting the ousted Afghan government have put conditions on a ceasefire.</p>
<p>Gen. Ahmad Shah Masood, whose ethnic Tajik forces hold territory close to the capital, said through a spokesman that ceasefire negotiations had failed and that Kabul should be demilitarized first.</p>
<p>Masood has formed an alliance against the Taleban with his former rival, Abdul Rashid Dostum, an ethnic Uzbek, who holds territory in the north. For the past week fighting has been confined to a 20 mile (32 km) stretch of the main road from Kabul to the Hindu Kush strongholds of Masood and Dostum.</p>
<p>The council's draft resolution warned Afghan leaders about the use of landmines. It also said that the war provided &quot;a fertile ground for terrorism and drug traffic which destabilises the region and beyond.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
