<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135694" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHELSEA FOOTBALL CLUB'S HARDING DIES IN AIR CRASH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHELSEA FOOTBALL CLUB'S HARDING DIES IN AIR CRASH.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matthew Harding, multi-millionaire vice-chairman of Prime Minister John Major's favourite football team Chelsea, was killed in a helicopter crash on Tuesday night, the club said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Harding, 42, was one of five people who died when the helicopter crashed into a field on the way back to London after a match between Chelsea and Bolton Wanderers in northwest England.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Harding hit the headlines when he donated one million pounds ($1.60 million) to the opposition Labour Party, the biggest donation by an individual in the party's 90-year history.</p>
<p>The other crash victims had not been named early on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is confirmed that Matthew C. Harding...was killed last night,&quot; the company that owns Chelsea football club said in a brief statement.</p>
<p>The Eurocopter Twin Squirrel came down at about 11.00 pm (2200 gmt) on Tuesday evening in Cheshire, northwest England.</p>
<p>Residents reported hearing a helicopter engine in difficulties moments before and police ruled out speculation of a mid-air collision.</p>
<p>They first suspected Harding was among those killed when they found a charred football programme among the wreckage.</p>
<p>Harding, Britain's 89th richest man, began his working life as an office junior. By his early 40s he was the chairman of one of Britain's most profitable reinsurance companies, Benfield Group Ltd.</p>
<p>Although Chelsea's most prominent supporters include Major and former Conservative cabinet minister David Mellor, Harding was a supporter of the left-leaning Labour Party.</p>
<p>Labour leader Tony Blair described Harding's death as &quot;an appalling tragedy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We all feel devastated for his family. He was so full of life and vigour and someone deeply committed to his country,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>Despite his great wealth and jet-set lifestyle, Harding endeared himself to Chelsea fans with his down-to-earth ways.</p>
<p>On match days, he would take a train into London and enjoy a beer in the Imperial Arms, a pub near Chelsea's Stamford Bridge football ground.</p>
<p>On the train he would stand in the buffet car chatting happily with fans about football. He watched matches from the public stand rather than the directors' box.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a real football fan. Even a major business coup didn't give him the same thrill as Chelsea scoring,&quot; said Mellor, now a part-time sports broadcaster.</p>
<p>Last year, Harding was involved in a public feud with Chelsea chairman Ken Bates year over control of the club, but the dispute was finally resolved amicably.</p>
<p>He bought the Stamford Bridge ground in London's Fulham Road for 16.5 million pounds ($26 million) in 1995 and provided more cash for stadium improvements and to buy top overseas players including Italians Gianluca Vialli and Roberto Di Matteo and France's Franck Leboeuf.</p>
<p>Harding was married with two sons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
