<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135657" id="root" date="1996-10-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FEATURE - Dutch commercial TV - a game with no winners?.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Dutch commercial TV - a game with no winners?.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Kelly</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>As more and more channels seek a slice of a flat advertising market, Dutch commercial TV looks like a game with no winners for the time being.</p>
<p>Aggressive newcomer SBS6 has led a round of deep ad-rate discounts aimed at wooing advertisers but this has left all players except market leader RTL4 with losses.</p>
<p>&quot;Only RTL4 is making a profit at the moment, and it's not a big profit. The rest are losing money because they are offering big advertising discounts,&quot; said Ab Barneveld of Generale Bank.</p>
<p>RTL4 -- 38 percent owned by publisher VNU and 61 percent by Luxembourg media group CLT -- became the first Dutch commercial TV station in 1989, followed by its stablemate RTL5 in 1993. Philips Electronics has a one percent stake</p>
<p>Veronica, which quit the public TV system in 1995, was initially seen as the main threat, but the three channels joined forces that year to form the Holland Media Group (HMG).</p>
<p>This potentially powerful bloc drew the attention of European Union trust-busters but this has since abated with the advent of new channels such as SBS6, Sport7 and TV10.</p>
<p>In particular SBS6 -- 70 percent owned by Scandinavian Broadcasting System SA and 30 percent by Dutch publisher De Telegraaf -- has emerged as a powerful player.</p>
<p>&quot;SBS6 really put the cat among the pigeons...It is a new competitor which the HMG group probably underestimated at first,&quot; said Andre Moons of ING Barings.</p>
<p>The channel, whose majority shareholder is partly owned by big names such as Walt Disney Co and Viacom Inc, has captured an eight percent share of the TV audience with a mix of popular programmes in Dutch and big Hollywood films.</p>
<p>Latest newcomer is Sport7 which bought rights to all Dutch league soccer matches in a 1.04 billion guilder ($601.2 million) seven-year deal. In September, its first month, it had a four percent audience share.</p>
<p>Sport7 triggered hostile reactions for daring to suggest that television viewers should pay a modest extra fee for televised soccer, a commodity previously regarded as public property.</p>
<p>Newspapers have gloated over its initial setbacks, but the station insists everything is going to plan, including &quot;normal&quot; start-up losses in its first two years of operation.</p>
<p>ING, Philips and PTT Nederland each have 19.5 percent stakes in Sport7. De Telegraaf has five percent, the Dutch soccer association KNVB 10 and Telekabel, a subsidiary of the Dutch power utility Nuon has seven percent.</p>
<p>The many new channels and resulting audience fragmentation have disgruntled advertisers who initially welcomed the end of the monopoly previously held by the three Dutch public channels.</p>
<p>&quot;Uncertainty about the effectiveness of TV advertising is growing,&quot; Bob Steetskamp, deputy chairman of the Dutch advertisers association BVA told an industry conference.</p>
<p>As a result, spending on TV advertising has stabilised at just over one billion guilders a year or roughly one tenth of overall spending on all forms of advertising in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>There has even been a reallocation of spending back towards newspapers and magazines.</p>
<p>Analysts said this should provide some solace to investors in groups such as VNU, De Telegraaf and Wegener Arcade which have interests in both print and broadcast media.</p>
<p>Most analysts believe a shakeout in the Dutch television industry is inevitable with only a few general interest channels and a handful of special-interest channels eventually remaining.</p>
<p>&quot;Not everybody can keep up with this competitive battle and only those channels which are financially strong, or have strong shareholders behind them, will survive,&quot; said Barneveld.</p>
<p>Greater differentiation could revive the TV advertising market by enabling advertisers to reach specific viewer types.</p>
<p>&quot;In the longer term, as the identity of the various channels becomes clearer and as they begin to reach specific target audiences, TV advertising will recover,&quot; said Moons.</p>
<p>RTL5 is already weighing such an approach by recasting itself as a CNN-style news channel while Wegener Arcade's Music Factory is proving popular with young viewers and advertisers as a Dutch alternative to pop video station MTV Europe.</p>
<p>Barneveld and Moons both see RTL4 and SBS6 among the survivors and Moons also expects Sport7 to move into profit in its third year despite its current battles with cable network operators who pipe TV signals into over 90 pct of Dutch homes. ($1=1.730 Guilder)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
