<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135676" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-MUSTER HOBBLES OUT OF STUTTGART OPEN WITH HIP INJURY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-MUSTER HOBBLES OUT OF STUTTGART OPEN WITH HIP INJURY.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>STUTTGART, Germany 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champion Thomas Muster limped out of the Stuttgart Open on Wednesday, frustrated by a recurring hip injury.</p>
<p>The Austrian world number three retired from his second-round clash with Mark Woodforde because of pain in his left hip. The Australian had taken a 3-0 lead in the decisive third set when Muster was hobbling about the court.</p>
<p>Afterwards a gloomy Muster said: &quot;I have had this for a few years and it is not getting better. If I knew what to do with it I would be a doctor, not a tennis player.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be a long-term thing but it is too early to say. I'll have to talk over things with the physiotherapist.&quot;</p>
<p>Muster aggravated the injury at an invitational event in Hong Kong last week. He had few problems in taking the first set 6-3 against Woodforde but struggled in the second, losing it 6-1.</p>
<p>After lying down on his back during a change-over to get intensive treatment on his left leg at the start of the third set, Muster tried to play on but eventually had to retire after the third game.</p>
<p>&quot;It was okay in the first set but it then got worse and worse from game to game,&quot; he said. &quot;It is frustrating. You practice and get ready for a tournament and you can't really do what you want to do.</p>
<p>&quot;I am used to being injured but some injuries you can play with and some you can't.&quot;</p>
<p>The $2.2 million Stuttgart event is one of the nine top tournaments on the ATP Tour and has attracted most of the leading 20 players in the world.</p>
<p>The Austrian said he did not know whether he would  be fit for next week's high-class Paris indoor event or at next month's world championship in Hanover, the prestigious season-ending tournament formerly known as the Masters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
