<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135695" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHELSEA VICE-CHAIRMAN HARDING DIES IN AIR CRASH - TV.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHELSEA VICE-CHAIRMAN HARDING DIES IN AIR CRASH - TV.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matthew Harding, vice-chairman of English premier league soccer club Chelsea, was killed in a helicopter crash on Tuesday night, the Sky television channel said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Harding and four other people were killed when their helicopter crashed with no survivors in Cheshire, northern England, on the way back from Chelsea's League Cup match in Bolton, it said.  </p>
<p>Police said earlier four men and a woman died in the crash when the helicopter came down in farmland. There was no immediate indication of the cause of the crash.</p>
<p>Harding, a millionaire businessman who was believed to be one of the 50 wealthiest men in Britain, was involved in a public feud with Chelsea chairman Ken Bates last year over control of the club. It was finally resolved amicably.</p>
<p>Harding, 41, bought the club's Stamford Bridge ground in 1995 for 16.5 million sterling ($26 million) and provided further cash for stadium improvements and new players.</p>
<p>The cash injection helped the club sign top overseas players such as Italians Gianluca Vialli and Roberto Di Matteo and France's Franck Leboeuf.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
