<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135663" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-JOHNNY MILLER ELECTED TO PGA TOUR HALL OF FAME.</title>
<headline>GOLF-JOHNNY MILLER ELECTED TO PGA TOUR HALL OF FAME.</headline>
<dateline>PONTE VEDRA BEACH, Florida 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former U.S. Open and British Open champion Johnny Miller Wednesday became the first player elected to the PGA Tour Hall of Fame.</p>
<p>The 49-year-old Miller, who won 24 PGA titles during his career, was the only player named on the required 75 percent of the ballots in the first-ever Hall of Fame voting, the PGA Tour announced.</p>
<p>Miller, currently a commentator for NBC Sports, was named on 79 percent of the ballots.</p>
<p>Former U.S. Open champion Lloyd Mangrum was second in the voting but fell short, turning up on 63 percent of the ballots. He was followed by Tom Kite (54), Ben Crenshaw (44) and Greg Norman (42).</p>
<p>Miller will be inducted into the World Golf Hall of Fame in St Augustine, Florida when the facility opens in 1998. He will be inducted along with any players selected in 1997, those elected through the 1996 and 1997 International Ballot and any LPGA Tour player who fulfils that tour's Hall of Fame requirements.</p>
<p>Miller joined the PGA Tour in 1969 and four years later won the U.S. Open with final round 63 at Oakmont Country Club.</p>
<p>He won eight titles in 1974, four more in 1975 and three tournaments, including the British Open at Royal Birkdale, in 1976.</p>
<p>A lingering back injury forced Miller into virtual retirement in 1990, although he managed to stun the golf world by winning the Pebble Beach National Pro-Am in 1994 -- one of only four events he entered that year.</p>
<p>To be eligible for election into the Hall of Fame, a PGA Tour player must have at least 10 victories in approved tournaments, or at least two wins among The Players Championship, Masters Tournament, U.S. Open, British Open and PGA Championship, be at least 40 years old and have been a member of the PGA Tour for a minimum of 10 years.</p>
<p>Mark O'Meara, Nick Price and Payne Stewart will all become eligible for Hall of Fame balloting in 1997. All three have the requisite victories and turn 40 next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PONTE VEDRA BEACH, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
