<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135795" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ITALY, SLOVENIA AND HUNGARY STRENGTHEN TIES.</title>
<headline>ITALY, SLOVENIA AND HUNGARY STRENGTHEN TIES.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy, Slovenia and Hungary agreed on Wednesday to strengthen trilateral ties to shape regional policy in security, transport and a wide range of other areas.</p>
<p>A joint declaration, issued after the countries' foreign ministers met in Rome, also said Slovenia and Hungary should be among the first to join the eventual expansion of the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organsation (NATO).</p>
<p>The statement said the countries were &quot;firmly convinced that Europe's future stability and development can only be based upon the final completion of the processes of European and Atlantic integration&quot;.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini said Italy, which is an EU and NATO member, wanted to play a larger role in the relaunching of central Europe and fully supported Slovenian and Hungarian applications to join the two organisations.</p>
<p>Dini said the countries also would seek to link central and southeastern Europe more closely in areas of transport, the economy, technology and culture.</p>
<p>He said they would concentrate efforts on completing a highway linking Trieste in northeast Italy to Budapest as well as improving border crossings and Adriatic port infrastructures.</p>
<p>Dini said the prime ministers of the three countries would meet in Budapest next spring as part of the countries' newly strengthened ties.</p>
<p>The joint declaration also addressed the issue of ethnic minorities which had in the past strained relations between Italy and Slovenia.</p>
<p>Slovenian Foreign Minister Davorin Kracun said the countries had agreed on &quot;a global safeguarding mechanism&quot; regarding ethnic minorities.</p>
<p>Dini said the ministers had agreed to seek legislation in their respective countries which would provide &quot;adequate protection&quot; to the rights of minorities.</p>
<p>Italy had long objected to closer ties between the EU and Slovenia over a long-running row with the former Yugoslav republic over property laws.</p>
<p>Ljubljana had angered Rome by refusing to hand back state-owned property confiscated from ethnic Italians who fled from the Istria region after Italy's defeat in World War Two.</p>
<p>Italy also had been angered by a Slovenian ban on foreigners owning real estate.</p>
<p>Italy dropped its objections after Slovenia agreed in May to bring in legislation to allow foreigners to own real estate within four years of an EU association agreement taking effect.</p>
<p>Hungarian Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs, noting that central Europe was &quot;traditionally a multi-ethnic society&quot;, said: &quot;Without recognition of the rights of minorities, there will be no stability&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
