<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135718" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BERNIE WILLIAMS COMES BACK TO LIFE, AND SO DO YANKEES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BERNIE WILLIAMS COMES BACK TO LIFE, AND SO DO YANKEES.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bernie Williams came back to life on Tuesday, and so did the road-warrior New York Yankees when his two-run homer in the eighth inning helped seal a 5-2 victory over the Atlanta Braves in Game 3 of the World Series.</p>
<p>Williams, the American League Championship Series Most Valuable Player who went hitless in losses in Games 1 and 2 of the World Series, drove in three runs and scored twice for the Yankees.</p>
<p>New York is trying to become just the third team ever to win a World Series after losing the first two games at home.</p>
<p>Yankee starter David Cone survived a tense pitchers' duel with Tom Glavine, leaving the game with the Yanks ahead 2-1 after six innings.</p>
<p>Glavine left after seven, but his reliever Greg McMichael let open the floodgates, allowing three runs, including Williams's home run.</p>
<p>The Yankees are now a perfect 6-0 on the road this post-season and need to win one of the next two games in Atlanta to guarantee a return of the best-of-seven series to New York.</p>
<p>The loss snapped a five-game win streak by the defending World Series champion Braves, who had won three in a row to take the National League Championship Series after trailing the St Louis Cardinals three games to one.</p>
<p>Cone, who got the win, allowed four hits, one run and four walks with three strikeouts.</p>
<p>Glavine, who pitched last year's Series clincher for the Braves, also allowed four hits, but two runs -- only one of them earned -- along with eight strikeouts and three walks.</p>
<p>McMichael allowed three runs on three hits without getting an out.</p>
<p>John Wetteland got the save, retiring three batters after a Derek Jeter error allowed the leadoff man on in the ninth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
