<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135769" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - OCT 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - OCT 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- BOC Gazy chemical firm will construct an 80 million zloty oxygen separation unit for Huta Ostrowiec steel mill.</p>
<p>- Gdansk's duty free zone will operate as of October 25. About 20 firms want to open branches in the 33.5-hectare zone, located around one of the Gdansk port basins.</p>
<p>- The recently opened Volvo Bus Poland plant in Wroclaw, southwestern Poland, will make around 250 buses a year. The plant cost about $11 million to build.</p>
<p>- The president of Gdansk-based Bank Gdanski, Edmund Tolwinski, has died.</p>
<p>- Poland's Post Office, telecoms monopolist TPSA and chemical companies made the biggest profits in the first eight months of 1996, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said.</p>
<p>- The transport ministers of Poland and China, Boguslaw Liberadzki and Huang Zhendong, have signed an agreement on avoiding double taxation of shipping companies and free transfer of the shippers' revenues.</p>
<p>- The Polkomtel digital mobile phone company, known under the GSM Plus trade name, has contracted Sony telephone equipment from Sony Poland SA which will deliver the phones directly to subscribers. The Sony phone costs 1,999 zlotys.</p>
<p>- The Gorzow province governor has proposed creating a new special economic zone in Kostrzyn, western Poland. The zone near the German border would cover 455 hectares including the site of the Kostrzyn paper mill.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- The Famak machinery and transmission equipment plant was awarded Poland's Quality Prize for 1996.</p>
<p>- Poland's state-owned farming bank Bank Gospodarki Zywnosciowej SA will receive 13 million sterling from the British Know-How Fund to help restructure 600 food sector firms, BGZ officials said.</p>
<p>- The environmental protection bank, Bank Ochrony Srodowiska (BOS), has started new preferential credits for environmental protection projects, it said.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- The listed Zywiec breweries have decided to close down its Bielsko-Biala plant which used to make soft drinks for PepsiCo. PepsiCo is to open its own bottling plant in Znin, Bydgoszcz province, Pepsico public relations officer Barbara Szolomicka said.</p>
<p>- The Poznan-based BMT brokerage house is organising a credit to acquire shares from the current share issue of Warsaw-based BOS bank.</p>
<p>- South Korea's Daewoo will probably acquire the Thomson Polkolor plant in Piaseczno in a move related to the French company's current privatisation, Gazeta Wyborcza wrote. Daewoo representatives said it was too early to comment on any such acquisition.</p>
<p>- Poland's foreign trade ministry is considering abolishing duty free import quotas for goods now carrying duties of up to four percent, Foreign Trade Minister Janusz Kaczurba said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- &quot;The Warsaw bourse board is worried over the recent results of Swarzedz furniture factory. This is the result of the not ideal methods of accounting in the company&quot;, bourse president Wieslaw Rozlucki said.</p>
<p>- The BGZ-bank brokerage house has recently introduced free telephone investment consulting services for its customers, the bank's representatives said.</p>
<p>- The Navigator Finance subsidiary of National Investment Fund 2 came into operation yesterday. The new firm will assist the leading firms in the Fund's portfolio.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
