<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135714" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-AUSSIE GRAEME LLOYD DOING THE JOB.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-AUSSIE GRAEME LLOYD DOING THE JOB.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suddenly, Graeme Lloyd, the first Australian to appear in a World Series, isn't looking like such a bad pick-up for the New York Yankees, after all.</p>
<p>The tall left-hander came over in a trade that had Yankees boss George Steinbrenner howling at his employee who made the trade, general manager Bob Watson, and Lloyd was booed on a regular basis in his ineffectual showings.</p>
<p>He was 0-2 with a startling 17.46 earned run average in the regular season for New York.</p>
<p>But Lloyd had his second successive effective appearance in the World Series Tuesday, throwing six key pitches in the Yankees' vital 5-2 win over the Atlanta Braves.</p>
<p>In the bottom of the eighth, with a man on, one out and the score 5-2, he defused two left-handed Atlanta power hitters, getting Fred McGriff to pop out and striking out Ryan Klesko.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just going out there and doing the job,&quot; Lloyd said. &quot;Coming into the game in that kind of situation where it could have gotten out of hand, it was a confidence builder. I threw the pitches I wanted and I got the job done.&quot;</p>
<p>He outlined his strategy against McGriff: &quot;He hits the ball to all fields. I try to throw the ball inside and outside and just keep him guessing what I'm going to throw.&quot;</p>
<p>Klesko had tried to bunt during his at-bat. &quot;It puts a little bit of confidence in you that maybe he thinks he can't hit me. I decided to go right after him after that,&quot; said Lloyd. &quot;With Klesko I just threw three sliders away.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyd, who had a cortisone shot for his ailing pitching elbow just before joining the Yankees, came to New York with utility man Pat Listach, also injured, for outfielder Gerald Williams and right-handed reliever Bob Wickman.</p>
<p>Milwaukee later supplied lefty Ricky Bones to New York and took Listach back after the Yankees complained.</p>
<p>Watson has said Steinbrenner threatened to fire him if the trade is not reversed. But now the trade is looking pretty good for the Yankees.</p>
<p>&quot;The general manager's pretty smart, isn't he?&quot; joked field manager Joe Torre. &quot;He made a helluva deal.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyd, reflecting on his travails, said: &quot;It seems a long way away from the World Series. With Milwaukee I had one of my best years, then when I was traded everything hit the fan. It was a tough time for me and I've gotten through that. I've looked at these playoffs and World Series like a clean slate.&quot;</p>
<p>The Yankees still have a grievance pending alleging the Brewers knew they were trading damaged goods in both cases.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
