<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135708" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: SOCCER-WARSAW'S LEGIA HOPE TO CATCH HOOLIGANS ON CAMERA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WARSAW'S LEGIA HOPE TO CATCH HOOLIGANS ON CAMERA.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish first division leaders Legia Warszawa have installed some 20 security cameras in and around their stadium in the hope of catching soccer hooligans, it was reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Nearly 60 people were injured during clashes between police and fans at two matches last weekend.</p>
<p>A news report on public television said Warsaw's Legia, quarter-finalist in last year's Champions' League, had installed cameras for their Wednesday match against mid-table Krakow Wisla.</p>
<p>&quot;The cameras are specially shielded so that fans cannot get to them...(but) it seems they are not interested in the cameras so far,&quot; a television reporter said during a live broadcast from the match.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, governor of the western Polish city of Poznan ordered that Lech soccer stadium be closed until the end of the season following crowd trouble. Police used a water-cannon to disperse the unruly crowd, following the home side's 2-0 loss to Legia.</p>
<p>Hooligans and police also clashed in the southwestern city of Wroclaw after home side Slask lost to Widzew Lodz.</p>
<p>Poland's interior ministry has called for tougher laws to ensure security at public events after the weekend violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
