<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135739" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-UNHAPPY TROTTA SENT ON ENFORCED LEAVE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-UNHAPPY TROTTA SENT ON ENFORCED LEAVE.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roma ordered their unhappy defender Roberto Trotta to go home to Argentina on two weeks' leave on Wednesday in a move certain to fuel speculation over his future at the Italian serie A side.</p>
<p>The club's Argentine coach Carlos Bianchi said Trotta, under fire from impatient fans, would fly to Buenos Aires on Thursday and was not expected back in Rome until November 8.</p>
<p>The decision followed a meeting between Bianchi, Trotta and chairman Franco Sensi on Tuesday and will allow Trotta to see his two children, aged seven and nine, for the first time for more than three months.</p>
<p>It rules him out of Saturday's league clash against European Cup holders Juventus. His place will be taken by locally-born Fabio Petruzzi.</p>
<p>Bianchi brought Trotta to Roma with him from Velez Sarsfeld at the start of the season but he has failed to live up to his reputation.</p>
<p>He looked lost against Verona when they beat Roma 2-1 last weekend. His confidence crisis has not been helped by fans who displayed a banner saying &quot;Trotta Go Away&quot;.</p>
<p>Bianchi denied on Wednesday the decision to send him on leave had anything to do with the supporters' verdict or that the player himself had requested time off.</p>
<p>&quot;If anyone thinks Sunday's banners have got anything to do with this, then they don't know me,&quot; Bianchi said. &quot;Trotta has been under pressure for three and a half months and not just since last week.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a technical decision. There is much more to him than he has shown up to now. I know him and he has my total confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>Trotta's dismal start at Roma has been made worse by constant chatter that he has special protection as Bianchi's favourite, a theory the coach dismissed.</p>
<p>&quot;In three years at Velez I brought in only three or four players and none of them with the guarantee of a place,&quot; he said. &quot;You call up a player to be part of a group with no certainty that he will succeed.&quot;</p>
<p>Support for Trotta came on Wednesday from the Rome sports newspaper Corriere dello Sport which urged fans to give him time to settle.</p>
<p>It urged supporters to fax the newspaper messages. &quot;Trotta needs you,&quot; the newspaper said. &quot;Let him know you love him&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
