<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135732" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-ELBER AND BOBIC PROPEL STUTTGART TO CUP WIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ELBER AND BOBIC PROPEL STUTTGART TO CUP WIN.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>VfB Stuttgart's twin strike force of German international Fredi Bobic and Brazilian Giovane Elber put the Bundesliga leaders into the quarter-finals of the German Cup on Wednesday with a 2-0 win over second division Zwickau.</p>
<p>Despite Elber's goal shortly before the interval of the third round tie, Stuttgart never looked safe until Bobic struck in the 82nd minute.</p>
<p>Karlsruhe made easier work of their tie with Greuther Fuerth, conquerors of holders Kaiserslautern in the first round.</p>
<p>Sean Dundee, the Bundesliga's top scorer, netted one of Karlsruhe's goals in their 3-1 win.</p>
<p>The only upset of the day came when regional league side Energie Cottbus eliminated Bundesliga strugglers Duisburg on penalties.</p>
<p>Cottbus looked to have the tie wrapped up within normal time with a single second half goal but Duisburg hit an 88th-minute equaliser to take the game into extra time.</p>
<p>The east German side took the lead once more only for another Duisburg equaliser to take the match to penalties.</p>
<p>Cottbus keeper Kay Wehner held one Duisburg kick, which proved enough to give his side a 5-4 win on penalties.</p>
<p>&quot;I could've done with a few headache tablets at the end,&quot; Cottbus coach Eduard Geyer said of the tense climax to the game. &quot;We were definitely the better side but when the score got to 1-1, I thought we'd struggle.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
