<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135743" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-ROMA PENPIX.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-ROMA PENPIX.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pen pictures of the Roma players most likely to play against Juventus in Saturday's serie A clash at the Olympic Stadium:</p>
<p>Giorgio Sterchele, goalkeeper, 26 years old. Joined Roma last season from Vicenza where he started his career. Nicknamed &quot;SuperGino&quot;, has taken over from injured veteran 'keeper Giovanni Cervone so far this season. Son of former Italian national hammer-throwing champion Francesco Sterchele.</p>
<p>Aldair, defender, 30. Brazilian international previously at Flamengo and Benfica. Joined Roma in 1990 and is the longest-serving foreign player at the club. The lynchpin of Roma's notoriously porous defence, Aldair also headed in Roma's first goal of the season against Piacenza. His experience and class make him probably the club's most valued player.</p>
<p>Roberto Trotta, defender, 27. Argentine signing who joined Roma with coach Carlos Bianchi from Velez Sarsfeld. Has failed to live up to his reputation and looked lost against Verona who beat Roma 2-1 last weekend. His confidence crisis not helped by fans, who displayed a banner saying &quot;Trotta Go Away&quot;. </p>
<p>Fabio Petruzzi, defender, 26. Celebrates his birthday on Thursday and is the popular local-born choice to replace Trotta should Bianchi decide to ditch the unhappy Argentine. Has not had a look in yet this season and reportedly unhappy about Bianchi wanting to play him out of position.</p>
<p>Enrico Annoni, defender, 30. Under pressure this season because targeted by critics as a weak link in defence. Nicknamed Tarzan because of his stocky, muscular physique.</p>
<p>Marco Lanna, defender, 28. Italian international and only Roma player with experience of winning a league title, which he captured with Sampdoria in 1991.</p>
<p>Amedeo Carboni, defender, 31. Veteran former Italian international now in his seventh season at the club. Expected to return from injury last weekend but suffered further leg pains. Should be passed fit by Saturday.</p>
<p>Damiano Tommasi, midfielder, 22. Signed from Verona this season, has exceeded expectations and now a favourite of the &quot;Curva Sud&quot;. Man of the match on his debut with Roma at Piacenza, scored his first goal against Reggiana and was called up by Italy last month to cap rapid rise. A pacifist, refused military service as a conscientious objector.</p>
<p>Jonas Thern, midfielder, 29. Swedish international captain who joined Roma in 1994. Key player whose experience much missed in recent matches due to an injured foot. Has been working out hard and may be given the all clear. Could make all the difference to Roma as one of few players capable of dictating pace of match and stamping authority on midfield.</p>
<p>Francesco Statuto, midfielder, 25. The hard man of the team, short and squat with a reputation as a very tough tackler. Briefly called up by Italy but made little impression. Roma could use his bite in midfield if he passed fit.</p>
<p>Abel Balbo, striker, 30. Team captain and Roma's leading scorer with four goals in six serie A games this season. Played with Newell's Old Boys and River Plate in his native Argentina before joining Udinese in 1989. Signed for Roma in 1993 and is ninth all-time scorer for club. Clashed with former coach Carlo Mazzone last season but happier under Bianchi.</p>
<p>Daniel Fonseca, striker, 27. Uruguayan who has developed good South American partnership with Balbo. Cool penalty taker, has recovered his form this season after poor 1995-96 season during which he was jeered by fans. Has scored two goals in serie A this season, three in UEFA Cup competition.</p>
<p>Marco Delvecchio, striker, 23. Former Italy under-21 player, joined Roma from Inter last season. A crowd favourite.</p>
<p>Francesco Totti, striker, 20. The boy wonder of Roman soccer, capped by Italy under-21 team and a good one-touch player. Generally used as partner for Delvecchio, should be a substitute if Bianchi goes for Balbo-Fonseca.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
