<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135721" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-ACTING COMMISSIONER STILL CAGEY ON DEAL.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-ACTING COMMISSIONER STILL CAGEY ON DEAL.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baseball's acting commissioner Bud Selig said on Tuesday that a labour deal was &quot;imperative&quot; but refused to say how he thought the clubs were likely to vote on a proposal under discussion for the past 2 1/2 months.</p>
<p>&quot;We are finishing an agreement that will shape our future for many years but I want to err on the side of caution so that all teams understand the deal and the ramifications to them,&quot; Selig told reporters at an informal news conference before Game 3 of the World Series.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been a lot of labour deals over the years where the by-products have been very unpleasant,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The clubs are still discussing a proposed deal that was hammered out in August by chief owners' negotiator Randy Levine and players' union head Donald Fehr.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the time has been useful,&quot; said Selig, owner of the Milwaukee Brewers.</p>
<p>The proposal was reported to have stalled when several clubs did not want to grant service time to players who had been on strike two years ago. The proposal was also believed to include a &quot;luxury tax&quot; on high-payrolls and revenue-sharing for low-revenue clubs.</p>
<p>Selig refused to say how close to the 21 of 28 owners needed now favour the deal and he said no meeting of owners was currently scheduled.</p>
<p>&quot;I do think I understand how each club feels, but how they would vote, I don't know,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously different clubs have different concerns -- their own financial situations.&quot;</p>
<p>One concern that Selig has emphasised the past couple of years is the differing interests of small-market clubs like his own and the richer big-market teams.</p>
<p>He noted that this World Series pits the highest-paid club in the major leagues, the New York Yankees, against the highest-paid team in the National League, the Atlanta Braves.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that you have payroll number one meeting payroll number one is not an accident,&quot; he said. He made a similar point at last year's Series between the Braves and Cleveland Indians.</p>
<p>He disclaimed much of a role for himself in promoting any deal. &quot;The clubs are the ones who are going to have to make this decision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody wants to make deal more than I do. A deal is imperative.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that with the new revenue-sharing plan in use, &quot;everybody knows everybody else's numbers.&quot; He added: &quot;There is not one stitch of information that I have that they don't have.</p>
<p>&quot;I think everybody understands we are much better off with a deal,&quot; said Selig. &quot;I hope we will have a deal. I really do believe we will.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
