<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135704" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: SOCCER-NIGERIA AT ODDS WITH DUTCH COACH OVER RESIGNATION.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-NIGERIA AT ODDS WITH DUTCH COACH OVER RESIGNATION.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Olympic champions Nigeria said on Wednesday Dutch coach Jo Bonfrere still had almost a year of his contract to run, even though he claims he resigned months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we're concerned Mr Bonfrere signed a two-year contract with us in August 1995,&quot; Nigeria Football Association (NFA) spokesman Austin Mgbolu said.</p>
<p>But Bonfrere, who masterminded Nigeria's Olympic success in Atlanta, told the BBC by telephone: &quot;I finished my contract with Nigeria in August after the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>&quot;I gave my resignation letter to the NFA secretary and chairman, and to (soccer's world governing body) FIFA.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I left because of some reasons which I don't want to mention in this interview,&quot; said Bonfrere, speaking from Oman where he was coaching the Qatar national side in the Gulf Cup. &quot;But people in Nigeria know why I resigned.&quot;</p>
<p>Relations between the Dutchman and Nigeria's soccer authorities have been poor since January when the military government ordered the national team to boycott the African Nations' Cup in South Africa.</p>
<p>Nigeria, winners of the cup in Tunisia in 1994, were subsequently banned from the next two editions of the tournament. The ban was later reduced to one.</p>
<p>Mgbolu said the NFA expected Bonfrere to return to his post by next Monday, the day before Nigeria face Turkey in a friendly in Istanbul. Their next competitive match is a World Cup qualifier against Burkina Faso in Lagos on November 9.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not aware of any resignation letter submitted by Mr Bonfrere,&quot; Mgbolu said. &quot;He did not return from Atlanta with us, fuelling speculation then that he had resigned.</p>
<p>&quot;But in September he came to (the Nigerian capital) Abuja where he met government officials and said he had not resigned. He was then given a two-month holiday for our Olympic victory.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
