<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135759" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE MONEY RATES FIRMER IN SHORT MARKET.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE MONEY RATES FIRMER IN SHORT MARKET.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Short-term trading rates on Zimbabwe's local money market were quoted firmer on Wednesday in continued cash shortage, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said liquidity was likely to stay low with only a few maturities expected in the next few days and that the benchmark treasury bill rate was likely to go up at Thursday's weekly auction.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will all depend on whether there are no people holding a lot of treasury bills at current rates, in which case they would want to keep them at these levels,&quot; a dealer commented.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, discount houses were buying central bank treasury bills at 19.73 percent and selling them in the market at 19.70 percent, with NCD bills maturing after 30, 60 and 90 days buying and selling firmer at 23.5 and 22.5 percent respectively compared to Tuesday's 22 and 21 percent.</p>
<p>Bankers acceptances were quoted at 21 percent and 20.50 percent, up from 20.50 and 20 percent, while call money added one percentage point to 22 percent.</p>
<p>--Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
