<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135729" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-JUVENTUS HELD TO DRAW BY PART-TIMERS IN ITALIAN CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JUVENTUS HELD TO DRAW BY PART-TIMERS IN ITALIAN CUP.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>League leaders and European champions Juventus were held to a goalless draw in the third round of the Italian cup on Wednesday by Nocerina -- a team of part-timers who have just replaced their manager.</p>
<p>The 0-0 scoreline in the match, played before a crowd of 35,000 in the southern city of Avellino because Nocerina do not have a stadium big enough, was the shock result of a night of seven ties.</p>
<p>It earned serie C side Nocerina, who had seen off first division clubs Piacenza and Perugia on their way to the last 16, a lucrative replay away to Juventus, probably on November 6.</p>
<p>Both teams had a man sent off in the 48th minute in a match which also saw the referee show five yellow cards.</p>
<p>Second division side Genoa also had a game to remember, holding serie A Vicenza 1-1 in the night's only other draw. Both goals came from penalties.</p>
<p>Roberto Baggio scored a brace of goals as AC Milan booked a quarter-final berth with a 2-0 victory against Reggiana.</p>
<p>The only lower division side certain of place in the quarter-finals are Cremonese who won 2-1 away to fellow serie B side Cesena.</p>
<p>Nocerina hail from of Nocera Inferiore, a run down small town in the Naples hinterland.</p>
<p>Their coach, Gianni Balugani, was only brought in this week after his predecessor was sacked with the side one place from the bottom of serie C.</p>
<p>&quot;If someone had told me a couple of months ago that I'd be returning to the bench on the eve of a game against Juve I'd have said he was mad,&quot; Balugani, 50, said before the match.</p>
<p>The two teams last met 18 years ago, also in the Italian cup, when Juventus won 3-1.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
