<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135786" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH CHURCH IN LAST STAND AGAINST ABORTION BILL.</title>
<headline>POLISH CHURCH IN LAST STAND AGAINST ABORTION BILL.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's Roman Catholic Church staged a massive last stand on Wednesday against a bill to liberalise Poland's tough anti-abortion law, as parliament held its final debate on an issue that has split the nation.</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of believers heard the Primate, Cardinal Jozef Glemp say a solemn mass against the measure at a central Warsaw church and then marched towards parliament waving such banners as: &quot;We reject the legislation of death.&quot;</p>
<p>Lower house deputies will vote on Thursday whether to overthrow a Senate veto on the bill, which would let women end pregnancies before the 12th week if they faced financial or personal problems, but only after counselling and reflection.</p>
<p>Under the current law, passed in 1993 by a pro-Catholic government, abortions are now allowed only if a pregnancy threatens a woman's life or health, results from rape or incest, or when the foetus is irreparably damaged.</p>
<p>Poland's bishops, ending a plenary conference on Tuesday, wrote to deputies begging them not to pass the bill, which President Aleksander Kwasniewski has promised to sign into law.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand that you face a decision which -- for various reasons -- is hard for you. But we appeal to you: Stand in defence of life,&quot; said the letter.</p>
<p>The Senate blocked the reform early this month and its lower house backers must secure a majority of 50 percent plus one vote to pass the measure, which they approved in August.</p>
<p>The vote could be close, but even some of the bill's opponents, who include members of the co-ruling Peasant party, admit that the reform is likely to pass.</p>
<p>The church fears a return to the situation before the 1989 fall of communism, when abortion was freely available.</p>
<p>The bill's backers, including the dominant ruling ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD), say the bill provides for sex education in schools and cheaper contraception and may even reduce the number of abortions.</p>
<p>These are anyway widely available in underground clinics or neighbouring countries to women with money.</p>
<p>&quot;The current law has caused much social harm and human suffering. We cannot pretend that there is no problem, no abortion tourism or underground, that there are no abandoned infants,&quot; SLD deputy Izabella Sierakowska told parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Women cannot be made to give birth under compulsion. Love cannot be accompanied by fear,&quot; she declared.</p>
<p>The church, backed by the authority of Polish-born Pope John Paul, sees the bill as a licence to kill unborn children.</p>
<p>The issue is one of several deeply straining relations between the church and the ruling, secular-minded left, led by politicians who were part of the pre-1989 communist system.</p>
<p>On Monday the Episcopate's Secretary-General, Bishop Tadeusz Pieronek, said that these relations had never been so bad since 1993, when the ex-communists won parliamentary polls.</p>
<p>Apart from the abortion issue, the church and SLD have clashed over parliament's delays in ratifying a concordat treaty with the Vatican which was concluded by a previous, pro-Catholic government just before the 1993 elections.</p>
<p>The church also wants Poland's new constitution now being drafted to invoke God -- an idea rejected by much of the SLD.</p>
<p>Such issues may be a key theme in parliamentary polls next year, as 90 percent of Poles are at least nominally Catholics.</p>
<p>An alliance of right-wing parties grouped around the militantly pro-church Solidarity, which has promised to reverse the abortion bill is about level with the SLD in opinion polls. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
