<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135745" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-THE OLD LADY CAN EXPECT NO RESPECT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-THE OLD LADY CAN EXPECT NO RESPECT.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treating old ladies with respect has never gone down well with Roma fans.</p>
<p>Not that the diehard -- some would suggest lunatic -- flare-throwing supporters in the cheap seats on the &quot;Curva Sud&quot; of the city's Olympic Stadium treat senior citizens with anything but care and consideration.</p>
<p>They just don't care for &quot;La Vecchia Signora&quot; (The Old Lady) -- the popular nickname given by Italians to the Turin club otherwise known as European champions Juventus.</p>
<p>Call it the politics of envy or just a symptom of the north-south divide but for years Roma fans have drawn a special pleasure in putting one over on the wealthy northerners whose success has been in inverse proportion to Roma's.</p>
<p>Their team may have won the league title only once since World War Two but they lead Juventus 26-18 in wins at the Olympic Stadium and well over 60,000 fans will crowd into the beautiful bowl for Saturday's late night match.</p>
<p>If city rivals Lazio are the team every Roma coach has to beat, Juventus and AC Milan are next on the list.</p>
<p>Expectations will be higher than ever, despite two consecutive defeats for Roma at the hands of UEFA Cup opponents Karlsruhe last week and lowly Verona at the weekend.</p>
<p>The fact is that Roma are notoriously inconsistent, generally rising to the occasion against top opponents such as champions AC Milan whom they beat 3-0 this month while often shooting themselves in the foot against underdogs.</p>
<p>It is still too early to talk of the championship, although Juventus players already are after putting in one of their finest displays in months against Inter on Sunday, but victory in Rome will be a major boost for either club.</p>
<p>If Roma triumph, they will catch up with league leaders Juventus on 13 points and banish the doubts unsettling a team that has yet to gel under Argentine Carlos Bianchi.</p>
<p>If Juventus win, they will stay top and also receive a useful boost ahead of their Champions' League group match against Rapid Vienna of Austria next Wednesday.</p>
<p>By every reckoning, Juventus are favourites.</p>
<p>Owned by the Agnelli family of FIAT car fame for three quarters of a century, they celebrate their 100th birthday next season having won everything there is to win.</p>
<p>The &quot;bianconeri&quot; (black-and-whites) have helped themselves greedily to second and third helpings in most European competitions but the real gluttony begins at home -- with a record 23 serie A titles since their first in 1905.</p>
<p>By contrast Roma -- the &quot;Giallorossi&quot; (yellow-and-reds) -- have just two league titles to their name: the first in 1942 and the second at the peak of their form in 1983.</p>
<p>Roma fans blame a refereeing mistake for robbing them of another in 1981, when a Ramon Turrone goal against Juventus in Turin was disallowed. Juventus beat Roma by two points after their direct confrontations both ended 0-0.</p>
<p>Roma have not finished a season in the top three since 1988 and nearly went bust in 1991 after the death of patriarchal president Dino Viola and again in 1993.</p>
<p>Perhaps it is no coincidence that the club's symbol is a wolf's head -- for the best part of the last decade the team has cried wolf, promising much and delivering little.</p>
<p>But despite the statistical gulf, Roma v Juventus remains one of the great emotional clashes of the season -- not just because Roma have Italy's most evocative stadium and Juventus often the best team -- but because of past glories.</p>
<p>In the early 1980s, before billionaire media mogul Silvio Berlusconi turned a slumbering AC Milan back into the powerhouse of world soccer, Roma and Juventus were rampant.</p>
<p>Between 1981 and 1986, Juventus won serie A four times and the European Cup and Cup Winners' Cup. They also took the Italian Cup and Intercontinental Cup for good measure.</p>
<p>Roma won the Italian Cup four times, serie A once and lost a European Cup final in Rome on penalties to Liverpool in 1984.</p>
<p>Add to that memorable battles involving French football genius Michel Platini for Juventus, Poland's Zbigniew Boniek -- who played for both clubs -- and a cast of some of the most resonant names in Italian soccer history.</p>
<p>Juventus provided six of the team that beat West Germany in the 1982 World Cup final in Barcelona, including goalkeeper captain Dino Zoff who now runs Roma rivals Lazio.</p>
<p>Roma provided just one -- Bruno Conti -- but boasted Brazilian Falcao and later provided a backdrop for such skilful stars as German Rudi Voeller, Italy's Giuseppe &quot;The Prince&quot; Giannini and Carlo Ancelotti, now Parma coach.</p>
<p>The two clubs also shared the honours for top goalscorer in serie A for the first half of the 1980s.</p>
<p>Current Juventus vice-president Roberto Bettega was top scorer in 1980, followed by Roma's Roberto Pruzzo in 1981 and 1982. Platini then grabbed the top slot for the next three years before Pruzzo once again took the honours in 1986.</p>
<p>Roma's Argentine striker Abel Balbo is second in this season's list of scorers. If he adds to his tally on Saturday, it will ironically be at the expense of another Roman. Juventus goalkeeper Angelo Peruzzi started off at Roma.</p>
<p>But Peruzzi has been used to the emotion of the Olympic Stadium for years -- he was a ballboy behind the goal during the 1984 European Cup final won by Liverpool.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
