<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135742" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-JUVENTUS PENPIX.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-JUVENTUS PENPIX.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pen pictures of the probable Juventus team for Saturday's serie A clash with Roma:</p>
<p>Angelo Peruzzi, goalkeeper, 26 years old. Italy's first choice goalkeeper. Was suspended for a year in 1990 after he and then Roma team mate Andrea Carnevale tested positive for amphetamines. Played 16 serie A matches for Roma.</p>
<p>Moreno Torricelli, defender, 26. Long-haired former carpenter discovered as amateur by Juventus in 1992. Tough, capable of moving forward to good effect. Returned from injury in impressive form against Inter at the weekend when he was key defender in 2-0 win. Was also outstanding for Juventus in European Cup final and has been in Italy squad.</p>
<p>Gianluca Pessotto, defender, 26. Joined from city rivals Torino in 1995 before they were relegated. Now well established as a steady defender, pacy in attack with a good tactical brain. This month became the 100th Juventus player to play for Italy since goalkeeper Giovanni Giacone in 1920.</p>
<p>Ciro Ferrara, defender, 29. Arguably the most versatile defensive talent in Italian soccer, Naples-born Ferrara spent 10 years at Napoli, often alongside Diego Maradona, before joining Juventus three seasons ago. Italian international.</p>
<p>Paolo Montero, defender, 25. Juve's lone South American, son of former Uruguayan World Cup star Julio Montero. Combines excellent technical skills with a tendency to wander. Wandered more than usual earlier this month when he clashed with a photographer after Juventus lost 2-1 at Vicenza. Escaped match ban because referee did not see the incident.</p>
<p>Angelo Di Livio, midfielder, 30. Current Italian international who was born in Rome and started at Roma. He moved on after one season without a full serie A match. Then spent nine years in second and third divisions before joining Juventus in 1994 and helping them win league title in 1995.</p>
<p>Didier Deschamps, midfielder, 28. The key link with French international team mate Zinedine Zidane. Now in his third season at Juventus. Won European Cup with Marseille as well. Juventus reportedly close to selling him after first season but has developed impressively under coach Marcello Lippi.</p>
<p>Zinedine Zidane, midfielder, 24. Arrived this season from Bordeaux amid fanfare and tag of &quot;new Michel Platini&quot;. The honeymoon has not lasted and Zidane has had a rough start to the season. But he came good last weekend, scoring his first goal and showing good understanding with Alen Boksic in a match seen as turning point for the player. Roma should beware.</p>
<p>Vladimir Jugovic, midfielder, 27, Former Red Star Belgrade and Sampdoria player. Skilful ball-winner. Also won European Cup with Red Star in 1991.</p>
<p>Alessandro Del Piero, midfielder/striker, 21. Team fell for a while from top of table during his absence after he injured foot against Fiorentina at end of last month. But the boy wonder of Italian soccer, who effectively forced Roberto Baggio to exile in Milan, is fit again and may be back to face Roma.</p>
<p>Michele Padovano, striker, 30. Scored equaliser against Roma at Olympic stadium last year.</p>
<p>Alen Boksic, striker, 26. Coming good after three frustrating years at Lazio. Son of a Croatian truck driver from Split, started out at Hajduk before moving to France. Has scored twice in Champions' League this season and twice for his country, although has missed far more in the league. A crowd favourite, already tipped as frontrunner for player of the year award. Likened to Polish great Zbigniew Boniek by some.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
