<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135715" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-A LITTLE LIE KEEPS CONE IN THE GAME.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-A LITTLE LIE KEEPS CONE IN THE GAME.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A key moment in the New York Yankees' life-saving World Series victory Tuesday came in the sixth inning, when pitcher David Cone told a little lie that kept him in the game.</p>
<p>Cone was starting to lose it a little bit. He had done the the unthinkable by walking his opposing pitcher, Tom Glavine, to lead off the inning on a 3-2 pitch. He then yielded a single to Marquis Grissom and an out later walked Chipper Jones to load the bases with the dangerous Atlanta Braves slugger Fred McGriff coming to the plate.</p>
<p>Yankee manager Joe Torre walked out to the mound to confer with Cone. &quot;I just wanted him to level with me because I knew he wanted to stay in the game no matter what. And I just needed him to be real truthful and be there, and he was,&quot; said Torre.</p>
<p>&quot;I just asked him, I said, 'It's very important here,' I said, 'I've got to know are you OK?' He said, 'I'm fine, I'm just losing the splitter and it's more a mechanical thing than anything else.' He wasn't tired and he felt fine, and I looked in his eyes and I believed him,&quot; recalled Torre, who left Cone in the game.</p>
<p>But Cone said there was a little deception involved.</p>
<p>&quot;Joe got as close as he could to me, face to face, and implored me to be honest with him. And I did my best to lie, to tell him I had something left and I'm going to get him through this inning.</p>
<p>&quot;I got us in that jam. There's no worse feeling than coming out with the bases loaded and the next guy comes in and it's a burden on the relief guy.</p>
<p>&quot;That game right there was mine to win or lose.&quot;</p>
<p>Cone said the deception was as much directed at himself as at his manager.</p>
<p>&quot;You sort of trick yourself, yeah, I can get Fred McGriff out with the bases loaded, yeah, right.&quot;</p>
<p>Cone did get McGriff out on pop-up before walking Ryan Klesko for Atlanta's first run, which made it 2-1. But he got Javier Lopez on a foul pop-out, and the threat was over.</p>
<p>Cone was done, too, yielding the mound to the Yankees' nonpareil set-up man Mariano Rivera in the next inning.</p>
<p>The Yanks were on their way to the 5-2 win that got them back in the Series, although trailing two games to one.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
