<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135784" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: SLOVAK PARLIAMENT RAMS THROUGH CONTROVERSIAL BILL.</title>
<headline>SLOVAK PARLIAMENT RAMS THROUGH CONTROVERSIAL BILL.</headline>
<byline>Peter Javurek</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak parliament on Wednesday brushed aside concerns over the country's path to democracy by approving the first of several controversial laws criticised by the European Union and the United States.</p>
<p>Deputies of the three-party coalition approved a law giving the public prosecutor's office unprecedented supervisory and executive powers which President Michal Kovac has rejected.</p>
<p>The law, originally passed in September and returned by Kovac for revision, was approved by 74 votes to 60 in 150-seat parliament.</p>
<p>Under the constitution the president can refuse to sign a law only once. If parliament approves a law for a second time, he is obliged to sign it.</p>
<p>Wednesday's vote was taken a day after the U.S. and European Union ambassadors indicated that the government had to improve its record on democratic reform and commitment to the rule of law if Slovakia wanted to join organisations such as the EU and NATO.</p>
<p>Later in its 14-day session the coalition of Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar is expected to rubber-stamp two laws, both of which Kovac has rejected and which the West has criticised in their present form.</p>
<p>One on protecting the republic borrows heavily on communist-era anti-subversion legislation and the other covers universities.</p>
<p>Deputies of Meciar's Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS) and their coalition partenrs, the far-right Slovak National Party and the ultra-left Workers' Party (ZRS), ignored presidential and opposition objections, passing the prosecution law in its original form.</p>
<p>Kovac attacked the law as undemocratic.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot consider that such a law conforms to the constitution, the principles acknowledged in democratic states and the principles of a legal state,&quot; he told parliament.</p>
<p>One of his main objections was that the general prosecutor would become an independent power in the state uncontrolled by either executive or legislative power.</p>
<p>&quot;The constitution explicitly recognises the legislature, executive and judiciary. It does not recognise the prosecutor as an independent power,&quot; Kovac said.</p>
<p>Kovac and the opposition say the law would create a military-style pyramid structure in the prosecutor's office, such as before the 1989 fall of communism, allowing political abuse of this power.</p>
<p>&quot;The prosecutor is an independent state activity outside legislative, executive or judiciary powers,&quot; the law says.</p>
<p>The law gives the general prosecutor the power to remove a prosecutor from a case and hand it to another, or to himself. &quot;Everybody&quot; must present themselves to a prosecutor if summoned or be forced to do so under police power, the law says.</p>
<p>Kovac said the general prosecutor would be virtually irremovable before his term of office expired. &quot;There is no state post which has such a virtually permanent position.&quot;</p>
<p>The coalition, during a brief debate, brushed the objections aside, saying they were groundless, and politically and ideologically motivated.</p>
<p>On Tuesday U.S. Ambassador Ralph Johnson repeated U.S. concerns over a number of Slovak laws &quot;which do not conform to generally accepted notions of a democratic society&quot;.</p>
<p>EU ambassador Georgious Zavvos said there was much work to do for Slovakia to earn a place in Western structures.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava newsroom (42 2) 24 23 0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
