<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135793" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY '56 UPRISING LEADERS PASS TORCH TO YOUNG.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY '56 UPRISING LEADERS PASS TORCH TO YOUNG.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Veterans of Hungary's 1956 uprising against Soviet rule said on Tuesday, the eve of the 40th anniversary, that it was time to pass the torch to the young.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's face it, my friends: We are 40 years older,&quot; Hungarian President Arpad Goncz said in a speech during a solemn ceremony of music and poetry at a Budapest theatre.</p>
<p>Goncz was sentenced to life imprisonment for his role in what was then the boldest blow to Soviet domination of eastern Europe.</p>
<p>The first shots of the uprising were fired on October 23, 1956 as Hungarians fought in the streets with small arms and petrol bombs against Soviet tanks and troops, and drove them out of Budapest. </p>
<p>But the West, after fanning the flames of rebellion in radio broadcasts, failed to intervene directly and a Soviet invasion in November crushed the revolution.</p>
<p>About 25,000 people were killed.</p>
<p>&quot;If we do not tell the truth about 1956 to our children, then they will not tell it to their children,&quot; Goncz said. &quot;But then our nephews will dig out the truth from under the earth, if need be.&quot; </p>
<p>This year's commemorations, which began by marking events leading up to the fighting, have included pointed attacks by opposition parties and some 1956 veterans against Hungary's ruling Socialist party, comprised mostly of former communists.</p>
<p>Apart from a few official functions, most of the events have been organised by 1956 associations and the opposition.</p>
<p>At a small ceremony attended by about 1,000 students in the cold and rain at Bem Square, near the Danube River, student groups and other associations laid wreaths at the statue of a Polish hero of Hungary's 1848 revolution.</p>
<p>None were placed by pro-government groups. </p>
<p>&quot;We of the '56 generation are fewer and fewer,&quot; said Bela Pomogats, president of the Hungarian Writers Association, who was in Bem Square 40 years ago for the uprising.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it is the young the generation which has to take over,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Csilla Bodnar, a 24-year-old theology student, said that for her, &quot;1956 is part of our national identity, but I wish it hadn't happened&quot;. </p>
<p>The uprising, in addition to the toll of dead and wounded and serious damage in Budapest, forced an estimated 250,000 people to flee the country.</p>
<p>Events on Wednesday will begin with a flag-raising ceremony at Parliament followed by the lighting of &quot;a flame of the revolution&quot; which will remain lit until November 4, the day Soviet tanks crushed the uprising.</p>
<p>Other events include an awards ceremony in Parliament and later in the afternoon another rally at Bem Square. </p>
<p>There also will be events at scenes of important battles, including the Corvin Cinema and Szena Square, and an evening reception at Parliament. 221838 GMT oct 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
