<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135772" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH RATING AGENCY TO START OPERATING EARLY 1997.</title>
<headline>POLISH RATING AGENCY TO START OPERATING EARLY 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish Rating Agency, which will be set up next month, is likely to issue first ratings early next year, an official of the Polish Banking Association (ZPB) responsible for the creation of the agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the agency will be able to issue first ratings in the first months of next year,&quot; Wojciech Lipka told Reuters.</p>
<p>The company Srodkowo-Europejskie Centrum Ratingu i Analiz SA wants to concentrate on the Polish market at first and later expand its operations to borrowers from other countries in eastern and central Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets of eastern and central Europe are often treated as one area, so we want to enter the market to make comparisons and we believe our ratings would be interesting for investors from developed markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lipka said the agency would evaluate commercial and municipal borrowers' debt instruments such as corporate bonds, convertible bonds, municipal bonds, and others.</p>
<p>He said the company's more than 20 shareholders would be mainly Polish financial institutions, but said there were also several foreign institutions joining in. None of the shareholders would have more than five percent in the company.</p>
<p>-- Malgorzata Rzepka +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8395416">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
