<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135762" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: GREATER ROLE SEEN FOR S.AFRICAN POST OFFICE.</title>
<headline>GREATER ROLE SEEN FOR S.AFRICAN POST OFFICE.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greater attention should be paid to the role that could be played by the post office's Postbank in providing improved financial services to long-neglected rural communities.</p>
<p>This was one of the main findings released on Wednesday in the final report by a commission of enquiry appointed by President Nelson Mandela last year.</p>
<p>The commission, headed by banker Conrad Strauss, also recommended that the Land Bank be reformed to provide both wholelsale and retail services, paying special attention to people benefitting from land reform programmes.</p>
<p>The report said that Postbank was well suited to satisfying several financial service needs of the rural poor through savings facilities and transmission services, because it already had a wide network of outlets in rural areas.</p>
<p>The commission said Postbank should review its interest rates. &quot;Savers should not be penalised by negative interest rates,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Postbank's interest rates range from 2.5 to 13.5 percent depending on the type of savings chosen.</p>
<p>Although Postbank had said that lower interest rates subsidised the cost of the post office's wide network, the commission said it &quot;would prefer real costing and a request for identified grant finance rather than the current policy of implicit cross-subsidisation&quot;.</p>
<p>In its initial report, the commission had proposed that the financial aspects of rural development should be co-ordinated by the Land Bank, which should be transformed and re-named the Rural Bank.</p>
<p>This idea was dropped in the final report, which said that the Land Bank should continue to play a significant role as the financier of commercial agriculture but should broaden its clientele to support land reform.</p>
<p>The commission said government should also encourage commercial banks to further expand their rural services.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary office + 27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
