<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135771" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - YUGOSLAVIA - OCT 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - YUGOSLAVIA - OCT 23.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified them and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Yugoslav President Zoran Lilic meeting Greek Prime Minister Costas Simitis in Athens today. Lilic is returning for a seven-day African tour.</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia and Slovakia initial agreement on avoidance of double taxation of income and property, the federal information ministry reported.</p>
<p>- Loznica Viskoza factory starts realisation of agreement with China worth $3 million a month, which is within the scope of the Yugosalv-Chinese barter deal.</p>
<p>- New Alcatel telephone exchange to be put into operation in Novi Sad Wednesday. It will open 16,800 new telephone lines.</p>
<p>- Sabac pharmaceutical industry Zorka Farma starts construction of new 41 million dinar ($8.1 million) plant.</p>
<p>- Priority of Yugoslavia's economic policy in 1997 will be maintaining stable prices and foreign exchange rate through measures based on market principles and promotion of structural changes, the federal government said.</p>
<p>- Bosnian Serb Republic abolishes transit visas for passengers on the Belgrade-Sarajevo bus line operated jointly by Belgrade Lasta and Sarajevo Centrotrans.</p>
<p>-  Yugoslavia has 7,597,504 eligible voters, says the federal election commission ahead of the November 3 federal and local elections.</p>
<p>- Montenegrin police arrests man who admits to the abduction and killing of passengers on the Strpci Belgrade-Bar railway station in February 1993.</p>
<p>- Member of the opposition Serbian Radical Party from Sombor arrested for holding large quantity of illegal weapons and ammunition, believed to be linked with a Sombor terrorist group.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- World bank representatives will visit Belgrade in November but will not be authorised to negotiate Yugoslavia's membership in the organisation, says spokesman of Lowe Bell International, Yugoslavia's  public relations representative.</p>
<p>- Kragujevac Zastava arms workers resume street protests again after 18-day break during which talks with management yielded no results.</p>
<p>- Belgrade city transport company GSP drivers threaten to go on strike on October 28 if they are not paid oustanding wages by that date.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- First vice-governor of the central bank of Yugoslavia Zarko Trbojevic says he expects Yugoslavia to resolve its status in the IMF and the World Bank by the end of the year. -- Belgrade Newsroom 381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
