<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135866" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - John Walter, AT&amp;T's new president.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - John Walter, AT&amp;T's new president.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Walter believes that making strategies work within the machinery of AT&amp;T Corp will be the core both of his job as chief operating officer and when he steps up to become chief executive (CEO) in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;You can have the greatest strategy in the world, but if you dont execute, it doesnt matter,&quot; Walter told Reuters.</p>
<p>Walter, chairman and chief executive of commercial printing firm R.R. Donnelley &amp; Sons Co, was on Wednesday appointed by AT&amp;T as president and chief operating officer, and heir apparent to AT&amp;T CEO and chairman Robert Allen.  </p>
<p>Walter will immerse himself in the operations of AT&amp;T during the 14 months when he and Robert Allen work as a team, and emerge capable of holding the reins.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very comfortable with my ability to move this enterprise forward,&quot; he said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Walter declined to outline areas where he believed AT&amp;T had failed, but underlined achieving objectives and having an appropriate cost base as his clear focus.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to have a cost platform which allows us to compete effectively or we are disadvantaged even before we come into the ring,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Analysts have repeatedly criticised AT&amp;T's inability to meet its objectives, which has resulted in an erosion of the value of the brand name and a sliding share price.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T has flung tens of millions in $100 checks at consumer long distance customers only to find them desert again to rivals in the industry. Its share in the $75 billion market has fallen to around 55 percent from 60 two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;They haven't had the level of execution on the consumer side that we should have seen,&quot; said consultant Chris Landis of TeleChoice, who is also an ex-AT&amp;T executive.  </p>
<p>AT&amp;T has made repeated attempts to make money in online services and the Internet, but has sold off almost all its creative content efforts and has retreated to a core offering of Internet access.</p>
<p>For every acquisition that worked well, like the 1994 purchase of McCaw Cellular, there have been others that failed, like the $7.5 billion 1991 takeover of NCR Corp.</p>
<p>Adjusted for the split-off of Lucent Technologies Inc, AT&amp;T shares have fallen 16 percent this year, about the same as the broad market has risen.  </p>
<p>Among Walter's favorite quotes: &quot;When you hire, hire people better than you and then you'll build a company of giants. Hire people worse than you and you'll disappear.&quot;</p>
<p>Printing industry analysts say Walter has used technology very effectively to make Donnelley grow, but some say growth came at a price.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of things have been going wrong,&quot; said one analyst, citing the lower earnings outlook and falling stock price.</p>
<p>But analyst Rudolf Hokanson of Deutsche Morgan Grenfell said Walter was an effective manager.</p>
<p>&quot;He tried to make people more accountable, tried to flatten some of the reporting structure,&quot; said Hokanson.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsroom 212 859 1712</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
