<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135804" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Fletcher Canada to split into pulp, paper.</title>
<headline>Fletcher Canada to split into pulp, paper.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fletcher Challenge Canada Ltd announced a restructuring Wednesday that will split its pulp and paper operations into separate business units and said it expects to decide their future in about nine months.</p>
<p>Asked if the restructuring was a prelude to divesting assets into a new public company, chief executive Doug Whitehead said, &quot;We'll look at all options in the future. But there's nothing definitive yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking after the company's annual meeting, he said a decision was &quot;probably nine months away.&quot; Fletcher is majority owned by New Zealand's Fletcher Challenge Ltd.  </p>
<p>He said the move was designed to improve financial performance in the operations because their returns currently do not exceed the cost of capital.</p>
<p>The separation will make the divisions more focused in the face of intense competition. &quot;If you look around the world, we're up against pure plays,&quot; Whitehead said.</p>
<p>Whitehead said the restructuring would generate significant cost savings but he declined to estimate the amount. There will be unspecified job cuts, notably in the ranks of management and staff. The company has about 1,800 workers in its pulp operations and 1,200 in paper.  </p>
<p>The company will likely determine its job cut plans within two months.</p>
<p>The restructuring will also involve the company's integrated mills. Whitehead said Fletcher &quot;is going to split the mills a lot more definitively&quot; between their pulp and paper operations but gave no details.</p>
<p>Fletcher's move comes on the heels of its decision earlier this month to shed its remaining 52 percent stake in TimberWest Forest Ltd. TimberWest, a lumber producer, was wholly owned by Fletcher until 1993 when it spun the unit off to focus more closely on pulp and paper.  </p>
<p>TimberWest has put itself up for sale and Whitehead hoped a deal would be completed in 1997's first calendar quarter. Any deal would be designed to ensure the continued flow of wood fiber from TimberWest to Fletcher in the future, he said.</p>
<p>Whitehead said the entire British Columbia forest industry is plagued by inadequate returns, which he blamed partly on poor markets for their products and partly on what he called the high cost policies of the British Columbia government.</p>
<p>He said it was likely Fletcher's printing paper mills will take further downtime, but he said he was hopeful there would be no further production cuts in pulp.  </p>
<p>News of the restructuring Wednesday prompted analysts to speculate that Fletcher could ultimately sell its pulp operations.</p>
<p>In the annual meeting, Whitehead said the company had previously viewed the pulp business as supporting its core focus on printing papers. &quot;Since then, we've been prompted to review that position,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Whitehead said the markets for groundwood printing papers and pulp are still slow and likely to remain that way for several more months.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
