<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135816" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada eliminating book tax for libraries, schools.</title>
<headline>Canada eliminating book tax for libraries, schools.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Finance Minister Paul Martin announced on Wednesday that the government intended to eliminate the seven-percent federal sales tax on books for schools and libraries but not for the general public.</p>
<p>&quot;The 100 percent rebate I am announcing today means that there will be no GST (Goods and Services Tax) on all books purchased by educational institutions and learning organizations across Canada,&quot; Martin told Parliament.</p>
<p>It will apply to public libraries, schools, universities and certain charities and other front-line literacy groups.  </p>
<p>He made the declaration in announcing detailed agreements with the governments of three Maritime provinces -- Nova Scotia, New Brunswick and Newfoundland -- to implement a &quot;Harmonized Sales Tax,&quot; merging the GST with provincial taxes.</p>
<p>The provinces had complained that the new tax system would increase levies on books, prompting Prime Minister Jean Chretien to allow provinces that wished to to exclude all books from the provincial component of the merged tax.</p>
<p>Under intense pressure from opposition parties and literacy groups, Martin in the present announcement went further to grant a partial exemption to the federal portion.  </p>
<p>Under the federal government's agreement with the three Atlantic provinces, the GST will be merged with provincial sales taxes into a sigle combined value-added tax, to be called the Harmonized Sales Tax (HST).</p>
<p>The new 15 percent tax will be implemented on April 1, 1997. It will be included in the prices consumers pay for goods and services, rather than the current practice of adding the taxes at the cash register.</p>
<p>Martin also said his government would continue to seek agreement with other provinces &quot;interested in harmonization.&quot;</p>
<p>He had previously said that the federal government will provide C$961 million to the three Atlantic provinces over four years to compensate them for lost revenue.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Ottawa Bureau 613-235-6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
