<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135854" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PacifiCorp saw Q3 electric customer growth.</title>
<headline>PacifiCorp saw Q3 electric customer growth.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>PacifiCorp said on Wednesday it saw growth in each of its major businesses during the third quarter, including a 2 percent increase in the average number of domestic retail electric customers.</p>
<p>The Portland, Ore.-based utility also reported 14 percent customer load growth at Powercor, its Australian electricity distribution and marketing company.</p>
<p>Earnings from the company's domestic electric operations increased 14 percent to $100 million. Domestic retail electric revenues were up 7 percent to $546 million, while associated energy sales volume rose 5 percent.  </p>
<p>Despite lower energy prices, PacifiCorp said wholesale business also grew substantially in the quarter, with wholesale revenues and energy volumes up 45 percent and 86 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Retail customer growth, price increases in the company's Oregon and Wyoming customer service territories and strong demand for power drove the increase in earnings.</p>
<p>Warmer and drier weather added an estimated $7 million, or $0.02 per share, to earnings in the quarter.</p>
<p>Fuel expense for the quarter was up slightly to $121 million, PacifiCorp said. Thermal generation was up 1 percent, to 13.3 million MWh.  Hydroelectric generation increased 8 percent, to 712,400 MWh due to increased river flows.</p>
<p>--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
