<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135818" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada says to resume daily lumber export reports.</title>
<headline>Canada says to resume daily lumber export reports.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Canadian government spokeswoman said on Wednesday that Canada would resume publication of a daily update of its softwood lumber exports to the United States on Thursday.</p>
<p>But she said Canadian lumber exporting companies would not know the final quarterly quota for their exports until October 31.</p>
<p>&quot;The deadline is October 31, at which time the companies will know the exact amount of their allocation,&quot; said Nicole Bourget, communications assistant to International Trade Minister Art Eggleton.  </p>
<p>Bourget said the International Trade Department had decided in principle on each company's export allocation, but that the precise quotas were subject to discussion and verification between the government and the companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Now they (trade department officials) are doing the verification with the companies and they are doing the individual allocation,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Under an agreement between Ottawa and Washington that took effect on April 1, Canadian lumber exports that exceed 14.7 billion board feet annually, or 4.226 billion board feet quarterly, are subject to export fees.  </p>
<p>At the end of September, Canada temporarily suspended the daily publication of export updates due to a change in the system for processing export permits.</p>
<p>During the first two quarters of the agreement, export permits were processed on a first-come-first-first-served basis. Starting with the third quarter, which began on October 1, export permits are to be issued according to individual exports quotas for every lumber exporting company.</p>
<p>Under the new allocation, British Columbia will get 59 percent of the total annual quota for Canada, Quebec will get 23 percent, Ontario 10.3 percent and Alberta 7.7 percent.  </p>
<p>The new allocation will go to primary producers and remanufacturers who further process lumber. Wholesalers of lumber will not be allowed direct allocations.</p>
<p>The allocation will be reviewed annually for the next four years of the life of the Canada-U.S. agreement.</p>
<p>-- Malina Poshtova Zang, Reuters Ottawa Bureau (613) 235-6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
