<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135882" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Avon CEO sees ramp up in advertising.</title>
<headline>Avon CEO sees ramp up in advertising.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK, Oct 23, Reuter  - A doubling or more of spending on advertising in coming years will be needed to fight growing cosmetics rivals and increase worldwide sales of lipsticks, lotions and other personal-care items, Avon Products Inc chief executive James Preston said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to get our advertising up in established markets to three-to-four percent of sales. Otherwise, we won't get our message out,&quot; Avon chief executive James Preston told an investors meeting here.</p>
<p>Avon sells cosmetics, household items and other goods in some 125 countries, mostly through armies of direct-sales representatives. Last year, Avon spent $52.8 million on advertising, or a bit more than one percent of net sales of nearly $5 billion.</p>
<p>Preston gave no timetable for the step-up in advertising, other than to say it would be over several years.</p>
<p>Christina Gold, president of Avon's North American operations, the company's biggest market, said the company had doubled its advertising spending to $30 million in the United States this year over 1995. Avon planned to increase U.S. advertising again next year to help the launch of skincare and other new products, but at a slower pace than during 1996.</p>
<p>-- Michael Connor 212-859-1713</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
