<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135845" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks sharply lower at midday.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks sharply lower at midday.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dow Industrials were down more than 50 points at midday unsettled by a multitude of worries that included the possibility of a Democratic sweep in Congress and a market which has run very far very fast recently.</p>
<p>The Industrials were down 60 points, or 1.09 percent, at 5995, triggering the New York Stock Exchange's automatic curbs on index-arbitrage trades at 1147 EDT/1537 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing is a discounting process ahead of the election in November,&quot; said Joseph Barthel, chief investment strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Big Board decliners led advancing issues by more than two to one on volume of about 195 million shares.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite Index, which enjoyed a brief spell in positive territory this morning, was down five points, or 0.37 percent, at 1215.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries were weak and offered no support. The long bond was down 4/32 to yield 6.87 percent.</p>
<p>Barthel said the possibility of the Democrats regaining control of one or both houses of Congress was starting to resonate on Wall Street, and the reaction was jittery.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street likes Clinton with a Republican Congress,&quot; Barthel said. &quot;A Democratic Congress could mean less curtailment of entitlements and less fiscal restraint, something the bond and stock markets do not like.&quot;</p>
<p>The six-year-old rally picked up steam in November 1994 after Republican majorities took control of the House and Senate.</p>
<p>Barthel sees no specific catalyst for today's sell-off. Analysts say the market is overextended on the upside, and they question whether the earnings momentum needed to keep it going can be sustained.</p>
<p>&quot;We are up almost 13 percent in 65 trading days. Put a pencil to that and you can make the case that the market got full very quickly, and that calls for a normal consolidation,&quot; Barthel said. &quot;I wouldn't rule out a visit to Dow 5800.&quot;</p>
<p>Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said there was a &quot;mini-stampede&quot; to get out of stocks because of fear that earnings could not keep up momentum.</p>
<p>&quot;What do you do for an encore?&quot; he asked. &quot;We are way overextended on the upside. Valuations are very rich. From here on in, it will be more difficult to maintain these near-record profit margins.&quot;</p>
<p>While the Dow Industrials fell, the laggard Dow Transportation Average rallied in what analysts said was an aberration due to strength in one stock, Conrail Inc.</p>
<p>Conrail, the second most active stock on the NYSE, was up 12-1/8 at 96-5/8, driven by Norfolk Southern Corp's $100 per share takeover offer. The bid is intended to derail CSX Corp's $92.50 per share merger pact with Conrail.</p>
<p>Norfolk fell 7/8 to 93-5/8. CSX was off 1/4 at 46.</p>
<p>The Dow Transportation Average was up 32 points, or 1.48 percent, at 2155.</p>
<p>The most actively traded stock on the NYSE was AT&amp;T Corp, down 1-3/4 at 38-1/8. The company named R.R. Donnelley &amp; Sons Co chairman John R. Walter to the position of president and chief operating officer. A spokesman said that Walter would replace Robert Allen as AT&amp;T's chief executive in January 1998 and chairman later that year.</p>
<p>Shares of Netscape Communications Corp rallied 2-1/8 to 46-5/8 after reporting on Tuesday a quadrupling of quarterly earnings from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212-859-1737</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
