<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135843" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries tread lower at midday before supply.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries tread lower at midday before supply.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasury prices treaded lower at midday on Wednesday just in front of the Treasury's auction of five-year notes.</p>
<p>The Treasury will sell $12.5 billion in five-year notes in the afternoon. The deadline for bids is 1300 EDT/1700 GMT. Auction results are due around 1340 EDT.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Treasury sold $18.25 billion in two-year notes. The auction was well bid but despite that, there was little follow-through buying and the market conceded territory in the trading that followed the sale.</p>
<p>The market opened a touch firmer and then lost a tiny bit of ground in early trade. In late morning activity, prices were moving in the narrowest of trading ranges.</p>
<p>In the hour preceding the bidding deadline for the five-year note auction, the market backed down a bit.</p>
<p>The when-issued yield on the new five-year notes edged up to 6.32 percent.</p>
<p>Late Monday, traders had estimated that the five-year notes would be sold at a yield between 6.30 percent and 6.32 percent.</p>
<p>Five-year Treasury notes last were auctioned on September 26. At that time the notes were sold at a 6.409 percent yield, the bid-to-cover ratio was 2.57, and non-competitive bids totaled $477 million.</p>
<p>Dimick said he saw no reason for this auction to fail and said, &quot;It could give us a little boost if we get another successful auction.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said he did not think a good auction could generate a larger move.</p>
<p>&quot;We could move back to overnight highs -- back to about 6.83 percent on the bond yield,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>For while Dimick said there was not much to block a market path upward, there was also nothing specific to propel it to higher levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The 110-16 area on the bond contract represents the bottom of the trading channel that you can draw on the September-October rally,&quot; said Dimick. &quot;You break the trend if you close below that floor and that would trigger selling rather than buying.&quot;</p>
<p>Dimick said that while he is fundamentally constructive on the bond market, technical factors and supply make him a little defensive.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply and the fact that we're challenging the bottom of recent ranges lead me to tread cautiously here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, McDonough, president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, will speak at a small business awards luncheon in New Jersey at 1300 EDT/1700 GMT.</p>
<p>In early afternoon, three-month bill rates were up one basis point to five percent, six-month and year-bill rates were unchanged at 5.14 percent and 5.27 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The 6-1/2 percent ten-year note was down 3/32 to 99-12/32, yielding 6.59 percent.</p>
<p>After being up 2/32 at the open, the 6-3/4 percent 30-year bond was down 2/32 to 98-19/32, yielding 6.86 percent.</p>
<p>-- North American Treasury Desk, 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
