<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135864" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot resids mostly lose ground with crude.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot resids mostly lose ground with crude.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot residual fuel prices mostly lost ground Wednesday in sluggish trade, with a sharp slide in crude and forecasts for mild East Coast weather driving buyers to the sidelines, industry sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The general tone seems to be changing for lower levels. I don't see it totally collapsing, but I think we're in for a little correction,&quot; said one cash trader, noting sharp losses in crude left buyers reluctant to commit.</p>
<p>In New York Harbor, physical one percent was off slightly to about $21.25 a barrel, with November paper more than 30 cents lower at $21.10-30 on weaker crude, traders said.  </p>
<p>NYH December one percent paper also lost about 30 cents to $21.20-40.</p>
<p>Traders said prospects for better high sulphur supplies and softer bunkers were pressuring HSFO prices. NYH 2.2 percent was down slightly to $20.50-75.</p>
<p>At the U.S. Gulf, one percent was a quarter lower at $19.75, while three percent was down by 25-50 cents to $19.25-50.</p>
<p>No NYH or USG deals were reported.</p>
<p>New York City gate gas prices firmed another five cents Wednesday to the high-$2.90s/mmBtu versus NYH one percent resid at a $3.37/mmBtu equivalent. November New York gas was still quoted at about NYMEX plus 65 cents, or in the $3.20/mmBtu area versus a resid paper equivalent of $3.37.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
