<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135828" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sun Microsystems unveils java chip design.</title>
<headline>Sun Microsystems unveils java chip design.</headline>
<byline>Barbara Grady</byline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Calif. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sun Microsystems Inc on Wednesday unveiled an eagerly awaited chip designed to boost the speed of computers running Java applications and supply a broad new market for low-cost Internet devices.</p>
<p>When the new microprocessor -- called the picoJava -- comes on the market late next year, it could sharply boost revenues generated by Sun's Microelectronics unit, company officials said at the Microprocessor Forum in San Jose. Sun unveiled the chip's design at the conference.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will participate in a much larger market for chips than before,&quot; said Raj Parekh, general manager of Sun's Volume Products group, which developed picoJava.</p>
<p>Sun designed the picoJava chip for use in low-priced devices for accessing the Internet, including so-called network computers. PicoJava is also intended for pagers, cellular phones, navigational devices and pocket communicators.  </p>
<p>In addition to making and directly selling picoJava chips, Sun has already agreed to license the design to four major Asian electronics companies -- NEC Corp. Samsung LG, Semicon LTD and Mitsubishi -- which will pay royalties.</p>
<p>&quot;The good thing about royalties is they go right to the bottom line,&quot; said Harlan McGhan, strategic marketing director for the unit.</p>
<p>Java applications for the Internet are written in a programming language introduced by Sun about a year ago.  </p>
<p>Java has quickly become the most popular language in the software world. Sun estimates that 200,000 programmers have used it to create about 80,000 pages on the Internet's World Wide Web area.</p>
<p>Programmers like Java because it allows them to write an application once for users of any type of computer, rather than having to redo it for each latform. Java is tailor-made for the Internet.</p>
<p>However, Java applications often run slowly because of the ways that conventional microprocessors read the code.  </p>
<p>Most commonly, the processor &quot;interprets&quot; the Java code for the computer's underlying operating system. In some high-end computers, the processor &quot;compiles&quot; all the Java codes and then effectively retells them in the computer's native code. That requires lots of memory on a central processing unit because the code is expanded two to three times.</p>
<p>The picoJava executes Java code directly, because it is designed for such applications and doesn't have to interpret or compile.  </p>
<p>Analysts say neither the interpreting or compiling methods are satisfactory for use in a new breed of devices called network appliances, designed specifically for the Internet. Those low-cost units require smaller less-expensive chips, a market often addressed by embedded controllers.</p>
<p>&quot;PicoJava is the best solution for the embedded market,&quot; he said Robert Garner, Sun's director of Java Media products.</p>
<p>&quot;You'll get the best price/performance and also lower power consumption,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>PicoJava processes 15 to 20 percent faster than &quot;interpreting&quot; and five times faster than compiling.  </p>
<p>He said the chip also enabled programmers to write more reliable and secure Java applications, allowing for shorter product-development time.</p>
<p>The picoJava chip is built around an RISC architecture -- also used in Sun's workstations and others. The processor has a small cache, or memory, compared with other chips, and simplified instruction code.</p>
<p>&quot;Only those instructions that directly improve Java execution are implemented in hardware,&quot; Sun said.  </p>
<p>Despite Sun's description of picoJava as the answer to the slow execution of Java applications, MicroDesign analyst Jim Turley said he was yet not sold on its merits.</p>
<p>&quot;Looking at the internals of the picoJava, I'm not convinced it will execute faster than a Pentium and I think it will not be as fast as workstation chips like Sparc,&quot; Turley said.</p>
<p>Pentium is Intel Corp's microprocessor for personal computers. Sparc is Sun's workstation chip.</p>
<p>Still, Turley agreed the picoJava &quot;makes sense&quot; for low-cost network appliances and hand-held devices where space and price are big considerations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
