<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135872" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Most US corporate debt steady, TCI off yet again.</title>
<headline>Most US corporate debt steady, TCI off yet again.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cable and media debt dominated corporate bond trade on Wednesday, the sector marred by further widening in TCI Communications paper, traders said.</p>
<p>High-grades spreads outside the sector held in against light to moderate customer selling, meanwhile. Two to three large bid lists circulated the Street, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Spreads have been stable for the last couple of days with some sellers coming in,&quot; said one high-grades trader. &quot;But it's pretty quiet because we're in the fourth quarter when people's appetite for risk diminishes.&quot;  </p>
<p>Back in cables, dealers stressed the slide in TCI debt has slowed, but issues still widened in the five- to 10-basis -point range into the close. TCI debt has widened more than 40 basis points since the Standard &amp; Poor's rating agency late Friday said it may downgrade the credit to junk status.</p>
<p>TCI's 6-7/8 percent debt due 2006 were bid seven basis points wider at 227 basis points near the close.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Viacom Inc debt was softer for the second consecutive session following news it may pay MCA $1.45 billion and exchange its 50 percent interest in the SciFi Channel for complete control of the USA Network.  </p>
<p>Viacom debt due 2005 closed at 190 basis point bid, 185 basis point offer. Spreads firmed early on Wednesday after an S&amp;P ratings affirmation late on Tuesday, one trader said, but the paper soon retreated to wider levels.</p>
<p>Time Warner Inc's debt faded in sympathy with the sector as it has for the week, dealers said. Most paper widened about two basis points, one trader said, including the 9.15 percent debentures due 2023 -- the debt closed at 158 basis point bid, 153 offer.  </p>
<p>Looking at new issues, ABN AMRO Bank issued $500 million in Aa3/single-A rated five year subordinated debt to yield 40 basis points over the U.S. Treasury curve. The deal was managed through ABN AMRO and Morgan Stanley &amp; Co Inc.</p>
<p>Tuesday's $200 million in Aa3/A-plus rated three year 6-1/4 percent notes from CIT Group Holdings Inc widened 10 basis points to 32 bid, 28 offer, one trader said. Several traders said the notes were priced too aggressively and the wider spread did not reflect market weakness.</p>
<p>The deal was priced via lead manager Smith Barney Inc.  </p>
<p>Future investment grade issuance is expected to include $500 million in A1/A-plus rated 30-year subordinated bank debt, priced via a CS First Boston Corp led syndicate. Price talk is between 76 and 79 basis points, sources said.</p>
<p>Also, Mirage Resorts is expected to price $200 million of a 10-year bullet via Goldman Sachs &amp; Co and CS First Boston.</p>
<p>In the high-yield market, prices sank as much as one point into mid-session as the Dow Jones Industrial Average posted more than 60 point losses. The broad market recovered late, traders said, and prices closed down 1/4 to 1/2 point.</p>
<p>The bonds of several U.K. cable companies not directly involved in Tuesday's British cable merger announcement, retreated from gains achieved in Tuesday's trade.</p>
<p>TeleWest, Diamond Cable and International Cabletel credits rose as much as four points on Tuesday in sympathy with companies such as Videotron Holdings and Bell Cablemedia which were involved in the merger, traders said.</p>
<p>Price fluctuations were exacerbated by light trade overall, dealer said.</p>
<p>--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
