<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135817" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CP Rail to sell 1,839 km of U.S. track.</title>
<headline>CP Rail to sell 1,839 km of U.S. track.</headline>
<text>
<p>CALGARY, Oct 23 (Reuter) Canadian Pacific Ltd unit Canadian Pacific Railway (CPR) said on Wednesday that it agreed to sell 1,839 km of rail lines and associated assets in the midwestern United States to the Washington Organization.</p>
<p>A CPR official said financial terms of the transaction with the Montana-based Washington Organization were still be discussed and were not divulged. The Washington Organization will create a new company, in which CPR will hold a minority interest, to operate the network.  </p>
<p>In a statement, CPR president and chief executive Robert Ritchie said the railway examined 15 bids for the track.</p>
<p>&quot;We've reached an agreement that will benefit not only the CPR and Washington, but employees, shippers and consumers in the region,&quot; Ritchie said.</p>
<p>For the Washington Organization, the new rail venture will complement the company's current rail presence in the Northwestern United States by providing access to a number of Midwest U.S. markets.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're bringing a talented management team, along with solid railway and business experience, to a region that greatly depends on efficient, well-managed rail transportation,&quot; said Montana industrialist Dennis Washington in a statement.</p>
<p>The proposed agreement calls for the CPR to sell an 826-km (513-mile) line between Chicago and Kansas City, including a branchline into southern Wisconsin, and 1,013 km (630 miles) of rail lines in northern Iowa and southern Minnesota.  As well, the CPR will sell some equipment, including freight cars, locomotives and track equipment to the new company.  </p>
<p>The principal routes the proposed joint-venture company will operate are from Chicago to Kansas City; Marquette to Sheldon, Iowa; Sabula, Iowa, to LaCrescent, Minn.; Mason City, Iowa, to Comus, Minn. (Twin Cities); Austin to Jackson, Minn.; and a branchline to Janesville, Wis.</p>
<p>Under the proposed agreement, the CPR will provide the new company with access to connecting carriers in Chicago and the Twin Cities.  As well, the CPR may provide the new operator with switching and access to intermodal facilities and terminal services in selected areas.  </p>
<p>The U.S. track sale is part of CPR's plan announced in August to rationalize 25 percent of its Canada/U.S. network.</p>
<p>The Washington Organization has worldwide interests in mining, construction and transportation including marine operations in both Canada and the United States as well as rail operations such as Montana Rail Link (MRL) and the Southern Railway of British Columbia.</p>
<p>MRL operates more than 1,440 km (900 route-miles) of high-density rail line in Montana, Idaho and Washington. -- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
