<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135867" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pakistan reform implementation key to rating - S&amp;P.</title>
<headline>Pakistan reform implementation key to rating - S&amp;P.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said Wednesday it would be watching how Pakistan implements its budget stabilization plan including an agricultural income tax to help it determine any changes in the country's credit rating.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is going to have to be much more aggressive in terms of putting in place the kinds of revenue mobilization measures that the agricultural income tax represents to push forward on tax reform in a way that actually brings results,&quot; Standard &amp; Poor's Director Guido Cipriani told Reuters.  </p>
<p>An apparent commitment from the provinces on the agricultural income tax, which had been a sticking point for years, seemed a positive step, Cipriani said.</p>
<p>&quot;From an equity and a political standpoint, it's very important to show that the landed classes are participating in the fiscal adjustment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cipriani said the agency would also be looking for further details of the economic package and signs of progress of Pakistan's relations with the Internatonal Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>S&amp;P maintains a B-plus rating on Pakistan's foreign currency debt. The outlook is stable.  </p>
<p>Pakistan unveiled an economic program on Tuesday that seeks to narrow its budget deficit by 40 billion rupees  through spending cuts and added taxes, including higher oil taxes and an agricultural income tax.</p>
<p>Shortly before the package was announced, Pakistan's central bank devalued the rupee 7.86 percent and raised its key repurchase (repo) discount rate to 20 percent per year from 17 percent.</p>
<p>The interest rate hike should attract back short term capital, or at least stem the recent exodus of funds, and bolster international reserves, Cipriani said.  </p>
<p>As S&amp;P awaits further details of the plan, Cipriani said the ratings agency will also observe how privatizations would be affected.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan has found itself in a tight corner and has been forced to introduce these types of budget measures halfway through the fiscal year because things were going significantly awry,&quot; Cipriani said.</p>
<p>An IMF team will arrive in Pakistan Thursday for an economic review that must be completed before the fund releases any further tranches of a stalled $600 million standby loan.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Pakistani opposition parties called for a nationwide general strike on Saturday to protest the package. One opposition leader charged that the central bank's action violated the constitution and should have been presented before the National Assembly (lower house) for approval.</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
