<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135939" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NL Industries suspends div on bleak forecast.</title>
<headline>NL Industries suspends div on bleak forecast.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NL Industries Inc said Wednesday that a continuing decline in prices for titanium dioxide pigments is likely to result in a fourth quarter loss, prompting it to suspend the regular quarterly dividend.</p>
<p>The company said the outlook for titanium dioxide pigments pricing remains bleak.</p>
<p>Average selling prices for the pigments for this year's third quarter were 15 percent below prices in the same period in the prior year, and 6 percent lower than in this year's second quarter.  </p>
<p>The company said it expects average prices in the fourth quarter to be &quot;somewhat below&quot; the third quarter average. Although prices have dropped, demand for titanium dioxide pigments has continued to grow, it said.</p>
<p>The company had set a dividend of $0.10 per share for shareholders of record on September 16, payable September 30.</p>
<p>In this year's third quarter, the company reported a net loss of $4.2 million, or $0.08 per share, compared with a net profit of $17.4 million, or $0.34 per share, in the prior year's third quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
