<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135916" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADR REPORT - Latam ADRs fall on peso, politics.</title>
<headline>ADR REPORT - Latam ADRs fall on peso, politics.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin American shares fell on Wednesday on worries about the Mexican peso and Argentine political concerns, traders said.</p>
<p>Luxury goods makers also saw share prices soften as American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) largely followed the New York markets lower.</p>
<p>One trader in Latin ADRs said, &quot;There is only bad news, and no news to be buying on. The whole market is focusing on the peso.&quot;  </p>
<p>The peso was battered on spot markets amid a speculative onslaught by Mexican and foreign investors. The benchmark 48-hour peso opened 8.5 centavos weaker at 7.8650/7.8750 a dollar.</p>
<p>The currency also was hit by comments from Massachusetts Institute of Technology economist Rudiger Dornbusch. In a newspaper interview, Dornbusch said the peso should be 20 percent lower than at current levels, or nine pesos to the dollar.</p>
<p>Among Mexican ADRs, Telefonos de Mexico S.A. was off 1/8 to 30-5/8 in early trade.  </p>
<p>Argentine shares also were hit by continuing allegations of corruption made by former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo against President Carlos Menem. Telefonica de Argentina was off 1/8 to 22-1/2.</p>
<p>In Brazil, state telecommunications company Telebras fell 1-1/8 to 76-7/8 on speculation the company would report nine-month earnings below expectations.</p>
<p>Brazilian shares also were hurt by Senate passage of a measure that would impose a 0.2 percent tax on financial transactions.  </p>
<p>Luxury and brand-name retail stocks softened, with Fila Holdings SpA off 1-7/8 to 81-1/2 and Gucci Group NV off 5/8 to 73-1/8. Traders said the sector had lost some luster after strong interest early this year.</p>
<p>British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc fell 3-3/4 to 61-1/8 after Tuesday's cable merger involving Cable &amp; Wireless Plc and a negative ruling from Britain's telecommunications regulator.</p>
<p>Among 441 selected ADR stocks, 159 had declined and 72 advanced by late morning. Volume was 23 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Ian Simpson, Wall Street desk, (212) 859-1879</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
