<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135995" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pacific Intertie DC line seen down for more tests.</title>
<headline>Pacific Intertie DC line seen down for more tests.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The DC (direct current) segment of the Pacific Intertie will be taken out of service for additional testing sometime within the next few days, a spokesman for the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power (LADWP) said Wednesday.</p>
<p>LADWP operates the substation at the California end of the line, which runs from the California-Oregon border.</p>
<p>The Bonneville Power Administration, which operates the Northwest portions of the Intertie, also said additional tests are likely, although the line is still officially scheduled to ramp up to 2,200 megawatts (MW) early Thursday morning.</p>
<p>The line returned to around 1,080 MW on Sunday night after being shut since mid-October for annual maintenance.</p>
<p>After the latest round of studies, the DC line is expected to stay capped near 2,000 MW, compared with full capacity of 3,200, due to voltage support concerns following a major power outage in early August.</p>
<p>The Intertie's 4,800 AC (alternating current) line is also running at a reduced rate of 3,200 MW because of outage-related considerations.</p>
<p>--D Beasley, Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
