<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135966" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMP sees pressures on Q4, consolidation.</title>
<headline>AMP sees pressures on Q4, consolidation.</headline>
<dateline>HARRISBURG, Pa. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMP Inc said on Wednesday that &quot;significant price erosion&quot; personal computers and communications has taken a greater than expected toll on its gross margins, exerting pressure that will probably continue into the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The company said that prognosis may ultimately lead to consolidation of some of its underperforming businesses and &quot;more aggressive improvement of manufacturing efficiencies to better realign our costs with revenues,&quot; AMP Chief Executive and President William Hudson said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Hudson said that going into the year, the company expected sales growth to be &quot;rather modest&quot; in the first part of the year before strengthening in the second half.</p>
<p>However, key industries, such as personal computer and communications areas softened, serving as a drag on automotive and consumer/commercial segments that were deemed &quot;strong.&quot;</p>
<p>The 1996 fiscal year year, he said, &quot;has turned out to be an exceptionally challenging experience.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to take decisive actions to reduce manufacturing costs and cut expenses to align more realistically with actual sales,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, it is clear we must increase our efforts to both accelerate growth and reduce costs and expenses to offset price reductions.&quot;</p>
<p>When the consolidation and cost cutting measures are implemented, &quot;the effects will increase 1997 financial returns and enhance the prospects of AMP to continue its leadership in global markets,&quot; Hudson said.</p>
<p>The company said it also is determined to expand geographically, diversify its product and market mix and make &quot;significant&quot; investment in research and development and engineering for new products and processes.  </p>
<p>For the third quarter, the company reported net income of $94.8 million, or $0.43 per share, compared with $110.7 million, or $0.51 per share, for the same period in the prior year.</p>
<p>AMP said the earnings per share of $0.43 were &quot;slightly below&quot; earlier expectations because of the greater than expected price erosion.</p>
<p>In mid-September, it had lowered expectations to between $0.45 and $0.50 per share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARRISBURG, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
