<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135959" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lamar files for 2.8 mln Class A shares.</title>
<headline>Lamar files for 2.8 mln Class A shares.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lamar Advertising Inc said it filed a registration with the Securities and Exchange Commission to sell up to 2.8 million Class A common shares.</p>
<p>Of the total, 2.2 million Class A common are being offered to the public by the company and 600,000 Class A common are being sold by certain stockholders, the filing said.</p>
<p>Concurrently with the stock sale, the company intends to offer $225 million senior subordinated notes due 2006, the filing said.  </p>
<p>The company and the selling shareholders have granted the underwriters an 30-day over-allotment option of up to 420,000 additional Class A common shares, the filing said.</p>
<p>The offering will be made through Smith Barney Inc, Alex. Brown &amp; Sons Inc and Prudential Securities Inc.</p>
<p>After the offering, outstanding Class A shares will total 17,526,615 common and outstanding Class B shares will total 13,467,965 common, the filing said.  </p>
<p>The company will use the proceeds for the payment of a portion of the purchase price payable in connection with pending acquitisions, the filing said.</p>
<p>Last month, the company entered into a stock purchase agreement with the shareholders of FKM Advertising Inc for a cash purchase price of $40 million.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Lamar agreed to acquire all of the assets of Outdoor East LP for $60 million in cash.  </p>
<p>Of the selling shareholders, 309,950 common shares are being offered by the Reilly Family Limited Partnership and 437,485 common shares are being sold by all the directors and executive officers as a group, the filing said.</p>
<p>Lamar Advertising, headquartered in Baton Rouge, La., is an owner and operator of outdoor advertising structures.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
