<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="135941" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSX says its Conrail offer is better.</title>
<headline>CSX says its Conrail offer is better.</headline>
<dateline>RICHMOND, Va. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSX Corp said on Wednesday that it believes its cash-and-stock merger offer for Conrail Inc is better than the rival bid made earlier today by Norfolk Southern Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;By every measure, the CSX-Conrail merger is superior in economic, operational and public policy terms to the Norfolk Southern non-bid,&quot; CSX said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;Norfolk Southern's hostile offer comes as no surprise,&quot; CSX said in a statement. &quot;It simply does not provide the same long-term value as the strategic CSX-Conrail partnership, which offers Conrail shareholders tax-free equity and the substantial upside potential that only comes from the benefits derived from the merger of CSX and Conrail.</p>
<p>The Norfolk Southern $100-per-share tender offer came just eight days after CSX agreed to acquire Conrial in a cash and stock deal valued at $8.4 billion, or about $92.50 a share.  </p>
<p>Norfolk Southern has also asked a federal court to block CSX's intial tender offer for Conrail and also a Conrail shareholders meeting set for November 14.</p>
<p>CSX said that Norfolk Southern's &quot;highly conditional non-bid&quot; would inevitably face serious delay and could not be completed without the approval of the Conrail board.</p>
<p>It added that the provisions of the CSX-Conrail merger agreement specifically preclude in effect the Conrail board of directors' approval of any competing offers before mid-April 1997. It said the CSX cash tender offer would close in November 1996.</p>
<p>It said certain delays involved in the Norfolk Southern offer &quot;severely and negatively impact the present value of its proposal.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Using a customary discount rate of two percent per month, the Norfolk Southern non-bid is worth less than $90 per Conrail share, far less than Norfolk Southern would have Conrail shareholders believe,&quot; CSX said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHMOND, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
