<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136034" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Midwest Express Q3 results set record.</title>
<headline>Midwest Express Q3 results set record.</headline>
<dateline>MILWAUKEE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Midwest Express Holdings Inc said Wednesday it reported its best-ever results in the third quarter, with record earnings for its Midwest Express Airlines and Astral Aviation, which does business as Skyway Airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;We experienced record passenger traffic and continued strong revenue yields in the third quarter,&quot; said Timothy Hoeksema, chairman, said in a statement. &quot;Traffic increased 13 percent and capacity 17 percent. And equally important, our yield increased 6 percent system-wide.&quot;</p>
<p>Midwest Express earned $1.31 in the third quarter, up from $0.93 a year ago after $0.13 in non-recurring costs.  </p>
<p>Increased aircraft fuel costs, Midwest Express' second largest expense , cut operating income $2.3 million in the quarter and $6.0 million year-to-date.</p>
<p>The company's cost per available seat mile increased 3.8 percent quarter over quarter, primarily as a result of the increased fuel costs. However, the cost per seat mile was four percent lower than in the second quarter, mainly due to efficiencies realized through increased capacity.</p>
<p>In September, Midwest Express Airlines placed an additional jet aircraft into scheduled service, resulting in new nonstop service between Kansas City and Boston, and between Kansas City and Omaha.</p>
<p>Also, Astral Aviation added nonstop turboprop service between Kansas City and Omaha, the company said.</p>
<p>Midwest Express said its 23rd jet will enter service in late 1996 and will be used in place of aircraft going off-line for routine heavy maintenance.</p>
<p>Three DC-9 aircraft acquired this year will go into service during 1997 after maintenance and other work. Midwest Express did not say how it will utilize those aircraft.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILWAUKEE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
