<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136025" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/PHLX wins with Conrail, EDS.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/PHLX wins with Conrail, EDS.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philadelphia Stock Exchange (PHLX) had some of the busiest options Wednesday as a result of its listings of options on stocks with the biggest moves and the most trading.</p>
<p>Conrail Inc was the net gain leader in New York Stock Exchange trading, climbing 11-1/8 to 95-5/89 by 1445 CDT (1945 GMT). More than 5.6 million shares traded on the NYSE, making it third most active.</p>
<p>On the flip side, Electronic Data Systems Corp tumbled 11-1/2 to 48 on NYSE volume of more than 9.6 million shares. Consolidated volume topped 11 million shares.  </p>
<p>Conrail had by far the most active options on the PHLX, with most of the action on the call side seen in newly listed options at the 95 and 100 strike prices.</p>
<p>The Conrail December 100 call was most active and traded more than 4,500 contracts. The option was newly listed and was trading at 1-5/16.</p>
<p>Other active Conrail options included the newly listed November 100 call, which traded about 2,700, the November 95 call, also a new issue, which traded about 2,360 contracts, and the new December 95 call, which traded 2,265.  </p>
<p>The Conrail December 90 put was the most active put, with more than 3,400 contracts changing hands. Its open interest was 260 and it lost 6-1/8 to 1-3/4.</p>
<p>Other active puts included the December 95, the January 85 and the January 90.</p>
<p>Conrail rallied after Norfolk Southern Corp offered $100 per share all cash for Conrail, topping a roughly $92.50 per share cash and stock bid from CSX Corp.</p>
<p>EDS shares fell dramatically after the company reported third quarter earnings of $0.55 a share compared with $0.51 a share in the year ago period.  </p>
<p>EDS chief financial officer Jody Grant later told Reuters he was puzzled by the stock's decline and attributed it to market volatility.</p>
<p>Most EDS options activity was on the call side, led by the December 50, which traded about 2,200 contracts. The December 65 call traded 2,100 and the November 55 call traded 1,600.</p>
<p>Among the puts, the December 45 was most active, with about 525 contracts changing hands.</p>
<p>The most active option overall was a Long Term Equity Anticipation Security (LEAPS) in Alza Corp traded on the Pacific Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>The Alza January 1998 35 put traded 10,000 contracts. The trade was done in two blocks of 5,000.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz at Oppenheimer &amp; Co said the activity could have been a LEAP married put.</p>
<p>&quot;I would venture to say no one buys that many in the money LEAPS with the expectation the stock is going down precipitously,&quot; he said. &quot;Usually they're doing it for a long-term limited risk situation.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the risk of holding the option in conjunction with the stock was only 7/8 of a point for the 451 days remaining until the option expires.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
