<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136037" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures end mixed, yen expands losses.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures end mixed, yen expands losses.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures closed mixed, with yen contracts widening losses in reaction to a wire-service story that contributed to ideas the U.S.-Japan trade gap would continue to narrow, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>An unnamed U.S. administration official was quoted as saying that the U.S. dollar's strength was not enough to outweigh the postive factors that will support U.S.-Japan trade.</p>
<p>December yen sank to a contract low of $0.008906, compared to the old contract high which was set on GLOBEX at $0.008912. December fell through support at $0.008911, or 113.05 spot.  </p>
<p>Most traders and analysts believe it is a matter of time before December yen tests $0.008877, which corresponds to the next major upside dollar/yen objective of 113.50 spot.</p>
<p>Yen's slide dampened the short-term bullish sentiment seen in the Swiss franc and mark pits all morning. One U.S. firm sold 400 December Swiss franc futures, helping push the contract to the daily low of $0.8007, as the dollar/Swiss franc rose above 1.2530 spot.</p>
<p>Bundesbank vice president Wilhelm Gaddum's comments that current economic conditions and M3 money supply data indicated that present German interest rates were correct.  </p>
<p>Gaddum's comments reinforced Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing's statements overnight, and supported mark futures in the midst of the breakdown in Swiss franc futures, they said.</p>
<p>The comments swept away any concerns of an imminent German rate cut, and continued to lift the cash mark/yen cross in the afternoon.</p>
<p>However, activity on the floor was most apparent in the Mexican peso and Canadian dollar pits, traders said.</p>
<p>Several major firms were each seen placing orders in the exchange's all-or-nothing peso pit.  </p>
<p>&quot;Anytime the Canadian dollar sells off, you get considerable buying which is indicative of how bullish sentiment is right now,&quot; Katherine Beattie, a currency analyst at MMS International, said.</p>
<p>She is looking for December to test $0.7478, or 1.3410 spot, and possibly the $0.7515 to $0.7530 area, or 1.3330 to 1.3345 spot.</p>
<p>At the close, December yen was down $0.000052 at $0.008914, marks were up $0.0012 at $0.6595, Swiss francs fell $0.0001 at $0.8024, sterling down $0.0014 at $1.5964, Can dollars rose $0.0011 at $0.7466 and pesos off $0.000675 at $0.122750.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
