<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136032" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Atlantic Energy sees Q3 charges.</title>
<headline>Atlantic Energy sees Q3 charges.</headline>
<dateline>EGG HARBOR TOWNSHIP, N.J. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atlantic Energy said Wednesday it expects third quarter net income to be reduced by a $5.7 million or $0.11 per share charge for three settlements related to the Salem Nuclear Generating station.  </p>
<p>The company said the charge results from rate settlements its Atlantic Electric subsidiary reached on Tuesday with the New Jersey Division of the Ratepayer Advocate and the Staff of the New Jersey Board of Public Utilities.</p>
<p>These concerned the board's investigation into the continuing outage of the Salem Nuclear Generating Station, the recovery of capacity costs associated with power purchases from cogenerators and other power purchasers and a 1994 Salem Nuclear Generating Station outage.  </p>
<p>The utility's replacement power costs for the current outage for each unit, up to the scheduled return-to-service dates, will be recoverable in it's next annual levelized energy clause proceeding. In stipulating provisional 1996/1997 rates in July, these replacement power costs were estimated at $27.8 million and will continue to be deferred until the utility's next energy clause proceeding.</p>
<p>Replacement power costs incurred after the scheduled return-to-service dates will not be recoverable in rates, the company said, noting such costs are about $700,000 per month per unit.  </p>
<p>The company said it agreed to provide credits to customers totaling $12 million during the months of January and February 1997 based on customer usage between January 1, 1996 through October 31, 1996. These amounts, net of previously accrued costs, make up the charge, it said.</p>
<p>Atlantic Energy said the parties agree that the scheduled return-to-service date for Salem Unit 1 is June 30, 1997 and the scheduled return-to-service date for Salem Unit 2 is December 31, 1996.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, Salem operator Public Service Electric &amp; Gas Co said unit 2 is not expected to be in full operation until some time in 1997.</p>
<p>If litigation with the Public Service Enterprise Group Inc subsidiary results in a recovery of damages related to the outage, the first $8 million Atlantic Electric recovers will not be subject to any claim on behalf of its customers. Any claim in excess of $8 million may be addressed in later proceedings, the company said.</p>
<p>The settlement means Salem will not be included in the calculation of any penalty under state performance standards.  </p>
<p>The parties have also agreed there will be no penalty or reward under the nuclear performance standard for the years 1995 and 1996. Atlantic Electric reported an after tax nuclear performance penalty of $845,000 in 1995 and has accrued $1.9 million through September 30. It said these amounts would be offset against the settlement amount.</p>
<p>The agreement also covers the double recovery of capacity costs from non-utility generation projects alleged by the Ratepayer Advocate, Atlantic Energy said.</p>
<p>The Ratepayer Advocate had claimed Atlantic Electric's over-recovery the four years through May 1995 was $38.3 million. The utility had disputed this claim and agreed to provide credits of $1.0 million in settlement of the claim.</p>
<p>In March 1996, the company sought a $49.7 million increase in annual energy clause revenues. Under a stipulation dated July 12, it implemented provisional rates resulting in an increase of $27.6 million a year and agreed to defer replacement power costs associated with a 1994 Salem outage.</p>
<p>The amount deferred, $1.74 million, shall be fully recoverable through Atlantic Electric's next energy clause proceeding, it said.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EGG HARBOR TOWNSHIP, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
