<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136021" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow ends well off lows as high-techs rebound.</title>
<headline>Dow ends well off lows as high-techs rebound.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. blue chips extended their fall to a third consecutive session but losses were more than halved as the hemorrhaging in high-techs abated.</p>
<p>&quot;The techs are looking strong as we close out the day. Intel, Microsoft, Cisco and IBM have had very nice rebounds. The correction for techs in terms of time may go on for awhile but it's mostly over in terms of price,&quot; said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials lost 25 to about 6036 after tumbling nearly 70 points earlier in the session.  </p>
<p>The blue chip index lost 33 points over the past two trading sessions.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the tech-studded Nasdaq Composite surged eight to about 1228 after falling 22 points on Monday and Tuesday. IBM rose 2-1/8 to 129-1/8, Intel added 3-7/8 to 109-3/8, Cisco was up 1-5/8 to 62-7/8 and Microsoft rose 2-1/8 to 129-1/8.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 was fractionally higher at 707. Losers beat gainers 6-5 on heavy NYSE volume of about 439 million shares.</p>
<p>Canelo attributed early stiff selling to &quot;profit-taking after earnings, good or bad, some concerns about the dollar and (the possible) GOP (loss of the) the House&quot; in the upcoming elections.  </p>
<p>Thom Brown, a managing director of Rutherford Brown and Catherwood, said, &quot;EDS was the story of the day. There was a gross overreaction to their news. The market is most punishing when it comes to any doubts about the outlook. At EDS the big question was slowing orders from the federal government.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares of the computer services provider lost 11-1/2 points or 19 percent to 48 and topped the NYSE actives list. EDS said slack orders and lower government spending will pressure its growth in the fourth quarter. It said an EDS customer filed for Chapter 11 on October 15. Computer Sciences, EDS's chief rival, lost 2-1/4 to 77-5/8.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's an instant reaction to news and an obsession with 'What are they going to do this quarter?' There's no long-term outlook left, especially with so many momentum funds in here. It really creates the impression that they're operating in a giant gaming parlor down on Wall Street. It's not healthy,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Another major market feature was Conrail, which rallied 11-1/8 to 95-5/8 after Norfolk Southern launched a $100 per share cash offer for the company in a bid intended to derail CSX Corp's friendly $92.50 a share merger pact. CSX slipped 3/4 to 45-1/2 and Norfolk Southern lost 3/8 to 94-1/8.  </p>
<p>Conrail urged shareholders to take no immediate action on the latest offer and said its board has unanimously determined that the CSX bid is best.</p>
<p>The surge in Conrail shares helped catapult the Dow Jones Transportation Average up 30 points to 2153.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T lost two to 37-7/8. It ended weeks of speculation and named R.R. Donnelley &amp; Sons Chairman John Walter as president and chief operating officer and eventual successor to Robert Allen as chairman and chief executive. SBC Warburg downgraded AT&amp;T to hold from buy on the appointment, saying it had expected a &quot;fresh face with a well-known high tech resume.&quot;  </p>
<p>United Auto Group surged 4-7/8 to 34-7/8 in its Wall Street debut. The company operates franchised automotive and light truck dealerships and related businesses.</p>
<p>Another IPO, CyberMedia Inc, also drew interest and climbed 4-3/4 to 20-3/4. The company sells &quot;First Aid&quot; kits for personal computers, aimed at helping customers cut down on lengthy, frustrating calls to computer centers and helping PC companies to cut down on expensive technical support.</p>
<p>Boston Beer lost 3-3/8 to 12-5/8 after news its orders were lower than expected. Alex Brown downgraded the stock and Goldman Sachs removed the stock from its recommended list.  </p>
<p>Dean Witter downgraded the maker of Samuel Adams beer. Other microbrewery stocks also tumbled with Redhook Ale off 1-5/16 to 14-11/16, Pete's Brewing off 3/8 to 7-3/8, Pyramid Breweries off 1/4 to 5-1/2 and Nor'Wester Brewing off 5/8 to 4-1/8.</p>
<p>St. Jude Medical lost 1-1/4 to 37-3/8 and Ventritex added 15/16 to 21-9/16 after they agreed to merge Ventritex into St. Jude's PaceSetter subsidiary.</p>
<p>Netscape rallied 5-3/8 to 49-7/8 after reporting a jump in quarterly profits on Tuesday after the market closed.  </p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite rose 7.88 to 1227.88.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 index rose 0.70 to 707.27.</p>
<p>(Figures official as of 1645 EDT/2045 GMT)</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
