<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136067" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DuPont says 40 percent toward savings goal.</title>
<headline>DuPont says 40 percent toward savings goal.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>DuPont Co has achieved about 40 percent of $1 billion in cost cuts targeted for 1996-1997, but the relative contribution of cost cuts to profit growth will decline in the future, said John Himes, vice president for investor relations.</p>
<p>&quot;As we look forward obviously we're not going to have the kind of benefit from cost (savings) that we had in the last three or four years, but we still have in front of us an objective of taking an additional $1 billion of cost out over the '96-'97 time frame. We're about 40 percent of the way there,&quot; Himes told a telephone news conference.  </p>
<p>Himes said third quarter results released Wednesday probably reflected a one-to-two percent improvement in productivity on a sales basis.</p>
<p>He said DuPont hoped white-pigment prices were nearing bottom, and the company was seeing volume improvement in the key product, although the supply-demand balance was weak in Europe, Asia and South America.</p>
<p>Polyester sales were likely to rebound in the fourth quarter, with demand improving for polyester staple and filament plants recovering from third-quarter outages.  </p>
<p>Himes echoed previous indications by company officials that DuPont was on track for a record earnings year in 1996, after 10 consecutive record quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly with the very solid performance we had in the third quarter, it places us well on the track for a continued record performance in 1996, without question. I think we're feeling more confident that that's clearly the case,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>DuPont has earned $4.95 per share through the first three quarters of 1996, compared with $4.47 in the same period last year, when the company went on to earn a record $5.61 per share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
