<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136038" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. debt futures erase losses late, most end up.</title>
<headline>U.S. debt futures erase losses late, most end up.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. debt futures erased losses late, with most units endings in the plus column.</p>
<p>Traders in Treasury bond and Eurodollar futures tied the final leg upward to widespread but unconfirmed talk that the Federal Reserve was buying five-year Treasury notes for a customer that they said likely was a foreign central bank.</p>
<p>One floor broker noted talk the Fed was buying four-year paper, or old five-years, plus the current five year. Another also noted talk of buying in the two-year sector of the curve.</p>
<p>The rumors and move higher, magnified by thin trade, &quot;caught the market unaware,&quot; said a T-bond floor broker.  </p>
<p>Earlier, futures showed muted reaction when the five-year T-note sale produced results that traders said were in-line to slightly on the soft side of expectations.</p>
<p>The five-year note produced a high yield of 6.325 percent, close to forecasts for 6.32 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The rest of it was nasty,&quot; said one T-bond futures floor broke of the auction results.</p>
<p>He said the 2.33 bid/cover was low and the $326 million in non-competitive bids also was on the low end of expectations.</p>
<p>But the market also caught a bid on relief supply was out of the way, with attention now shifting to next week's data.  </p>
<p>Trading was light overall, with the short end mostly following the long bond, Eurodollar traders said.</p>
<p>One Eurodollar trader said the short end would likely remain rangebound until some definitive news emerges.</p>
<p>&quot;We came off the last couple days on profit-taking and supply concerns and that's been it,&quot; he said. &quot;People think the Fed's going to be on hold for the rest of the year, the election is already factored in and the only wildcard is if the Democrats can control Congress,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Overall, traders said, the short end should continue sideways trading near term.  </p>
<p>Traders said the late recovery in Euros and December T-bonds produced no great change in sentiment, but said a positive tone could prevail Thursday.</p>
<p>December T-bonds finished up 7/32 to 110-27/32, 10-year notes rose 2/32 to 108-11/32, muni-bonds gained 20/32 to 114-19/32 and March Eurodollars ended flat at 94.29. March T-bills lost one basis point to 94.80. -Derivatives Desk(312)408-8750/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
