<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136068" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - Norfolk Southern's lawsuit.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Norfolk Southern's lawsuit.</headline>
<byline>Randall Mikkelsen</byline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norfolk Southern Corp asked a federal court to block CSX Corp's initial tender offer for 19.9 percent of Conrail shares, and to block a Conrail shareholders' meeting set for Nov 14 to facilitate a proposed merger of CSX and Conrail.</p>
<p>Norfolk Southern also asked in a suit filed in U.S. District Court for Eastern Pennsylvania that the court declare that the merger violates Pennsylvania and U.S. law.  </p>
<p>Norfolk Southern also said in the suit that it would seek to replace Conrail's board of directors at the company's annual meeting on May 21, 1997, and asked that the court declare it had the right to do so under Conrail's charter.</p>
<p>&quot;This action arises from the attempt by ... Conrail, its directors and ... CSX to coerce, mislead and fraudulently manipulate Conrail's shareholders to swiftly deliver control of Conrail to CSX and to forestall any competing bid for Conrail by ... Norfolk Southern Corporation,&quot; Norfolk Southern alleged in the suit.  </p>
<p>A Conrail spokesman said the company had no immediate comment on the suit. Conrail said earlier it would review Norfolk Southern's $100 per share cash bid for Conrail, but that it had already determined a merger with CSX was in the company's best interests.</p>
<p>In the suit, Norfolk Southern said Conrail had rejected a 1994 offer of a 1.1-to-1 stock swap merger that would have been worth $101 per share on Oct 14, 1996, the day before announcement of the CSX merger. The proposed CSX-Conrail merger is a  cash-and-stock transaction valued at $92.50 per share.  </p>
<p>Conrail rejected a renewed Norfolk Southern approach as recently as October 4, and therefore had to have known that higher offers than CSX's were available, the suit said.</p>
<p>It said after the merger was announced, CSX told Norfolk Southern the deal was &quot;bulletproof&quot; and Norfolk Southern could only negotiate for access to the rail system of the merged company.</p>
<p>Conrail rejected Norfolk Southern, in violation of the board's fiduciary duties, the suit alleged, to preserve the jobs of board members and top management.  </p>
<p>The suit said a $300 million break-up fee in the CSX-Conrail deal was excessive, as was a stock option &quot;lock-up&quot;, which it said imposed an increasingly severe disincentive to higher bids.</p>
<p>The lock-up provision entails a stock option awarded to CSX by Conrail allowing CSX to purchase nearly 16 million shares of Conrail stock at $92.50, and would enable CSX to receive cash for the difference in any higher successful bid for Conrail.  </p>
<p>It said the lock-up would dilute Norfolk Southern's stake in Conrail by $120 million if Norfolk Southern's cash bid of $100 per share for Conrail were successful, and by more if a higher bid were made.</p>
<p>Norfolk Southern said that although Conrail's board members serve staggered terms, the company's by-laws also allow for the replacement of the entire board at a single meeting.</p>
<p>It said it was asking the court to declare that interpretation valid.  </p>
<p>The suit challenged a provision in Conrail's &quot;poison pill&quot; anti-takeover plan requiring that any action to lift a poison pill must be approved by a majority of &quot;continuing directors&quot; on the board. It said continuing directors were incumbents or their chosen successors.</p>
<p>Such a provision violated Pennsylvania law by limiting the discretion of future boards, the suit said.  </p>
<p>The suit also alleged Conrail was using provisions in Pennsylvania's anti-takeover law in an illegally discriminatory manner. The provision requires that a company acquiring 20 percent of a Pennsylvania firm must acquire the rest of the shares for cash.</p>
<p>Conrail's board has endorsed waiving the provision for the CSX deal, and asked its shareholders to do so also at the November 14 meeting. But Conrail also has said it would not waive the provision except to facilitate the CSX offer.  </p>
<p>If that provision is accepted by shareholders, Norfolk Southern said, &quot;CSX will be in a position to acquire either effective or absolute control over Conrail.&quot;</p>
<p>It said CSX could accomplish this by raising the number of shares it was seeking through the tender offer and exercising the stock option Conrail gave it.</p>
<p>The suit alleged Conrail violated federal securities laws by filing federal documents containing misleading information about the deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
