<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136089" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Duramed sees $5 - $6 mln Q3 loss.</title>
<headline>Duramed sees $5 - $6 mln Q3 loss.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Duramed Pharmaceuticals Inc said on Wednesday it expected to report a loss of between $5 million and $6 million in the third quarter, before one-time charges related to its Hallmark Pharmaceuticals acquisition.</p>
<p>Duramed said the estimate included the impact of price erosion, $3.4 million in product development expense, a $500,000 reserve for possible uncollected funds owed by a large wholesale customer, and about $600,000 in continuing expenses.  </p>
<p>The First Call mean earnings estimate for fiscal 1996 was $0.01 per share. There was no estimate for the third quarter.</p>
<p>The company also said it believed the U.S. Food and Drug Administration review process for approval of its 0.625 milligram dosage of conjugated estrogens had been prolonged by a challenge from an innovator company.</p>
<p>Management said it expected the product would be approved by end 1996 and that the challenge was without merit.</p>
<p>Conjugated estrogens are used to relieve symptoms of menopause and osteoporosis, a Duramed spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on information recently made known to the company, we believe there is new momentum and a new commitment to closure on this important issue by the FDA,&quot; Thomas Arington, chairman and chief executive officer, said.</p>
<p>Duramed also said it was continuing its aggressive product development program.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
