<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136035" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends firmer but most gains pared.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends firmer but most gains pared.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper settled barely higher after losing most of the gains made early in a hesitant and relatively rangebound session.</p>
<p>Most active December rose to 93.90 cents, its highest since September 5 as LME three-months broke through a key upside technical barrier.</p>
<p>Once the technical picture improved, uncertainty surrounding the resurgent Sumitomo scandal encouraged some profit taking on the highs, Bette Raptopoulos of Prudential Securities said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless we are facing the potential for short-term supply tightness. Fabricators say they cannot get their hands quickly on material in the U.S. and in Europe,&quot; Raptopoulos said.</p>
<p>December COMEX ended 0.50 cent firmer at 92.95 cents per pound, traded 93.90 to 92.50 cents. Spot October went out 1.20 cents firmer at 96.90 cents.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 12,000 lots, compared to an official 9,028 lots on Tuesday. Switches on Wednesday totalled 1,122.</p>
<p>Union members at Kennecott Utah Copper Corp were voting Wednesday and Thursday on a new six-year labor deal.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected stocks at the LME warehouse in Long Beach to continue falling with one broker forecasting a dip of 15,000 to 20,000 tonnes over the coming few weeks.</p>
<p>The metal is going to three locations - the COMEX warehouse in Tucson, to consumers in the U.S. Midwest, and to the Far East, brokers said.</p>
<p>Long Beach holds 40,125 tonnes of copper, the largest concentration of LME copper stocks after Hamburg's 58,350 tones.</p>
<p>LME stocks total 159,350 tonnes, while COMEX stocks have been rising and reached 22,314 short tons Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
