<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136046" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AlliedSignal expects 15-17 pct yr growth.</title>
<headline>AlliedSignal expects 15-17 pct yr growth.</headline>
<byline>Lisa Marie Pane</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>AlliedSignal Inc Chief Executive Larry Bossidy said Wednesday that the company expects current fiscal year earnings growth between 15 percent and 17 percent.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the company had been projecting growth in the range of between 13 percent and 17 percent. The latest projection increases the lower range of possible growth.</p>
<p>While last year's results were driven largely by its materials business, this year's gains have been fueled by the aerospace unit, Bossidy said in a telephone interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are enthused because our revenues continue to grow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We think this year (earnings growth) will be close to 15 to 17 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>That prediction comes as the company matched First Call earnings estimates for the third quarter of $0.90 per share.</p>
<p>The company reported its third quarter results Wednesday, of net of $253 million, or $0.90 per share, compared with $217 million, or $0.77 per share, in the same period the prior year. The results represent a 17 percent increase in earnings.  </p>
<p>Sales in the aerospace area increased 12 percent to $1.45 billion compared with $1.289 billion during the 1995 third quarter.  Sales in its engineered materials division were up nine percent to $1.01 billion compared with $918 million in the same period the prior year.</p>
<p>Bossidy said he was confident of improved results in the automotive area since the company shed its braking business in April.  </p>
<p>The third quarter's results seemed to underscore that optimism. Including the braking business, automotive sales dropped 31 percent to $891 million compared with $1.29 billion in the prior year's third quarter.  Excluding the braking business, the company's automotive sales increased five percent, AlliedSignal said.</p>
<p>The sale, Bossidy said, &quot;takes away a business that we were having some difficulty with.  It leaves us in a better position.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Our automotive business is coming back nicely,&quot; he added. &quot;We don't see any significant drags&quot; from other segments, he said.</p>
<p>The company ended the 1995 fiscal year with net income of $875 million, or $3.09 per share, compared with net income of $759 million, or $2.68 per share for the 1994 fiscal year.</p>
<p>AlliedSignal manufactures aerospace and automotive products, chemicals, fibers, plastics and advanced materials.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk, 212 859-1709</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
