<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136044" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends mixed, spot December higher.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends mixed, spot December higher.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended mixed in volatile trade with the spot contract advancing amid persistent near-term supply jitters, traders said.</p>
<p>But a late round of speculative and local profit taking cut deeply into December's earlier gains and pushed the back months into negative territory, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market ran up so fast it hit a vacuum,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka. &quot;It got overbought and we saw some profit taking.&quot;</p>
<p>The December contract surged more than 5.00 cents a lb to peak at 122.75, before ending up 1.70, at 119.70, its highest settlement since August 26. The low was 116.50.</p>
<p>Second-month March finished 1.50 cents lower at 105.10, while the rest closed 0.10 to 1.75 weaker.</p>
<p>Spilka said tight near-term availability continued to benefit the December/March switch, which swelled to 14.20 cents compared with 11.00 cents at the close Tuesday.</p>
<p>A steep 80 percent drawdown in weekly certified stocks highlighted the supply woes, Spilka said. He added that delays in the Central American and Mexican coffee harvest due to heavy rains, and mounting worries about truckers' strike in Colombia contributed to concerns.</p>
<p>Traders said talk on the floor Wednesday about a possible end to the 10-day truckers' strike may have weighed on the market.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Colombian Interior Minister Horacio Serpa met with representatives of striking truck drivers in an effort to end the work stoppage.</p>
<p>There was no immediate word on the outcome of the talks, but truckers said they were hopeful about reaching a quick settlement.</p>
<p>The head of Colombia's National Coffee Growers Federation said Tuesday that the strike had paralyzed the nation's coffee industry and forced delays in the shipment of about 250,000 60-kilo bags of coffee promised for delivery in October.</p>
<p>Volume was heavy, at an estimated 13,922 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
