<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136053" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Anheuser-Busch sees double-digit EPS rise.</title>
<headline>Anheuser-Busch sees double-digit EPS rise.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS, Mo. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anheuser-Busch Cos Inc, which reported higher third quarter earnings, said it expects to meet its double-digit earnings per share growth target for the year.</p>
<p>Earlier, the brewer reported third quarter earnings of $0.74 per fully diluted share, which was in line with the First Call mean of analysts' estimates. A year ago, it earned $0.66 per fully diluted share from continuing operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Our focus is sharper than ever and we are confident of achieving our double-digit earnings per share growth objective for the year,&quot; August Busch III, chairman, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Anheuser-Busch said its beer sales volume set a record of 24.9 million barrels in the third quarter, up 660,000 barrels, or 2.7 percent, from a year ago.</p>
<p>Beer sales volume for the nine-month 1996 period was a record 70.0 million barrels, up 2.8 percent from 68.1 million barrels a year ago.</p>
<p>Anheuser-Busch said its market share for the nine-month period was 44.8 percent, up 0.7 share points compared with the nine-month 1995 period.</p>
<p>The company said its revenue per barrel for the 1996 year-to-date period was up about three percent.  </p>
<p>Anheuser said sales to retailers rose 2.4 percent for the nine-month period compared with a year ago. The gain was led by Bud Light, the second largest U.S. beer brand and the market leader in the light beer category. Bud Light continues to grow at an annualized double-digit pace.</p>
<p>Overall, the Bud brands saw a 2.1 percent increase in sales for the nine-month period.</p>
<p>The company said its wholesaler inventories, the lowest of all major brewers, remain well below last year's levels.</p>
<p>In October, Anheuser raised prices about three percent in seven states. As expected, the company said it plans to raise prices in the remainder of the country in February, 1997.</p>
<p>The company said its Busch Entertainment Corp theme park subsidiary was hurt by lower attendance due to hurricanes and the Summer Olympic Games in Atlanta. Busch Entertainment still expects to report a fifth consecutive year of record profits in 1996, it added.</p>
<p>Metal Container Corp, the can manufacturing unit, had lower profits for the nine-month period due to start-up costs for a new can plant in Mira Loma, Calif., and weaker can pricing in the soft drink market.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
