<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136031" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EDS Q4 base business rise may slow to single digit.</title>
<headline>EDS Q4 base business rise may slow to single digit.</headline>
<dateline>PLANO, Texas 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronic Data Systems Corp expects the growth of its base business, or non-General Motors Corp  business, to slow to low double digits or high single digits in the fourth quarter, Chief Financial Officer Jody Grant said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect growth to be low double digits to high single digits,&quot; Grant told Reuters, adding that the figures refer to the usually more dynamic sector of non-GM contracts which EDS calls its base business.</p>
<p>Growth in its base business grew 23.8 percent in the first three quarters of the year, Grant said.  </p>
<p>Grant said GM business has been stronger than anticipated so far this year and grew almost eight percent in the third quarter.</p>
<p>The company earlier reported a third quarter profit of $266.4 million, or $0.55 a share, up from $245.7 million or $0.51 share in the same period last year. Operating revenues increased 16.2 percent over year-ago levels to $3.6 billion.</p>
<p>But the stock price fell sharply after company warnings that revenue growth would slow sharply in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>EDS shares were down 12-5/8 to 46-7/8 on the New York Stock Exchange in afternoon trade.  </p>
<p>Grant said he was &quot;puzzled&quot; by the stock price drop and attributed it to market volatility.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems to have a knee-jerk reaction to every muscle twitch,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the expected fourth quarter decline in growth was in large part due to a drop in new business contracts signed in the first nine months of the year, but noted that the third quarter was much stronger than the previous two.</p>
<p>&quot;It was one of the better quarters we've experienced and .... gives us confidence looking ahead at 1997,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Grant said EDS' pipeline is strong and that he was confident of strong growth in 1997. &quot;There are a very large number of potential contracts in the pipeline,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said those potential contracts include nine worth over $1 billion each, 16 worth between $500 million and $1 billion and 100 priced at between $100 million and $500 million.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of total contract value, the pipeline is very full,&quot; he said. &quot;It is as robust and as big as we've seen it.&quot;</p>
<p>EDS, based in Plano, Texas, specializes in integrating information systems for governments and corporations. It was founded 34 years ago by billionaire Ross Perot, sold to GM in 1984 and then spun off again in June this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PLANO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
