<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136197" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tosco sees Q4 weakness, but to outdo peers.</title>
<headline>Tosco sees Q4 weakness, but to outdo peers.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tosco Corp, fresh from reporting a 33 percent expansion in third quarter earnings per share, said it is likely to weather a tough business environment in the fourth quarter better than its peers.</p>
<p>&quot;Industry conditions at the start of the fourth quarter have been weak so far,&quot; Tosco Chief Executive Thomas O'Malley said in a prepared statement.</p>
<p>&quot;High crude prices continue to put pressure on refining and retail margins.  However, Tosco's low cost structure and advantaged East and West Coast markets should allow us to continue to outperform our peers,&quot; O'Malley said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tosco's third quarter results were</p>
<p>very good given the mediocre to conditions the market gave us toward the end of the period,&quot; Tosco Chief Executive Thomas O'Malley said in a prepared statement, noting that weakness has extended to the fourth quarter.  </p>
<p>The company reported third quarter net income of $42.5 million or $0.95 a share on sales of $2.71 billion compared to net of 26.8 million or $0.72 a share on sales of 1.82 billion in the the 1995 third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Tosco's third quarter results were very good given the mediocre to conditions the market gave us toward the end of the period,&quot; Tosco Chief Executive Thomas O'Malley said in a prepared statement, noting that weakness has extended to the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>He noted that while both refining and retail profits were squeezed during the quarter, both sectors of its business had &quot;good results&quot; during the quarter.</p>
<p>Tosco is also raising its quarterly common stock dividend to $0.17 per share from $0.16 prior in a signal from its board of directors of satisfaction with past performance and optimism about strong results in the future, O'Malley said.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
