<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136172" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Waban to spin off BJ's Wholesale unit.</title>
<headline>Waban to spin off BJ's Wholesale unit.</headline>
<dateline>NATICK, Mass. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Waban Inc said Wednesday its board has approved a proposal to spin off BJ's Wholesale Club Inc to shareholders as a stock dividend.</p>
<p>The new company will be publicly traded and will apply for listing on the New York Stock Exchange, Waban said</p>
<p>In the proposed distribution, it said, stockholders will receive one share in the new BJ's corporation for each Waban share now held. The distribution will separate BJ's Wholesale Club, the company's food and general merchandise warehouse club business, from HomeBase, the company's home improvement warehouse business.</p>
<p>After the distribution, which is anticipated to be completed in the spring of 1997, Waban will change its name to HomeBase Inc and will continue to operate and develop the home improvement business, the company said.</p>
<p>The declaration of the special dividend has not yet occurred and is conditioned, among other things, upon receipt of a favorable ruling from the Internal Revenue Service as to the tax free status of the dividend, shareholder approval and the absence of orther circumstances, such as a change in market conditions, that would cause a change in the board's view. -- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NATICK, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
