<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136159" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rorer drops amid recall worries.</title>
<headline>Rorer drops amid recall worries.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc Rorer Inc fell in U.S. trading on Wednesday amid continued concern over the earnings impact of a plasma product recall.</p>
<p>&quot;There's some nervousness about whether or not the recalled products will make it back to market in a timely manner,&quot; Salomon Brothers analyst Robert Uhl said.</p>
<p>Rorer's shares were off 3-4/8 to 69-3/8 in early afternoon New York Stock Exchange trading.  </p>
<p>The U.S.-based drug arm of France's Rhone-Poulenc SA said its fourth quarter results would be impacted by lost sales of Albuminar and Plasma Plex products, which it said it did not expect to resume shipping before January.</p>
<p>The company on Wednesday said its third quarter earnings per share were reduced $0.17 due to the effect of a voluntary recall of the products by Centeon LLC, a joint venture with Hoechst AG.</p>
<p>It reported third quarter profits of $0.72 compared with pro forma earnings of $0.61 a year ago.  </p>
<p>Independent pharmaceutical industry analyst Hemant Shah said the earnings hit for the lost sales of the products could be $0.25 a share per quarter.</p>
<p>There are investor worries that the products' return to the market would be delayed beyond the fourth quarter. &quot;Those uncertainties are driving the stock down,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The joint venture announced the recall earlier this month citing precaution against risk of bacterial contamination due to vials cracked in transit.</p>
<p>At that time Rorer said the recall costs combined with potential lost sales could cut the consensus estimate for its 1996 earnings by 10 or 12 percent.</p>
<p>Estimates for its 1996 earnings at that time stood at $3.56 a share.</p>
<p>Analysts said Rorer's third quarter earnings per share number was in line with expectations.</p>
<p>Without the recall impact the company would have earned $0.89 a share. Uhl said he had a $0.90 estimate.</p>
<p>Analysts said the First Call consensus estimate for the third quarter of $0.80 was skewed by some estimates that included the recall impact and others that did not.</p>
<p>-- R. Jacobsen, 212-859-1733</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
