<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136127" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed to watch incipient inflation signs-McDonough.</title>
<headline>Fed to watch incipient inflation signs-McDonough.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Federal Reserve must remain vigilant about incipient signs of inflation since failure to contain price pressures at an early stage may prove costly to the economy later, Federal Reserve Bank of New York President William McDonough said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear that the failure to contain price inflation at its earliest stages makes it more difficult and costly to bring it under control later,&quot; McDonough said in a speech prepared for delivery before the Morris County Chamber of Commerce in Morristown, New Jersey. The remarks were also available in New York.  </p>
<p>McDonough, vice chairman of the Federal Open Market Committee, noted a current U.S. jobless &quot;around 5.0 percent,&quot; which analysts see as &quot;close to full employment&quot;, along with &quot;spot shortages of skilled labor.&quot; He also noted that &quot;Growth of wages has begun to increase somewhat recently, but in this era of global competition there remains some question as to whether that necessarily is a harbinger of a faster pace of price inflation&quot;</p>
<p>He said &quot;Recent experience suggests that it is difficult to identify with any precision the so-called 'natural rate' of unemployment associated with intensified inflationary pressures.&quot;  </p>
<p>The New York Fed president, while expressing satisfaction over the good inflation performance in the sixth year of U.S. expansion, warned against complacency.</p>
<p>&quot;I disagree with those who feel the current behavior of prices means we can ignore signs of intensified use of labor and capital resources,&quot; McDonough said.</p>
<p>&quot;While high rates of resource utilization may not immediately result in inflation, most economists believe that it will lead to accelerating price increases in time,&quot; he added. &quot;Thus, the Fed must remain vigilant with regard to incipient signs of inflation.&quot;  </p>
<p>McDonough expressed &quot;frustration&quot; over the fact the U.S. economy has failed to score solid productivity gains.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy's long-run potential growth rate is substantially lower than it was in the 1960s, or even the 1970s,&quot; he said. &quot;More important, the gains in labor productivity continue to be disappointing.&quot;</p>
<p>McDonough stressed the United States cannot &quot;just wait for some high-technology miracle to generate higher growth,&quot; and &quot;must do more to raise the overall level of savings in our economy so that we can finance more investments in physical and human capital, as well as public infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>The New York Fed president further saw &quot;the potential for some moderation in U.S. economic growth in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Isabelle Clary, 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
