<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136149" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clover grants proxy in Calif.Microwave vote.</title>
<headline>Clover grants proxy in Calif.Microwave vote.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clover Capital Management Inc, a large shareholder in California Microwave Inc, said Wednesday it granted three men a revocable proxy to vote at the company's annual meeting on October 25.</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Clover said on October 21 it granted Herbert Denton, Fredrick Whitridge Jr and Terry Ward the proxy to vote cumulatively for Ward and Whitridge on a number of issue.</p>
<p>Clover said the proxy would be used to elect its choice for directors of the company and to vote against the approval of an amendment to the company's employee stock purchase plan.  </p>
<p>The proxy will also be used to vote against the ratification of the selection of Ernst &amp; Young LLP as independent public accountants for the company.</p>
<p>Neither Ward nor Whitridge were recommended by California's board for election at the annual meeting, the filing said.</p>
<p>Clover holds a 7.5 percent stake in California Microwave or 1,214,250 common shares. In its latest transactions, Clover sold 3,750 common shares between Sept 25 and Oct 14 at prices ranging from $13.125 to $14.9375 per share.</p>
<p>California Microwave, based in Redwood City, Calif., supplies microwave radios and other telecommunications products to satellite systems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
