<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136280" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ldn dry cargo freight rates firm, Panamaxes lead.</title>
<headline>Ldn dry cargo freight rates firm, Panamaxes lead.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Firm conditions prevailed in the freight market on Wednesday, again led by improvements in rates for Panamaxes.</p>
<p>The BFI rose by 22 points to 1221 with panellists once again marking up all Panamax routes, especially in the Atlantic. An encouraging sign for owners was continued interest by charterers in short period business with some sharp gains scored for 4-6 month timecharters in particular. Some brokers said Caper enquiry was looking more promising in the Pacific, although Atlantic conditions have yet to see any real improvement in demand from minerals charterers.</p>
<p>Handy sizes are in short supply in the North Atlantic but elsewhere these vessels are struggling to find profitable employment.</p>
<p>GRAIN</p>
<p>Caper involvement in the grain trades was reported with Soufflet's fixture of 90,000 barley Hamburg-Rotterdam range/Jeddah for October shipment at $16.00 basis 2-1, possibly flag Mersinidi 123,034 dwt, and Commander 123,180 dwt for Mississippi/Continent for mid-November at a lumpsum equivalent of about $12.00 basis heavy grain, possibly for account of Cargill.</p>
<p>Some relatively cheap Panamax fixtures were seen in the US Gulf/Far East trades: Tradigrain fixed a 1970-built Chinese vessel with 50,000 heavy grain to N China for early Nov loading at $21.25 and Andre were linked with Bontrader for similar business at $20.50. But Glencore paid a firmer $13.00 or 13.25 for the 1974-built Vernal Spirit for 50,000 soyabeans from US Gulf to Ghent for end Oct.</p>
<p>Timecharter business was very steady with Captain John L 64,584, for example, fixed by Klaveness delivery prompt Porto Vesme for 4-6 months redelivery Atlantic at $9,000 daily and Olympic Galaxy 64,000 dwt believed to be working closely with NSAC delivery Passero Oct 25 trip via US Gulf to Taiwan at $11,750 daily. The 1972-built Magnum 68,000 dwt was rumoured fully fixed to Continental Charters for 6-8 months at $6,000 daily.</p>
<p>Report spoke of considerable Chinese activity in the North Pacific grain trades with a number of Panamaxes under offer for November loading. Handy-size business in the Atlantic included Andre's fixture on subjects of 25,000 wheat Rouen/Port Sudan at about $25.50/26.00 and CNAN's timecharter of a 22,000 dwt vessel delivery Continent or West Med for a trip via US Gulf to Algeria at about $5,750 daily. Fresh grain enquiry included Continental with up to 2m cft hss and SBM Mississippi/Jeddah for prompt/early Nov, Andre 30/34,000 dwt delivery US Gulf Nov 8/12 for 6-9 months redelivery Atlantic, Cargill 16/17,000 wheat Duluth/Guayaquil for 1/10 Nov, 15/19,500 corn Mississippi/ Buenaventura for Nov 1/15, 20,000 hss US Gulf/Guaymas for Nov 1/10 and 1m cft S Brazil/Lisbon-Hamburg, Glencore 18,000 hss Lakes/Sete for Nov 10/20, and Toepfer 22,000 wheat Immingham/Spanish Med for Oct 30/Nov 8.</p>
<p>MINERALS</p>
<p>There were many rumours of Caper fixtures but few were confirmed. Cockerill fixed 100,000 ironore Seven Islands /Antwerp and Catherine venture 132,016 dwt open prompt Continent and Mega Hill 118,000 dwt open since early Nov were both understood to be covered on private terms. S G China 179,872 dwt was believed booked for ironore from PDM to Taranto by Ilva or Sidermar. Nafsika M 162,458 dwt open spot Gibraltar was fixed yesterday and failed on subjects. Bocimar took Wah Shan 149,507 dwt delivery Kaohsiung for a BHP cargo from Australia to Continent/Med on private terms.</p>
<p>In Panamaxes there was further evidence of period business - Seatrans fixed space 69,000 dwt delivery Japan Nov 5/15 for 12 months at close to $8,400 daily (believed finalized last week), and BTG booked Endeavour 71,200 dwt delivery Far East Nov 10/20 for 4-6 months at a firm rate reported to be either $9,800 or $10,250 daily (first leg is understood as Bunbury/St Lawrence breaking IWL). Guinomar have fixed an early 1980's Panamax for 1 option 1 Kamsar/San Ciprian bauxite rounds at about $9,200.</p>
<p>HANDIES</p>
<p>The North Atlantic is firm with Italian and Danish charterers said to be busy in the period market. In the Far East market conditions were quieter but Showa chartered a 33,000 dwt geared bulker delivery Singapore trip Japan at $6,000 daily and Navix booked a 43,000 dwt vessel Kalimantan/Japan on private terms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
