<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136296" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK keeps industry guessing on air alliance.</title>
<headline>UK keeps industry guessing on air alliance.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Trade Secretary Ian Lang is not expected to say until at least next week whether he will approve British Airways' proposed alliance with American Airlines, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lang is due to give his ruling, along with the findings of a three-month investigation by the Office of Fair Trading (OFT), on whether or not the controversial deal should be referred to the Monopolies and Mergers Commission (MMC).</p>
<p>Industry sources said the issue clearly had been delayed. While some said that showed Lang was unsure whether to allow the deal to go through, others thought it might be a simple procedural complication.</p>
<p>&quot;There are less leaks on this than anything in history,&quot; said one interested party.</p>
<p>The Department of Trade and Industry routinely declines to say when the minister might make an announcement, pointing out there is no formal timetable for vetting such deals.</p>
<p>Industry and media reports have speculated that Lang is most likely to give the alliance qualified clearance, provided BA's home hub of London&quot;s Heathrow Airport is opened to competition.</p>
<p>However, opponents such as British long-haul operator Virgin Atlantic hope he will impose such onerous conditions that the deal will never get off the ground.</p>
<p>BA and American's plans have attracted fierce criticism from Virgin and several U.S. airlines, including BA's estranged U.S. partner USAir. They and some consumer groups argue the alliance would dominate the trans-Atlantic market.</p>
<p>Under the alliance, BA intends to coordinate its 244 flights a week from Britain to 22 U.S. destinations with American's 238 flights a week from seven U.S. airports to 12 European cities.</p>
<p>They would also combine their frequent flyer programmes and share flight booking codes to promote connecting flights on computer reservation systems.</p>
<p>BA and American argue the deal would lead to greater competition on transatlantic routes because it would only go ahead if Britain and the U.S. allowed more airlines to compete in the market by agreeing an &quot;open skies&quot; aviation trade pact.</p>
<p>At the same time they say they must be allowed to combine to compete in the wider market against rival alliances, such as that between United Airlines and Germany's Lufthansa, for important transfer traffic.</p>
<p>British clearance for the deal would still leave BA and American with the task of winning approval from the U.S. government. This, in turn, is conditional on Britain agreeing to create an &quot;open skies&quot; transatlantic air market.</p>
<p>BA and American had hoped their deal would break the deadlock in government negotiations on open skies, which have dragged on for the last five years.</p>
<p>Talks broke down again in August, although there has been strong industry speculation they might restart, depending on what the British government has to say in its competition review of the BA/American alliance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
