<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136298" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IBCA removes Credit Immobilier rating from watch.</title>
<headline>IBCA removes Credit Immobilier rating from watch.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IBCA, the European rating agency, said on Wednesday it had removed the long-term rating of both Credit Immobilier de France group (CIF) and the group's main issuing vehicle, Caisse Centrale de Credit Immobilier de France (3CIF), from ratingwatch.</p>
<p>IBCA said it comfirmed the CIF and 3CIF AA minus long-term and A1 short-term ratings.  </p>
<p>IBCA also said it confirmed CIF and 3CIF individual rating of B and legal rating of 2.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of CIF's recent offer to take over both the management of Credit Foncier de France's (CFF) 110 billion French franc portfolio of prets aides a l'accession a la propriete (PAP) loans and to acquire 1,500 staff from CFF, the long-term ratings of CIF and 3CIF were placed on ratingwatch with negative implications in July of this year,&quot; IBCA said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is now IBCA's opinion that if the terms and the cost of the operation remain in line with those currently proposed, CIF's financial strength will not be greatly affected, at least in the shorter term,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The agency therefore reaffirmed CIF's and 3CIF's ratings as above.</p>
<p>&quot;CIF continues to enjoy a high level of profitability and a healthy equity base in relation to other French banking groups,&quot; IBCA said.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, the scale of the proposed take-over of part of the CFF business is considerable; CIF's loan book currently totals some 120 billion French francs and the group has about 2,800 staff. Furthermore, the terms of the restructuring of CFF, which has been delayed, may change.&quot;</p>
<p>IBCA said it would continue to monitor the impact of any new developments on CIF, particularly those regarding the integration of CFF's personnel.</p>
<p>--International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 4041</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
