<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136243" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyd's under pressure to review service structure.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's under pressure to review service structure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Lloyd's of London insurance market, which has just emerged from a crisis that threatened to bankrupt it, is coming under growing pressure to cut costs and increase accountability in the internal services it provides.</p>
<p>Lloyd's head of strategy Nick Prettejohn said on Wednesday that it was difficult to measure the commercial performance of the &quot;corporation,&quot; which is facing increased scrutiny amid intensifying competition in the insurance industry worlwide.</p>
<p>The corporation is the internal organisation responsible for regulating business at Lloyd's, helping to set strategy and policy and providing services to the insurance market.</p>
<p>A worldwide decline in premium rates has added to pressure for insurance companies to operate more efficiently and Lloyd's too is looking to be more competitive.</p>
<p>Prettejohn said there was a need to reduce corporation costs, but added the quality of services must not suffer.  </p>
<p>One way forward which would bring about economies of scale, particularly in processing areas of the business, and which won support in a recent survey, would be to contemplate solutions involving the rest of the London insurance market.</p>
<p>He targetted insurance services in particular, where 80 percent of the corporation's 2,000 staff work. In 1996, that area is likely to account for 140 million stg in costs.</p>
<p>&quot;It (insurance services) is really the guts and activities of costs in the corporation, but not alone that part of the corporation which drives the commercial performance,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Cooperation with the rest of the London market looks more likely now that Lloyd's has put behind it the crippling 8.0 billion stg losses of 1988 to 1992.</p>
<p>These threatened to make Lloyd's insolvent until a deal with investors was finalised last month under which they helped pay to reinsure the losses in return for compensation.</p>
<p>Lloyd's has already embarked on a wide-ranging review, which is to take several months yet and consider not only how services to members are provided, but also how the market is regulated.  </p>
<p>David Gittings, regulatory director at Lloyd's, said some responsibility for regulation may be transferred to outside bodies, altering the policing role of Lloyd's ruling council.</p>
<p>He shed more light on what Lloyd's is doing over the short term to ensure a &quot;seamless trasition,&quot; if and when that happens.</p>
<p>The aim was to bring Lloyd's more into line with other financial markets, Gittings said. Lloyd's has been seeking to identify &quot;drunken drivers&quot; among its professionals, who could cause a risk to themselves and the rest of the insurance market.</p>
<p>Lloyd's is also looking at a set of rules to cover capital providers and embracing some of the issues associated with the rapid consolidation of syndicates and their managing agents, many of whom want closer ties with new corporate investors.</p>
<p>These included guidelines for the timing, voting arrangements and appropriate level of support required in minority buyouts and mandatory offers, Gittings told delegates.</p>
<p>-- Christopher Adams, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 7721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
