<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136239" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reuters historical calendar - October 30.</title>
<headline>Reuters historical calendar - October 30.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the major events to have occurred on October 30 in history.</p>
<p>1735 - John Adams, first vice-president and second president of the United States, born. He helped draft the Declaration of Independence in 1776.</p>
<p>1839 - Alfred Sisley, British-born painter who was one of the creators of French impressionism, born.</p>
<p>1864 - The Peace of Vienna, under which Denmark ceded Schleswig, Holstein and Lauenburg to Prussia, was signed.</p>
<p>1873 - Francisco Indalecio Madero, revolutionary who became president of Mexico in 1911, born.</p>
<p>1885 - U.S. poet Ezra Pound, an early champion of T.S. Eliot and James Joyce and best known for his Cantos, born. He broadcast Fascist propaganda over Italian radio during the Second World War and was later charged with treason.</p>
<p>1905 - Tsar Nicholas II issued the &quot;October Manifesto&quot;, offering extended suffrage, an elected parliament (Duma) with legislative powers and guaranteeing civil liberties.</p>
<p>1911 - Five-year-old Emperor Pu Yi of China was granted a constitution as well as a new cabinet, ending the Manchu domination of China which had lasted for three centuries.</p>
<p>1918 - The Slovaks agreed to a union with the Czechs under the name of Czechoslovakia.</p>
<p>1918 - Turkey signed an armistice which ended its participation in World War One.</p>
<p>1922 - Benito Mussolini and his followers formed a Fascist government in Italy.</p>
<p>1932 - Louis Malle, French film director who won wide acclaim for films such as &quot;Atlantic City&quot; and &quot;The Lovers&quot;, born.</p>
<p>1938 - Millions of Americans were panicked by the radio broadcast of &quot;The War of the Worlds&quot;, a book by H.G. Wells dramatised by Orson Welles. Many believed its description of a Martian invasion of Earth.</p>
<p>1960 - Diego Maradona, Argentinian footballer who led Argentina to victory in the 1986 World Cup, born.</p>
<p>1974 - Muhammad Ali accomplished the most remarkable comeback in boxing when, at 32, he knocked out George Foreman and regained the world heavyweight boxing title.</p>
<p>1975 - Prince Juan Carlos assumed the role of Spain's acting head of state after General Francisco Franco fell ill.</p>
<p>1988 - Over 6,500 couples from the Unification Church were married in Seoul in a service conducted by the church's Korean leader, Sun Myung Moon.</p>
<p>1989 - Socialist Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez clinched an absolute majority in the Spanish general election, winning 176 seats in the 350-seat parliament.</p>
<p>1990 - China announced the results of a nationwide census which showed its population totalled 1.13 billion people.</p>
<p>1990 - Engineers digging a rail tunnel under the English Channel connected Britain with the continent of Europe for the first time since the Ice Age when they linked up under the seabed.</p>
<p>1990 - Indian Prime Minister Vishwanath Pratap Singh offered to resign after security forces killed at least six people to stop Hindu militants from storming a mosque in Uttar Pradesh.</p>
<p>1995 - Voters in Canada's Quebec province voted by a narrow margin in a referendum to remain part of Canada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
