<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136258" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Harding was prominent in London insurance market.</title>
<headline>Harding was prominent in London insurance market.</headline>
<byline>Gordon Mackenzie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matthew Harding, the millionaire vice chairman of Chelsea Football Club who died on Tuesday in a helicopter crash, was as well known in London's insurance market as he was on the soccer terraces.</p>
<p>To football supporters, he was the fan who left his seat in the stands to bankroll his favourite club. To politicians, he was the man who gave the Labour Party a donation of one million pounds, the biggest in its 90-year history.</p>
<p>His fortune came from the insurance world, and there he was known as the flamboyant character who rose from the bottom to become chairman of the Benfield Group -- a global reinsurance and broking operation worth more than one billion pounds a year.</p>
<p>After starting out in banking, Harding joined Benfield, then a fledgling company, as a teaboy and messenger after a chance meeting with its owner, Ted Benfield.</p>
<p>He rose through the ranks until Benfield stepped down in 1984, when Harding was appointed managing director of the company's broking arm.</p>
<p>Four years later as profits increased, Harding led a management move to buy back equity from the holding company. In the seven years that followed, Benfield saw pre-tax profits rise from six million pounds in 1989 to 30 million in 1996.</p>
<p>Harding's salary rose to 2.5 million pounds a year, making him one of Britain's richest men.</p>
<p>An aggressive operator, Harding led a series of acquisitions of units such as Ellinger Heath, the formation of a reinsurance company Benfield Re, and the creation of Benfield &amp; Rea Investment Trust (BRIT).</p>
<p>In August, Harding shattered the normally tranquil world of Lloyd's investment trusts when he jumped uninvited into the cosy merger recently agreed between two of the quoted corporate players in the insurance market.</p>
<p>BRIT announced an 80 million pounds counter-offer for HCG Lloyd's Investment Trust, which last month agreed a merger with the CLM Insurance Fund to create the second biggest &quot;spread&quot; investment fund in the market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
