<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136252" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel oil softens with crude, paper, poor deman.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel oil softens with crude, paper, poor deman.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil drifted lower on Wednesday despite being thinly offered. Dealers said the lack of visible demand was knocking off up to $2 a tonne.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges failed to recover even though bunker demand was higher. Barges traded between $122-124 fob ARA with Russian straight-run material in tank seen as a limiter.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked cargoes were also lower in line with paper.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been so little physical we are all following swaps,&quot; said one trader. Physical cargoes were pegged at $114-116 fob NWE. A utility was heard buying a cargo of Russian M-100 at $121 cif NWE, supporting the those in the market that say the overhang of straight-run material has not been cleared.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked fuel was marginally softer with buyers unwilling to be locked into what they see as a falling market with fixed prices. The U.S. east coast was seen to be a better bet for holders of cargoes in the Caribs than Europe. Cargoes were put at $126-128 fob NWE, close to paper levels.</p>
<p>A low sulphur barge of 500 tonnes was heard traded at $132 fob ARA, although some dealers thoght the prices was well over the market.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Jones, London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
