<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136277" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: French wheat resists pressure, others tumble in EU.</title>
<headline>French wheat resists pressure, others tumble in EU.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>French wheat just held steady but other European grains prices were eroded this week on news of bumper crops worldwide and tumbling U.S. futures.</p>
<p>Wheat was firmer in France than last week, ignoring the Chicago futures at the lowest levels since June 1995 below $4 a bushel on Tuesday, on higher Australian supply estimate. French traders were content with a 20 franc-fall in wheat prices over the last 10 days and, despite grim export prospects and increasing competition, saw no room for further declines.</p>
<p>But frustration was running high among traders as competitive grain from the southern hemisphere threatened to pressure an already oversupplied market, while the European Union (EU) refused to give higher export subsidies.</p>
<p>It wants to see prices edging towards intervention at home to avoid a confrontation with the U.S. over subsidies, but traders say the market has reached a threshold below which farmers would stop selling.</p>
<p>German sellers slashed prices as a period of some weeks of brisk trade with eastern Europe appeared to be ending and buyers turned to cheaper products from Britain and France.</p>
<p>&quot;European millers are not buying our bread wheat,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Prices were expected to move nearer the lower European average sooner or later given ample supplies.</p>
<p>In the fob export market, wheat with 12 percent protein was quoted three to five marks cheaper than last week at 287-294 marks.</p>
<p>UK wheat ticked lower, with wheat clinging to the psychological 100 stg level in E.Anglia deliveries for November. At this level it saw support from domestic and EU millers while a weaker sterling also underpinned prices.</p>
<p>But pressure was seen continuing on European markets with 4.5 million tonnes of wheat in surplus expected just in the UK this season. &quot;Export business is very slack at the moment. Only a large wheat contract would be likely to move prices,&quot; one French dealer said.</p>
<p>Spanish wheat eased, except durum which remained firm as farmers held back supplies.</p>
<p>French maize traded heavily into southern Europe and steadied in France after slides on good harvest progress.</p>
<p>Spanish harvesting in the southern regions is seen fairly advanced but most of the harvest comes from the north.</p>
<p>Fine weather in the south meant that maize harvesting is likely to be around 70 percent completed there, while in the north it is only just getting under way, dealers said.</p>
<p>Italian maize was sharply lower, while durum fell on record harvest and poor quality.</p>
<p>Soft wheat was unchanged, but dealers expected a turnaround in November when buying seasonally picks up ahead of Christmas.</p>
<p>Barley saw sluggish trade in France with Rouen delivery for October/December quoted a nominal 840 francs. It remained under pressure in the UK.</p>
<p>Here is how some key European grains performed on Wednesday compared with last week. All prices are per tonne and French prices exclude carrying charges.</p>
<p>					   Oct 23		Oct 16</p>
<p>French Rouen dlvd wheat Nov-Dec  855 Ffr ($166)    850 (Oct-Dec)</p>
<p>French Rouen dlv wheat Jan-March 835 Ffr ($162)    NA</p>
<p>French Rouen dlvd barley Oct-Dec 845 Ffr ($164)    860</p>
<p>French Bordeaux dlvd maize Oct-Dec  875 Ffr ($170) 880 Germany Hamburg exch bread wheat 285 DM ($188)     285</p>
<p>12.5 pct protein</p>
<p>Germany Hamburg exch fd wheat    275 DM ($181)     275</p>
<p>Germany barley free Hamburg	257.50 DM ($169)  257.50</p>
<p>UK fd wht Nov E.Anglia	     100 stg ($159)    102</p>
<p>UK barley Nov E.Anglia		99 stg ($157)    104</p>
<p>Spain milling wheat spot    24,000 Pta ($187)    24,600</p>
<p>Spain barley spot	     21,000 Pta ($164)    21,000</p>
<p>Spain maize spot		25,000 Pta ($195)    25,500</p>
<p>Italian durum wht spot 310-315,000 lire($203-206)  322-332,000</p>
<p>Italian soft wht spot centre    315,000 lire ($206)    317,000</p>
<p>Italian maize spot	   270-275,000 lire ($177-180) 287,000</p>
<p>-- compiled by Clelia Oziel in London (44-171-542 8072) with contributions from Paris, Hamburg, Madrid and Milan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
