<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136269" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Late bond market prices.</title>
<headline>Late bond market prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Wednesday.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Bunds stay weak after falling in reaction to Buba's Issing who quashed lingering hopes of a credit easing by saying he sees no reason to expect lower key German rates. The December Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) was trading at 99.46, down 0.35 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - UK gilts settle lower after weaker-than-expected retail sales fail to give market sustained boost. Dealers say hang-over of long positions after Tuesday's auction and falling European markets pressuring gilts. Thursday's 20-year auction seen well bid. The December long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 109-24/32, down 10/32 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>FRANCE - December bond future down after Buba economist Issing says no reason for key rate cuts, finds support around 126.40. The December notional bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 126.36 down 0.28 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>ITALY - The rally in Italian bond futures after encouraging CPI figures faltered as the lira weakened and bunds and T-bonds turned lower. Some cautious as investors have one eye on a government confidence vote on the Bank of Naples' restructuring plan later today. The December bond future on LIFFE was trading at 123.90 up 0.15 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - US Treasuries unchanged to slightly higher at mid-morning. Gains held in check ahead of supply in Treasury auction of $12.5 billion in 5-yr notes. Bid deadline 1300 EDT/1700 GMT. 5-yr W-I yield 6.3075 percent. Fed expected to add via customer RPs or overnight system. The December Treasury bond future on the Chicago Board of Trade was trading at 110-14/32, down 06/32 from Tuesday's settlement price. The long bond was quoted to yield 6.87 percent.</p>
<p>JAPAN - The key December Japanese government bond ended Tokyo higher on Wednesday, but well off its all-time high of 124.36 touched in the morning session. In after hours trading the December future on LIFFE was trading at 123.83, down 0.17 from Tuesday's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - Eurobond activity was steady on Wednesday, with mark deals providing much of the interest. Toyota Motor Credit Corp (TMCC) launched the first mark-denominated Euro-Asian bond. The 1.0 billion mark five-year deal will be priced later to yield between five and seven basis points over the September 2001 Bund. &quot;The pricing seems fair, but the institutional bid for mark paper remains quite weak,&quot; said a syndicate manager at a European bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
