<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136215" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Norfolk sees Conrail upping EPS.</title>
<headline>Norfolk sees Conrail upping EPS.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norfolk Southern Corp chairman David Goode called Norfolk's $100 per share unsolicited bid for Conrail Inc &quot;an aggressive offer that we intend to win&quot; as he formally introduced the move to Wall Street.</p>
<p>In a presentation before securities analyst held less than two hours after the all-cash bid was announced, Goode said the offer provides the &quot;highest value and the lowest risk&quot; for shareholders when compared with CSX Corp's friendly, $92.50 per share offer for Conrail, announced last Tuesday.</p>
<p>The CSX offer is composed of 40 percent cash and 60 percent CSX stock.  </p>
<p>Goode said Norfolk also initiated this morning legal action in federal court in Pennsylvania to &quot;invalidate certain aspects of the Conrail, CSX agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Regarding earnings, Goode said that, on a cash basis, the Conrail deal would be accretive to earnings in the first year, but would be about 15 percent dilutive under generally accepted accounting principle.</p>
<p>Dilution on a GAAP basis would come primarily from the purchase accounting of the deal, which would require the write-off of goodwill, he said.  </p>
<p>In 1998, the acquisition would be three to four percent accretive to Norfolk's earnings, a gain that, when added to current analyst estimates, would put earnings for the year at about $8.00 per share.</p>
<p>In years two and three of the merger -- 1999 and 2000 -- the combination with Conrail is expected to raise Norfolk's botton line by 20 to 30 percent, Goode said.  </p>
<p>J.P. Morgan and Merrill Lynch have each committed $2 billion to finance the transaction, which Goode says does not require the approval of Norfolk shareholders and does not contemplate issuance of fresh Norfolk equity.</p>
<p>&quot;We are clearly the best strategic partner for Conrail. Norfolk Southern has the best financial and operating record in the industry. We have been ready to move for some time but Conrail was not,&quot; he said, noting earlier overtures to Conrail had been rebuffed and Norfolk launched the bid since the CSX agreement effectively put Conrail in play.  </p>
<p>&quot;Norfolk Southern would have 60 percent of the Eastern rail market and we are willing to create equitable systems in terms of improved access for other rails. We are confident we can obtain regulatory approval,&quot; the chairman said.</p>
<p>The CSX-Conrail proposal would be &quot;anti-competitive&quot; it would result in control by the new company of 70 percent of the rail traffic in the Eastern United States.</p>
<p>&quot;What rail competition that does exist in the Northeast is fragile and the risk of (regulatory) approval is being placed on the backs of (Conrail) shareholders,&quot; Goode said.  </p>
<p>&quot;This risk goes directly to the heart of the problem of the Conrail/ CSX proposal. It is anticompetitive,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We have long been interested in a combination with Conrail, (but) Conrail has not been willing to enter into a transaction with us. It now appears the Conrail board is interested in considering transactions. We have been unable over the years to bring them to a point where we could seriously consider an acquisition,&quot; Goode said.  </p>
<p>Conrail declined to immediately comment of the rival bid.</p>
<p>Norfolk also said at the presentation that pro forma 1997 revenue for the combined company would be about $9 billion.</p>
<p>Goode also expects the strong third quarter results that were announced earlier today to continue in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>Norfolk said it netted $1.61 per share in the third quarter on revenues of $1.21 billion, up from $1.40 per share on $1.18 billion in revenues in the year ago period.</p>
<p>In middsession New York Stock Exchange trade, Conrail shares were up 12-1/8 to 96-5/8, Norfolk stock shed 1-3/8 to 93-1/8 and CSX was unchanged at 46-1/4.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk, 212-859-1734.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
