<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136295" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil rally to slow U.S. output decline - IPAA.</title>
<headline>Oil rally to slow U.S. output decline - IPAA.</headline>
<byline>Mark Thompson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A furious oil price rally, which has boosted crude by $8 a barrel compared with a year ago, will slow the decline in U.S. domestic output this year and next, senior industry executives said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Independent Petroleum Association of America (IPAA), which represents 5,000 exploration and production companies, accounting for about half of U.S. oil production, will release revised short-term forecasts early next month.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not expecting as large a decline (in 1996 oil output),&quot; IPAA vice president for economic and information services Scott Espenshade told Reuters after an investment seminar in London.</p>
<p>&quot;And it's quite possible that 1997 could be more robust for production as extra wells drilled this year come on stream.&quot;</p>
<p>In April, the IPAA forecast U.S. oil production would fall by 2.5 percent to 6.37 million barrels per day (bpd), its lowest level in 42 years. Gas output was expected to rise by 3.5 percent to 19.36 trillion cubic feet.</p>
<p>But higher oil prices have brought windfall revenues and improved capital flows, encouraging development of marginal fields and a sharp increase in exploration activity, IPAA officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Marginal economic production is about 40 percent of U.S. resources.</p>
<p>'When you get stability of prices at a higher level, you minimise the danger of shutting in production and you can go into some of those wells and do some work which will increase output,&quot; said IPAA president Denise Bode.</p>
<p>IPAA chairman and chief executive officer of Ward Petroleum Corp Lew Ward and others said the vast majority of the extra revenue would be spent on additional exploration.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the real difference it's made is in the extra cashflow that has allowed independents to plough back into exploration and that's finding future production,&quot; said Bruce Vincent, chairman of the IPAA international committee and a senior vice president of Houston-based Swift Energy Co.</p>
<p>Vincent said the industry was emerging from 10 to 15 years of hibernation when a shortage of capital forced it to focus on exploiting existing resources and shun higher risk exploration activity.</p>
<p>&quot;We went through a siginificant price decline which created what I call a depression in our industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the opportunity is there and the returns are there, so you're seeing an influx of capital.&quot;</p>
<p>Companies that survived the 1980s were ideally placed to take advantage of the upturn, having slashed costs -- by as much as 50 percent -- and taken the lead in developing new technology like 3-D seismic surveys and horizontal drilling, he added.</p>
<p>Provided they can overcome high rig rates and a shortage of skilled staff, resurgent independents would look to build on domestic success -- their share of U.S. offshore oil output has climbed to 60 percent from 35 percent in five years -- by acquiring frontier and established acreage around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;We've come on really strong in that area so it would be very natural to look internationally for the same opportunities,&quot; said Bode.</p>
<p>Natural gas -- where independents currently account for about 65 percent of U.S. domestic production -- was likely to attract more than its fair share of new money, given the favourable taxation and regulatory regime.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not a conscious shift (from oil to gas), it's just easier to find gas than it is to find oil,&quot; said Ward.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7930</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
