<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136245" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea Brent trades high, other grades softer.</title>
<headline>North Sea Brent trades high, other grades softer.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea Brent crude traded at a comparatively high level again on Wednesday as this week's main buyer came into the market again.</p>
<p>Other sweet grades showed their vulnerability to the reduced refining margins, holding at recent lower levels, traders said.</p>
<p>Outright IPE December Brent lost 48 cents by 1940 GMT to trade at $24.18 a barrel.</p>
<p>Brent intermonth spreads lost ground in line with Dec/Jan, which traded late on Tuesday at +68 cents, was offered late on Wednesday some 10 cents lower.</p>
<p>Oseberg - with a couple of October cargoes still unsold - traded twice on Wednesday - once at Dated Brent +42 cents for a November 10-12 cargo and again at Dated +25 cents for a Nov 5-7 loader.</p>
<p>Talk of an end October Ekofisk moving at a very low level could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>The trader who has bought some five Brent cargoes this week picked up one of Wednesday's cargoes (November 7-9) from the equity holder at November Brent +10 cents.</p>
<p>Some traders said this level was artifically high and not a true representation of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;They can't justify these levels for refining when you look at the cost of Brent relative to alternative crudes,&quot; one refiner said.</p>
<p>In the Mediterranean Urals levels held steady in a balanced supply/demand situation, traders said.</p>
<p>Some three large cargoes and a handful of smaller vessels were on offer and the level was held around dated Brent -60/-55 cents. ---London Newsroom +44 71 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
