<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136213" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Unisys makes progress with new structure. [CORRECTED 19:03 GMT]</title>
<headline>Unisys makes progress with new structure. [CORRECTED 19:03 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BLUE BELL, Pa. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unisys Corp said that it made further progress in the third quarter with its new business unit structure that it formed at the beginning of this year, with revenues up in each of its three units.</p>
<p>Unisys reported third quarter net income of $14.2 million (corrects from $32.2 million and shows a profit, not loss, was achieved) and a loss per share of $0.09, after the payment of preferred dividends, compared with a loss of $0.36 a share a year ago.</p>
<p>The computer maker also said that services now represents 63 percent of its total revenues and that it was particularly pleased with the performance of its computer systems business.  </p>
<p>According to First Call, the consensus among analysts was for a loss of $0.09 a share, exactly what Unisys reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The computer systems group has made excellent progress in working through a major product transition,&quot; said James Unruh, chairman and CEO, in a statement.</p>
<p>Unisys said that the transition continued to impact its financial results, but that sales of computer systems and profitability in this unit &quot;rebounded nicely&quot; in the quarter.</p>
<p>Unisys also said it plans to meet its revised shipment schedule for its new mainframe computers, which it now calls large scale enterprise servers, after a previous delay.  </p>
<p>The mainframes were delayed due to ongoing testing of a complex new chip architecture. Unisys reiterated that the delay would preclude it from reaching the level of shipments and profitability it had originally planned for 1996.</p>
<p>Unisys said as another move to improve its profitability, its management has imposed constraints in selected market areas while continuing double-digit revenue growth in other markets. Its computer systems revenue increased 14 percent, due in large part to a major contract for more than 50,000 electronic voting machines. Strong revenue increases occurred in both the U.S. and in its international business.  </p>
<p>Revenues also increased in its global customer services business, which was up six percent as strong growth in distributed computing support services offset the decline of servicing its traditional mainframe business.</p>
<p>Unisys said worldwide orders were up about the same level versus a year ago, and higher orders in the U.S. and Latin America offset a drop in orders in Europe and Asia/Pacific.</p>
<p>&quot;After nine months of operations under the new business structure, our three businesses...are more cost-competitive, streamlined, and focused on capturing opportunities in their respective markets,&quot; Unruh added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLUE BELL, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
