<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136281" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GDR REPORT - India runs out of steam as locals rally.</title>
<headline>GDR REPORT - India runs out of steam as locals rally.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian global depositary receipts (GDRs) ran out of steam on Wednesday, after a rally which was inspired by a cut in bank cash reserve requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;The local market was higher, with genuine buying and was up in after-market trade, so it is a bit strange that the GDRs should have come off at the end,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>The HSBC James Capel Indian GDR index  JCEAI closed down 0.07 points, 0.10 percent, at 65.15 points, with the premium over the local market at 10.85 percent, after the Bombay Stock Exchange 30-share index added 114.73 points, or 3.56 percent, to 3,344.35.</p>
<p>The BSE-30 was up 6.5 percent in the two trading days since the end of last week, while the GDRs put on 6.46 percent on Monday, when the Indian markets were closed for a holiday.</p>
<p>The BSE closed just off its high of 3,344.35.</p>
<p>&quot;The local markets should open higher tomorrow, there is demand in India,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Other traders said that the GDR market usually led the local market, but had seen profit-taking set in after this week's gains.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to see where we can go from here as any more gains will certainly see people selling into strength,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>The Capel Korea GDR Index fell 0.01 points 71.73, a premium of 30.58 percent over the local market, after the Korea Composite Index fell 7.24 points to provisionally close at 811.98.</p>
<p>The Capel Taiwan GDR Index ended down 0.87 points at 87.67, a premium of 2.68 percent after the Taiwan Weighted Index rose 10.76 points to 6,437.06.</p>
<p>-- David Chance, London Newsroom 44 171 542 5887</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
