<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136225" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Boost for skin-cancer war - sharks get suntans,too.</title>
<headline>Boost for skin-cancer war - sharks get suntans,too.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sharks get suntans, U.S. scientists said on Wednesday in a finding could help combat skin cancer.</p>
<p>As sharks do not get cancer, the revelation may boost the search for other cancer cures also.</p>
<p>Christopher Lowe and Gwen Goodman-Lowe of the University of Hawaii wrote in a letter to the science journal Nature that they had found hammerhead sharks got noticeable tans from the sun.</p>
<p>The Lowes were working with baby hammerheads, which normally stay in deep, murky water.</p>
<p>&quot;The pups are light tan in colour but change to dark brown or black over several weeks when held in a shallow (one metre deep) seawater pond,&quot; they wrote.</p>
<p>They put sunlight filters on some of the baby sharks and filters that cut out ultraviolet rays, known to cause tans in people.</p>
<p>Sure enough, the sharks &quot;tanned,&quot; with tan lines showing where the filters had been. Tests on the skin showed melanin, the same chemical that causes skin to darken in humans, increased in the skin of sun-exposed sharks.</p>
<p>They said the findings could have medical applications as skin cancer, and indeed cancers of all types, are unknown in sharks.</p>
<p>&quot;Finally, these observations are important for the assessment of biological responses to global increases in ultraviolet,&quot; they wrote.  </p>
<p>(c) Reuters Limited 1996 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
