<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136274" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Jaguar advertises its cars on outside of planes.</title>
<headline>Jaguar advertises its cars on outside of planes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jaguar, the sports car company, launched an unusual advertising campaign on Wednesday by paying an airline to have huge jaguars painted on its planes.</p>
<p>Jaguar Ltd said it expected about 40 million people over the next year to see the green &quot;big cat&quot; mascot on the fuselage of Ryanair, a British-based airline.</p>
<p>&quot;It's tremendous value for money,&quot; Colin Cook, Jaguar's director of corporate affairs, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jaguar paid an estimated 100,000 pounds for Ryanair, an Irish-owned carrier which flies throughout Britain and Ireland, to carry the huge ads on its Boeing 737 aircraft.  </p>
<p>Jaguar, which was bought by Ford Motor Co, America's second biggest carmaker, in 1989, said it had wanted to find a &quot;new and innovative promotional programme&quot;.</p>
<p>Ryanair flies 13 routes between Ireland and Britain, and plans to fly to continental Europe in the spring.</p>
<p>In June Marketing magazine said Ryanair had offered the exterior of its fleet of 11 Boeing 737's for hire to potential advertisers for 120,000 pounds for one year.</p>
<p>Ryanair said it was the first British-based carrier to carry ads on planes and was following the example of other airlines in the United States that had acted as &quot;billboards in the sky&quot;.</p>
<p>The new ad campaign is meant to promote the &quot;leaper&quot;, Jaguar's XK8 high performance sports car, which was due to fill showrooms this month and which costs over $65,000.</p>
<p>Jaguar and other sports car makers are struggling to attract consumers in with what industry experts say is a dwindling market.</p>
<p>&quot;Sports cars are a dying and shrinking market...&quot; Peter Schmidt, with Automotive Industry Data, told Reuters at the Paris car show a few weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;...people's tastes are changing in Europe and America. They don't want to flaunt their wealth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2792</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
