<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136293" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar ends volatile European session lower.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends volatile European session lower.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed lower in Europe after a surge in mark/yen to 3-1/2 year highs helped reinvigorate the German unit across the board, traders said.</p>
<p>Strength in the mark/yen cross combined with comments from Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing to buoy the mark. Issing said there was no reason to expect lower official German interest rates.</p>
<p>The broad-based weakness of the yen, however, helped the dollar push to a fresh 33-month high at 113.00 before settling back into the mid-112 area. Dealers said any downmoves in the dollar should be seen as consolidation.  </p>
<p>At 1450 GMT the dollar stood at 1.5225/32 marks and 112.75/82 yen compared with 1.5339/43 and 112.84/89 in late European trading on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mark/yen was at 74.17/19 yen, just off a high at 74.23 yen, its highest level since January 1993, and up from 73.54/56 at the previous European close.</p>
<p>Japanese investor demand for high-yielding foreign assets continued to put the yen under selling pressure, dealers said. Renewed confidence in Japanese interest rates staying low for the foreseeable future combined with profit-taking on short-mark positions in Europe.  </p>
<p>&quot;Mark/yen was the big mover today and that dominated everything else,&quot; said Peter Wood, a trader at Bank of Boston in London. &quot;The dollar still looks in good shape, and any dowmoves are part of a consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>The low interest rate story in Japan was reinforced by the latest comments from Bank of Japan governor Yasuo Matsushita.</p>
<p>Speaking after the two-day BOJ branch managers meeting, Matsushita said while the economy is growing gradually, it is unlikely to accelerate soon. BOJ monetary policy is geared toward ensuring economic recovery and market expectations of higher rates are receding, he said.  </p>
<p>The Norwegian crown was dealt a blow by the sudden resignation of Prime Minister Gro Harlem Bruntland. The timing of the move surprised traders as Norway is in the midst of 1997 budget negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;...the problem here is that the budget negotiation is under way and they are running into problems,&quot; said Keld Holm, Lehman Brothers international economist.</p>
<p>Strong oil prices, Norway's key source of revenue, and a stable economy will ensure the crown's weakness is short-lived, analysts said.</p>
<p>Mark/crown was at 4.2435/45 from 4.2345/55 late on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
