<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136235" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. and European stocks drop, mark makes progress.</title>
<headline>U.S. and European stocks drop, mark makes progress.</headline>
<byline>Roger Jeal</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices dropped on both sides of the Atlantic on Wednesday as investors cashed in profits and took to the sidelines, while the mark made progress against the dollar and a weak yen.</p>
<p>Wall Street, which had slipped from record levels earlier this week, fell over 40 points on the Dow Jones industrial average within 15 minutes of its opening and was later more than 60 points adrift, led by further selling in technology shares.</p>
<p>In Europe, leading bourses which had lost ground on Tuesday and in morning trading on Wednesday showed even less enthusiasm after Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing said there was no reason to expect more cuts in key German interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The market definitely turned today,&quot; said one London dealer. &quot;We were getting a little too blase about going up 20 points a day.&quot;</p>
<p>Whatever Wall Street's immediate prospects, investors pondering whether the world's biggest stock market can add to its heady gains were given encouragement by Steven Einhorn, partner and head of global investment research at Goldman Sachs.</p>
<p>Speaking in Hong Kong, he said the bull market that has swept U.S. share prices to record levels should continue into 1998 and European equities could do even better.</p>
<p>On the foreign exchanges, Issing's comments gave further fuel to the mark, which hit its highest level in more than 3-1/2 years versus the yen, rising through a previous 1996 high of 73.78 yen to peak at 74.23.</p>
<p>Traders said a growing belief that Japanese interest rates would stay low for a while was depressing the yen, with Japanese investors seeking high-yielding foreign assets.</p>
<p>Reinforcing this view, Bank of Japan governor Yasuo Matsushita said that while the economy was growing gradually, it was unlikely to accelerate soon and market expectations of higher rates were receding.</p>
<p>The dollar, while losing more than a pfennig against the German currency, revived from early weakness to set its highest level against the yen since January 1994 at 113.12 yen.</p>
<p>A few hours earlier, comments about the harm that a high dollar rate could do to trade had sent it down to 112.04 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;Mark/yen was the big mover today and that dominated everything else,&quot; said Peter Wood, a trader at Bank of Boston in London. &quot;The dollar still looks in good shape and any downmoves are part of a consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>In the slightly longer term, currency analysts said that while the market was turning a blind eye to the looming U.S. election, the dollar could lose its composure even if President Bill Clinton scores his expected victory on November 5.</p>
<p>If the Democrats seized control of the U.S. Congress from the Republicans, this could prompt market fears of looser U.S. fiscal and trade policy, unsettling the dollar, they said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the London stock market fell in dull trading, with little fresh domestic company and economic news to come to its aid. Investors took profits after a record-breaking run but the market ended above the day's lows.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt stock market was dragged down by Issing's comments and by a plunge of almost a quarter in the shares of business software firm SAP after a profits warning.</p>
<p>French shares also retreated more than one percent, taking their cue from Wall Street to consolidate big recent gains. Resorts group Club Mediterranee, which also issued a profits warning late on Tuesday, fell by almost a fifth.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1530 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was around 1.5225 marks and 112.95 yen in late European trade, compared with 1.5347 and 112.83 a day earlier.</p>
<p>The Norwegian crown slipped to 4.2440 against the mark from 4.2350 after the sudden resignation of Prime Minister Gro Harlem Bruntland.</p>
<p>STOCKS AT THE EUROPEAN CLOSE</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares ended 28.8 points lower at 4,028.4.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index closed bourse trade 19.45 lower at 2,699.53 and dropped to 2,678.89 in later electronic business. In Paris, the CAC-40 share index finished down 26.75 at 2,148.86.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed London trading at $383.55 an ounce after being fixed at $383.50 in the afternoon and earlier topping $384, compared with $383.65 at the London close on Tuesday. Silver rose one cent to $4.98.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
