<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136240" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Brent crude ends down, just off the day's lows.</title>
<headline>IPE Brent crude ends down, just off the day's lows.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE December Brent crude oil futures ended down and nearly at the day's lows Wednesday as NYMEX heating oil lost ground rapidly in the last 15 minutes of trade, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The heating oil got slammed. Brent just followed,&quot; one commented.</p>
<p>December Brent closed down 59 cents at $24.07 a barrel, just six cents above the day's low.</p>
<p>NYMEX November heating oil contract closed at 70.80 cents a gallon - well below support at 71.40. Brokers saw this as bearish, signalling possible further losses on Thursday.  </p>
<p>IPE November gas oil, which closed earlier down $5.00 at $225.75 a tonne was expected to open on Thursday down a further $1.50 on the back of the weakness in Brent crude and NYMEX heating oil.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute reported after markets closed on Tuesday that, while overall U.S. distillates edged down by 17,000 barrels last week, the heating oil component grew by 2.4 million barrels, with strong increases in the key northeast and Gulf of Mexico districts.  </p>
<p>The Energy Information Agency showed similar data in its weekly report early Wednesday, with an overall drop of 100,000 barrels in national distillate stocks, but a rise in the northeast of 2.2 million barrels.</p>
<p>With the Colonial Pipeline Co earlier this week saying it would open up one of its gasoline lines to distillate flow and refineries making efforts to pump more distillate product, traders see some upward pressure taken out of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the support we had from low U.S. inventories is going out of the market and it looks like we will see lower numbers but perhaps not substantially lower,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>--S Hayden London Newsroom +44 71 542 8978</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
