<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136218" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Athens Stock Exchange short selling in two months.</title>
<headline>Athens Stock Exchange short selling in two months.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Athens Stock Exchange said before a meeting with U.S. mutual fund portfolio managers on Wednesday that he expected short-selling to begin on the exchange before Christmas.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that, if we have the cooperation of the brokers and the Capital Markets Commission that it can be done before Christmas...in about two months,&quot; said Dr. Manolis Xanthakis, president of the Athens Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>The Greek market has been thirsty for short-selling. Traders who sell securities &quot;short&quot; borrow stock and sell it, betting the stock's price will fall and they will be able to buy back the shares later at a lower price for repayment to the lender.</p>
<p>Officially, stocks cannot be borrowed in Greece, but both Xanthakis and Capital Markets Commission head Stravos Thomadakis concede that it is regularly done - just not regulated.  </p>
<p>Thomadakis said in an interview that his regulatory agency is working &quot;on a set of regulations that's going to in fact put in order a whole set of activities which at present are in the twilight zone.&quot;</p>
<p>He was referring to short-selling and selling on margins.</p>
<p>&quot;It's allowed, but if you practice them they are not regulated and so forth...we want do away with the twilight zone,&quot; he said. The regulations are linked to the timing of a derivatives exchange, which he said &quot;will come on line about September 1997. These other regulatory decisions must come well before that...Some time in the Spring, early Spring.&quot;  </p>
<p>Thomadakis said he received the file of &quot;the investigation of the stock exchange&quot; last week and expected to have the review of what he called &quot;a variety of cases and a variety of violations&quot; completed in November when fines would be handed down.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be very careful about imposing fines. We're not trying to evade our responsibility, we're just trying to be careful so that what we do is just and gives the right incentives for people not to repeat offences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He expects to double his staff of 13 shortly, adding auditors, lawyers and analysts to better monitor the market.  </p>
<p>Athen Stock Exchange head Xanthakis attributed the recent downturn in his market to new European Union regulations 2396/96 that come into effect on November 1.</p>
<p>&quot;My feeling is that this is a short-term problem,&quot; Xanthakis said. &quot;Why in 1989, when other stock (European) exchanges did not do well, the Greek stock exchange was doing well...It's very difficult to say why at this particular moment, it is doing poorly. In my own opinion, the first of November is the official enactment of the law that incorporates the two directives of the community, while the timing is not the same as the other European stock exchanges.&quot;  </p>
<p>Xanthakis put current U.S. investment in the Greek market at $1 billion, which represents 1.0 percent of the amount that U.S. investors have in emerging markets. He said his goal was to double that to 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
