<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136234" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Major, Blair scrap for moral high ground.</title>
<headline>Britain's Major, Blair scrap for moral high ground.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major on Wednesday launched a bid to make law-and-order an election vote-winner for his Conservatives by announcing a raft of bills to tackle crime and violence in Britain.</p>
<p>Mocking the opposition Labour Party as the champion of trendy causes which undermined Britain's moral fabric, Major told its leader, Tony Blair: &quot;I don't think I am inclined to accept sanctimonious lectures from you.&quot;</p>
<p>Measures in the legislative programme for a new session of parliament, announced by Queen Elizabeth, included bills to put criminals in jail for longer and tighten school discipline.</p>
<p>And in a U-turn, Major said the government would sponsor bills for a register of paedophiles and to make &quot;stalking&quot;, or frightening people by following them around, a criminal offence.</p>
<p>The government previously planned that these bills should be put forward by ordinary legislators, which would have greatly reduced their chances of becoming law.</p>
<p>The new parliamentary session will be a truncated one since Major, whose party is between 14 and 20 points behind in opinion polls, must call a general election by next May.</p>
<p>He hopes the new bills will prove popular with Britons alarmed at a recent spate of horrific crimes such as the Dunblane massacre of 16 children last March and the knifing to death of a headmaster outside his school gates.</p>
<p>Frances Lawrence, the headmaster's widow, launched a nationwide debate on morality and standards of behaviour this week with a full-page article in the Times newspaper.</p>
<p>Speaking in a parliamentary debate on the &quot;Queen's Speech&quot;, Major said his government had battled against Britain's crime wave for years, and had got little help from Labour.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know how you can disclaim responsibility for faults in society today,&quot; he told Blair.</p>
<p>&quot;Your own Labour Party has consistently championed every fashionable, politically correct cause that has undermined our traditional way of life and opposed every measure we have taken to redress the balance.&quot;</p>
<p>But Blair accused Major of pretending the Conservatives, in power since 1979, were not to blame for the state of the nation. &quot;Seventeen years in office, and they never take responsibility for their mistakes,&quot; Blair told parliament.</p>
<p>Blaming the ruling party for leaving many young people jobless and homeless, he said the Conservatives had created a fractured society in which only the well-off had prospered.</p>
<p>&quot;We will mend this fractured society when those who fractured it...are no longer governing our society,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Both Blair and Paddy Ashdown, leader of the minority Liberal Democrats, accused Major of thinking solely of the election.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a Queen's Speech driven more by what will wrong-foot the opposition than what is right for the country,&quot; Ashdown said.</p>
<p>Key among the bills in the Queen's Speech is one to ban almost all handguns, except low calibre guns used in target shooting, in the wake of the massacre of 16 children and their teacher by crazed gunman Thomas Hamilton in Dunblane.</p>
<p>The bill has already run into trouble, with both Labour and the Liberals warning they will vote instead for a total ban.</p>
<p>There was also a bill fixing automatic life sentences for anyone convicted of a series of sex or violent crimes, another designed to crack down on welfare fraud and moves to tighten school discipline.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
