<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136242" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Be Prince Charles's neighbour for $7.5 million?.</title>
<headline>Be Prince Charles's neighbour for $7.5 million?.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>House hunters looking for a better neighbourhood can now, for a price, move next door to the heir to the British throne.</p>
<p>The owners of the 1,400-acre (560-hectare) Estcourt Park bordering Prince Charles's Highgrove home put their estate up for sale on Wednesday for five million pounds ($7.5 million).</p>
<p>A royal spokeswoman refused to comment on speculation that the prince might buy the property himself.</p>
<p>An imposing Georgian manor house on the estate near Tetbury, Gloucestershire, 100 miles (150 km) west of London, was demolished in 1964.</p>
<p>But there is planning permission for a 1.5 million pound ($2.25 million) nine-bedroom chateau-style replacement.</p>
<p>The manor has been the home of the Estcourt family since 1303 and comes complete with a swan lake, stables and woodland.</p>
<p>The last surviving member of the family, reclusive bachelor Desmond Sotheron Estcourt, has no heirs and has been forced to sell because he needs the money.</p>
<p>&quot;It is tragic for me but what is the good of whining. We all have our trials,&quot; Estcourt said. &quot;I am hating all this - my family has been here 700 years.&quot;</p>
<p>Desmond inherited the estate from his father Thomas in 1961. Six rented cottages remain, along with an imposing gate and a tree-lined drive which was used in the BBC television drama &quot;Pride and Prejudice&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
