<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136221" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sara Lee sees record FY97 sales, earnings.</title>
<headline>Sara Lee sees record FY97 sales, earnings.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sara Lee Corp, which reported a 10.8 percent rise in fiscal first quarter earnings per share, said it expects continued record sales and earnings this year.</p>
<p>&quot;A combination of internal growth and acquisitions contributed to our sales and operating profit gains during the quarter,&quot; John Bryan, chairman, said in a statement. &quot;We expect continued record sales and earnings throughout the remainder of fiscal 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>For the first quarter ended September 28, it earned $0.41 a primary share, up from $0.37 a year ago.  </p>
<p>Sara Lee said packaged meats and bakery sales rose 17 percent to $1.89 billion in the first quarter while operating income gained 19.2 percent to $95.0 million. Results were aided by growth in the base business and the acquisition of Aoste, a European meats company, in July, it added.</p>
<p>Worldwide packaged meats unit volume fell two percent in the first quarter as higher commodity costs led to increased retail prices. Worldwide unit volume for Sara Lee Bakery fell nine percent in the first quarter. Foodservice unit volume rose three percent.  </p>
<p>Sara Lee said coffee and grocery sales fell 7.1 percent to $673.0 million due to lower coffee prices and a stronger U.S. dollar relative to European currencies. Operating income rose 3.9 percent to $117.0 million due to cost efficiencies and increased unit sales that improved operating margins.</p>
<p>Household and body care sales were flat at $431.0 million, while operating income rose 7.3 percent to $40.0 million. Results benefited from a strong performance in the direct selling division, higher profitability in core household and body car products, and contributions from acquired brands.</p>
<p>Personal products sales rose 0.5 percent to $1.90 billion, but operating income dropped five percent to $152.0 million. The company said these results were as planned, reflecting increased media spending behind major brands.</p>
<p>Sara Lee said it expects to report increased operating income for personal products on a year-over-year basis in the three remaining quarters and the full fiscal year.</p>
<p>Worldwide unit volumes for legwear dropped one percent, while knit products unit volume rose six percent. Intimate apparel unit volumes rose one percent globally.</p>
<p>Sara Lee said net interest expense fell 8.7 percent to $43 million in the quarter from $47.0 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
