<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136247" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products mostly ease, low sulphur stable.</title>
<headline>Med oil products mostly ease, low sulphur stable.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were unchanged to slightly weaker, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil weakened on easier IPE futures and premiums for heating oil and low sulphur diesel were pressured by poor demand.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really lacklustre,&quot; one trader in the region said. Russian was discussed at quotes high +$1 basis Genoa.</p>
<p>Attention focussed on the award on Thursday of a Turkish tender for two 10,000-tonne cargoes of Turkish import grade 0.5 heating oil for delivery into Tutunciftlik, with the result expected to give direction to premiums.  </p>
<p>Gasoline prices were little changed as early gains were given up in the afternoon when U.S. prices fell about 0.5 cent a gallon.</p>
<p>Dealers said premium unleaded was tracking barges at a discount of $2.00 a tonne on an fob Italy basis.</p>
<p>Naphtha was weaker in line with crude futures, but physical discussion was thin, traders said. A full-range Egyptian cargo was still seen on offer at quotes cif high +$4 a tonne, cif Lavera. Buyers were seen to be fairly relaxed.</p>
<p>Fuel oil was weaker, in line with lower crude prices.  </p>
<p>Some dealers also thought there was pressure to push prices lower in anticipation of pricing in the next few days of a couple of large cargoes.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked cargoes were knocked down to $113-115 fob Med although buyers would only look at floating prices. Paper was heard, but not done, at $112.50.</p>
<p>Low sulphur was broadly steady, taking a little comfort from a fading likelihood that Caribbean material would seek a home in the Med because of strong U.S. prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
