<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136219" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Teleport to acquire Eastern Telelogic.</title>
<headline>Teleport to acquire Eastern Telelogic.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Teleport Communications Group Inc on Wednesday said it will acquire Eastern Telelogic Corp, in a deal expected to total about $233 million and involve a combination of cash, stock and assumption of debt.</p>
<p>In the first of the two steps, Eastern will redeem the shares of its stock, about 49 percent, not held by Comcast CAP, a corporation owned 51 percent by Comcast Corp and 49 percent by Teleport.</p>
<p>Comcast CAP will borrow at a market interest rate about $120 million from Teleport as a short-term loan and will, in turn, lend this amount to Eastern for the redemption.  </p>
<p>This first step is expected to close as soon as mid-November, Teleport said.</p>
<p>In the second step, TCG will acquire Comcast's 51 percent of Comcast CAP in exchange for 2,757,083 shares of Teleport Class A common stock, resulting in Eastern becoming a wholly owned subsidiary of Teleport.</p>
<p>Teleport will also assume about $45 million of Eastern debt and $5 million of management appreciation rights.</p>
<p>The second transaction is expected to close in the first quarter of 1997.  </p>
<p>With the acquisition of Eastern, a local exchange carrier in Pennsylvania, New Jersey and Delaware, Teleport will operate extensive local fiber optic networks throughout the Northeast Corridor, from northern Virginia through New York, Boston and into southern New Hampshire, Teleport said.</p>
<p>Eastern said its &quot;position as a leading provider of local telecommunications services fits in with Teleport's strategy of being the leading local telecommunications competitor in all the major markets in the United States,&quot; said Bob Annunziata, chairman, president and chief executive of Teleport, in a statement.</p>
<p>The acquisition of Eastern will raise to 57 the number of major markets Teleport serves, including 18 of the top 20.</p>
<p>Gary Lasher, president and chief executive of Eastern, said that &quot;We are looking forward to becoming part of this highly successful and growing organization.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk +1 212 859 1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
