<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136222" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Murdoch to &quot;mortgage&quot; BSkyB stake - report.</title>
<headline>Murdoch to &quot;mortgage&quot; BSkyB stake - report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rupert Murdoch plans to mortgage part of his stake in satellite broadcaster BSkyB in order to raise up to $2 billion to finance development elsewhere in his media empire, the Independent reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>News America Holdings, a U.S.-based subsidiary of Murdoch's News Corp, is seeking to raise the money through an issue of preference shares, convertible at a pre-determined price into BSkyB shares, the report added.</p>
<p>It said the issue would be convertible into as much as 11 percent of BSkyB -- a company in which News Corp has a 40 percent stake.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch, which is placing the issue, is seeking to raise about $1 billion but &quot;greenshoe&quot; provisions means the total financing could be double that, the newspaper added.</p>
<p>It said the issue would carry a dividend of about five percent and be priced next week. It added that the proceeds were believed to be earmarked for the development of Murdoch's digital TV plans in the U.S. and Asia.</p>
<p>It said the stock would be convertible at a premium of about 20 percent to the price of BSkyB shares at the time of issue and would be redeemable after five years.</p>
<p>News America Holdings will have the right to offer converting stockholders cash instead of shares, equivalent to the then ruling BSkyB share price.</p>
<p>The report quoted &quot;sources familiar with the financing&quot; as saying the move amounted to a bet by Murdoch that he will be able to retire the shares at their conversion date, possibly within five years, even if shares soar well above the pre-set conversion price.</p>
<p>Murdoch could thus avoid diluting his 40 percent BSkyB stake when the shares become convertible, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
