<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136249" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British widow to send late husband off with bang.</title>
<headline>British widow to send late husband off with bang.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A young widow is planning a big-bang send-off for her late husband next month by strapping his ashes to a rocket which will be launched during a fireworks party.</p>
<p>In accordance with her husband's dying wish, his last remains will be rocketed heavenwards on &quot;Bonfire Night&quot;, an annual British celebration which takes place on November 5.</p>
<p>The annual fireworks festival commemorates an unsuccesful attempt by Roman Catholic dissidents to blow up the largely Protestant British parliament on that day in 1605.</p>
<p>The widow, who has wished to remain anonymous has purchased the biggest firework rocket on public sale in Britain from firework company, Fantastic Fireworks, located in the town of Luton, 20 miles (30 kilometres) north  of London.</p>
<p>&quot;The ashes will be dispersed over a wide area in a starburst display -- it is a wonderful idea,&quot; said Fantastic Fireworks managing director Jon Culverhouse.</p>
<p>&quot;His dying wish was that his ashes should be sent up in a rocket at a party, as something to celebrate and remember him by.&quot;</p>
<p>The four-feet long rocket was the biggest which could be sold in Britain for private use, he said.</p>
<p>The company had placed the ashes in the compartment made for the mixture of gunpowder and chemicals which would create the &quot;starburst&quot; effect once the rocket reaches a height of about 200ft, Culverhouse said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
