<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136259" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Reckitt move seen attracting few followers.</title>
<headline>Reckitt move seen attracting few followers.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Few British firms may qualify for the same benefits enjoyed by household products group Reckitt &amp; Colman, which plans to give back 152 million pounds ($242.8 million) to shareholders without incurring tax hitches, experts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reckitt's move would work only for firms with very large income streams generated by overseas business, ruling out many British firms that saw their share buyback plans thwarted by the government earlier this month.</p>
<p>&quot;It may solve the problem for a handful of companies, but it does not provide a way out for the likes such as Reuters,&quot; said Derek Jenkins, tax partner at consultants Coopers &amp; Lybrand.</p>
<p>News and information group Reuters aborted plans for a 613 million sterling share buyback two weeks ago after the British government scrapped generous tax credit claims for institutional shareholders previously allowed under such schemes.</p>
<p>The level of claims were reaching unacceptable levels as an ever growing number of firms with excess cash were looking at share buybacks, the government said at the time.</p>
<p>Reckitt &amp; Colman, however, unveiled a scheme on Tuesday that in effect is a share buyback but complies with the new rules under which its 35.65 pence per share special payout will be treated as a foreign income dividend, the tax experts said.</p>
<p>The Inland Revenue said it would have no problems with such a scheme as announced by Reckitt.</p>
<p>While this ruling gives tax disadvantages for most companies, it works out well for a firm such as Reckitt, which posts 92 percent of its annual revenues outside Britain, tax experts said.</p>
<p>Combined with plans to take one in every 20 of its shares out of circulation, its scheme will boost earnings per share in the same way as share buyback.</p>
<p>&quot;Reckitt simply says that approach cannot hurt us because we've got the foreign income,&quot; said Jenkins. &quot;What they're doing is saying: Okay Treasury, we will use your rules to create an advantage for our shareholders'.&quot;</p>
<p>But these advantages are probably only available for firms, such as B.A.T Industries and Cable &amp; Wireless, which post well over 50 percent of revenues abroad, Jenkins said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is going to depend very much on having a significant amount of taxed profits coming from abroad,&quot; said Gary Richards, a partner at Price Waterhouse.</p>
<p>&quot;But whilst one can speculate which companies might fit the bill, it will depend on their directors whether they want to wish to return cash to shareholders or not.&quot; ($1=.6260 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
