<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136305" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION-Counties meet with lawyers on Lomu appeal.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-Counties meet with lawyers on Lomu appeal.</headline>
<text>
<p>WELLINGTON, Oct 24 - Counties-Manukau rugby administrators will meet with their solicitors on Thursday to see if they can appeal the the decision that has ruled Jonah Lomu out of Sunday's national championship final, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Counties' chief executive officer Brian Bangs confirmed his officials had discussed the issue soon after the New Zealand Rugby Football Union judicial committee decided to suspend the team's star winger for a week on Wednesday night.  </p>
<p>Lomu, cited by the union's disciplinary commissioner David Howman, was accused of making a dangerous tackle on Canterbury fullback Kieran Flynn during Counties' 46-33 semifinal win in Pukekohe last Sunday.</p>
<p>The victory launched Counties into the championship final against Auckland at Eden Park on Sunday.</p>
<p>Flynn was not injured in the tackle and the incident went unnoticed by match officials.  </p>
<p>Bangs said Counties coach Mac MacCallion was on his way to the rugby union's headquarters in Wellington on Thursday for a totally unrelated matter. But he could discuss Lomu's suspension with the union's administrators, Bangs said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm absolutely devastated,&quot; MacCallion said of Lomu's suspension.</p>
<p>&quot;It's thrown out all our plans for Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very disappointed with the inconsistency of the citings by the commissioner -- it concerns me a great deal,&quot; MacCallion said.  </p>
<p>&quot;There were far worse things in that match that went unnoticed.</p>
<p>&quot;As a coach I can say I saw nothing wrong with the tackle and you will agree with it if you saw the video of the game,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now I can't comment too much on it because I haven't seen the written decision or the referee's report.&quot;</p>
<p>The week-long suspension adds to a disappointing season for the hefty winger who missed three of the four tests in South Africa this year following a knee injury.  </p>
<p>Judicial committee chairman Bruce Squire said his committee viewed a videotape of the game and heard evidence from Lomu and submissions from his legal counsel in Wellington on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>He said the committee heard of Lomu's good record and factors which, it was submitted, contributed to the tackle, described as a spear tackle, being made in the fashion it was.</p>
<p>&quot;The committee accepted that the tackle was not effected with any intent on Lomu's part to cause injury to the Canterbury player, and that absence of intent was a significant factor in the assessment of penalty,&quot; Squire said.  </p>
<p>He said the committee concluded that the tackle was dangerous because of the capacity for serious injury it carried.</p>
<p>Squire said a short suspension was a sufficient penalty in the circumstances.</p>
<p>The committee suspended Lomu up to and including October 30.</p>
<p>Lomu will likely be replaced by David Wood, who has played the majority of Counties games on the left wing this year.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
