<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136363" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria says it is safe for foregin investment.</title>
<headline>Nigeria says it is safe for foregin investment.</headline>
<byline>Felix Onuah</byline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's military government, piqued that its opening up of sub-Sahara's biggest economy has failed to lure foreign investors, said on Wednesday the country was a safe place for business.</p>
<p>&quot;Nigeria is safe for foreign investors and generous incentives exist to attract investment inflows,&quot; Nigeria's second in command Lieutenant-General Oladipo Diya told a seminar in the capital Abuja.</p>
<p>The seminar is the second in a series organised by the Nigerian Diamond Bank in conjunction with the World Bank's Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency (MIGA) and aims at aggressively attracting foreign investment into the country.</p>
<p>The first session took place in the commercial hub of Lagos on Monday when finance minister Anthony Ani said Nigeria was seriously considering selling its 57 percent equity in joint venture firms that produce its crude oil.</p>
<p>Ani also announced that the country's badly managed four oil refineries could be privatised.</p>
<p>The government last year backed up its trumpeted opening of the economy to foreign with decrees allowing foreign investors unlimited stock in businesses and full repatration of profits.</p>
<p>The law also prohibits nationalisation or seizure of foreign businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Inspite of the various measures taken by government aimed at creating a conducive investment climate, the response is still very low,&quot; Diya said, announcing that an investment promotion commission would be set up to woe investors.</p>
<p>Diamond Bank chief executive Pascal Dozie said government should immediately start a promotion campaign abroad on its privatisation programme.</p>
<p>Participants, however, said Nigeria's was a poor image abroad for continued military rule and human rights abuses.</p>
<p>The trouble started in 1993 when the then army rulers annulled an election to restore democratic rule. The presumed winner of the vote is detained and so are many opposition figures.</p>
<p>Many others fled abroad where they have waged a campaign against the populous and mineral-rich West African nation.</p>
<p>Executives of MIGA, which provides political risk insurance guarantee for foreign investors and since 1991, urged the government to work with their agency to sell Nigeria abroad.</p>
<p>The agency has issued about $190 million in coverage for over $1.2 billion of foreign investment in nine African nations and is active in 30 countries but Nigeria is among them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
