<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136349" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Aid agencies warn of catastrophe in eastern Zaire.</title>
<headline>Aid agencies warn of catastrophe in eastern Zaire.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>BUKAVU, Zaire 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aid agencies warned on Wednesday of catastrophe facing hundreds of thousands of people in eastern Zaire as refugees and others fled fighting.</p>
<p>Aid workers said that unless food arrived within days in the town of Bukavu, hundreds of thousands of Rwandan and Burundian refugees and displaced Zairean civilians would go hungry.</p>
<p>&quot;We are definitely facing a looming catastrophe if food supplies cannot arrive in Bukavu. We need food there immediately to go ahead for the distribution scheduled for November 3,&quot; said U.N. World Food Programme (WFP) spokeswoman Brenda Barton.</p>
<p>She said the WFP supply to Goma town, north of Bukavu, was cut when Zaire closed its borders with Uganda, stranding 2,500 tonnes of food in 68 trucks for camps in Zaire on the frontier.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali said on Tuesday he feared fighting between the army and ethnic Tutsis would deteriorate further and that there would be confrontation between Zaire and Rwanda.</p>
<p>Eastern Zaire has been set to explode in ethnic violence since genocide and civil war in Rwanda in 1994 sent more than a million Hutu refugees streaming in, stoking local rivalries.</p>
<p>But fighting has widened in the last six weeks since Zairean troops joined ethnic clashes between Tutsis, who have lived in Zaire for generations and are known as Banyamulenge, and native Zaireans.</p>
<p>U.N. officials say they fear an emergency similar to the 1994 Rwanda genocide and refugee exodus and are concerned at the possibility of regional conflict involving Rwanda and Burundi.</p>
<p>Aid workers said some 36,000 refugees abandoned Nyangezi and Nyangezi-Mulwa camps southwest of Bukavu on Tuesday and they estimated up to 50,000 refugees and displaced Zaireans crossed from Uvira area into south Bukavu on the same day.</p>
<p>&quot;These people are moving not only north but west to camps southwest of Bukavu but as many are travelling through the hills their numbers are hard to estimate,&quot; said Paul Stromberg, spokesman for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR).</p>
<p>&quot;About 1,000 people had arrived on the southern edges of Bukavu town by Tuesday night and this morning,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Aid workers said 700 refugees per hour on Tuesday were passing their hospital at Nyangezi, 22 km (14 miles) south of Bukavu, heading for the border town, which has enough food for only a few days.</p>
<p>Stromberg said 12 refugees crossed from Zaire into Rwanda on Tuesday but UNHCR was planning it would receive 75,000</p>
<p>Aid workers said on Wednesday angry Zaireans armed with spears and machetes tried to block their evacuation from eastern Zaire and it was impossible for aid agencies to work in Uvira town as nervous Zairean soldiers were looting agency vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't really afraid of the Banyamulenge. I was more afraid of defeated soldiers,&quot; said one aid worker, who declined to be identified but was evacuated from Bukavu, north of Uvira.</p>
<p>They said aid workers trying to reach Uvira airport on Monday to take a flight out were confronted by crowds of angry Zaireans wearing red bandannas and armed with spears, machetes and stones.</p>
<p>Zairean troops escorting the aid workers opened fire mostly in the air and one person in the crowd was killed, they added.</p>
<p>Troops cleared militia roadblocks from the route to Uvira airport on Tuesday, allowing a total of 58 foreign aid workers, the last in Uvira, to be evacuated to Bukavu, Uganda and Kenya.</p>
<p>&quot;People are bitter as they feel the international community is abandoning them to the Banyamulenge,&quot; one aid worker said.</p>
<p>They said they estimated 78 people were killed and 60 wounded when fighting between Banyamulenge, Zairean militas and Zairean troops broke out at Kiliba airstrip 15 km (nine miles) from Uvira on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
