<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136373" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela names S.Africa's first black chief justice.</title>
<headline>Mandela names S.Africa's first black chief justice.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela on Wednesday named Ismail Mahomed to become South Africa's first black chief justice on January 1.</p>
<p>Mandela's decision, announced by cabinet secretary Jakes Gerwel, followed a sometimes bitter public debate tinged with racial overtones.</p>
<p>Mahomed, an ethnic Indian, was appointed ahead of veteran white judge Hennie van Heerden, who, as the longest serving member of the Appeal Court, was formally in line for the job.</p>
<p>Mahomed, 65, is a South African currently serving as chief justice of neighbouring Namibia and as a member of the Constitutional Court appointed after South Africa's transition to democracy in 1994.</p>
<p>He began his career in Pretoria, where he was forced to take his tea and sandwiches in the corridors of the Supreme Court and he had to borrow desk space from sympathetic white colleagues.</p>
<p>His nomination initially won support of about a dozen of the country's Supreme Court and Appeal Court judges, almost all of them white.</p>
<p>But Mandela, charged in the constitution with the final decision who to appoint, altered the race by supporting Mahomed's candidacy at an early stage.</p>
<p>Under apartheid, judges were appointed by the government without any outside consultation.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, however, the statutory Judicial Service Commission, headed by outgoing chief justice Michael Corbett, made history by publicly interviewing the two candidates.</p>
<p>Mahomed argued for the transformation of the judiciary, which, he said, was tainted with the stain of apartheid, which it upheld in scores of judgments.</p>
<p>Declaring a &quot;moral passion...to achieve justice&quot;, he said he would see it as his role to travel widely in South Africa and abroad proclaiming his vision of transformation.</p>
<p>Van Heerden, professing contract law as his passion, said he believed the chief justice should guide the judiciary through his judgments alone.</p>
<p>The commission said in a report to Mandela that both men were fit and proper candidates for the job, but advised him to appoint Mahomed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
