<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136392" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Northam strike likely to be averted - union.</title>
<headline>Northam strike likely to be averted - union.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Union of Mineworkers (NUM) said on Wednesday that workers at Northam Platinum Ltd were debating management's latest wage offer and a planned strike at the mine was likely to be averted.</p>
<p>NUM regional coordinator Mahlakeng Mahlakeng told Reuters workers were due to discuss Northam management's latest revised wage offer at a meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The workers will be having a further meeting tomorrow and see what they can make of management's further offer,&quot; Mahlakeng said. He said chances of the workers going on strike were slim.  </p>
<p>&quot;The possibility of strike action at the moment is very slim. It is a very, very small hiccup but a final decision has to be taken by workers tomorrow,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The majority of Northam's 3,300 union members voted to strike last week after management and the union reached deadlock over wages on September 26.</p>
<p>The union had initially demanded a 15 percent pay hike but was prepared to accept management's offer of 10 percent.</p>
<p>NUM said the point of contention was wage parity, as Northam's minimum wage of around 556 rand was well below that of other mines.</p>
<p>Northam produced 75,365 ounces of precious metals in concentrates in the three months to September.</p>
<p>The mine recorded a net loss before capital spending of 7.39 million rand in the September quarter after turning in a profit of 8.17 million in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
