<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136310" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Gaelic Games - Critics say GAA too soft on disciplining players.</title>
<headline>Gaelic Games - Critics say GAA too soft on disciplining players.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Games Administration Committee (GAC) of the GAA should stiffen disciplinary action against players, former inter-county senior football manager Art McRory told Irish national broadcaster, RTE, on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The former Tyrone senior football manager, who led his team to two all-Ireland finals, said match suspensions rather than time suspensions should be handed out for player indiscretions in games.</p>
<p>&quot;The disciplinary rules of the GAA are in serious danger of breaking down if they are not tightened. Penalties for indiscipline must be much more severe,&quot; McRory said.  </p>
<p>At Tuesday night's meeting of the Games Administration Committee (GAC), suspensions were handed out to 15 players accused of being involved in a brawl in an All-Ireland final replay in Croke Park on September 29.</p>
<p>The GAA's national referee administrator, Paddy Collins, an inter-county referee for 27 years, said the GAA should have an in-depth look at player suspensions.</p>
<p>&quot;A few years the GAA tried to introduce match bans in the National Football League, but (GAA's) membership decided in a democratic fashion that they would not accept the bans and they would not enshrine them in the rules of the official guide,&quot; Collins told RTE in a telephone interview on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>--Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9779</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
