<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136399" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zambia says 21 firms interested in ZCCM assets.</title>
<headline>Zambia says 21 firms interested in ZCCM assets.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambian Finance Minister Ronald Penza said on Wednesday the country had a pre-qualification shortlist of 21 firms interested in the assets of state copper mining group, Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines (ZCCM).</p>
<p>Zambia is pushing ahead with an aggressive privatisation programme which has seen more than 130 companies sold off to date. But the up and coming privatisation of ZCCM is the by far the biggest and is expected to attract wide foreign interest.</p>
<p>Penza said pre-qualification bidders represented a wide range of international investors.</p>
<p>&quot;They range from Chinese companies to Americans,&quot; he told Reuters at the Southern African Trade and Investment Summit in Harare. Firms from France, Japan, South Africa and Britain were also on the list.</p>
<p>An announcement detailing further plans for ZCCM's sell off is expected early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;March, 1997 should have the selection process done and we will be able to start announcements,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Penza declined to say how much the ZCCM privatisation would raise for the Zambian government, but said cash was not the main issue.</p>
<p>Instead privatisation would create a more efficient, stream-lined and modern mining industry that would better add to economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to create an industry that will make the company a net contributor to the growth of the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Harare Newsroom + 263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
