<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136321" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: GM Canada pact paves way for production, UAW deal.</title>
<headline>GM Canada pact paves way for production, UAW deal.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Hopkins</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp. plants and suppliers idled by a 20-day strike in Canada were set to creak back to life after Wednesday's expected ratification of a new labour contract with the Canadian Auto Workers union.</p>
<p>About 26,000 CAW workers were set to vote on the new contract at meetings in Ontario and Quebec and results were due Wednesday evening, union officials said.</p>
<p>Approval of the new pact also was expected to clear the way for GM to reach a quick labour agreement in the United States with the much-larger United Auto Workers union.</p>
<p>Some UAW sources said Wednesday that a deal could be reached in a matter of days. The U.S. talks, which affect 215,000 hourly workers, were moving quickly when the Canadian strike started on Oct. 2 and stole the spotlight from UAW President Stephen Yokich.</p>
<p>&quot;I think without question they would have settled by now, but the UAW did not want to undermine the Canadian union's negotiating stance,&quot; said Harley Shaiken, a professor of labour relations at the University of California-Berkeley. &quot;The (UAW) negotiations will move very quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>Sources close to the talks said they thought that GM will agree to guarantee jobs for 95 percent of its UAW work force -- nominally the same terms that rivals Ford Motor Co. and Chrysler Corp. agreed to -- but that level may exclude some U.S. parts plants now up for sale.</p>
<p>As in Canada, the major unresolved issues in the United States include GM's ability to shift work to outside suppliers, known as outsourcing, and the sale of parts plants.</p>
<p>In the Canadian settlement, GM won the right to sell parts plants in Windsor and Oshawa, Ontario, employing 3,850. The automaker also wants to sell a door hardware plant in Flint, Mich., and an interior trim plant in Livonia, Mich., that together employ 2,100 UAW members.</p>
<p>UAW officials said the buyer for all four of the U.S. and Canadian plants was Joseph, Littlejohn and Levy, a New York-based investment firm that owns other auto parts firms.</p>
<p>GM also has said it was studying options for other parts plants. It has about a dozen facilities that it considers &quot;troubled.&quot;</p>
<p>The three-year Canadian pact, in addition to allowing GM to sell the Ontario parts plants, includes a pledge by the automaker to recognise limits on outsourcing.</p>
<p>The union, in turn, made a major concession by accepting that GM's business plan may require deviance from a pattern agreement reached in September with Chrysler.</p>
<p>Some of GM's Canadian workers will return to their jobs on Thursday and all of the automaker's Canadian operations will be running normally by Nov. 4, union officials said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our employees are going to get back to work and we're going to get this Canadian economy rolling,&quot; GM Canada chief negotiator Dean Munger said after the deal was reached Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The walkout by Canadian workers idled 20,000 GM workers in the United States and Mexico and paralysed suppliers across North America.</p>
<p>Oshawa, Ontario-based Verspeeten Cartage Ltd., which idled about 360 of its 400 workers during the walkout, said a return to pre-strike delivery levels for its fleet of transport trucks would take up to 10 days.</p>
<p>&quot;(GM is) telling us that all the operations won't be back until Nov. 4. The truck plant in Oshawa is starting tomorrow night, the car plants (in Oshawa and Ste-Therese, Quebec) will start up Nov. 4. So we should be back to normal Nov. 4,&quot; said Verspeeten's operations manager Frank Cassano.</p>
<p>Analysts said the strike's effect on U.S. plants could last for several more days becuse the parts pipeline from Canada may take a while to refill.</p>
<p>David Healy, an auto analyst with Burnham Securities Inc., said production losses due to the strike will not be fully known until all plants return to pre-strike levels.</p>
<p>Healy said GM's fourth-quarter net income will be reduced by at least $225 million, a quarter of the $900 million impact of a strike at two GM brake plants in Dayton, Ohio, in March.</p>
<p>Ronald Glantz, of Dean Witter Reynolds Inc., estimated the earnings hit at $150 million to $450 million.</p>
<p>Economists initially said the strike at Canada's largest private employer could cost the Canadian economy at least C$1 billion ($740 million), but analysts said the brevity of the strike will minimise its impact.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
