<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136330" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Imasco sees poor results at Hardee's.</title>
<headline>Imasco sees poor results at Hardee's.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Imasco Ltd said on Wednesday that it expects unsatisfactory results from its U.S.-based Hardee's fast-food chain in the current fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are clearly going to have unsatisfactory results from Hardee's this year, Imasco's other businesses are all growing and performing well. This should result in satisfactory earnings growth for Imasco as a whole in 1996,&quot; Brian Levitt, president and chief executive, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Imasco said that while showing some improvement over the second quarter, the sales trends at Hardee's continue to be negative, producing a further deterioratin in earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Efforts to strengthen marketing and operations are continuing, but progress in rebuilding sales is being hindered by the heightened level of competitor activity that currently defines the industry,&quot; Imasco said.</p>
<p>Imasco said it expects a pre-tax gain of about C$320 million on total proceeds of about C$937 million from its sale announced in August of First Federal Savings and Loan Association of Rochester. The sale is subject to regulatory approval and is expected to close within four months, the company said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
