<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136357" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian group seeks coalition of opposition.</title>
<headline>Nigerian group seeks coalition of opposition.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Nigerian opposition group called on anti-government organisations on Wednesday to forge a common front against the country's military rulers.</p>
<p>&quot;A time has come for all of us to close ranks and organise ourselves into a common front to face the common enemy -- the military,&quot; Osagie Obayuwana, spokesman of the National Conscience Party (NCP), said at a Lagos news conference to mark the second anniversary of the party's founding.</p>
<p>It is not clear how many people the NCP represents. The party is unregistered and did not seek legitimacy from the electoral commission, which last month licensed five political parties to contest elections under General Sani Abacha's programme to hand over power to an elected president in 1998.</p>
<p>NCP founder Gani Fawehinmi, a radical lawyer, was arrested last January before he could address an anti-government rally.</p>
<p>Obayuwana said Fawehinmi had been transferred to an eye hospital in northern Kaduna after he &quot;developed an eye problem serious enough to make us fear he might go blind.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We should eschew bitterness, acrimony and rancour in our various organisations so that we will not be a disappointment to the masses whose cause we profess to fight for,&quot; he told the press conference attended by leaders of some human rights groups, families of detainees, students and reporters.</p>
<p>The NCP earlier in the year initiated a coalition of all human rights organisations that led to formation of the Joint Action Committee, but which has remained dormant.</p>
<p>Dozens of pro-democracy and human rights groups have sprung up in Nigeria since 1993 when the army annulled a presidential poll to restore democracy but their opposition has hardly gone beyond issuing press statements.</p>
<p>Nigeria was widely condemned last November after the hanging of author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority activists for murder despite worldwide appeals for clemency.</p>
<p>Dozens of opposition figures are in detention or in exile, including Moshood Abiola who is widely believed to have won the annulled election. Three detainees were released recently.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
