<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136308" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Rugby Union-Campese gets a kick out of 100th cap.</title>
<headline>Rugby Union-Campese gets a kick out of 100th cap.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>PADUA, Italy 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian winger David Campese collected his 100th international cap -- and a first minute kick -- on Wednesday before his adoring fans as the Wallabies pushed aside Italy 40-18.</p>
<p>The visitors celebrated at the whistle but it was more in relief than anything else after finding themselves lagging behind the hosts 18-13 in the second half.</p>
<p>Campese, 34 years old last Monday, was first out of the tunnel to a roar from the 7,000 strong crowd in the northern city where the Australian of Italian origin played three seasons and won two league titles.</p>
<p>A banner read &quot;Some say God, we say Campo!&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was great...but the guys didn't follow me,&quot; the winger said of his ovation at the start of his 18th tour.</p>
<p>Only Frenchman Philippe Sella -- with 111 caps -- has played more internationals than Campese and the Australian intends to pick up a few more before he is done.</p>
<p>Campese was unable to add to his tally of 64 tries but it was undoubtedly his night even if Australia were labouring up until the later stages of the second half.</p>
<p>The winger, despite a few delightful touches, admitted he had a subdued first half after being kicked.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I just tried too hard,&quot; he said, surrounded by well-wishers and autograph seekers. &quot;It's my first game for seven weeks and we knew it was always going to be hard.</p>
<p>&quot;I just got a kick in the (left) leg in the first minute of the game,&quot; he said, an ice-pack strapped to it.</p>
<p>Full-back Mathew Burke missed three penalty kicks in the first 10 minutes before flanker David Wilson put the visitors ahead with a try after Michael Brial made the run.</p>
<p>Stefano Bordon put Italy back in the game with a 22nd minute try and former Puma fly-half Diego Dominguez delighted the crowd with a drop goal in the 25th as a confident Italy team took the lead for the first time.</p>
<p>Burke replied with a penalty in the 33rd and another on the stroke of half time.</p>
<p>Six minutes into the second half Dominguez deftly side-stepped limping fly-half David Knox for Italy's second try and then converted for a 15-13 lead.</p>
<p>Knox was replaced by Jason Little in the 47th minute as Australia went further behind to a Dominguez penalty. Knox said he would be having an X-ray of his knee.</p>
<p>Burke kicked two more penalties to put Australia 18-19 ahead before the American referee Ed Sorenson -- officiating with two U.S. line judges as well -- gave the visitors a helping hand with a call that incensed the locals.</p>
<p>He ruled Australia had scored a pushover try despite Italian protests that he had not as the crowd shouted &quot;idiot, idiot&quot;. Daniel Manu was later awarded the try.</p>
<p>Italy scored no further points and faded badly, with Australian vice-captain Tim Horan scoring a beautiful try in the 75th minute -- depite further Italian protests about its legitimacy -- and Wilson his second in the last minute.</p>
<p>&quot;I was very worried but its a game of 80 minutes and the final result showed the difference between the sides,&quot; declared Australian coach Greg Smith afterwards.</p>
<p>Italy's French coach Georges Coste was incensed by the refereeing and said two of the visitor's tries were dubious.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sorry about the score. They (Australia) didn't deserve it. It's too much for them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Italy - 15-Javier Pertile, 14-Massimo Ravazzolo, 13-Stefano Bordon, 12-Ivan Francescato, 11-Leandro Manteri, 10-Diego Dominguez, 9-Alesandro Troncon, 8-Orazio Arancio, 7-Andrea Sgorlon, 6-Massimo Giovanelli, 5-Diego Scaglia, 4-Walter Cristofoletto (Andrea Baratin, 76th), 3-Franco Properzi, 2-Carlo Orlandi, 1-Mauro Dal Sie.</p>
<p>Australia - 15-Matthew Burke, 14-Tim Horan, 13-Daniel Herbert, 12-Pat Howard, 11-David Campese, 10-David Knox (17-Jason Little, 47th), 9-George Gregan, 8-Michael Brial (19-Brett Robinson, 45th), 7-David Wilson, 6-Daniel Manu, 5-John Eales, 4-John Welborn, 3-Andrew Heath, 2-Michael Foley, 1-Richard Harry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PADUA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
