<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136348" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Zambia's Kaunda, hindered by laws, boycotts poll.</title>
<headline>Zambia's Kaunda, hindered by laws, boycotts poll.</headline>
<byline>Jowie Mwiinga</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambia's former president Kenneth Kaunda, now the main opposition leader, said on Wednesday his party would boycott general elections that President Frederick Chiluba has called for November 18.</p>
<p>Disputed constitutional changes passed in May by a parliament dominated by Chiluba supporters block Kaunda from running for president, but his United National Independence Party (UNIP) is free to take part.</p>
<p>Kaunda, president for almost three decades until Chiluba ousted him in Zambia's first free elections in 1991, told a news conference neither he nor his party would participate.</p>
<p>&quot;After a thorough examination of the state of our nation and events leading up to the election, UNIP has decided deliberately and consciously that we will not participate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to peace-loving Zambians not to cast their votes in this sham election.&quot;</p>
<p>Kaunda said Chiluba's Movement for Multiparty Democracy (MMD) had changed the rules and tampered with the voters' register -- which omits half the country's 4.6 million adults -- to give itself a sure majority.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not legitimise an arrangement like that. It is criminal,&quot; said Kaunda, 72.</p>
<p>He said UNIP would stage rallies against the government even if the gatherings were banned, but would refrain from violence.</p>
<p>&quot;We will fight them through demonstrations and rallies, whether we have police permits or not,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Usually tranquil Zambia has shown growing signs of unrest in the last year as criticism grows that Chiluba, whose election was heralded as the birth of a new democratic era, has changed the rules to stay in power.</p>
<p>Several members of Kaunda's UNIP are on trial for treason after allegedly executing a spate of bombings. UNIP says the charges are politically motivated.</p>
<p>Kaunda's threat of civil disobedience if police crack down on his rallies could spark fresh violence, while his boycott will cast further doubt on the legitimacy of a poll that foreign donor nations are already criticising.</p>
<p>They have threatened to block fresh aid to Zambia unless Chiluba, 52, overturns what they say are unfair constitutional amendments that stop Kaunda challenging him.</p>
<p>Analysts say voter turnout could be crucial for how donors react.</p>
<p>The new constitution bans presidential candidates who have served two terms as president already, which rules out Kaunda. He led Zambia to independence from Britain in 1964 and ruled without interruption until Chiluba won the last election.</p>
<p>It also bars anyone whose parents were not born in Zambia. Kaunda's came from neighbouring Malawi.</p>
<p>His deputy, chief Inyambo Yeta, is also disqualified by an new clause banning traditional leaders from active politics.</p>
<p>Ironically, most political observers say Chiluba faced no real threat even if Kaunda had run for president.</p>
<p>A plethora of smaller opposition parties who represent no danger to the president are still expected to take part in the election despite only a month's notice.</p>
<p>Zambians will have two votes -- one for a member of parliament and a direct vote for the presidential candidate.</p>
<p>Chiluba said at the weekend that constitutional amendments allowed his government to stay in office for up to three months beyond the expiry of its five-year term on October 31.</p>
<p>&quot;I remain president before, during and after the elections. And before I hand over power to myself or somebody else, I will still be in power. There will be no vacuum. I will still be in power,&quot; he told supporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
