<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136378" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rand finished a touch firmer in thin dealings at the official close on Wednesday, but the currency and long bonds then weakened in thin after-hours dealings, traders said.</p>
<p>The local currency stood at 4.5685/5735 on the dollar at 1400 GMT from 4.5705/5755 at the Tuesday finish, but had slipped to 4.5730/80 by 1500 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very quiet this afternoon. The rand stayed in a tight 4.5675-4.5750 range,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders said there had been light volume importer demand at the bottom of the range, while a handful of exporters had sold dollars at the top of the band.</p>
<p>In the morning, the rand succumbed to see-saw trade, starting off firmer on a weaker U.S. dollar overnight, exporter supply and long dollar position-squaring.</p>
<p>By noon, however, the local unit had retraced from its initial strength on offshore dollar demand sliding to a worst level of 4.5725 bid on the dollar early in the afternoon.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the rand to hold in a 4.5650-4.5750 band on Thursday.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last at 7.2984/3110 on the British pound after falling to an all-time low of 7.3067 bid in after-hours trade on Tuesday. On the mark, the rand was at 0.3322/3327 from 0.3353/3357 previously.</p>
<p>Key long bonds were weaker in late trading, still depressed by disappointing consumer inflation data.</p>
<p>September CPI rose 1.0 percent month-on-month and 8.4 percent year-on-year in September. A Reuters poll of economists forecast a consensus 0.7 percent month-on-month and 8.1 percent annual rise.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market was suffering from a lack of interest.</p>
<p>At 1400 GMT the key R150 was 15.44 percent from 15.375 percent, but rose steadily to a worst level of 15.55 percent on a technical break by 1500 GMT, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;When the key 15.45 percent level was broken, yields just went up. There has been selling from both offshore and local people,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>After-hours dealings are generally thin, allowing for sharp movements in bond yields.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures show foreigners bought a net 36.29 million rand worth of South African bonds on Tuesday after selling a net 47.77 million rand on Monday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 3.93 billion rand from 2.51 billion rand on Monday.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs were steady at between 16.15 percent bid and 16 percent. The 90-day BA rate was unchanged at between 15.55 and 15.40 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank indicated the daily shortage at 7.629 billion rand on Tuesday from 8.0 billion rand on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
