<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136371" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian shares rise in stormy trade.</title>
<headline>Nigerian shares rise in stormy trade.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nigerian stock trade rose in a stormy session on Wednesday despite continued slide in blue chip shares, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 6616.17, up from 6611.27 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Robust haggling over prices between bulls and bears punctuated the session, but the bears succeeded in keeping price gains on the moderate side, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Those making unjustifiably big prices want the market to collapse but we will resist the attempt,&quot; one of the bears said.</p>
<p>Recent slump in share prices precipitated by large dumping by investors who want to take cash has prompted many traders to maintain caution in price making.</p>
<p>Attempts to hike prices of petroleum marketing companies were blocked despite investors' interest in their shares because most traders said some half-year results were pending.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides, when these stocks get ridiculously high, the same people pushing them up now will be resisting their fall if they have to come down,&quot; one trader added.</p>
<p>National Oil managed to advance by 30 kobo to close at 36.50 naira, topping the oil sector's gainers chart.</p>
<p>Unipetrol was 15 kobo up at 43.35 naira while Total, Mobil and African Petroleum rose 10 kobo each to 48.60 naira, 41.10 naira and 35.00 naira respectively. Texaco added five kobo to 27.50 naira.</p>
<p>Nestle continued its impressive rise, rising 50 kobo to 36.00 naira.</p>
<p>West African Portland Cement climbed 20 kobo to 36.05 naira, the same as National Salt Company, whose 66.8 million shares offered in a recent rights issue, were listed for trading. It rose to 4.84 naira.</p>
<p>Lever Brothers was Wednesday's major decliner, five kobo down to 25.60 naira. Fellow conglomerate John Holt slumped to 10.40 naira, down three kobo.</p>
<p>But the biggest casualty in percentage terms was packaging firm Avon Crowncaps which shed 19 kobo at 3.71 naira. First Aluminium lost seven kobo at 4.50 naira.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
