<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136391" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Ethnic poison, old jealousies feed war in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Ethnic poison, old jealousies feed war in Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>BUKAVU, Zaire 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ethnic poison between Hutus and Tutsis in Central Africa is feeding a multi-sided war and a humanitarian crisis in east Zaire. Outlines of the main groups in the region follow:</p>
<p>BANYAMULENGE - An estimated 300,000 ethnic Tutsis who moved to what is now eastern Zaire from Rwanda generations ago but were denied Zairean citizenship in 1981. They are hated by many Zaireans on grounds of ethnicity, language and the land and cattle they own.</p>
<p>Thousands of Banyamulenge crossed back into Rwanda during the genocide in 1994 and joined Tutsi-led Rwandan rebels who seized power and now dominate the Rwandan government army.</p>
<p>Banyamulenge say their fighters are protecting their people from genocide planned by Zairean politicians and the army. They say 500 Banyamulenge have been killed since fighting began last month.</p>
<p>Aid officials say they are surprised by the relative military success recently of armed Banyamulenge groups, which have demonstrated a strong knowledge of key routes and ambush sites within their south Kivu homeland and can use large, sudden movements of frightened Rwandan and Burundian Hutu refugees to distract the army and cloak their own movements in the region.</p>
<p>ZAIREAN ARMY - One of the most notoriously ill-disciplined government forces in the world, the Zairean army beefed up its presence in eastern Zaire in September as confrontation grew with the Banyamulenge.</p>
<p>Its troops, particularly when they suffer a military defeat or lose comrades, frequently go on the rampage in civilian centres, shooting in the air, looting aid agency vehicles and stealing to augment their small and rarely paid salaries.</p>
<p>But state Zairean radio on Wednesday urged the population to contribute money to help Zairean troops in &quot;the war in the east&quot; and a spokesman quoted President Mobutu Sese Seko, being treated for cancer in Switzerland, as urging the government in Kinshasa to concentrate on blocking &quot;invaders devastating the east&quot;.</p>
<p>ZAIREAN MILITIAS - Zairean militias are drawn from various tribes in the east which resent the Banyamulenge presence and are keen to drive the ethnic Tutsis out and seize their land and cattle. They say they protect Zairean settlements from attack.</p>
<p>RWANDAN REFUGEES - An estimated 1.1 million Rwandan refugees from the Hutu majority who fled their homeland in 1994 during the genocide of up to one million Tutsis and Hutu moderates by Hutu troops, militiamen and mobs.</p>
<p>The Zairean government has demanded they return home and has repeatedly threatened to expel them all but most say they are too frightened of reprisals for the 1994 slaughter to go.</p>
<p>Refugee camps in eastern Zaire near the border with Rwanda are also used as bases by former Rwandan Hutu militiamen from groups such as the Interahamwe, which played a leading role in the 1994 genocide and threaten refugees against returning.</p>
<p>Eastern Zaire also has camps for the estimated 40,000 former Rwandan Hutu government troops which fled to Zaire. Rwanda accuses the Zairean government of backing exiled Hutu forces.</p>
<p>BURUNDIAN REFUGEES - An estimated 200,000 Burundian Hutu refugees, some of whom fled Burundi as long ago as 1972, are inter-mixed with Rwandan Hutus in the camps in eastern Zaire, particularly in the troubled Uvira area facing east Burundi.</p>
<p>The Burundian government accuses Hutu rebels fighting the Tutsi-dominated army inside Burundi of being based in Zaire and has repeatedly called on Zaire to crack down on them.</p>
<p>RWANDAN ARMY - The 54,000-strong Rwanda Patriotic Army (RPA) is dominated by the country's Tutsi minority which seized power in July 1994 and ended the genocide by the Hutu majority.</p>
<p>It says it has no plans to intervene in eastern Zaire in support of fellow Tutsis among the Banyamulenge. Zaire however says RPA troops fired on Bukavu last month and aided by Burundian troops has attacked both north and south Kivu. It says Rwandan soldiers with the help of aid workers infilatrated eastern Zaire before September to support the Banyamulenge.</p>
<p>BURUNDIAN ARMY - The 28,000 Burundian army is dominated by the Tutsi minority and is hard pressed fighting a grinding civil war with Hutu rebels. It has good relations with the RPA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
