<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136385" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: NSA buys 24 mln rand Master Fridge stake.</title>
<headline>NSA buys 24 mln rand Master Fridge stake.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>NSA Investments Ltd has bought an initial nine percent stake in Master Fridge Ltd with immediate effect for 23.9 million rand, the companies said in a joint statement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The companies were also examining ways in which the stake could be increased to 20 percent by July 1, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial transaction for a nine percent equity holding involves the issue of 7.5 million Master Fridge shares to NSA for cash of 23.9 million rand at an issue price of 3.20 rand per share,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;A further equity stake will be acquired by NSA through the issue of 17.3 million in non-interest bearing debentures by Master Fridge to NSA convertable into 5.4 million Master Fridge shares at a price of 3.20 rand per share on July 1, 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Master Fridge has an estimated 45 percent market share of refrigeration and freezer products in South Africa.</p>
<p>It listed on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange on April 29 and has five production plants - all located in Swaziland.</p>
<p>The companies said Master Fridge was well positioned for growth in view of electricity utility Eskom's aim to provide electricity to 10,000 new households every month.</p>
<p>NSA said Master Frigde fitted its investment strategy to take significant minority interests in high quality, medium-sized companies with long-term potential to grow earnings above the market average.</p>
<p>Master Fridge executive director Bronwen Phillips said the cash injection would impact positively on bottom line earnings and place it in an even more competitive export position.</p>
<p>&quot;This transaction will help maintain the momentum we have built up over the last few years,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
