<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136374" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Investors want predictable policies - Anglo.</title>
<headline>Investors want predictable policies - Anglo.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southern Africa must pursue predictable economic, social and political policies to attract vital foreign investment, Nicholas Oppenheimer, deputy chairman of Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer, who is also the deputy chairman of De Beers, told a Southern African Trade and Investment summit here that there was also need for a free market, a stable currency and an independent judiciary.</p>
<p>He also urged guarantees for profit and capital repatriation, non-punitive taxes and a flexible and productive labour market.</p>
<p>&quot;What they add up to is predictability. For nothing is more inimical to investors than uncertainty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer also cautioned government leaders in Southern Africa against hardline political rhetoric, which he said may scare away potential investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Speeches... will be heard and heeded on the trading floors of London, Tokyo and New York, and they could make the difference between joblessness and employment for hundreds of people, between poverty and a widening circle of wealth and prosperity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In an economic world without boundaries, politicians can no longer afford the luxury of different voices for different audiences, different strokes for different strokes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zimbabwean president Robert Mugabe has been pursuing such a two-track policy over the years, assuring foreign investors they are welcome but threatening to punish big businesses at home for allegedly failing to support some of his policies, including economic empowerment of the majority blacks.</p>
<p>Oppenheimer said he supported black economic empowerment. &quot;It needs to be done in a sensible way and in a way that is sustainable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Cris Chinaka, Harare newsroom +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
