<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136302" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Oct 24.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Oct 24.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Victoria Racing Club general manager of racing, Les Benton, yesterday declared Irish stayer Oscar Schindler was the &quot;reincarnation of Phar Lap&quot;, as thejoint favourite for the A$2.2 million Foster's Melbourne Cup arrived in Australia in a glare of publiciy. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following the recent Full Federal Court decision on the Super League case, proprietary racing company teleTrak Australia Pty Ltd has served the Principal Racing Clubs of Australia with letters of demand containing a potential A$40 million damages claim. Pae 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Speaking before the one-off clash with Italy in Padua this morning, Wallaby winger Joe Roff discussed the pain and anger he suffered when he was dumped for a Tri-Nation rugby union Test against the Springboks last year. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Aussie baseballer Graeme Lloyd fulfilled his dream this week by playing for the Yankees in the World Series against the Atlanta Braves at Yankee Stadium, where the Yankees won game three of the series, 5-2. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's top match-racing skipper for the past decade, Peter Gilmour, who was head coach for the Nippon challenge in 1995, is almost certainly going to be skippering the Japanese challenger in the next America's Cup, to be sailed from Auckland in 2000.Page 47.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The result of recent approaches by several State athletics bodies, amid ongoing discontent with the state of athletics in Australia, is that Hobart surgeon Terry Dwyer, a founder and now director of the Menzies Research Institute, will challenge for the presidency of Athletics Australia next month. Page 47.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Champion cricketer Shane Warne said last night he had been reassured by medicos his injured finger was recovering from May surgery at a respectable rate, dismissing fears about his long-term future in the sport. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>There was a momentary panic for the VRC Spring racing carnival yesterday about the visit of famed jockey Frankie Dettori, who may have other commitments overseas. However, Dettori said last night he is 99.9 per cent certain to be available to leave for Autralia next week as planned. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Age racing writer Les Carlyon received A$15,000 yesterday after winning the &quot;best previously published writing&quot; category of the 1996 CUB best Australian sportswriting and photography awards. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>After winning yesterday's Geelong Cup, front-running stayer Hereditas qualified for the Melbourne Cup, where he is still a long-shot at 66-1, running 49th in Cup order of entry. Still, the win gave trainer Peter Hayes a much needed boost. Page 96.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Up to 20 Fitzroy players are expected to be drafted following Friday's Australian Football League national draft, with the club's best-and-fairest winner Martin Pike among the 27 former Lions who nominated. Discarded Adelaide Crow Andrew Jarman has also rvealed he wants to play for Collingwood next season. Page 94.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Adelaide-trained Prince Miasma will attempt to be the first horse since Dayana in 1972 to complete the Derby Trial-Victoria Derby Double after winning yesterday's Geelong Derby Trial Stakes win. Page 92.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>With a view to betting on matches next season, FootyTAB officials are hoping to conduct favourable discussions with Super League in coming weeks to ensure the agency fields bets on the Australian Rugby League and Super League games. Page 94.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former Socceroo Abbas Saad, who has been back in Australia for the past six weeks, yesterday had his life ban on bribery charges lifted by FIFA and will resume his soccer career with his old club UTS Olympic. Page 94.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The West Australian Football Commission has informed the Australian Football League it will not be playing in the State of Origin season next year, meaning the only Origin game will be between Victoria and South Australia in Adelaide. Page 94.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
