<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136369" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South African meat board to be dissolved.</title>
<headline>South African meat board to be dissolved.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Meat Board is to be dissolved in line with stipulations of a new agricultural marketing bill passed by parliament last month, the board said on Monday.</p>
<p>The Marketing of Agricultural Products Bill calls for the dismantling of remaining agricultural control boards within a year of the first meeting of the marketing council, and requires industries to manage their affairs on a market-related basis.</p>
<p>&quot;The effect...is that the Meat Board, and the functions that the Meat Board performs, will be phased out over this period and will cease to exist once the sunset time period has expired,&quot; said Pieter Kempen, the board's general manager.</p>
<p>The board will be restructured into a non-profit making association in terms of section 21 of the Companies Act and will take over the board's current functions.</p>
<p>These include coordination and control of industry standards, promotion of meat consumption and supply, and provision of information to members, Kempen said.</p>
<p>Until 1993 the board intervened in the marketing of meat and meat products, setting floor prices in the domestic market and operating a single channel export and import system.</p>
<p>Kempen said the board would consult with the industry on a levy for the 1997 year. It was likely to be 5.50 rand per beef carcass, unchanged from 1996, and generate income of about 40 million rand.</p>
<p>In accordance with the new marketing bill, the board's funds will be transferred to a trust which will invest the money.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100119">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
