<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136350" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: FOCUS - Ivorian 96/97 farm-gate cocoa price flat.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Ivorian 96/97 farm-gate cocoa price flat.</headline>
<byline>Marc Koffi</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ivory Coast begins its 1996/97 cocoa marketing campaign on Thursday with the farm-gate price remaining unchanged at 320 CFA francs per kilo, Agriculture Minister Lambert Kouassi Konan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1995/96 cocoa campaign ends today October 23,&quot; he told a news conference on Wednesday. &quot;The 1996/97 campaign begins Thursday October 24.&quot;</p>
<p>Kouassi Konan said the 320 CFA franc per kilo price for cocoa, as last season, included five cents for the sack. Exporters had been expecting no significant change.  </p>
<p>Kouassi Konan said the government had approved on Wednesday without amendment a decision taken by the Caisse de Stabiliastion marketing board on the campaign.</p>
<p>Noting that the 1995/96 campaign was ending on Wednesday, he added: &quot;As a result, remaining stocks must be declared to the Caistab.&quot;</p>
<p>The opening of the season has been delayed by about three weeks. The government has given no explanation but some exporters link the delay to the appointment only last month of a new Caistab head, Yves-Marie Koissy.  </p>
<p>Koissy, who previously worked for the International Monetary Fund in Washington, has formally taken over but is not expected back in Ivory Coast until mid-November.</p>
<p>Exporters said earlier this week that they were expecting no significant change in the price but October cocoa arrivals have been slow, with everyone waiting for the formal announcement.</p>
<p>One Abidjan-based trader put weekly arrivals at 5,000-6,000 tonnes. &quot;Average weekly arrivals are on average 5,000-6,000 tonnes, 7,000 maximum, for both Abidjan and San Pedro (combined),&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would say arrivals since the beginning of October are at least 20,000 tonnes, but it is very difficult to say,&quot; said a second Abidjan exporter.</p>
<p>Estimated arrivals by this time in the 1995/96 season ranged from 22,000 to 47,000 tonnes, about the same as during the 1994/95 season. October 1995 presidential elections and political and ethnic violence in part of the western cocoa growing zone slowed arrivals at the start of the 1995/96 season, which produced a record of around 1.2 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>Exporters in Abidjan and the western port of San Pedro say quality of arrivals is very good and pod count estimations range from 95 to 100 beans per 100 grammes. &quot;Quality is excellent, and average pod count is between 95-98. There are no problems with humidity,&quot; said one San Pedro exporter earlier this week.</p>
<p>Kouassi Konan, noting that world coffee prices were low, said Ivory Coast would announce a date for the start of its coffee campaign and farm-gate priced before the end of this year. The two are normally announced at the same time as the cocoa but the season general does not start until November.  </p>
<p>Commodities Minister Guy-Alain Gauze, speaking on the sidelines of a two-day ministerial review in Gabon of the 1993 International Cocoa Agreement, said on Monday Ivory Coast's 1996/97 cocoa production would be between 900,000 and 950,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very important element as it coincides with World Bank and International Monetary Fund plans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=515 CFA francs)</p>
<p>-- Abidjan newsroom +225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
