<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136340" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BHP hopes for final Canada mine approval.</title>
<headline>BHP hopes for final Canada mine approval.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd said Wednesday it is hopeful of gaining final approval from the Canadian government for its Arctic diamond mine after signing a socio-economic accord with the Northwest Territories.</p>
<p>BHP manager Jim Excell said the company signed the agreement Tuesday. It formalizes BHP's commitment to ensure thet two-thirds of the jobs at the Lac de Gras mine go to northern resodents and half of those to aboriginal people. It also provides for training and other benefits. BHP is in a venture with Dia Met Minerals Ltd on the project.  </p>
<p>Canada's federal government approved the diamond mine in principle in August and said it aimed to grant final approval in early October after the company made significant progress toward socio-economic benefit agreements with local groups and an environmental accord. The company has been in intense negotiations over the past two months.</p>
<p>Asked if he felt the pact with the Northwest Territories government brought the project closer to final approval, Excell said, &quot;All these agreements are helpful in gaining that.&quot; The company hopes &quot;to hear something fairly soon&quot; from the federal cabinet.  </p>
<p>BHP wants a speedy decision so it can take advantage of a short transportation and construction season in the frigid area.</p>
<p>The company also completed hearings Tuesday on a water license for the project. A decision from the territorial water board is expected in several weeks, Excell said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
