<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136394" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius stocks stable in quiet trading.</title>
<headline>Mauritius stocks stable in quiet trading.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks on the Mauritian bourse ended generally unchanged in quiet trading on Wednesday as market sentiment is still on a &quot;wait and see attitude&quot;, brokers said.</p>
<p>Market index Semdex eased 0.05 points to 305.41 with turnover of 5.23 million rupees on 153,911 shares from 5.65 million rupees on 176,839 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>The Semdex was seen stabilising after weekend comments by Prime Minister Navin Ramgoolam who indicated a long awaited government cabinet reshuffle would be announced after the country's municipal elections on October 27.</p>
<p>&quot;The Semdex is still retreading, that's true. But as compared to the past two weeks when the index has been losing about two points per session, the slide has slowed down,&quot; a share dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although investors are always shy before any reshuffle, some more adventurous ones are taking positions on stocks of companies operating in more promising sectors like banking and hotel,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank was unchanged at 70 rupees on 18,550 shares and State Bank of Mauritius remained at 8.50 rupees on 37,700 shares.</p>
<p>In the hotel sector, Sun Resorts was unchanged at 34 rupees on 5,068 shares and New Mauritius Hotels was stable at 26.50 rupees on 21,224 shares.</p>
<p>One big deal also was noted in sugar based stock Harel Freres which gained 20 cents to 41 rupees on 30,300 shares.</p>
<p>Record earnings of 8.1 billion rupees anticipated for the country's sugar exports this year recently boosted stocks in the sugar sector.</p>
<p>British American Insurance was stable at 7 rupees on 5,700 shares. Fincorp Investment gained 50 cents to 69.50 rupees on 3,034 shares.</p>
<p>National Investment Trust fell by 30 cents to 10.50 rupees on 2,570 shares but Mauritius Development Investment Trust rose 10 cents to 6.80 rupees on 7,894 shares.</p>
<p>Happy World Foods was flat at 14 rupees on 1,891 shares. National carrier Air Mauritius remained at 46.70 rupees on 5,450 shares and Caudan Debentures ended unchanged at 1,080 rupees on 720 units traded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
