<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136354" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's Forbes gives terms of Servgro offer.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's Forbes gives terms of Servgro offer.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Forbes Group Ltd on Wednesday gave the terms of a 26.2 million rand renounceable offer to Servgro International Ltd shareholders, made as part of its listing programme.</p>
<p>&quot;Forbes is offering Servgro shareholders the right to subscribe for shares in Forbes on the basis of four new Forbes shares for every 100 Servgro shares at 535 cents a Forbes share,&quot; a statement from the financial services concern said.</p>
<p>It said Servgro's stake in Forbes would be reduced to 63.8 percent from 70 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Forbes's listing will raise approximately 102.25 million rand and the group will have a market capitalisation of approximately 1.0 billion rand,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The company said on Monday that institutions had eagerly snapped up a tender offer aimed at raising 60 million rand.</p>
<p>Forbes consists of employee benefits consultancy Alexander Forbes and Price Forbes, Africa's largest short-term insurance broker and risk management company.</p>
<p>The group has forecast gross revenues of 611 million rand and attributable earnings of 70 million rand for the year to March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>The firm wants to list in order to establish itself as an independent business with its own profile and objectives, to raise additional capital for expansion of the business in the short-term both locally and internationally, and to facilitate its future long-term expansion.</p>
<p>Forbes shares are expected to start trading in the JSE's insurance sector on November 4.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
