<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136396" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius rupee weakened vs dollar, pound in Sept.</title>
<headline>Mauritius rupee weakened vs dollar, pound in Sept.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritian rupee weakened by 1.4 percent against the dollar during the month of September, trading on a daily average rate of 20.650 rupees for one dollar in September from 20.360 rupees in August, a central bank report said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Bank of Mauritius attributed the weaker rupee in September to international trends and added the rupee was also down by three percent against the U.S. currency during the third quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Against the pound, the rupee lost two percent in September and four percent during the third quarter 1996. The rupee was trading at a daily average rate of 32.166 against the pound in September, 31.527 in August and 30.860 in June.</p>
<p>The bank said it sold a total 23.85 million dollars to commercial banks in September at a weighted average intervention rate of 20.4820 rupees for one dollar but did not buy any dollars from the interbank forex market.</p>
<p>In August, the Bank sold 38 million dollars in market interventions at the weighted average intervention rate of 20.2204 rupees but did not make any dollar purchase during that month either.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Mauritius average intervention rupee/dollar rate (in September) was three cents lower than the interbank transaction rate,&quot; the central bank report said.</p>
<p>&quot;During the first two weeks of September 1996, commercial banks traded the U.S. dollar on the interbank foreign exchange market at an average weighted rate higher than the average weighted intervention rate of the Bank of Mauritius,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
