<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136362" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGER: Niger to privatise 10 state companies.</title>
<headline>Niger to privatise 10 state companies.</headline>
<dateline>NIAMEY 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Niger, part way through a turbulent transition from military rule to multi-party politics, has announced plans to privatise 10 state companies -- including the state power, telephone and water utilities.</p>
<p>The government, in a statement released after a cabinet meeting on Tuesday, said the plan to sell off all or part of its stake in the various companies was part of its efforts to liberalise the economy.</p>
<p>Sources close to the government said the sales were expected to raise around 20 billion CFA francs for the cash-strapped West African nation, one of the world's poorest.</p>
<p>Power utility NIGELEC, water utility SNE and STIN, the telephone wing of the state posts and telecommunications company, head the list.</p>
<p>Other candidates for sale include the state company importing petroleum products SONIDEP, the state company responsible for underground water, the state slaughter house, the state milk company, the cement works SNC, the state textile company SONITEXTIL and hotel company SPEHG, which owns and runs the Gaweye hotel.</p>
<p>Military leader Ibrahim Bare Mainassara, who toppled an elected civilian president in January, won July's disputed multi-party presidential election after scrapping the electoral commission part-way through the poll. Multi-party legislative elections are planned for November 23.</p>
<p>The government and the International Monetary Fund agreed a 1996/98 Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility in June.</p>
<p>($=515 CFA)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NIAMEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGER"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
