<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136386" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST-Economists edge up S.Africa CPI forecasts.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Economists edge up S.Africa CPI forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consumer inflation was expected to peak at a slightly higher rate than initially anticipated after the release of worse-than-expected September data on Wednesday, economists said.</p>
<p>Central Statistical Service data released on Wednesday showed the consumer price index (CPI) rose 1.0 percent month-on-month and 8.4 percent year-on-year in September.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of economists forecast a consensus 0.7 percent month-on-month and 8.1 percent year-on-year rise.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a bad number but not too serious. We were expecting a 9.0 percent peak (for the year), but now we are expecting 9.2 or 9.3 percent in November/December,&quot; Nedcor chief economist Dennis Dykes said.</p>
<p>Standard Bank Economics Division also said it was lifting its forecast to 9.0 percent from the 8.7 percent it originally expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The higher-than-expected number does not make much difference to our 1996 year average forecast, which rises slightly from 7.2 percent to 7.3 percent,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the peak for the year is now expected to reach 9.o percent,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>ING Barings economist Hania Farhan said she expected a year end rate of 9.5 percent, primarily as a result of rising food prices.</p>
<p>The food component of the overall CPI increased 1.9 percent in September from August, the main reason for the overall 1.0 percent rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The food price index is expected to continue to increase as the availability of its components changes with the season,&quot; Farhan said, &quot;and this will account for most of the monthly CPI increases for the rest of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Farhan said the transport and fuel and power components of the index would also begin to rise in October as a result of higher international oil prices.</p>
<p>The transport component, which has a 14.43 percent weighting in the overall index, eased 0.1 percent in September from August, while the fuel and power component with a 3.26 percent weigthing rose 0.1 percent month-on-month.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect their contribution to CPI to be 0.2-0.3 percent per month while oil prices are rising,&quot; Farhan said.</p>
<p>The housing component, which has a 20.54 percent weighting and rose 0.6 percent month-on-month, was a result of some surveys being carried out in that category, Standard Bank said.</p>
<p>Farhan said she did not expect the housing component to increase significantly for the rest of the year as no more interest rate rises were anticipated.</p>
<p>-- Paul Richardson, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
