<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136376" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa's Cape sees 3.6-4.3 pct growth in 1996.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's Cape sees 3.6-4.3 pct growth in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite growing &quot;shadows&quot; on the South African business horizon, the Western Cape was expected to grow by between 3.6 percent and 4.3 percent this year, the Western Cape Economic Monitor said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In its latest report, the Monitor said the shadows included the depreciation of the rand and caution among foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Notwithstanding these forces, to which recent rumblings in the clothing industry can be added, overall prospects still seem good for a 3.6 to 4.3 percent real growth in the Western Cape in 1996,&quot; the group said.</p>
<p>Factors contributing to growth included the fact that, after a late start, rain in most parts of the province seemed sufficient for reasonable crops.</p>
<p>At the same time, the further depreciation of the rand was expected to contribute to export earnings while the  start of the construction on the Saldanha steel project would boost spending in the region.</p>
<p>Reconstruction and Development Programme-related infrastructure spending was also accelerating. &quot;This also applies to projects related to the Olympic bid,&quot; the monitor said. Cape Town is bidding to host the Games in 2004.</p>
<p>Growth in the South African economy as a whole is expected to slow to around three percent, after 3.3 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom + 27 21 25-2238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
