<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136338" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Poll shows slip in Quebec independence support.</title>
<headline>Poll shows slip in Quebec independence support.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Support for Quebec independence from Canada is continuing to slip, nearly a year after the narrow defeat of a sovereignty proposal in a referendum in the majority French-speaking province, according to a poll released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Leger &amp; Leger poll, commissioned by The Globe and Mail and the Journal de Montreal newspapers, put federalists ahead of separatists by 51.2 percent to 48.8 percent when asked the same question as posed in the referendum.</p>
<p>This was a slight change from the 50.6 to 49.4 percent split in September and was within the margin of error. But it contrasted with consistent post-referendum leads for the separatists in every monthly Leger poll prior to September.</p>
<p>Jean-Marc Leger, president of the polling group, said support was also declining for separatist political parties -- the provincial ruling Parti Quebecois, headed by Premier Lucien Bouchard, and the federal Bloc Quebecois.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear that for Lucien Bouchard the honeymoon is over,&quot; The Globe and Mail quoted him as saying. &quot;People are looking for effective government, not more talk about the Constitution.&quot;</p>
<p>Before apportioning undecided voters, support for the Parti Quebecois has slipped to 42.7 percent from 48.4 percent in August. Backing for the provincial Liberals, who favour unity, rose to 33.1 percent from 27.8 percent, The Globe and Mail said.</p>
<p>The poll found support for separation even weaker if a tougher question were posed than the one put to voters in the referendum -- in which voters were asked whether Quebec should become sovereign after having made an offer of political and economic partnership to Canada.</p>
<p>The Globe and Mail said a clear majority would vote against sovereignty if such negotiations on partnership turned out to be impossible. The poll showed 48 percent voting against sovereignty in this case, 38.5 percent Yes, with the rest undecided or not responding.</p>
<p>The poll surveyed 1,005 voters between October 10 and 17, and would carry a margin of error of 3.1 percentage points 19 times out of 20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
