<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136359" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Survey shows S.Africans unhappy with government.</title>
<headline>Survey shows S.Africans unhappy with government.</headline>
<byline>Allan Seccombe</byline>
<dateline>DURBAN, South Africa 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Increasing numbers of South Africans are unhappy with the political and economic climate in the country since the first all-race elections in April 1994, according to an opinion poll published on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The widespread feeling of optimism after the general election has been replaced by a larger degree of realism and an awakening to the outstanding issues that South Africa still has to address,&quot; said Vincent Maphai, executive director of the state-funded Human Sciences Research Council (HSRC).</p>
<p>About 2,200 people were questioned for the survey in June, which reported that 45 percent of respondents were satisfied with political developments now as opposed to 76 percent in the month after the election.</p>
<p>The percentage of people satisfied with economic developments had dropped to 34 percent from 51 percent in May 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The expectation that a change of government would automatically and immediately lead to improved economic conditions has given rise to some frustration and dissatisfaction due to the slow progress that has been made,&quot; Maphai said in a statement.</p>
<p>The survey results reflected perceptions that President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress has been slow to implement election promises on housing and on improving the lot of the black majority.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel unveiled a macro-economic strategy for growth, employment and redistribution (GEAR) in June which foresees economic growth up from almost three percent now to six percent by the end of the century. It also envisages massive job creation.</p>
<p>Maphai said 66 percent of whites questioned regarded the fight against crime as the country's most important goal while only 18 percent of blacks thought so. More than half the blacks thought job creation was the most important goal.</p>
<p>A 71 percent majority wanted the death penalty to be brought back, although Mandela has said he will never allow this. No one has been hanged in South Africa since a moratorium on executions was imposed in 1990.</p>
<p>On race relations, 34 percent of blacks said their attitude to whites had improved since the election while 12 percent reported a deterioration. For whites the figures were 36 percent and 10 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
