<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136306" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: CRICKET - Rixon can revive NZ cricket - Simpson.</title>
<headline>CRICKET - Rixon can revive NZ cricket - Simpson.</headline>
<text>
<p>Wellington, Oct 23 - If anyone can, an Aussie can. Just ask one.</p>
<p>A nation of sporting achievers, Australians are respected for their competitive spirit, their in-your-face combativeness.</p>
<p>They also tend to have thick skins, which is one attribute New Zealand cricket coach Steve Rixon may find helpful when he leaves tomorrow with the national side bound for Cairns as they finalise preparations for their tour of Sharjah and Pakistan.  </p>
<p>Any hints of problems among the squad during the tour will be pounced on by a public at home fed up with poor results and internal conflicts undermining the country's cricketing reputation.</p>
<p>As the first foreigner in charge of the New Zealand team, Rixon is wading into potentially stormy waters, but NZPA reports that one person with no doubts about the Sydneysider's ability to do the job is his mentor, former Australian coach Bobby Simpson.</p>
<p>Simpson has a healthy regard for both Rixon, whom he has known for 20 years, and for New Zealand cricketers.  </p>
<p>Simpson, whose hugely successful 10-year reign with the Australian team ended this year, played with wicketkeeper-batsman Rixon at club, state and test level in the mid-1970s and early 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;He's been well trained the Simpson way,&quot; Simpson said of Rixon, who guided New South Wales to three Sheffield Shield titles between 1989 and 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;He'll be very straight, which is good. He had a very, very good record early on with New South Wales when he had the difficult situation of coaching a team with seven Australian players in it,&quot; Simpson told NZPA.  </p>
<p>&quot;He will train the boys well. He is using similar methods to what I used. And he knows the ropes.&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson understands the unease many New Zealanders felt about having an Australian in charge of the national cricket side. However, he doesn't see that impeding Rixon's ability to get the best out of his players.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not necessarily a handicap as long as he wins the respect of the players. The fact he is from overseas may help because the players may feel he is a totally new broom.&quot;  </p>
<p>Simpson assumed control of a poorly performing Australian side in 1986, and gradually restored their world standing through hard work.</p>
<p>He believes Rixon faces a similar process.</p>
<p>&quot;New Zealand have got to rediscover their cussedness,&quot; he said from his Sydney office where he now runs his own cricketing consultancy business.</p>
<p>&quot;It's plain old fashioned stubbornness. It's pride in their performance and pride in their country.  </p>
<p>&quot;I worked hard on instilling that when I took over as coach of Australia,&quot; said Simpson, who inherited an Australian side in 1986 who were being beaten by allcomers, and developed them into arguably the best team in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;It didn't happen overnight. It took time; you have to get the right team around you but firstly you need the right attitudes.</p>
<p>&quot;Since we have had success with the Australian side, Australian coaches are very much the flavour of the month.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think in that regard, Australians have always had a very good work ethic. I think it has been accepted now that if you are to reach the top you have to have that work ethic to succeed.&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson has been disturbed at New Zealand's gradual decline in recent years. During his time at the helm of Australia, he developed a liking for the many qualities New Zealand teams displayed.  </p>
<p>&quot;New Zealand to me were always a team who played almost above their natural talents; they had this amazing drive and desire to prove they were a really tough team, and they played that way.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of time we looked at the New Zealand side and thought there's not much there, fellas' but they always played above themselves, particularly against Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;On a population basis New Zealand is one of the great sports nations of the world.&quot;</p>
<p>If they revived past attitudes they could still be a very competitive team, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;On a population basis alone New Zealand cannot expect to have a great cricket team, but there will be periods when they'll be very, very hard to beat.</p>
<p>&quot;Rixon's record probably indicates he can get the best out of the players.&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson has been far from an idol since being deposed as Australian coach earlier this year by former test opener Geoff Marsh.</p>
<p>He has established a cricketing consultancy business and hires out his coaching services to those who think he still has something to offer.  </p>
<p>Simpson arrived in Wellington today as a guest of the Wellington Cricket Association. He is to spend a week in the capital, helping out at representative team practice sessions, attending a series of speaking engagements, talking to representative managers, coaches and selectors and addressing primary school and women players.</p>
<p>Simpson arrived back in Sydney only this week after a brief coaching stint in Bermuda, whom he will guide at the International Cricket Council tournament in Malaysia next year.  </p>
<p>A top-three finish there will see Bermuda included in the next World Cup tournament, and Simpson said he might maintain his involvement with Bermuda should they progress to the sport's showpiece.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
