<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136304" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT-NZ Maori coach Bell picks Kiwis to win.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT-NZ Maori coach Bell picks Kiwis to win.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALMERSTON NORTH, Oct 24 - New Zealand Maori coach Cameron Bell picks the Kiwis to wrap up the three-test rugby league series against Great Britain in a tight second contest here at the Manawatu Showgrounds on Friday night, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Bell's Maori team notched a historic first ever win over the Great Britain in Whangarei on Tuesday night giving him the rare personal distinction of having achieved two wins as coach over the Lions. His previous success was with Auckland.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be close again and I believe it might go the way of the Kiwis because they have the edge of being one-up in the series,&quot; Bell said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It depends too on how hungry Great Britain are to level it from here.&quot;</p>
<p>But Bell said he expected Kiwis coach Frank Endacott to keep ramming home the urgency and need for New Zealand to make it two-nil ahead of going to Christchurch.</p>
<p>New Zealand have not beaten Great Britain in a series since 1984 and that has been a bug bear for Endacott ever since he took over coaching the Kiwis three years ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a very good Great Britain side, sure they've got some players who aren't here for various reasons and they do seem to be missing them, but this is still a very good side,&quot; Bell warned.</p>
<p>&quot;And I can't laud these guys (British) high enough because I know they are good footballers back in England and I have seen them.&quot;</p>
<p>It is for that reason he expects Endacott to spend another tense 80-minutes in the stands when the Kiwis front up for the second test.  </p>
<p>&quot;I do believe the British guys who are here are good enough to beat New Zealand in the last two tests if they get a sniff at it,&quot; Bell said.</p>
<p>&quot;I know they will be competitive and we have to expect that. They were competitive right up until the last 10-minutes of that first test.</p>
<p>Endacott himself spoke of the need to wrap up the series here in Palmerston North.</p>
<p>&quot;There's more riding on this test than there was in the first test,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have to wrap up this series here before going to Christchurch, we've taken one step toward it and we must complete that process here.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to have to go to the third test tied at 1-1, it will make the job all the more harder.&quot;</p>
<p>New Zealand have enjoyed a relatively injury-free build-up to the second test with only minor niggles affecting some of the players.  </p>
<p>In contrast Great Britain go into the test with centre Daryl Powell's hamstring still a concern while halfback Bobbie Goulding, who played the role of concert conductor for Great Britain in the first test, still has a suspect knee.</p>
<p>Teams --</p>
<p>Great Britain: Stuart Spruce, Alan Hunte, Kris Radlinski, Daryl Powell, Anthony Sullivan, Iestyn Harris, Bobbie Goulding; Andy Farrell, Paul Sculthorpe, Denis Betts, Terry O'Connor, Keiron Cunningham, Paul Broadbent. Reserves - Barrie-Jon Mather, Karle Hammond, Steve Molloy, Chris Joynt.  </p>
<p>New Zealand (squad): Matthew Ridge, Sean Hoppe, Richard Blackmore, John Timu, Richard Barnett, Gene Ngamu, Stacey Jones; Tyran Smith, Stephen Kearney, Tony Iro, Grant Young, Syd Eru, Quentin Pongia; Marc Ellis, Joe Vagana, Ruben Wiki, Logan Swann.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
