<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136390" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Kenya to retain auctions in latest coffee reforms.</title>
<headline>Kenya to retain auctions in latest coffee reforms.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kenya's agriculture minister and leading coffee industry players have agreed a new package of reforms under which central export auctions will be retained, Minister Simeon Nyachae and industry leaders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Coffee Board of Kenya will continue to coordinate marketing of coffee through the auction system,&quot; Nyachae said.</p>
<p>&quot;The board shall modernise the central auction through introduction of electronic communications and displays to enhance its transparency, efficiency and accountability to all stakeholders,&quot; Nyachae told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Nyachae's news conference was attended by representatives of trade houses, planters, millers and the Kenya Coffee Board.</p>
<p>The reforms are meant to end a long dispute in the sector over marketing. Private millers had argued that marketing should be freed to end a coffee board monopoly.</p>
<p>Nyachae said the major problem in the industry remained the speed of payments to farmers and their need for credit to improve production.</p>
<p>Currently, it takes three to four months after an auction to pay farmers. Nyachae wants this cut to two weeks.</p>
<p>Nyachae said coffee farmers would have a right to fix a reserve price for their coffee at the central auction.</p>
<p>The board would sell all or part of its 70 percent shareholding in the Kenya Coffee Auctions Ltd (KCA) to planters and other stakeholders and would institute a balloting mechanism for lots to be auctioned at the central auction.</p>
<p>The board would also look at the feasibility of introducing of more auctioneers, but all coffee auctioneers, including the KCA, would operate under a central auction.</p>
<p>Nyachae said the board would develop other financing mechanisms where warehousing receipts, warrants or other legally acceptable documents could be used as collateral by coffee farmers to secure credit at favourable terms.</p>
<p>He also said the board would release money to planters and individual coffee factory accounts of respective cooperative societies and the money would be handled by elected officials.</p>
<p>&quot;This measure will help in improving on payments to farmers while at the same time preserving the authority to those mandated to manage the societies,&quot; Nyachae added.</p>
<p>Planters and commercial millers wishing to engage in coffee trading and export as a separate function would be allowed to acquire a dealer &quot;A&quot; licence. Their participation at the auction had the potential to increase competition, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Holders of a dealer 'A' licence, be they planters or commercial millers, shall be at liberty to appoint their own brokers to represent their interest at the central auction under existing rules,&quot; Nyachae said.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
