<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136316" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks finish at new highs on earnings.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks finish at new highs on earnings.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks hit their fourth straight record high on Wednesday, propelled by healthy earnings and the prospect of lower Canadian interest rates.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Index soared 43.02 points to a record close of 5576.01, extending its record-setting streak since last Friday. Trading was very heavy with 103.1 million shares exchanging hands worth C$1.6 billion ($1.2 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;There has been some concern about the integrity of earnings of Canadian companies, but they are coming on stream here,&quot; said Fred Ketchen, director of equity trading for ScotiaMcLeod Inc.</p>
<p>Strong gains in conglomerates, communications and utilities and golds powered 11 of 14 sub-groups higher. The weak side was led by a 56-point drop in transportation.</p>
<p>Advancing stocks narrowly outnumbered declines 473 to 462 with 306 issues flat.</p>
<p>A strong Canadian dollar and the potential for lower Canadian rates added to the buoyant mood in equities, Kethcen said. &quot;There is continuing optimism that there will be a further rate cut by the Bank of Canada because the dollar was higher today and could support a rate cut,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Telecommunications giant Northern Telecom Ltd. led net gainers, jumping 5.50 to 87.20, a 52-week high. The company's third quarter profits on Tuesday beat analysts' estimates.</p>
<p>* BCE Inc., Canada's biggest publicly-traded firm, pushed the utilities group ahead. BCE closed up 2.45 at 61.75, a 52-week peak, after reporting higher third quarter profits.</p>
<p>* Canadian Pacific Ltd. sparked the conglomerates sector to a 210-point rally. CP jumped 1.20 to close at 33.30 after earlier hitting a 52-week high of 33.75 on good earnings.</p>
<p>* In the weak transportation group, Air Canada fell 0.20 to 5.10. The airline's president, Lamar Durrett, said he would not be surprised if low-cost, U.S.-based Southwest Airlines entered the Canadian market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
