<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136398" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Spokesman says no chemotherapy for Mobutu.</title>
<headline>Spokesman says no chemotherapy for Mobutu.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's president, convalescing after prostate surgery in Switzerland, does not need chemotherapy treatment, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>Kabuya Lumuna told state television on Tuesday night that 66-year-old President Mobutu Sese Seko was convalescing normally and his doctors were satisfied with his progress.</p>
<p>&quot;Reports concerning chemotherapy with harmful side effects are without foundation,&quot; Kabuya told the nation, denying a Swiss television report suggesting Mobutu would have chemotherapy treatment until the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The report of the personal doctor of the head of state shows that his convalescence is continuing normally to the satisfaction of the doctors treating him,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A cloak of secrecy surrounds Mobutu in Switzerland.</p>
<p>Since undergoing surgery for prostate cancer on August 22 at Lausanne's University Hospital, he has been staying with his entourage at the Beau-Rivage Palace hotel, one of the world's most exclusive.</p>
<p>Witnesses report rare sightings at gourmet restaurants in Lausanne and at the University Hospital.</p>
<p>Reports on Mobutu's health within Zaire most often take the form of denials of foreign reports. One newspaper was banned from publishing after saying Mobutu was riddled with cancer.</p>
<p>Opposition newspapers have highlighted differences between the reports from Europe and those broadcast within Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;On Fieldmarshall Mobutu's illness, domestic news continues to contradict reports from our European colleagues,&quot; one opposition newspaper, La Reference, said on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
