<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136365" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe stocks end mixed in active trade.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe stocks end mixed in active trade.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean industrial shares, pushed to record heights for five consecutive days by strong investor sentiment for economic growth next year, took a temporary breather on Wednesday largely due to losses in five counters.</p>
<p>&quot;The index did lose a few points but I think that's only temporary. The market generally still looks pretty firm,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Wednesday's losers included Apex and spinners and weavers Spinweave, each down 10 cents at 120 and 115 respectively, while financial group UDC shed 15 cents to 240.</p>
<p>Paper and packaging firm Hunyani lost 20 cents to 360 and clothing retailer Edgars were 200 cents easier at 3,300, pushing the 57-counter index down 7.88 points to close at 7,442.33.</p>
<p>In minings, nickel producer Bindura traded unchanged at 1,100, coal miners Wankie added five cents to 355 while losses in gold companies Falgold, down five cents and Ashanti 110 cents weaker at 14,000, cost the secondary seven-share index 7.23 points to close at 1,246.71.</p>
<p>--Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
