<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136381" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa to end white privilege in education.</title>
<headline>S.Africa to end white privilege in education.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's ruling black majority is about to topple a founding pillar of apartheid with the adoption by parliament of a new education law breaking the white stranglehold on state funding for schools.</p>
<p>With guaranteed support from President Nelson Mandela's dominant African National Congress (ANC) and some opposition parties, the South African Schools Bill scheduled for debate on Thursday is assured of passage when it comes to a vote.</p>
<p>&quot;Equality is not going to be achieved overnight, but changes are going to start being felt very quickly,&quot; parliamentary education committee head Blade Nzimande told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major event in South Africa's transition.&quot;</p>
<p>Exclusive whites-only schools were a cornerstone of apartheid rule, with spending on white children up to 10 times the equivalent figure for blacks in the 1970s.</p>
<p>Education has been compulsory for white children for decades, but was once actively discouraged for blacks and is still both voluntary and vastly inferior in most black areas.</p>
<p>Nzimande said the new law would scrap the separate white, coloured, Indian and black education departments inherited from white rule and begin to enforce equality.</p>
<p>Compulsory segregation was scrapped before Mandela's ANC came to power in 1994, but schools largely retain the racial identity created by apartheid.</p>
<p>The disparity in government spending on traditionally white and still predominantly black schools would be eliminated, probably by the turn of the century, Nzimande said.</p>
<p>He estimated the disparity at four to one, though official figures show that the government is now spending about twice as much on each white child as it does on each black one.</p>
<p>&quot;The priority of government is to shift government spending from the privileged elite to the poor kids, but it will take time because if you were to change rapidly, just bang, sections of the system would collapse.&quot;</p>
<p>Beginning with primary school pupils, the law also will begin for the first time to make education compulsory for the five-to-one black majority.</p>
<p>Schools will be run by councils including pupils and teachers and with a guaranteed parent majority, subject to guidelines and standards set by the government.</p>
<p>Afrikaner efforts to use their minority culture as an entry bar to blacks were crushed by the ANC majority during weeks of public hearings and fiery debate on the draft law.</p>
<p>&quot;The new education law...creates the impression that the ANC wants to destroy the Afrikaner education institutions at all costs,&quot; said Kallie Kriel, chairman of the youth wing of the white separatist Freedom Front.</p>
<p>Former president F.W. de Klerk's white-led National Party is likely to make a last-minute bid to amend the bill during debate and might try to overturn aspects of it in a challenge to the Constitutional Court, the highest in the country.</p>
<p>Nzimande, deputy leader of the South African Communist Party, an ally of Mandela's ANC, said he doubted that elite state-funded schools would ever disappear.</p>
<p>But any semblance of segregation would have to go immediately and the difference between the facilities of the elite schools and those in the black townships created by apartheid would have to be funded by parents.</p>
<p>He said a key provision of the new law would be the right of any child to attend any school.</p>
<p>&quot;This bill is the last straw for those white communities that have tried to resist change,&quot; Nzimande said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
