<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136344" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Minister says S.Africa to open markets to region.</title>
<headline>Minister says S.Africa to open markets to region.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Trade and Industry Minister Alec Erwin said on Wednesday his country was working on quickly opening its markets to fellow southern African states to balance trade and secure long-term regional economic growth.</p>
<p>Addressing a Southern Africa Trade and Investment summit in Zimbabwe, Erwin said South Africa could not afford protectionist policies despite its fast growing exports to the region.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth of the matter is that, faced with this growing current account surplus in our favour...we need to open our markets more readily to our SADC partners than to other trading blocs like the European Union (EU),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Africa, he said, also needed to generate a capital account deficit in relation to its SADC (Southern African Development Community) partners and encourage more cross-border investment.</p>
<p>SADC is made up of Angola, Botswana, Malawi, Mozambique, Lesotho, Namibia, Mauritius, Tanzania, Swaziland, South Africa, Zambia and Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>South Africa has often been criticised by other SADC members, mostly Zimbabwe and Zambia, of employing unfair trade practices by dumping goods on their markets and shutting its markets through high tarrifs.</p>
<p>Pretoria says it is addressing the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to work at it together even if business, labour and government will not always agree,&quot; he said, urging South African exporters not to be too excited about their gains in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;South African exports into the region are growing too fast if we are to facilitate long-term growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Cris Chinaka, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
