<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136351" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Fighting cuts food aid routes into eastern Zaire.</title>
<headline>Fighting cuts food aid routes into eastern Zaire.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>BUKAVU, Zaire 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ethnic fighting in eastern Zaire has closed the only two overland food supply routes for the area's half a million displaced people, aid workers say.</p>
<p>Refugees and local Zaireans who have fled the fighting were threatened with hunger and disease in Bukavu, which has about 250,000 displaced people, they said.</p>
<p>Uvira, 100 km (65 miles) to the south, has about the same number of homeless.</p>
<p>Both towns have been cut off from food aid by fighting between the Zairean army and ethnic Tutsis or Banyamulenge, who settled from Rwanda 200 years ago.</p>
<p>Zaire has accused Rwanda of using them to destabilise the region, and the army and local Zaireans are trying to expel them by force.</p>
<p>There was no official confirmation of reports that Banyamulenge guerrillas had taken control of the towns of Kamanyola and Bwegera, south of Bukavu.</p>
<p>&quot;Rebels are controlling both Kamanyola and Bwegera,&quot; a junior army officer told Reuters. &quot;We had artillery guns but we ran out of ammunition.&quot;</p>
<p>Soldiers in Bukavu said they had been told reinforcements of troops and munitions were on the way from the Zairean capital Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Bukavu residents also faced the prospect of shortages. An Indian businessman said only two commercial vehicles had reached the town since Friday.</p>
<p>The town was gripped by panic on Wednesday when soldiers drove in truckloads of their families evacuated from one battlefront, stoking rumours of an imminent attack by Rwanda.</p>
<p>Eastern Zaire has been a powderkeg since the 1994 civil war and massacres in Rwanda sent a million Hutus in search of shelter in the area, fuelling local rivalries.</p>
<p>Diplomats and aid workers fear Tutsi-dominated armies in Burundi and Rwanda could be drawn into the fighting, sparking a wider conflict in Central Africa's volatile Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>Aid agencies said thousands of people could go hungry unless food arrived soon in Bukavu, where more refugees were headed.</p>
<p>&quot;We are reducing rations...but it still looks like we have only five to six days of supplies left,&quot; said Abdelwahad Mahmoud Jeme, Bukavu representative of the U.N. World Food Programme.</p>
<p>About 60 percent of food aid for eastern Zaire comes by land through Kenya and Uganda before travelling south via Goma. The other 40 percent passes through Tanzania across Lake Tanganyika to a port near Uvira.</p>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency UNHCR estimated about a quarter of a million people -- Rwandan and Burundian refugees and local Zaireans -- were on the move in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;We're trying to calm the people down and return them to existing camps,&quot; UNHCR spokesman Paul Stromberg told BBC World Service television.</p>
<p>He said that if refugees swamped Bukavu there could be a repeat of the scenes in nearby Goma in mid-1994 when chaos broke out as Rwandan war refugees flooded the town and cholera killed thousands of people daily at one stage.</p>
<p>Zaire stepped up its war of words against Tutsi-dominated Rwanda and Burundi on Wednesday, accusing them of attacking eastern Zaire. It urged people to give money to support Zairean troops.</p>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing in Switzerland after surgery for prostate cancer, sent a message saying the top priority should be blocking &quot;invaders devastating the east&quot;.</p>
<p>Both Burundi and Rwanda denied any military role in Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
