<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136345" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica's truth body leaves PW Botha's options open.</title>
<headline>SAfrica's truth body leaves PW Botha's options open.</headline>
<byline>Thabo Mabaso</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's &quot;truth commission&quot; will subpoena former president P.W. Botha only if he refuses to meet the body and discuss allegations against him, commission vice-chairman Alex Boraine said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Because Botha was a president, hasn't been well, is retired, is older, our approach may well be to try and see if we can...talk frankly about this,&quot; Boraine told a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;If that fails and if Botha simply rejects any approach from the commission we would have to proceed in terms of the act and we would do so,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Apartheid police commissioner Johan van der Merwe told the commission on Monday that Botha had personally ordered the 1988 bombing of Khotso House, a building used by black activists.</p>
<p>Boraine said van der Merwe's allegations had to be taken seriously.</p>
<p>The commission was recently forced to subpoena three apartheid police generals when it became clear they had adopted a wait-and-see attitude before applying for amnesty.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the commission's Amnesty Committee, which is hearing the applications of five police officers in Johannesburg, said it would subpoena four more police officers who could shed more light on the murders and atrocities.</p>
<p>Nobel peace laureate Desmond Tutu's Truth and Reconciliation Commission (TRC) has so far mainly heard testimony from victims of apartheid but the hearings this week have initiated what could be flood of disclosures by perpetrators of abuses.</p>
<p>The five policemen seeking amnesty said earlier this week they doubted claims of innocence by F.W. de Klerk, the country's last white president. He has declined comment.</p>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's African National Congress (ANC) on Wednesday slammed the revelations by the former police, saying they did not go far enough to advance national reconciliation.</p>
<p>Senior ANC official Matthew Phosa said many of the officers' bosses -- including Botha -- knew &quot;the whole truth&quot; but remained tight-lipped.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on all those who possess knowledge and are implicated in these crimes, including...Botha...to assist the truth and reconciliation process by breaking with the conspiracy of silence,&quot; Phosa told a Johannesburg news conference.</p>
<p>The commission, set up last year to investigate human rights abuses during 30 years of South Africa's race conflict, has the power to grant amnesty to persons who come clean.</p>
<p>The results of survey released by the country's Human Sciences Research Council on Wednesday showed that 60 percent of South Africans believed the commission would promote reconciliation and 78 percent favoured amnesty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
