<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136375" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Manuel briefs S.African cabinet on budget progress.</title>
<headline>Manuel briefs S.African cabinet on budget progress.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel on Wednesday briefed South Africa's cabinet on progress towards finalisation of the March budget for fiscal 1997/98.</p>
<p>Cabinet secretary Jakes Gerwel said premiers and finance ministers of the nine provinces attended the meeting and were given an opportunity to discuss proposed allocations.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an exchange of views on what the economy looks like, how the budgeting targets are envisaged to be met, how that affects departments and the divisions envisaged between the national (government) and the provinces.</p>
<p>&quot;There were differences of emphasis, yes, certainly...There was no disastrous dissatisfaction which threatened the governance of the country, but I'm sure all of the budgeting agencies would want more if they could get more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gerwel declined to reveal what targets or allocations were discussed, but said they were &quot;basically on target&quot; in relation to Manuel's June 14 macro-economic strategy for growth, employment and redistribution, known as GEAR.</p>
<p>The programme commits the government to reducing the budget deficit from an estimated 5.1 percent this year to four percent in fiscal 1997/98 (April-March).</p>
<p>&quot;The content of the budgeting process, for understandable reasons, is confidential until the day of the budget,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Parliamentary newsroom, +27-21-4032502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
