<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136379" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Africa urges foreign investment with a black role.</title>
<headline>Africa urges foreign investment with a black role.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African leaders on Wednesday urged foreign firms to invest in the region, but warned black empowerment had to play a pivotal role.</p>
<p>Political and business leaders are hoping to capitalise on the end of long wars in Angola and Mozambique and the collapse of apartheid in South Africa to woo much needed foreign investment.</p>
<p>Zimbabwean president Robert Mugabe, speaking at the South African Trade and Investment Summit in Harare, urged investors to plough cash into the twelve-member South African Development Community (SADC).</p>
<p>He said the region would strive to make overseas companies welcome.</p>
<p>&quot;SADC is committed to strengthening regional co-operation and integration...and to improve further the regional investment climate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Mugabe added that any foreign firm hoping to take part in Southern Africa's moves towards privatisation should ensure local black groups were given a significant role.</p>
<p>&quot;Privatisation is an opportunity to bring in blacks and empower them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In strident language, Mugabe said the area had won political power from its former colonial masters, but that economic power still eluded them.</p>
<p>&quot;We find ourselves in a situation where our people are nothing more than mere workers in a system that derives from the past and we would like to see them empowered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>All countries in the region have embarked to some degree on programmes of economic reform aimed at creating a market-friendly environment.</p>
<p>Mozambique, ravaged by years of war between its once-avowedly communist government and right-wing rebels, now holds itself up as a free trade country that has liberalised its foreign exchange regime and brought down customs tariffs.</p>
<p>&quot;Mozambique will have to work hand in hand with the private sector. It is partnership between the government and the private sector that will ensure success,&quot; said prime minister Pascoal Mocumbi.</p>
<p>One issue that has been raised at the conference is the role South Africa will now play in the SADC.</p>
<p>The country, shunned under apartheid, now dominates the region with its advanced financial infrastructure and industrial might.</p>
<p>Zambian finance minister Ronald Penza urged South Africa to press on with its fledgling privatisation programme, criticised for moving too slowly, in order to spur the rest of the region further down the road to economic reform.</p>
<p>&quot;(We) demand that South Africa gives leadership in this respect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a sign that having South Africa on your doorstep poses problems as well as opportunities, Penza also took a dig at South Africa's exchange controls which hamper the flow of funds out of the country.</p>
<p>South Africa's neighbours hope the eventual relaxation of the controls will allow firms to use the country as a base to penetrate the rest of the region.</p>
<p>&quot;The time for exchange controls is past,&quot; Penza said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SOUAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
