<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136421" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 23.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- The government announced another tax amnesty, promising it would be the last, but that it would be much more widely applicable than previous amnesties.</p>
<p>- Malbak's SA Druggists raised attributable earnings before exceptionals 28.2 percent to 150 million rand in the year to August, boosted by the first-time inclusion of offshore interests.</p>
<p>- JCI bucked the downward trend in gold mining quarterly results, posting a 30 percent rise in aggregate profit in the September quarter to 129 million rand.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Trevor Manuel and the Reserve Bank have approved Unibank's bid of about 65 million rand for Community Bank.</p>
<p>- Underperforming municipalities could have their licences to distribute electricity withdrawn following the development of a performance framework by the National Electricity Regulator.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Taxpayers who elected not to take advantage of the government's previous tax amnesty have been given a second chance to legitimise their tax position.</p>
<p>- A strong performance by H.J. Joel and higher gold output lifted September quarter profit 30 percent at JCI's gold division.</p>
<p>- South African mining houses and the ANC have found areas of agreement on the future of mining in a Green Paper delivered to minerals minister Penuell Maduna last Friday.</p>
<p>- Metropolitan Life is set to reduce its holding in South African Breweries to prepare for the role it will play in funding Nail's stake in the sale of Johnnic's control to the National Empowerment Consortium.</p>
<p>- The slow delivery of the RDP (reconstruction and development programme) has spared the government from budgetary pressures which would have arisen towards the end of the century, according to Andrew Roux, economist with the Development Bank of Southern Africa.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Former president P.W. Botha could be hauled before the Truth and Reconciliation Commission to given evidence whether he wants to or not.</p>
<p>- The south of Johannesburg was lashed by a major hailstorm on Tuesday night, coupled with howling winds and driving rain.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
