<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136491" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Latvia starts privatisation of shipping company.</title>
<headline>Latvia starts privatisation of shipping company.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Baltic state of Latvia on Wednesday said it was set to invite bids for the privatisation of its state-owned Latvian Shipping Company, ranked 19th out of the world's 20 largest shipping firms.</p>
<p>The Latvian Privatisation Agency (LPA) said in a statement that it would put out a call for expressions of interest to buy between a 25 and 35 percent stake in the company.</p>
<p>&quot;The privatisation agency expects several financial institutions to give their answer about taking part in the privatisation of the Shipping Company this week,&quot; LPA head Janis Naglis told a news conference.</p>
<p>The agency said the deadline for expressions of interest was December 20 and it hoped that an announcement on the sale could be made by the summer of 1997.</p>
<p>The Shipping Company's annual turnover is close to $300 million but it made a loss last year of more than $51 million.</p>
<p>It has 70 ships, two ships on order and 4,500 staff.</p>
<p>&quot;As soon as this major holding has been sold, the LPA would expect the new owner to assume a dominant role in determining the direction of the company and will immediately commence consideration of how to most quickly sell its remaining 65 to 75 percent interest,&quot; the LPA said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said that financial institutions could take part in the deal but were advised to link up with another shipping firm.</p>
<p>Nomura and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) have been reported in local media to be interested in the privatisation.</p>
<p>The LPA said that 19 to 22 percent of the firm's income came from dry cargo, 18 to 21 percent from refrigerated containers and 55 to 58 percent from its tanker fleet.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Lannin, Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
