<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136434" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>PRAVO - Labour Minister Jindrich Vodicka's proposals that the first three days of illness not be covered by worker's compensation was not approved during Tuesday's meeting of ministers, according to Prime Minster Vaclav Klaus.</p>
<p>- Low voter turnout in the senatorial elections would benefit Vaclav Klaus's Civic Democratic Party, according to a poll. Voters who are satisfied with the developments in the last few years, who are more likely to support Klaus and his coalition, are more inclined to vote.</p>
<p>- The number of prisoners in Czech prisons has increased to 20,974 from 19,508 at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>- The chairman of the National Property Fund, Roman Ceska, has voiced doubts about whether or not the Fund will be able to cover bad loans to small Czech banks as called for in a recent government plan.</p>
<p>- The Minister of Transport will become the Ministry of Transport and Telecommunications starting November 1. Minister Martin Riman will be responsible for the post and telecommunications.</p>
<p>- Ceska Rafinerska confirmed further price increases for petrol and diesel fuel of roughly 22 hellers and 26 hellers respectively.</p>
<p>- Prvni Novinova Spolecnost a.s. announced a pre-tax profit of 36 million crowns in the first half of this year on sales of 2.159 billion crowns. The company expects a gross profit of 56 million crowns on sales of 4.33 billion crowns for 1996.</p>
<p>- According to the 1997 budget proposal, the state should contribute 13.7 billion crowns to housing in 1997, an increase of 41.9 percent over the adjusted 1996 budget.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The possibility of fusing some of the large Czech banks before their further privatisation is part of the plan the Czech National Bank will present to the government before the end of this month, according to the bank's vice-governor, Pavel Kysilka.</p>
<p>- The Garant-Hospital and Gral insurance agencies have submitted a proposal to the Ministry of Health for their merging, according to the vice-minister of Health, Josef Suchopar.</p>
<p>- GiTy a.s., the largest Czech supplier of communications systems and services, obtained a licence for operating a public data network from the Czech Telecommunications Office on Monday, according to the general manager of the company, Alexandr Winkler. The company intends to offer extensive services in the area of data transmission including connections to the Internet.</p>
<p>- Biocel Paskov is expected to post losses of about half a billion crowns in 1996, according to a press spokesman from the company.</p>
<p>- Plzensky Prazdroj, the largest Czech brewery sold the same amount of beer in the first nine months of 1996 as in all of 1995. The company expects sales to increase by one quarter.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, +42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
