<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136461" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland must tackle structural reforms - World Bank.</title>
<headline>Poland must tackle structural reforms - World Bank.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland has a chance of sustaining fast growth if it keeps the momentum of structural reforms, especially in its capital markets, social security and farm sectors, a senior World Bank official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an enormous opportunity that if reforms maintain momentum...growth rates that are higher than what you have experienced recently -- in the range of seven percent plus -- should be possible,&quot; Caio Koch-Weser, World Bank Managing Director, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The Polish economy, after last year's seven percent growth, is expected to expand by about five percent this year and the goverment aims at maintaining a 5-6 percent growth rate in the next few years.</p>
<p>Koch-Weser, who was summing up his five day visit to Poland, said fast economic expansion was necessary to cut structural unemployment and help Poland achieve standards necessary to join the European Union.</p>
<p>He said that while Poland has done most of the work required to stabilise and liberalise its economy, it had to move faster with privatisation, overhaul its social security and reform social services.</p>
<p>&quot;I see more difficulties on the structural adjustments agenda than on the monetary or fiscal side,&quot; Koch-Weser said.</p>
<p>&quot;One main challenge is privatisation. It's half done... there's been a lot of progress and I am impressed with plans to privatise major firms next year but the momentum has lagged in recent years behind that of Poland's neighbours,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the social security reform, crucial to avert a looming fiscal crisis, was also needed to mobilise savings and speed up the development of Poland's shallow capital market.</p>
<p>But he said Poland had an advantage of popular support for reforms and the strength of local initiatives.</p>
<p>&quot;It is truly a bottom-up movement...local momentum and initiative is a very solid foundation for further progress,&quot; he said. -- Tomasz Janowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
