<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136431" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Chief Prosecutor's Office mulls possible surveillance measures against heads of commercial banks placed under receivership in a bid to prevent them from destroying credit files and official bank documents, the head of the investigation supervision department Angel Ganev said.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's parliament is expected today to reinstate controversial amendments to the Deposit Guarantee Law, which were vetoed last week by President Zhelyu Zhelev on grounds they would delay compensation to depositors in banks that the central bank seeks to close down.</p>
<p>-- The private Elitbank, which was placed under receivership a month ago, has settled all its outstanding payments, ammounting to some 261 million levs, Elitbank officials said.</p>
<p>STANDAR</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Citizens and companies will be able to withdraw their deposits from the nine commercial banks put under receivership on September 23 by the central bank.</p>
<p>Under Bulgaria's Banking Law deposits in those banks can not be blocked for more than one month, a Bulgarian National Bank official said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgarians spend almost half of their income on food, the National Statistics Institute said.</p>
<p>ONTINEN</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>-- Some eight billion levs were deposited in commercial banks since last Friday when a new lower main interest rate of 20 percent montly or 240 percent annually took effect, central bank governor Lyubomir Filipov said.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- The U.S. ABC TV company has bought 30 percent of Bulgaria's private TV station Nova Televizia (NTV), the NTV executive director said.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
