<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136422" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukrainian leader angered at Russian vote on fleet.</title>
<headline>Ukrainian leader angered at Russian vote on fleet.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma reacted angrily after Russian deputies voted on Wednesday to halt division of the Black Sea Fleet, an issue which has upset relations since the Soviet Union collapsed.</p>
<p>Ukrainian state television quoted Kuchma as saying that the vote in the State Duma, Russia's lower house of parliament, could lead to &quot;a worsening in relations between the Ukrainian and Russian people&quot;.</p>
<p>Kuchma's spokesman Dmytro Markov said the Ukrainian leader, due to meet Russian President Boris Yeltsin on Thursday, wanted the division of the 600-vessel fleet speeded up.</p>
<p>But Markov signalled that the Russian vote would not have a negative effect on Kuchma's meeting with the ailing Yeltsin, saying: &quot;It will be a meeting between friends.&quot;</p>
<p>The Russian deputies voted overwhelmingly that Moscow should unilaterally freeze its participation in sharing out the fleet.</p>
<p>Many Duma members argued that the fleet, created more than 200 years ago, would not survive the split, leaving both Russia and Ukraine without a naval force in the Black Sea.</p>
<p>Kuchma said a firm deal had been reached on Tuesday by members of a joint commission for Moscow to pay rent to keep the fleet at the Crimean port of Sevastopol, in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is goodwill between the sides, there will be an agreement. But if there is an attempt to flex muscles or solve this issue at the expense of the other side, heads will roll,&quot; Kuchma was quoted as saying by Interfax-Ukraine news agency.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a practical understanding, there are no differences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other Ukrainian officials also say negotiating teams have made considerable progress on the issue.</p>
<p>But Russia's Itar-Tass news agency quoted a source in Yeltsin's administration as saying that the Russian leader, who is preparing for heart surgery, did not share the optimism.</p>
<p>The source told Tass that Yeltsin expected Russian negotiators to brief him on the latest developments and planned to discuss the issue with Kuchma.</p>
<p>Broad accords have already been signed dividing the fleet but no decision has been reached on a share-out of bases and the future of its headquarters at Sevastopol.</p>
<p>Markov said &quot;principal and important&quot; issues could be raised by Kuchma and Yeltsin but that the full spectrum of bilateral questions would be addressed at a meeting with Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin.</p>
<p>Before falling ill in June, Yeltsin postponed six trips to Kiev to sign a friendship treaty in 20 months.</p>
<p>But Ukrainian Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said in Washington on Tuesday that the deal could be signed next month.</p>
<p>In a sign that Kiev could be softening its position on the fleet, three top Ukrainian navy officials who oppose giving in to Russia on the issue resigned.</p>
<p>&quot;The defence minister of Ukraine today signed a document accepting the resignation of three top navy officials, including the head of the navy, Volodymyr Bezkorovainy,&quot; Defence Ministry spokesman Igor Melnichuk said.</p>
<p>Officially, Bezkorovainy and his deputy Alexei Ryzhenko have resigned for health reasons, while chief-of-staff Nikolai Kostrov has gone to another post.</p>
<p>But the move is bound to be interpreted as a sign Kiev could be ready to compromise on the issue of where to put its post-Soviet share of the fleet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
