<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136468" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Foreigners in Poland spent PLN 5.23 bln in H1 1996.</title>
<headline>Foreigners in Poland spent PLN 5.23 bln in H1 1996.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreigners spent 5.23 billion zlotys in Poland during the first six months of this year, 27 percent more than in the same period last year, the Central Statistical Office (GUS) said in a report on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It said spending by foreigners entering from Poland's eastern and northern neigbours, which include Ukraine, Belarus, Lithuania and Russia, grew to 2.11 billion zlotys, 68 percent more than in the first half of last year.</p>
<p>Travellers who crossed Poland's western border with Germany spent 2.5 billion zlotys during the January-June period, about five percnt more than in the same time in 1995.</p>
<p>GUS, whose figures are based on polls taken at border crossings during the first half of 1996, said foreigners coming from Poland's southern border with the Czech Republic and Slovakia spent 612 million zlotys, up 34 percent.</p>
<p>Data from Poland's central bank, which estimates unofficial cross-border trade by bank flows, showed that foreigners spent $3.5 billion (9.86 billion zlotys) more in Poland than Poles spent abroad in the January-June period.</p>
<p>GUS said food products made up 19 percent of expenditures by travellers arriving in motor vehicles, while those who crossed the Polish border on foot spent 36 percent on food.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
