<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136486" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Institute cuts Yugo 1996 inflation forecast to 85%.</title>
<headline>Institute cuts Yugo 1996 inflation forecast to 85%.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Economics Institute of Belgrade has revised its earlier forecast for 1996 inflation down to 85 percent from 100 percent, but its figure remained above official forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;The slowdown in price growth over the past few months is expected to continue, and we forecast it will be around 1.25 percent in October, which would reduce inflation on an annual level to about 85 percent,&quot; said Goran Pitic, an analyst with the institute.</p>
<p>Official sources and the Institute for Market Research last month had forecast annual inflation as low as 60 percent, or half last year's figure.</p>
<p>According to figures published by the federal statistics office, August prices rose a modest 2.3 percent and September retail sales gained only 1.2 percent.</p>
<p>Although prices are still on an uptrend, their growth has &quot;decelerated,&quot; Pitic said after the release of the institute's latest Market Barometer report.</p>
<p>In September, prices were 84-percent above year ago levels, Pitic said. January-September price growth was up 47 percent against the same period last year.</p>
<p>Relative price stability in the past few months was mostly attributed to a halt in service prices, which were mostly blamed for a 6.6-percent surge in monthly inflation in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Having in mind that prices of services had the highest growth of 125 percent since the beginning of the year, their halting has had a significant impact on the September figure of just 1.2 percent,&quot; Pitic said.</p>
<p>But he warned that the expected electricity price rises had not been calculated in the October forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;If electricity prices go up 45-50 percent, it will certainly reflect on November inflation,&quot; Pitic said.</p>
<p>-- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
