<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136484" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish cabinet seeks higher budget gap, lower taxes.</title>
<headline>Polish cabinet seeks higher budget gap, lower taxes.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish goverment will propose a 1997 budget deficit of 2.8 percent of gross domestic product instead of an earlier planned 2.6 percent but will recommend lower income taxes, the finance minister told parliament.  </p>
<p>&quot;We want to ask the house to approve a budget that will have a deficit of 2.8 percent of GDP,&quot; Grzegorz Kolodko said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Earlier the government, which has until the end of this month to submit its final 1997 budget draft to parliament, signalled it would maintain the original finance ministry target of lowering the deficit to 2.6 percent from this year's planned 2.8 percent.</p>
<p>Kolodko also said the government would ask the Sejm, lower house, due to vote on a package of tax bills later this week, to vote in favour of a cut in personal income taxes to 20, 31 and 43 percent next year from 21, 33 and 45 percent respectively.</p>
<p>The government would also seek a two point cut in corporate income tax to 38 percent.  </p>
<p>Kolodko said the government would also propose a further cut in personal income taxes in 1998 to 20, 30 and 40 percent.</p>
<p>Parliament will debate the proposals on Thursday and vote on them on the same day or on Friday.</p>
<p>Kolodko's declaration means that the government has returned to its original plan to lower taxes, which it abandoned earlier this month under pressure from parliamentary committees.</p>
<p>Kolodko stressed the government maintained its goal of cutting inflation to about 13 percent in December 1997 from 17 percent planned for the end of this year and GDP was still expected to grow 5.5 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Kolodko said about two billion zlotys in lost tax revenues would be compensated by higher deficit, higher privatisation revenues and expected boost to receipts from value added tax, from more robust consumer spending.</p>
<p>The government expects to save between 150 and 200 million zlotys thanks to improved management of the public debt, whose ratio to GDP is set to fall next year, he added.</p>
<p>He confirmed Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz's statement earlier on Wednesday that the 1997 budget draft, due to go to parliament next week, envisaged higher real spending for many vital areas.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said real-term spending for education would grow by nearly six percent, for health care by nearly six percent, for the judicial system by nearly seven percent, for internal security and agriculture by five percent, for university education and science by 7.5 percent while for culture by 8.3 percent. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
