<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136419" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>BLANTYRE, Oct 23 (Reuter) These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- Straight Talk, a safe sex, Aids awareness, drug and alcohol control radio programme for the youth is threatened with a ban at the country's only state run radio, Malawi Broadcasting Corporation (MBC), for using language against the radio's policy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Government said it is taking seriously threats that some members of the opposition Alliance for Democracy (AFORD) will bring a Rwanda type of bloodshed to the country if their enstranged member of parliament, busines tycoon Chenda Mkandawire, was allowed to speak at presidential rallies.</p>
<p>- One of the big political parties is buying off voter registration cards in the run up to the by-elections to be held on November 19 in Blantyre city.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Prices of medicinal drugs will soon drop after a special committee set to probe drug pricing and sourcing said it would likely recommend government drop a 20 per cent surtax and 10 per cent customs duty on imported drugs.</p>
<p>- The National Compensation Tribunal, a tribunal set to compensate victims of former President Kamuzu Banda's 30-year-old dictatorship, has run out of funds and it is not known when it will be replenished.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
