<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136478" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia Duma votes to halt Black Sea Fleet division.</title>
<headline>Russia Duma votes to halt Black Sea Fleet division.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's parliament on Wednesday voted to halt the division of the Black Sea Fleet with Ukraine in a move likely to further stir emotions in the uneasy relations between the two Slav former Soviet republics.</p>
<p>The State Duma lower house of parliament passed by 334-1 a draft law under which Moscow should unilaterally freeze its participation in the share-out of the 600-vessel fleet.</p>
<p>Parliament analysts said however there was little chance that President Boris Yeltsin, who was due to discuss the problem of the fleet during a meeting with his Ukrainian counterpart, Leonid Kuchma, on Thursday, would sign the draft into law.</p>
<p>Many Duma deputies have argued that the fleet, created more than 200 years ago as a single highly-integrated force, will not survive the division and insiste it should either be declared wholly Russian or be run jointly by Moscow and Kiev.</p>
<p>The row over the fleet has upset relations between the two states ever since the Soviet Union collapsed in late 1991.</p>
<p>The fate of the fleet, whose division was sanctioned by a 1992 deal, is the main obstacle preventing Moscow and Kiev signing a long-delayed friendship treaty.</p>
<p>Broad accords have already been signed dividing the fleet but no decision has been reached on a share-out of bases and the future of its headquarters in the Crimean port of Sevastopol, in Ukraine.</p>
<p>On Monday Moscow's powerful mayor Yuri Luzhkov said Russia should not concede any ground over the status of Sevastopol.</p>
<p>Luzhkov, a possible future contender for the Russian presidency, said Sevastopol had never been part of the surrounding Crimean region that was granted to Ukraine by Soviet leader Nikita Khruschev in 1954.</p>
<p>Other Russian politicians, including sacked security chief Alexander Lebed, have also used the Sevastopol issue to demonstrate their nationalist credentials.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials say negotiating teams have made considerable progress over the problems of dividing the fleet.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted a source in Yeltsin's administration as saying that the Russian leader, who is preparing for heart surgery, did not share such optimism.</p>
<p>The source told Tass that Yeltsin expected Russian negotiators to brief him on the latest developments and planned to discuss the issue with Kuchma.</p>
<p>Kuchma has said he was not planning to discuss any major political issues with Yeltsin and his visit was intended to show support for the Kremlin leader ahead of the operation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
