<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136444" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: US again questions Slovakia's democracy.</title>
<headline>US again questions Slovakia's democracy.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Wednesday expressed concerns about Slovakia's commitment to the democratic basis of NATO membership, for the second time in as many days.</p>
<p>&quot;For Slovakia to achieve membership in NATO its government must demonstrate an active committment to democratic principles,&quot; Eric Newsom, U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Political Military Affairs, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;You are all aware of U.S. concerns about the state of Slovakia's democracy,&quot; Newsom told a news conference during an official visit to Bratislava.</p>
<p>Newsom's comments came a day after separate speeches by U.S. ambassador to Slovakia Ralph Johnson and European Union ambassador to Slovakia Georgios Zavvos.</p>
<p>Both warned Slovakia that foot dragging on democratic reforms could delay membership in NATO and the EU.</p>
<p>Johnson repeated U.S. concerns that a number of Slovak laws and proposals &quot;do not conform to generally accepted notions of a democratic society&quot;.</p>
<p>He listed as examples restrictive media laws, a law governing univesities, and a language law widely seen as discriminatory against the country's large Hungarian minority.</p>
<p>Johnson's speech came on the same day President Bill Clinton set 1999 as the target date for admitting new members to NATO from the former Soviet-bloc countries.</p>
<p>Slovakia insists that it should be in the earliest expansions of the EU and NATO, but recent statements by western diplomats suggests that Slovakia risks dropping out of the ranks of those considered for membership in the first round.</p>
<p>Hungary, Poland and the Czech Republic are believed to be front runners for entry by the end of the century.</p>
<p>The EU and the U.S. have expressed concerns about Slovakia's democracy since populist Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar was returned to power in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think NATO will seek to impose any conditions on a country's entry beyond that country's ability to meet the basic tests that any country has to meet in order to be part of this democratic alliance,&quot; Newsom said.</p>
<p>Newsom held talks in Bratislava on security and arms control issues with senior Slovak political and military officials, including discussions on NATO expansion.</p>
<p>Also on Tuesday, the EU's Zavvos told a town meeting in Stupava, near Bratislava that Slovakia still had &quot;much work to be done and in this task there can be no delay&quot; unless Slovakia wanted to be left behind on EU membership.</p>
<p>Last week Meciar brushed aside western fears and said NATO was trying to halt Slovak efforts to be a political bridge between east and west.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
