<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136495" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak c.bank says interest rates &quot;too high&quot; - paper.</title>
<headline>Slovak c.bank says interest rates &quot;too high&quot; - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Slovak central bank believes that steps taken to slow growth in money supply were working and interest rates were now &quot;too high&quot; given current inflation figures, the economic weekly Trend reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Current interest rates are too high, considering the relatively low inflation rate and it's good outlook,&quot; Marian Jusko, NBS vice-governor, told Trend.</p>
<p>Year-on-year inflation in September was 5.2 percent, down from 8.8 percent in the same period during 1995. The central bank was still waiting to see the full effect of recent measures to curb money supply growth, Jusko said.</p>
<p>&quot;The (measures) have shown their effect, the dynamics of credit extension and money supply growth have slowed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In mid-July the central bank attempted to choke money supply growth by raising bank minimum reserve requirements, raising its key Lombard rate to 15 percent from 13, and widening the band within which it fixes the daily crown rate.</p>
<p>Growth of the main money supply measure, M2, dipped below 19 percent year-on-year in September after 19.5 percent in August.</p>
<p>Jusko also criticised the attitude of the country's commercial banks, saying they must take more interest in monetary stability. Banks were only willing to buy state and central bank bills at &quot;high&quot; yields, he noted.</p>
<p>&quot;It (high yields) is not a healthy development. If our open market intervention proves insufficient...and such an attitude by commercial banks continues, we would be forced to implement some counter-measures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jusko said considerations included &quot;softer&quot; measures, such as a further rise in minimum reserves, or introducing a compulsory inclusion of state or central bank securities in commercial bank portfolios.</p>
<p>&quot;A reinforcement of credit limits also comes into consideration....though in my view the situation is not such that we would have to implement this very direct measure&quot;.</p>
<p>The NBS abolished credit limits at the start of 1996 after positive inflation figures allowed an easing of monetary policy.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
