<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136438" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poles receive Yad Vashem honour for saving Jews.</title>
<headline>Poles receive Yad Vashem honour for saving Jews.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Half a century after her quiet heroism saved a Jewish boy from the Holocaust, Marta Peplowska was honoured by Israel in Warsaw on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The frail 88-year-old villager was among 35 Poles decorated by Israel's ambassador on behalf of the Yad Vashem holocaust memorial Institute in Jerusalem for risking their lives and those of their families to shelter Jews from Nazi German invaders in World War Two.</p>
<p>Peplowska and her farmer husband hid Henryk Borczuk, a 12-year-old fugitive from the Warsaw Ghetto, even though they had five children of their own and a German officer, stationed in their village of Szulmierz, periodically checked her house.</p>
<p>&quot;I was terribly scared,&quot; she recalled with a gentle smile.</p>
<p>&quot;The German came one night and there was the boy, sleeping on the bed with my son, but no-one knew he was a Jew,&quot; she told Reuters after receiving a medal, a diploma and a single pink rose at the ceremony in Warsaw's Chamber Opera hall.</p>
<p>The award, known officially as the &quot;Righteous among the nations&quot; is given to gentiles who helped save Jews from Nazi terror in World War Two.</p>
<p>She did not hesitate when asked why she hid the fugitive from the Nazis, who murdered most of Poland's 3.5 million Jews.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt so sorry for him. He was so young,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Jerzy Zwierzchowski, a Warsaw driver who helped several Jews before himself being denounced and sent to a concentration camp, said he had never been frightened.</p>
<p>&quot;Me scared? No. I was a brave fellow,&quot; he laughed.</p>
<p>&quot;I had friends...I grew up among Jews. Where I lived there was a bazaar where most of the people were Jewish and I used to play with those children,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Poles make up around 4,700 of about 14,000 people honoured by Yad Vashem in Jerusalem for helping Jews during the war.</p>
<p>But the process of recognising them was long hindered by the anti-Israel stance of Poland's rulers before the 1989 fall of communism and for many public recognition has come too late.</p>
<p>At Wednesday's Warsaw ceremony more than half the awards were collected by relatives or friends of recipients who had either died or were too frail to attend.</p>
<p>Only a few thousand Jews remain in Poland -- the few religious congregations now number only about 3,500 ageing people -- following waves of emigration prompted in part by some ugly post-war anti-Semitic episodes.</p>
<p>&quot;Let those few Jews who survive among us with their families regard Poland as their own home,&quot; said Polish Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz in a speech read on his behalf at the ceremony.</p>
<p>He said he bowed low before those honoured by Yad Vashem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
