<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136498" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Zloty ends flat after tracking dollar losses.</title>
<headline>Zloty ends flat after tracking dollar losses.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty closed nearly unchanged against the basket of currencies after spending the session cautiously adjusting to the dollar's plunge against the mark in European trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>The session started with players selling zlotys on expectations that the dollar's slide was a correction, but the Polish unit hit support and was left to follow world trends.</p>
<p>&quot;Early dollar-buying pulled the zloty down to support at 1.80 percent from parity, but from then on the market followed international dollar movements with nothing special happening here,&quot; said Marcin Stefaniuk from BDK SA.  </p>
<p>The zloty closed at 1.92/1.82 percent from the trading band centre against 1.91/1.86 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Zloty was at 2.8150/80 to the dollar, up from 2.8261/76 on Tuesday and at 1.8505/25 to the mark, down from 1.8418/27.</p>
<p>Liquidity on the money market decreased slightly and pulled overnight deposit rates up to 19.1/19.5 percent, from 19.1/19.3 at opening, as banks did not want to let out cash before balancing end-of-month required reserve accounts.</p>
<p>Tomorrow/next were at 19.2/19.5 percent against opening's 19.1/19.35 percent, which may have also reflected the impact of the second day of monthly tax payment outflows.  </p>
<p>&quot;Banks had less money on Wednesday, but most probably set cash aside for taxes so the decreased liquidity was likely to be connected to the monthly reserve, which ends in a few days,&quot; said Renata Krajewska of PKO BP.</p>
<p>There were only small deals on the secondary T-bill market, focused on the longest 52-week papers quoted at 19.46/19.44 percent against the average yield of 19.46 percent at Monday's primary tender.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
