<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136432" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- An explosion of an as yet unidentified device caused severe damage to a bar in the northeastern city of Maribor on Tuesday morning, but noone was injured. Police said the device was most probably inside the building.</p>
<p>- Following unsuccessful negotiations between unions and employers over workers' benefits on Tuesday, the unions said they will hold a two-hour general strike on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Petrol prices should be increased by at least 20 percent, Slovenian petrol companies said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- The Foreign Ministers of Italy, Hungary and Slovenia will hold a meeting in Rome on Wednesday in order to sign an agreement on mutual cooperation.</p>
<p>- Slovenian Minister of Science Andrej Umek met his Croatian counterpart Ivica Kostovic on Tuesday. They discussed enforcing an agreement on scientific and technological cooperation that was signed two years ago.</p>
<p>- Slovenian pharmaceutical producer Lek celebrated its 50th anniversary on Tuesday. Lek is present on 80 markets worldwide.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- The average Slovenian consumes 31 kilos of fruit and 48 kilos of vegetables per year, compared to the average Austrian who consumes 152 kilos of fruit and 77 kilos of vegetables, a health study found.</p>
<p>- The president of Slovenia's parliament Jozef Skolc visited his Polish counterpart Adam Struzik on Tuesday. Talks concentrated on joining European and Atlantic alliances and mutual cooperation.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- More than 490 exhibitors from 28 countries are participating in an international fair of medical and pharmaceutical equipment, which opened on Tuesday in Ljubljana.</p>
<p>FINANCE</p>
<p>- According to unconfirmed reports banks UBK and Gorenjska banka could team up in the future. The manager of Gorenjska banka said he could neither deny neither confirm the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
