<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136408" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Community spending cuts Nigeria oil losses - Shell.</title>
<headline>Community spending cuts Nigeria oil losses - Shell.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<text>
<p>PORT HARCOURT, Nigeria, Oct 23 - Royal Dutch/Shell Group's Nigerian unit said its increased spending on community assistance in the oil-rich Delta region had reduced the amount of oil production lost to community disturbances and sabotage.</p>
<p>&quot;Disturbances are on the increase again recently but because of the community projects the effect on business is reducing,&quot; Victor Dania, public and community affairs manager in Shell's eastern Nigeria operations based in Port Harcourt told visitng reporters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Production losses arising from disturbances in the 500,000 barrels per day (bpd) Bonny fields in the region were reduced to 710,000 barrels in the first six months of 1996, Dania said.</p>
<p>That compares with 5.7 million barrels lost in all of 1995 and 11.4 million barrels in 1994 when oil workers involved in a political strike that lasted two months.</p>
<p>Shell in July this year shut in production at four fields pumping into its Bonny stream following a leak which it said was the result of sabotage.</p>
<p>Acts of sabotage led Shell, which pumps half of Nigeria's crude oil, to withdraw from Ogoniland in Delta region in 1993.</p>
<p>The company says it is in no hurry to resume operations there but is keen to restore goodwill in the volatile region.</p>
<p>Nigeria provoked worldwide outrage last November when it hanged nine Ogoni minority rights activists including author Ken Saro-Wiwa.</p>
<p>Since leaving Ogoniland, Shell has increased community assistance and it admits it failed in the past to do enough for the impoverished local commmunities which surround its operations.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we did enough,&quot; Shell Nigeria managing director Brian Anderson said in Lagos on Monday. &quot;At the time we could have done a bit more and we didn't but now I think we are doing what we have to.&quot;</p>
<p>Dania said the eastern division would spend $30 million this year on community assistance which he said was $10 million more than government expenditure for the region.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;Disruptions are not so bad but still too high and communities still tend to take the law into their own hands.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason is a perception of inequality in the distribution of wealth. The communities tell us they are using Shell to attract the attention of the government,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
