<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136465" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Gazprom chief launches part of Yamal gas link.</title>
<headline>Gazprom chief launches part of Yamal gas link.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Sayenko</byline>
<dateline>SLONIM, Belarus 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of Russia's natural gas monopoly, RAO Gazprom, ceremonially began construction work on Wednesday on a link in a massive pipeline network which will carry Russian gas to Western Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a historic day for us,&quot; chief executive Rem Vyakhirev told reporters as workers welded a section of the link near Slonim, about 150 km southwest of the Belarussian capital Minsk and 100 km east of the Polish border.</p>
<p>The pipeline section is a small but key part of Gazprom's ambitious, $40 billion Yamal-Europe project.</p>
<p>The project, when fully realised, will carry huge supplies of Russian gas from the Yamal peninsula in the Arctic to Germany and beyond via Belarus and Poland.</p>
<p>Yamal aims to double Russia's gas exports to Europe by 2010 via a vast, 4,107 km pipeline network.</p>
<p>Vyakhirev said, &quot;In four to five years the Yamal-Europe gas pipeline will unite Europe's entire energy system from Poland to Spain.&quot;</p>
<p>To help raise capital for Yamal, Gazprom is offering some of its shares abroad as part of a plan to sell a total nine percent stake to foreign investors.</p>
<p>On Monday it announced it had raised $373.275 million by selling about one percent of its shares through an issue of American Depositary Shares in London.</p>
<p>Russian gas already accounts for 60 percent of Europe's total gas imports, and Russia, the world's largest gas producer, has more than one-third of world reserves.</p>
<p>Vyakhirev said construction of the Belarussian section would be completed in 1998 as planned and that the first gas would reach Poland and Germany in 1999.</p>
<p>But initially it would carry half its capacity, he said.</p>
<p>The Belarussian section of the link comprises two spurs, each stretching over 575 km and capable of carrying about 68 billion cubic metres a year.</p>
<p>The two spurs will hook into an existing Belarussian pipeline and then into the Polish grid.</p>
<p>The entire Yamal system, which will be constructed in stages and link into existing pipelines in some places, will have an initial capacity of 83 billion cubic metres (bcm) per year, including around 52 bcm to Western Europe.</p>
<p>Belarus consumes 14 bcm of Russian gas a year.</p>
<p>Yamal has 20 percent of the country's reserves, or 10,400 bcm.</p>
<p>Gazprom has won financing from European banks for the European part of the Yamal pipeline, but has not yet found capital for the Russian section and to tap fully Yamal's reserves.</p>
<p>Vyakhirev said the Russian sections would be financed by Gazprom profits, credits and share sales.</p>
<p>&quot;I call this two and a half financing sources,&quot; he said. &quot;The first two are serious, but half of this (financing) will come from the sale of (our) shares.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SLONIM, Belarus"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
