<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136442" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Soviet invasion of Hungary was justified - Kryuchkov.</title>
<headline>Soviet invasion of Hungary was justified - Kryuchkov.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former leading Soviet official said on Wednesday Moscow was totally justified in crushing the 1956 uprising in Hungary because it prevented the country from descending into a bloodbath.</p>
<p>Vladimir Kryuchkov, a former head of the KGB secret police, also said Imre Nagy -- the Hungarian prime minister who led the uprising and was later executed -- had in fact been a criminal and an informer rather than a national hero.</p>
<p>As Kryuchkov talked to Russian television, hundreds gathered in Budapest to mark the 40th anniversary of the October 23 uprising in which 25,000 people died. Soviet forces withdrew on October 31 but returned on November 4 to crush the revolt.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a shame that hundreds of our troops lost their lives but I am deeply convinced we saved Hungary from further unhappiness,&quot; said Kryuchkov, who at the time was serving as press attache to the Soviet embassy in Budapest.</p>
<p>Kremlin officials now blame the Soviet Communist leadership for launching the invasion but Kryuchkov was unrepentant.</p>
<p>He said the true nature of the uprising had revealed itself in the reprisals which took place from October 31 to November 4, when many Hungarians used the period to settle scores with pro-Moscow officials and the hated AVO secret police.</p>
<p>&quot;I was on the streets of Budapest and I saw the robberies, the murders, the assaults. You can't even imagine seeing a man hanged upside down by his legs and tortured. It was violence of a mass character,&quot; said Kryuchkov.</p>
<p>&quot;When Hungarians saw this they realised what a deep chasm of unhappiness and woe they had been thrust into. I had many Hungarian friends who condemned our first entry into Budapest but who prayed to God that our forces would come back to help.&quot;</p>
<p>According to documents published in Novoe Vremya magazine, 669 Soviet officers and soldiers were killed in the uprising. A further 1,450 were injured and 51 went missing.</p>
<p>Nagy, a communist who led the revolution as prime minister, was executed in 1958. He was replaced by former ally Janos Kadar, who crucially changed sides in early November 1956 after a visit to Moscow and then ruled Hungary until 1988.</p>
<p>Hungary fared reasonably well under Kadar's 32-year reign, although people never forgot his role in the uprising.</p>
<p>But Kryuchkov said people would have been horrified had they known Nagy's true character, claiming he was a criminal and had been an informer for the NKVD, the predecessor to the KGB.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1989, when I became the head of the KGB, we quite by chance found documents which showed what kind of person Nagy was,&quot; said Kryuchkov, one of the eight-man gang who tried to overthrow Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev in August 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;I discovered that Imre Nagy was an out-and-out criminal. He worked for the NKVD, had the codename Volodya, and wrote denunciations in Russian and Hungarian (after World War Two).</p>
<p>&quot;These denunciations led to around 20 people being sentenced to death and another 300 being sentenced to various periods of time in jail.&quot;</p>
<p>Kryuchkov said Kadar had always suspected Nagy and blamed him for the executions of Hungarian Communist Party officials in Moscow in the 1930s when Stalin's purges were at their peak.</p>
<p>&quot;Now the Hungarians have begun to realise what happened and they don't praise Nagy as much. I think Kadar's tragedy was that he knew he was dealing with a traitor but didn't have the documents to prove it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
