<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136464" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Amerbank mulls various share issues.</title>
<headline>Amerbank mulls various share issues.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's Bank Amerykanski w Polsce Amerbank SA (Amerbank) is mulling a regular share issue as well as one to a strategic investor, the bank's deputy president said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Wlodzimierz Paszkowski told Reuters that shortly before the bank's planned shareholders meeting on November 15 it would make clear on what kind of issue the shareholders would vote.</p>
<p>&quot;We will propose a text for a potential new share issue but details of the size or how it will be addressed we will be much clearer in the next two weeks,&quot; Paszkowski told Reuters.</p>
<p>Paszkowski said Amerbank was seeking funds to boost its lending operations and to have the option to engage in capital investment projects in financial or non-financial firms.</p>
<p>&quot;Our regular banking activities are expanding so fast, together with our clients...that we have to increase our own funds and match this with assets we can lend to our clients,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day Paszkowski told Reuters the bank hoped to find a minority strategic investor by the end of the year who would help provide the Polish bank with expertise.</p>
<p>-- Steven Silber +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
