<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136424" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak deputies show contempt for democracy fears.</title>
<headline>Slovak deputies show contempt for democracy fears.</headline>
<byline>Peter Javurek</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovakia's ruling coalition on Wednesday brushed aside Western concerns over the country's path to democracy by approving two laws criticised by the European Union and the United States as undemocratic.</p>
<p>Deputies of the three-party coalition approved a law giving the public prosecutor's office unprecedented supervisory and executive powers which President Michal Kovac has rejected.</p>
<p>Later they passed a law on universities giving the education ministry broad powers over academic affairs, overturning another veto by Kovac.</p>
<p>The votes were taken a day after the U.S. and European Union ambassadors said that Slovakia had to improve its record on democratic reforms if it wanted to join organisations such as the EU and NATO.</p>
<p>The prosecution office law, originally passed by parliament in September but returned by Kovac for revision, was approved by 74 votes to 60 in the 150-seat house. The universities law, also passed in September but rejected by Kovac, was approved by 79 votes to 44.</p>
<p>Under the constitution the president can refuse to sign a law only once. If parliament approves a law for a second time, the president is obliged to sign it.</p>
<p>However, a law can still be challenged before the Constitutional Court which has the last say.</p>
<p>The United States publicly expressed concerns on Wednesday, for the second time in as many days, about Slovakia's commitment to democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;For Slovakia to achieve membership in NATO its government must demonstrate an active committment to democratic principles,&quot; Eric Newsom, U.S. Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Political Military Affairs, told reporters on a visit to Bratislava.</p>
<p>&quot;You are all aware of U.S. concerns about the state of Slovakia's democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, U.S. Ambassador Ralph Johnson repeated Washington's concerns over a number of Slovak laws &quot;which do not conform to generally accepted notions of a democratic society&quot;. EU ambassador Georgious Zavvos said there was much work  ahead if Slovakia was to earn a place in Western structures.</p>
<p>Kovac attacked the prosecution law as undemocratic. The president and the opposition say the law would create a military-style pyramid structure in the prosecutor's office, such as before the 1989 fall of communism, allowing political abuse of power.</p>
<p>Deputies of Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar's Movement for a Democratic Slovakia and its coalition partners, the far-right Slovak National Party and the ultra-left Workers' Party, also ignored objections from Kovac and the opposition to the education law, passing it with only minor changes.</p>
<p>Kovac and the opposition attacked that law as allowing inadmissible interference of the state in academic freedoms.</p>
<p>The law gives the education ministry the right to cancel decisions of university academic councils, including the granting of academic titles, and a say in creating or closing university faculties.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of the laws by which Slovakia is adopting the state dictate,&quot; said Peter Lauko of the opposition Christian Democratic Movement.</p>
<p>Later in the 14-day parliamentary session the coalition is expected to approve a law on the &quot;protection of the republic&quot; which borrows heavily on communist-era anti-subversion legislation.</p>
<p>Kovac has also rejected that measure.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
