<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136426" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Hansapank, Savings Bank in focus on Estonia market.</title>
<headline>Hansapank, Savings Bank in focus on Estonia market.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Estonia's two largest banks were in the spotlight on Wednesday as market leader Hansapank said it was considering selling its 21 percent stake in the country's number two bank, Savings Bank, dealers said.</p>
<p>Hansapank and Savings Bank were both well-traded stocks on the official list, which had overall volume of 8.3 million kroons. Hansapank turned over 2.7 million kroons and jumped to close a of 107 kroons from 105.60.</p>
<p>The Tallinn stock exchange index rose by a strong 0.93 percent to 106.12.</p>
<p>Hansapank earlier said it would make an extraordinary profit of 89.7 million kroons by the sale of the stake, over which it was talking to many companies, including foreign investors.</p>
<p>But Savings bank slipped to 40.40 kroons against 41.45 kroons and showed trade of 3.7 million kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;Some investors feared that some blocks of this stake could appear on the market and bring the price down but I doubt that,&quot; said Rein Ratsepp, dealer at Tallinna Pank.</p>
<p>Hansapank also published its nine-month consolidated results and said it made a net profit of 169 million kroons. But this was seen to have little impact on the share price.</p>
<p>The over-the-counter free market had volume of 7.6 million kroons and drug producer Tallinn Pharmaceutical factory was the most traded stock with the turn over of 5.3 million kroons.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical closed at 54.85 kroons versus 53.50 yesterday, although dealers could not pinpoint the cause of the rise.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
