<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136411" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 23.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- Central Bank Governor Paul Ogwuma tells commercial banks the government will intervene if they allow newly freed interest rates to go haywire.</p>
<p>- State-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corporation invites bids for purchase of Nigerian oil refineries.</p>
<p>- Pinnacle Commercial Bank gets 90 days to settle its debts with the central bank or face liquidation, sources say.</p>
<p>- A draft energy policy for Nigeria is now awaiting approval of the head of state, General Sani Abacha, Daily Times learns.</p>
<p>- Some 600 vehicles donated eight months ago to the federal government by the World Bank to ease transport problems in primary and secondary schools are lying idle.</p>
<p>- THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>- Local council polls likely to be held on December 17, sources in the electoral comsission say.</p>
<p>- Nigerian Ports Plc reverts to its previous name of Nigerian Port Authority in line with government directive.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Inflation falls by four percent in July to 44.7 percent from 48.7 percent in June, federal officie of statistics figures say.</p>
<p>- Nigeria donates bitumen to Burkina Faso, industry sources say.</p>
<p>- Value added tax overshoots target of 22 billion naira this year.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
