<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136402" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zambia urges speedy South African privatisation.</title>
<headline>Zambia urges speedy South African privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa needs to press ahead with its fledgling privatisation programme in order to spur the rest of the region down the path of economic reform, Zambia's finance minister said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ronald Penza, speaking at the Southern African Trade and Investment Summit in Harare, said South Africa had to show leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;(We) demand that South Africa gives leadership in this respect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Africa's privatisation programme has come under criticism from some business leaders and analysts for being too slow.</p>
<p>The first major sell-off of state assets, that of a 20 to 30 percent stake in telecommunications company Telkom, is still at the shortlist stage with seven potential partners in the wings.</p>
<p>After decades of being shunned by its neighbours, post-apartheid South Africa, with its advanced financial structure and industrial strength, has emerged as the leading power in the region.</p>
<p>But Penza also took a dig at South African exchange controls, which hamper the flow of funds from South Africa. Other nations in the area hope that the relaxation of controls will make it easier for firms to use South Africa as a base to expand to her neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;The time for exchange controls is past,&quot; Penza said.</p>
<p>The South African government is committed to gradually removing the controls, but with no time scale.</p>
<p>A report from Dutch bank ABN AMRO said last week that South Africa would probably abolish all remaining foreign exchange controls within two years.</p>
<p>Low foreign reserves, which stand at about 10 billion rand or four weeks import cover, will prevent any significant moves on liberalising the rand in the near term, the bank said.</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Harare Newsroom + 263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
