<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136441" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia sheltered Bosnian war crime suspect - paper.</title>
<headline>Croatia sheltered Bosnian war crime suspect - paper.</headline>
<byline>Laura Lui</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Bosnian Croat wanted by the U.N. War Crimes Tribunal had lived with impunity in Croatia's southern port of Split for almost a year, a leading independent newspaper said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Globus weekly said Ivica Rajic, a militia leader linked to the 1993 massacre of 16 Moslem civilians in the Bosnian village of Stupni Do, had lived in a Split hotel owned by the Croatian Defence Ministry since early 1996.</p>
<p>It published pictures of Rajic, said to have been taken last week, dressed in a track suit and reading a newspaper near the hotel.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council two weeks ago warned Croatia's nationalist government over a failure to arrest and hand over Rajic to the tribunal on former Yugoslavia, based in The Hague.</p>
<p>The Council of Europe admitted Croatia last week as its 40th member but diplomats said further progress by Zagreb towards European Union integration would depend in part on cooperation with the tribunal.</p>
<p>Under special legislation passed by parliament six months ago. Croatia is committed to extraditing indicted war criminals found on its territory. But only one of several indicted suspects spotted on Croatian territory has been handed over.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Mate Granic told Globus he did not know of Rajic's whereabouts but said Croatia would act if his presence in Croatia was proven.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a single excuse for Croatia not to act in accordance with the law,&quot; Granic said. &quot;His case presents one of our bigger foreign policy problems.&quot;</p>
<p>But Globus said it had found out from Defence Ministry intelligence sources that Rajic had left Croatia three days after its photographers tracked him down in Split.</p>
<p>Globus had a similar scoop in July when it published pictures of number one Bosnian Croat war crimes suspect Dario Kordic, former head of the Bosnian wing of Croatia's ruling HDZ party, allegedly living in a ministry apartment in Zagreb.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I know Kordic is now somewhere on the territory of the (Moslem-Croat) Federation (in Bosnia) and is out of reach of the Croatian police,&quot; Granic said.</p>
<p>Kordic is accused of complicity in massacres and ethnic expulsions of Moslems in the Lasva Valley of central Bosnia.</p>
<p>Granic said one reason why Croatia had so far failed to hand him and Rajic over was because a large part of the public remained fiercely opposed to their extradition.</p>
<p>The tribunal in September issued an international arrest warrant for Rajic, confirming year-old charges against him.</p>
<p>Bosnian Moslems and Croats fought a bitter 10-month war in 1993-94, overshadowed by the central Serb-Moslem conflict. They formed a federation only after strong Western pressure.</p>
<p>The tribunal said in September that evidence submitted in the case against Rajic was a breakthrough for having established Croatia's direct involvement in the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>Croatia has so far arrested only one suspect, former detention camp commander Zlatko Aleksovski, who is part Macedonian, and has decided to extradite him to The Hague.</p>
<p>The Croatian Supreme Court earlier this month turned down Aleksovski's appeal against extradition.</p>
<p>Kordic's former right hand man, General Tihomir Blaskic, turned himself in to the tribunal voluntarily last April. His trial is due to begin in January.</p>
<p>The tribunal has so far indicted 18 Croats, 54 Serbs and three Moslems for war crimes. It has seven suspects in custody.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
