<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136405" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire hikes war of words against Rwanda, Burundi.</title>
<headline>Zaire hikes war of words against Rwanda, Burundi.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Malu-Malu</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire has stepped up a war of words against neighbours Rwanda and Burundi, accusing them of attacking its eastern refugee zone where fighting between its soldiers and ethnic Tutsi rebels has sparked a civilian exodus.</p>
<p>Ailing President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing in Europe after surgery for prostate cancer, has sent a message saying the government's top priority should be protecting national unity.</p>
<p>State radio on Wednesday urged the population at large to contribute money to help Zairean troops.</p>
<p>&quot;The war in the east concerns all Zaireans,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Boguo Makeli said late on Tuesday that soldiers from Rwanda and Burundi's Tutsi-dominated armies had launched an attack inside South Kivu province and that Rwandan soldiers had launched raids inside North Kivu.</p>
<p>&quot;In South Kivu, elements of the Rwandan and Burundian armed forces, almost 1,700 men, attacked Zairean territory between Bwegera and Luvungi,&quot; he told reporters after an emergency cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;In North Kivu, elements of the Rwandan army attacked certain localities, disrupting traffic between Goma and Rutshuru,&quot; he added. &quot;The Zairean armed forces repulsed the Rwandan army attacks on Kibimba, Rugari and Bunangana.&quot;</p>
<p>Mobutu's spokesman, Kabuya Lumuna, told state television on Tuesday night the president &quot;deplored&quot; what was happening in the east.</p>
<p>&quot;The head of state directs the government to set aside all other business to safeguard national unity and secure national territorial integrity by ensuring the invaders devastating the east can do no further harm,&quot; Kabuya said.</p>
<p>Kabuya, speaking from Lausanne in Switzerland, said Mobutu would send an envoy to his counterparts in the Central African Great Lakes region to try to ensure a return to peace there.</p>
<p>&quot;The president asks each Zairean man and woman to maintain confidence in the fighting forces and in the authorities responsible for ensuring their security,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Zaire's national press, regardless of its political orientation, pointed the finger of blame at Rwanda.</p>
<p>&quot;The Banyamulenge problem has grown to such an extent that the only solution is their return to what is considered their country of origin, in other words Rwanda,&quot; said Le Standard, a weekly close to Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge, who migrated from Rwanda in the late 18th century, accuse local Zaireans of forcing them to leave.</p>
<p>The fighting has fueled fears that the Hutu and Tutsi rivalry that lay behind the 1994 genocide of minority Tutsis by Hutu hardliners in Rwanda and Burundi's equally bitter civil war could ignite a wider conflict in the region.</p>
<p>Up to a quarter of a million Hutu refugees took flight after fighting between the Zairean army and Banyamulenge rebels flared on Friday in the south near the town of Uvira and the border with Burundi.</p>
<p>Aid workers, who predict a humanitarian catastrophe, say Zairean civilians have started to join the refugees and warn that food is running short.</p>
<p>There is no reliable death toll but unconfirmed reports suggest dozens of people, mostly civilians, have been killed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
