<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136446" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria to offer three cement plants for sale.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria to offer three cement plants for sale.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria, in the throes of an economic crisis, plans to offer for sale three cement plants in November, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that we will be able to offer a memorandum for the sale of the plants to potential buyers on November 15-20,&quot; said Lyuben Petrov from the construction ministry.</p>
<p>The three plants at stake are Zlatna Panega, Beloizvorski Ziment and Granitoid.</p>
<p>Petrov said some foreign firms had already expressed interest in the plants. They included Germany's Heidelberger Zement AG and S.A. Cimenteries CBR of Belgium (owned since 1993 by Heidelberger), Swiss building materials group Holderbank Financiere Glarus AG, France's Lafarge-Coppe and other firms from Austria, Israel and Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;We want the government to take a quick decision on granting concessions to the foreign firms that will buy the cement plants as their production is linked to using quarries,&quot; Petrov told reporters.</p>
<p>Potential buyers want government guarantees that they can exploit the quarries next to the plants, Petrov said.</p>
<p>He said the ministry had not decided how large stakes is would sell.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a matter of negotiations,&quot; he said, adding that cement production had been among the most profitable industries in Bulgaria.</p>
<p>In addition to needing the sell-off revenues, the debt-ridden country lacked the capital to upgrade the cement plants, officials said.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
