<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136435" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Russia, Ukraine leaders to meet in Moscow.</title>
<headline>Russia, Ukraine leaders to meet in Moscow.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Kulikov</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma flies to Moscow on Thursday to meet President Boris Yeltsin for talks overshadowed by a Russian parliament vote to freeze division of the disputed Black Sea fleet.</p>
<p>Deputies in Russia's State Duma lower house voted overwhelmingly on Wednesday to halt division between Russia and Ukraine of the 600-vessel fleet, a vestige of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>They have argued that the fleet, created more than 200 years ago as a single highly-integrated structure, would not survive the split and the two countries would be left without a naval force in the Black Sea.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's representative in the Duma, Alexander Kotenkov, made clear the vote had not been coordinated with the president, who is preparing for heart surgery.</p>
<p>The vote is likely to upset already uneasy relations between the two Slav former Soviet states.</p>
<p>Kuchma reacted angrily, saying the vote could lead to &quot;a worsening in relations between the Ukrainian and Russian people&quot; -- and not just between two legislatures.</p>
<p>His spokesman Dmytro Markov suggested it would not have a negative effect on the meeting with the Russian leader, saying: &quot;It will be a meeting between friends.&quot;</p>
<p>Kuchma said a firm deal had been reached on Tuesday by members of a joint commission which foresaw Moscow paying rent to keep ships at the Crimean port of Sevastopol, in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a practical understanding, there are no differences,&quot; Kuchma was quoted as saying by Interfax-Ukraine news agency.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials also say negotiating teams have made considerable progress on the issue.</p>
<p>But Russia's Itar-Tass news agency quoted a source in Yeltsin's administration as saying the Russian leader did not share such optimism.</p>
<p>Broad accords have already been signed dividing the fleet but no decision has been reached on a share-out of bases and the future of its headquarters at Sevastopol.</p>
<p>Markov said &quot;principal and important&quot; issues could be raised by Kuchma and Yeltsin but that the full spectrum of bilateral questions would be addressed at a meeting with Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin.</p>
<p>Before falling ill in June, Yeltsin had postponed six trips to Kiev in 20 months to sign a friendship treaty.</p>
<p>Ukrainian Foreign Minister Hennady Udovenko said in Washington on Tuesday that a deal could be signed next month.</p>
<p>In a sign that Kiev could be softening its position on the fleet, three top Ukrainian navy officials who oppose giving in to Russia on the issue resigned.</p>
<p>&quot;The defence minister of Ukraine today signed a document accepting the resignation of three top navy officials, including the head of the navy, Volodymyr Bezkorovainy,&quot; said Defence Ministry spokesman Igor Melnichuk.</p>
<p>Officially, Bezkorovainy and his deputy Alexei Ryzhenko have resigned for health reasons, while chief-of-staff Nikolai Kostrov has gone to another post.</p>
<p>But the move was bound to be interpreted as a sign Kiev could be ready to compromise on the issue of where to put its post-Soviet share of the fleet of a few dozen vessels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
