<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136460" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: LUKoil preferred shares lead Russian stocks higher.</title>
<headline>LUKoil preferred shares lead Russian stocks higher.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Russian shares rose on Wednesday with LUKoil preferred shares leading the market higher after the company said it was planning an ADR issue for its preferred stock, traders said.</p>
<p>The Russian Trading System index of 24 shares rose by 2.09 percent to 187.56 on a large $33.84 million in volume.</p>
<p>&quot;Today is a very strong market,&quot; said Martin Diggle from Brunswick. &quot;We're seeing a lot of institutional buying interest. The biggest news on the market today was in LUKoil preferred shares.&quot;</p>
<p>LUKoil preferred shares were the gainer of the day with prices rising to $8.40 from $6.80 at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>LUKoil said on Tuesday it had started proceedings with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to issue level-one American Depository Receipts on preferred stock.</p>
<p>The LUKoil news triggered a strong interest in all preferred shares, Diggle said.</p>
<p>UES preferred shares rose to $0.0512 from $0.0468, Norilsk Nickel preferred were $3.46 after $3.22, Rostelekom preferred rose to $1.92 from $1.69 and Surgutneftegaz preferred were $0.275 after $0.255.</p>
<p>Gazprom  was again one of the most actively traded shares, after Mondays's pricing of its American Depositary Share issue, rising to $0.517 from $5.050.</p>
<p>Diggle forecast a further price rise in the next few days.</p>
<p>&quot;The tone of the market is good,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Surgutneftegaz ordinaries also rose strongly due to a big buy order for the paper with no sell orders, said Samit Yakovlev, chief trader at United City Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no sales in Surgutneftegaz traditionally,&quot; he said. &quot;Clients either do not sell Surgut, or buy it.&quot;</p>
<p>Surgut ordinaries rose to $0.465 from $0.439.</p>
<p>The State Duma lower house of parliament released on Wednesday a list of 73 companies with large tax arrears. The list included UES, Yuganksneftegaz, Varyoganneftegaz, Irkutskenergo and AvtoVAZ.</p>
<p>But Diggle said the market shrugged off the news.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not think people are really focusing on that. People know there are tax arreas. I do not think it is new news,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Red October was traded at $16.50 after $14.35 at Monday's close, when the paper was last traded, Irkutskenergo fell to $0.105 from $0.1075 at Tuesday's close, Yugansknetftegaz was $8.30 after $8.35 and GUM rose to $24.00 from $22.00.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
