<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136404" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Firms must offer role to blacks - Zimbabwe's Mugabe.</title>
<headline>Firms must offer role to blacks - Zimbabwe's Mugabe.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe president Robert Mugabe said on Wednesday it was vital foreign firms investing in Southern African nations offer a role to local black groups.</p>
<p>Mugabe, who was addressing the Southern African Trade and Investment Summit in Harare, said overseas investors were welcome to take stakes in newly privatised businesses but &quot;indigenisation&quot; of African economies was still vital.</p>
<p>&quot;Whilst there is much room for international investors in the privatisation programme, it is vital that the programme incorporates the policy of indigenisation to ensure the participation of the indigenous people in the economy of the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, which has embarked on a privatisation programme, would ensure that any foreign investors taking stakes in major state assets gave black empowerment groups a role within those enterprises, Mugabe said.</p>
<p>&quot;Privatisation is an opportunity to bring in blacks and empower them,&quot; Mugabe said.</p>
<p>Political and business leaders from Southern Africa have gathered to try to boost regional trade and lure foreign investment to their countries.</p>
<p>The region's nations have all to some extent embarked on policies aimed at encouraging the free market and selling off state assets.</p>
<p>But Mugabe said, though the region had won political power from its former colonial masters, it had yet to win economic power. &quot;Political power we do have, economic power we do not have,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We find ourselves in a situation where our people are nothing more than mere workers in a system that derives from the past, and we would want to see them empowered,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Mugabe said &quot;we are not going to nationalise them (businesses in Zimbabwe seen as denying blacks senior management roles), we are only going to persuade them to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paul Harris, Harare Newsroom + 263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
