<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136458" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Nomura no comment on Czech IPB sale.</title>
<headline>Nomura no comment on Czech IPB sale.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>London-based Nomura International Plc on Wednesday declined to comment on Czech media reports that it was looking to participate in the privatisation of Czech bank IPB, saying it was neutral on the subject.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not comment on it. Nothing has been decided so far, we are very neutral (over the Czech bank privatisation),&quot; said Hitoshi Tonomuru, president of Nomura International, during a brief visit to Slovakia.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage the decision is in the hands of the Czech government. It has to decide on its policy and it would be premature to discuss the topic now,&quot; he said after meeting Slovak Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar.</p>
<p>Last Friday, Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik said IPB would be the first of the big four Slovakian banks to undergo privatisation, but gave no details of how, or when the government will sell off its 30 percent holding in IPB.</p>
<p>But Kocarnik gave investors the signal they had been looking for when he said that a strong foreign strategic partner would be the most likely beneficiary of any selloff.</p>
<p>Since the announcement, Nomura and ING Bank have been rumoured in several Czech publications to be the frontrunners in any bid to participate in the bank's privatisation.</p>
<p>-- Peter Laca, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
