<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136430" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian PM seeks backing from security services.</title>
<headline>Russian PM seeks backing from security services.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, asserting his authority as President Boris Yeltsin prepares for heart surgery, urged Russia's security services on Wednesday to steer clear of political conflicts.</p>
<p>Itar-Tass news agency quoted Chernomyrdin as telling leaders of the Federal Security Service (FSB) that they should work with their agents &quot;so that they do not allow themselves to be dragged into conflict between various political groups&quot;.</p>
<p>His remarks were a clear sign of concern about the fragility of recent efforts to promote harmony and unity in the Kremlin following the dismissal by Yeltsin last week of outspoken security chief Alexander Lebed.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin told the FSB, a successor to the Soviet KGB, that certain people were striving &quot;to use the process of democratic reforms in the country to create extremist, militarised, terrorist and other formations&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the activity of such groups was a direct threat to state security. &quot;It is impossible not to see the gravitation towards a strong hand, towards simple, effective, but essentially forceful methods of resolving the problems accumulating in society in unconstitutional ways.&quot;</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, who is Yeltsin's constitutional stand-in and who has already assumed some presidential powers, made no direct reference to Lebed, who made bitter enemies in the Kremlin in four turbulent months as security supremo.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, due to undergo heart bypass surgery next month, sacked Lebed last week for sowing discord and striving for power.</p>
<p>The ex-paratroop general sees himself as a future president. He had been accused by Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov, his arch foe, of seeking to create a 50,000-strong private army and of plotting a coup.</p>
<p>Lebed's dismissal left Chernomyrdin and presidential chief of staff Anatoly Chubais as key decision-makers in Russia.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin and Chubais are to be part of a new &quot;permanent four&quot; policy coordination body proposed by Yeltsin earlier this week. The group will also include the chairmen of the two chambers of parliament.</p>
<p>Parliament, dominated by communists and their allies, on Wednesday condemned the government's handling of the 1996 budget and asked ministers to do more to bring in tax revenues.</p>
<p>Chubais, accused by Lebed of acting as a regent while Yeltsin is ill, attended Wednesday's meeting with the FSB leadership.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin said Yeltsin's election to a second term in office this summer showed that most Russians supported his economic reform course. He said FSB director Nikolai Kovalyov was keeping him informed about the situation in the country.</p>
<p>Kovalyov succeeded Mikhail Barsukov, who was sacked along with other close Yeltsin aides in a purge engineered by Chubais between the first and second rounds of the election.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin met the president on Tuesday and pledged to hold a steady course &quot;under any circumstances&quot;. He also demonstrated his resolve with a crackdown on tax dodgers.</p>
<p>&quot;It is impossible to move away from the main political line which we are following, impossible, impermissible and unacceptable under any circumstances,&quot; said the premier in remarks broadcast by NTV commercial television.</p>
<p>But Lebed, 46, predicted in an interview with a U.S. television network that Chernomyrdin would be dismissed by the middle of next month.</p>
<p>&quot;He's an extra person, he's become an extra person, an unnecessary one,&quot; Lebed told the ABC News programme &quot;Nightline&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The next person who will be dismissed, probably by the middle of November, will be Viktor Chernomyrdin,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
