<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136450" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo firms more optimistic on econ climate - poll.</title>
<headline>Yugo firms more optimistic on econ climate - poll.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Optimism among Yugoslav firms improved slightly in September, but most saw slim prospects for raising exports in the last quarter, the Economics Institute said in its latest Market Barometer report.</p>
<p>&quot;Optimism improved slightly, with 43.7 percent of the firms polled expecting better business in the coming period,&quot; Goran Pitic, an analyst with the institute said.</p>
<p>The institute polls 300 Yugoslav firms covering 55 percent of all industry and 35 percent of total employed.</p>
<p>Despite positive September indicators -- upward trends in industrial output and slowdown in prices -- most firms still saw the general economic climate as bad.</p>
<p>Two problems from previous months were carried over -- high inflationary expectations and lack of credits and working capital to raise production, Pitic said.</p>
<p>Some 63.3 percent expected prices of input to grow in the coming period, while only 1.2 percent said they would fall.</p>
<p>Lack of credits remained the dominant obstacle to increasing activity for 32.1 percent of the firms, followed closely by shortage of imported raw materials -- 27.5 percent.</p>
<p>Poor demand was listed as the main problem by 22.5 percent and lack of domestic raw materials by 3.7 percent.</p>
<p>Industrial output in September rose 6.9 percent on the previous month, with cummulative growth in the first nine months at 5.6 percent against the same period last year.</p>
<p>After a surge of 6.6 percent in July, monthly inflation slowed to 2.1 percent in August and further to 1.2 percent in September.</p>
<p>Use of capacities rose to the highest level of 58.7 percent since the institute began its study in 1994, but Pitic said it was still low and more firms registered a drop in employment in real terms in September.</p>
<p>Around 61.2 percent of the firms said stocks of raw and semi-finished materials were low, while 42.5 percent said their stocks of finished goods were depleted.</p>
<p>A positive sign is optimism with regard to local market conditions -- 53.1 percent believe domestic sales will pick up and only 6.1 see them falling, Pitic said.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, pessimism is still high on prospects for marketing abroad, with more than 40 firms not planning exports in the next three months,&quot; Pitic said.</p>
<p>Only 28.6 percent of the firms saw prospects of investments from local sources, while just 9.8 percent said they expected funds from abroad even though international trade sanctions against rump Yugoslavia were lifted early this month. -- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
