<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136452" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian leu unexpectedly firms to 3,320/30 vs dlr.</title>
<headline>Romanian leu unexpectedly firms to 3,320/30 vs dlr.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Romanian leu currency closed Wednesday slightly firmer against the dollar despite sliding street rates since the weekend.</p>
<p>The four market-making dealer banks quoted the leu at 3,320/30 compared with 3,325/35 in early trading. But exchange offices in central Bucharest were offering about 3,950 lei to the dollar, slightly down from Monday's rates.</p>
<p>Most traders were taken aback by what they saw as the inexplicable upward move on the interbank market, less than two weeks before general elections. The market has long faced hard currency shortages and sellers reluctant to do any dollar trades at current rates.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no explanation for the leu's upward move. It might be a maneouvre for a couple of days, but there were no economic factors behind it,&quot; said a trader with a dealer bank.</p>
<p>Since March, only four banks are allowed to work as dealers, setting quotes to be observed by all others operating in the market. Three of the four dealer banks are state-run.</p>
<p>Traders said only a handful of operators strike deals in dollars because other currencies offered at cross give much weaker prices, like the Austrian schilling, which delivered a leu-dollar of some 3,850.</p>
<p>Latest central bank data showed Tuesday's interbank volume at $16 million, exceeding intrabank trading, where sales to clients amounted to $11.9 million.</p>
<p>Short-term money market rates lingered at 43 percent. -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
