<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136448" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: UN girding for Croat pilgrimage to Serb enclave.</title>
<headline>UN girding for Croat pilgrimage to Serb enclave.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. peace troops will be out in force to allow thousands of Croat refugees to make a memorial day pilgrimage to Croatia's last Serb enclave, the U.N. administrator of the area said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said the U.N. Transitional Authority in Eastern Slavonia (UNTAES) had looked into and dismissed rumours that the Croatian army might attack if Serbs blocked Croats from revisiting family grave sites on November 1, All Saints Day.</p>
<p>&quot;I checked with the (Croatian) president's office yesterday and they had heard nothing about it. We've found no evidence of (Croatian army) mobilisation,&quot; said Jacques Klein, the U.S. diplomat who heads UNTAES.</p>
<p>&quot;(In the past) I've had all assurances from the highest levels that no such thing would ever happen, if peaceful reintegration of Eastern Slavonia is the goal of the Croatian government,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>UNTAES, endowed with 5,000 multinational combat troops, entered Eastern Slavonia last January with a mandate to foster ethnic reconciliation and reinstate Croatian government rule there in one year, with the option of up to a year's extension.</p>
<p>Croatia's nationalist government said recently it would grudgingly accept a three-month extension to April 15, 1997, believed to have been recommended by Klein. The U.N. Security Council will decide the issue next month.</p>
<p>After disarming Eastern Slavonia's Serb militia and taking infrastructural steps to prepare for Eastern Slavonia's return to Croatia, UNTAES is now preparing for All Saints Day.</p>
<p>&quot;UNTAES will have everyone out for security. We'll have a lot of people out on the streets. We will have sufficient security (to prevent unwarranted obstructions),&quot; Klein said.</p>
<p>He said the Croatian government had pressed for more than 60 communities in Eastern Slavonia to be opened for Croats wishing to mourn their dead at family cemeteries on November 1.</p>
<p>But UNTAES felt a sudden, mass Croat influx could inflame Serbs in an atmosphere still rife with fear and hatred over a 1991 war in which Serbs opposing Croatia's secession from Yugoslavia seized the enclave and drove out 80,000 Croats.</p>
<p>Klein said UNTAES, in talks with Croatian and Serb authorities to work out a compromise, had identified about 10 communities for All Saints Day pilgrimages.</p>
<p>&quot;We've come up with a reasonable number of Croat visitors -- 2,000 or 3,000. We know it's a significant Roman Catholic holiday and we're very serious about doing this,&quot; said Klein.</p>
<p>He said UNTAES had guarantees from local Serb officials there would be no mob blockades &quot;as long as (Croats are coming) for a religious observance, not political provocation&quot;.</p>
<p>Rumours of military action have circulated against a backdrop of pressure from rightists in President Franjo Tudjman's circle and a hard-line Croat refugee lobby to speed up the recovery of Eastern Slavonia.</p>
<p>But Foreign Minister Mate Granic on Wednesday ruled out anything that would put Croatia on a collision course with the U.N. and NATO, whose air power UNTAES could summon in a pinch.</p>
<p>&quot;Croatia cannot jeopardise its credibility in the international community by taking military action (here) despite the fact that it has the sovereign right to it,&quot; Granic said in a newspaper interview.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
