<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136451" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine T-bill yield drop drives away foreigners.</title>
<headline>Ukraine T-bill yield drop drives away foreigners.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A big fall in yields of Ukraine's three-month Treasury bills this week, combined with the hyrvnia's steady slide, will hit non-resident participation in the short term, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;When yields and the rate of the hryvnia go down at the same time, then non-residents will leave the game,&quot; Alexander Okhrymenko of Bank Ukraine said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, yields on three-month discount bills fell to 30.65 percent from 43.09 percent the week before.</p>
<p>The hryvnia slipped to 1.782 to the dollar on the Ukraine Interbank Currency Exchange on Wednesday from 1.780 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The currency has fallen steadily since the central bank stopped intervening in early October to keep it at 1.760 to the dollar, the rate at which it was introduced in September.</p>
<p>Traders at some banks said on Tuesday interest in next week's auction from non-residents, who made up less than 20 percent of the market even before yields fell, had halved.</p>
<p>Traders said a fall in yields of three-month paper last week to 43.09 from 49.98 percent had warned clients, especially non-residents, away from the market.</p>
<p>But they said demand should rise again at the end of the year when the Finance Ministry will have to raise yields to meet payments for previous T-bill purchases.</p>
<p>Privatbank's Lyudmilla Shmalchenko blamed the fall in yields on a lack of clear rules on T-bill issues and a lack of limits on non-competitive bid buying.</p>
<p>There were 1,076 competitive and 48,924 non-competitive bids at Tuesday's auction.</p>
<p>Shmalchenko said non-competitive bids should not be allowed to exceed 10-15 percent of total bids.</p>
<p>Some traders said a fall in yields to 30.65 percent meant the central bank could lower its refinancing rate from 40 percent in the near future.</p>
<p>They also said that in November and December, the Finance Ministry could release more short-term paper, which would be more attractive to banks. --Natalya Zinets, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
