<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136454" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak shares quiet, SAX dips 1.46 pts TO 201.55.</title>
<headline>Slovak shares quiet, SAX dips 1.46 pts TO 201.55.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Slovak shares closed mostly down in listless trading on the Bratislava Stock Exchange (BSE) on Wednesday, pulling the SAX index 1.46 points lower to 201.55 points.</p>
<p>Some brokers said market liquidity might be expected to lower gradually, with increasing number of issues having explicit majority owners.</p>
<p>&quot;Only a few owners currently place their shares on the market,&quot; Patrik Granec of Slovenska Sporitelna said. &quot;I hope the focus will slowly move to the bond market, as there are more new issues there.&quot;</p>
<p>Only 828 listed shares were traded on the BSE's floor. Trading with blue chips was dominated by steel maker VSZ, which closed down 16 crowns at 630, on a volume of 100 shares.</p>
<p>The heaviest issues, oil refinery Slovnaft and oil and gas storage firm Nafta, did not trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Slovnaft has a strong position on the market, as it dominates also the country's petrol distribution network,&quot; Granec said, adding: &quot;But I think it should perform the way which VSZ does; more expansion is needed to break a silence around this issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Granec said several direct sales were made through the bourse by the country's privatisation agency, the NPF, but brokers were unimpressed by these trades.</p>
<p>&quot;Although quite large stakes were traded, I found these companies unimportant to the market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Overall volume increased to 389,956 shares, from 191,000 shares traded on Tuesday, while turnover rose to 179.2 million crowns, from 168.09 million. -- Peter Javurek, Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
