<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136436" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish budget deficit endangers CPI target - c.bank.</title>
<headline>Polish budget deficit endangers CPI target - c.bank.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government's proposal to keep the 1997 budget deficit at 2.8 percent of gross domestic product instead of 2.6 percent, as planned earlier, endangers next year's inflation target, the central bank said.</p>
<p>Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz, President of the National Bank of Poland (NBP), told public television news on Wednesday the government's 13 percent inflation target for the end of 1997 would be difficult to reach with the proposed budget deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;With the (1997) budget deficit at 2.6 percent (of GDP), we said that monetary policy would be very restrictive as far as interest rates were concerned.  </p>
<p>If the deficit is even bigger, at 2.8 percent, we expect that the 13 percent inflation target is endangered,&quot; Gronkiewicz-Waltz said. In September, year-on-year inflation was at 19.5 percent, down from 21.6 at the end of 1996.</p>
<p>The government plans to reduce inflation to 17 percent by the end of this year, but analysts considered the target ambitious and see price growth at 18.7 percent in December.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, the goverment proposed a 1997 budget deficit of 2.8 percent of GDP, the same level as projected for this year, along with a recommendation that income taxes be lowered next year.</p>
<p>The government said it would try to push through the lower house, which is due to vote on a package of tax bills later this week, a plan which envisages a cut in personal income taxes to 20, 31 and 43 percent next year from the current 21, 33 and 45 percent.</p>
<p>The government would also seek a two point cut in the corporate income tax to 38 percent.</p>
<p>Last week, the NBP said a budget deficit at 2.6 percent of GDP would likely mean that official interest rates might not be lowered for several months.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
