<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136403" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Engen fuelled by result hopes, oil and rand.</title>
<headline>Engen fuelled by result hopes, oil and rand.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fuelled by high results expectations, rising oil prices and a weak rand, Engen Ltd surged nearly seven percent by Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;We've always maintained that these results would be at the higher end of expectations. We're confident that they will show a much better second half which will carry the year,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Engen is due to post year results next Monday. Engen's recently floated upstream exploration and production unit Energy Africa is due to post year results this Thursday.</p>
<p>By 1045 GMT Engen had added 170 cents or 6.85 percent to 26.50 rand amid volumes 269,400 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Oil prices are at their high and there is a lot of focus on energy stocks at the moment. The rand is also depreciating so that also might help,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The rand was last at 4.57 against the dollar.</p>
<p>The recent sale of a 30 percent stake in Engen to Malaysia's state-owned Petronas had added lustre to the share, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Petronas deal added a bit of froth to the price that wouldn't otherwise have come about,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Although the share looked set to rise further during the day against a relatively flat market, some analysts said that Engen was beginning to look too expensive.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not regard it as a particularly favourable company. At these price levels it is rich. Maybe market participants are latching on to the expectations of good results,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>-- Melanie Cheary, Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
