<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136423" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: US fails to win Serb support for OSCE poll role.</title>
<headline>US fails to win Serb support for OSCE poll role.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. envoy John Kornblum said on Wednesday he had failed to get Bosnian Serb leaders to agree to international supervision of municipal elections that have been delayed until next year.</p>
<p>But the body charged with organising the poll, the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe, played down Serb objections.</p>
<p>Kornblum held talks with Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic in the northern city of Banja Luka a day after election organisers announced the postponement of the local polls which had been scheduled for November.</p>
<p>The American diplomat said he had not been able to persuade Plavsic to endorse an extension of the mandate for the OSCE, which supervised general elections held on September 14.</p>
<p>The Moslem-Croat federation, which together with a Serb republic forms a post-war Bosnia union, has already agreed to OSCE supervision of the hotly-contested local polls.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way that there would be trust for the elections to be carried forward is if the mandate of the OSCE is extended right now,&quot; Kornblum told reporters after a 40-minute meeting with Plavsic.</p>
<p>&quot;President Plavsic unfortunately said that she was not able or willing to do that right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I told her that we consider this to be a severe problem which we would have to follow with the greatest concern.&quot;</p>
<p>But an OSCE statement said all was not lost</p>
<p>&quot;It is our clear understanding that the (Bosnian Serb republic) continues to support OSCE supervision of municipal elections and we expect that it will concur with the mandate extension as soon as possible,&quot; an OSCE statement said.</p>
<p>Robert Frowick, head of the OSCE's Bosnia mission, said in Vienna that local polls looked feasible between April and June 1997, but he too was cautious on achieving Serb cooperation.</p>
<p>An OSCE official who asked not to be named said his organisation had contacts with Plavsic later in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We've never gotten the impression that she completely opposed OSCE supervision,&quot; the official said. &quot;We have a long way ahead, but she has never closed the door to OSCE supervision.&quot;</p>
<p>The Serbs have criticised voter registration rules set down by the OSCE which aim to prevent nationalist authorities from concentrating votes in disputed municipalities.</p>
<p>The Serbs fear Moslem refugees will vote them out of power in towns where Moslem majorities were expelled during the 43-month war.</p>
<p>The United States remained concerned &quot;about a continuing record of less than full implementation of the (peace) process by the (Serb republic),&quot; Kornblum said.</p>
<p>Western diplomats say the Serbs risk missing out on millions of dollars worth of reconstruction aid unless they cooperate with the Bosnia peace process.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
