<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136425" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary '56 uprising events fail to draw crowds.</title>
<headline>Hungary '56 uprising events fail to draw crowds.</headline>
<byline>Denes Albert</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarians lit a thousand candles to mark the 40th anniversary of the country's 1956 anti-Soviet uprising on Wednesday but crowds were sparse in the most low-key commemoration since communism collapsed in 1989.</p>
<p>The biggest crowd, about 3,000 people, gathered in the early evening at Parliament where President Arpad Goncz, accompanied by his wife Zsuzsa, lit the first of the candles on the steps in memory of the uprising's victims.</p>
<p>Some 25,000 people were killed in the October 23 uprising, which posed the biggest challenge at that time to Soviet domination of Eastern Europe. Another 250,000 people fled from Hungary when Soviet troops crushed the revolt in November. Early in the day, Goncz had dedicated a &quot;Flame of the Revolution&quot; monument at Parliament to Hungarian youth, saying: &quot;Our generation is handing over this flame to the next generation in the spirit of freedom.</p>
<p>&quot;We are dwindling, but you are going to build the future,&quot; Goncz, who was sentenced to life imprisonment for his role in the uprising, told university students charged with maintaining the torchlit monument.</p>
<p>But despite the best efforts of 1956 veterans to spark interest in one of the formative events of Hungary's modern history, crowds remained sparse throughout the day, even after the weather changed from rain to sunshine.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be very careful in choosing our words, as there are so few of us,&quot; said Jeno Fonay, head of the Association of Political Prisoners, beginning a half-hour-long speech at Bem Square, one of the key rallying points of the uprising.</p>
<p>Fonay, who strongly opposed any participation in the events by the Socialist-led government, which includes many former communists, attacked Hungary's privatisation programme under which large chunks of state enterprises have been sold off.</p>
<p>&quot;Take care of your country, before they privatise it away from above your heads,&quot; Fonay said.</p>
<p>Fonay also warned the Socialists against trying to appropriate the memory of Imre Nagy, who was a communist but led the revolution as prime minister and was later executed.</p>
<p>&quot;Imre Nagy is ours, take your hands away from him,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite the pointedly political character of the event, relatively low attendance and the general lack of interest of the younger generation are all signs that 1956, while remaining a milestone for Hungary, is fading into the history books.</p>
<p>The reburial of Nagy in 1990, the year of the first free elections in Hungary since World War Two, drew some 200,000 people, while six celebrations in as many different locations on Wednesday brought together just over 10,000.</p>
<p>Two fringe skinhead groups took the opportunity to stage a small rally in cnetral Budapest's Szabadsag Square, home of both the U.S. Embassy and Hungarian Television.</p>
<p>Speakers at the skinhead rally, attended by some 500 people, suggested closing borders and driving out foreigners.</p>
<p>The day ended with two receptions at Parliament, one of which Socialist Prime Minister Gyula Horn was due to attend and another for foreign and invited guests.</p>
<p>But if the trend of this and the last few years is anything to go by, the 1956 commemorations will slowly become what President Goncz suggested earlier this week they should be.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's put a flower on the graves of our friends who fell in battle or were executed. Do it by yourselves, without any guard of honour, commands, heralding, speeches or impersonal formalities,&quot; Goncz said on Tuesday</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
