<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136449" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH SHARES BEGIN TO LOSE STEAM AS PSE SPUTTERS.</title>
<headline>CZECH SHARES BEGIN TO LOSE STEAM AS PSE SPUTTERS.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Prague Stock Exchange lost ground on Wednesday as the market suffered from profit-taking in financial shares and analysts said there were few fundamentals to push the market higher.</p>
<p>Financial shares, at the heart of recent gains, retreated on profit-taking, pushing the PX50 index down 3.3 points, or 0.61 percent, to 533.9, while the Reuters RPIX index eased six points to 1,089.</p>
<p>Overall, 161 issues gained, 153 lost and 88 were unchanged. Total volume was heavier at 940,964 shares on turnover of 681.1 million crowns.</p>
<p>Komercni Banka, Zivnostenska Banka, IPB and insurer Ceska Pojistovna all lost ground.</p>
<p>IPB lost 10 crowns. This was the first time the bank's share price fell since the government indicated IPB would be the first of the four major Czech banks to be privatised.</p>
<p>Even though no details of a possible sell-off have been announced, investors seized on the statement as the signal they had been looking for that a foreign strategic partner would be the most likely beneficiary of any sell-off, making the bank's shares attractive to other, smaller investors.</p>
<p>Since the announcement, Nomura and ING Bank have been rumoured as the frontrunners in any bid to participate in the sell-off. The government holds about 30 percent of IPB.</p>
<p>But analysts said that the bubble caused by the announcement was over, and there were few fundamentals to push the market further.</p>
<p>&quot;Corporate results just aren't that good so far, and there are few reasons for foreign investors to enter the market at this point. Instead, most are looking to Poland or Hungary,&quot; said one U.S.-based analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect to see the market move much higher over the next few months,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
