<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136418" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zambia - Oct 23.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zambian press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TIMES OF ZAMBIA</p>
<p>- Information minister Amusa Mwanamwamba said some pro-opposition officials in the Zambia Intelligence Security Services had launched a disinformation campaign to discredit the government ahead of elections set for November 18. He was reacting to media reports of intelligence service correspondence pointing to a government plan to rig the elections.</p>
<p>- Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines has sacked 68 miners involved in a work stoppage on Monday. Four miners who vandalised company equipment were arrested by police.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ZAMBIA DAILY MAIL</p>
<p>- The government said it would not allow two opposition leaders it deported to Malawi to return to Zambia because they were prohbited immigrants. The government deported William Banda and John Chinula of former president Kenneth Kaunda's United National Independence Porty because, it said, they were Malawian.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE POST</p>
<p>- The opposition Liberal Progressive Front said that Zambia's armed forces did not have a commander in chief since Parliament was dissolved on October 18. Party president Rodger Chongwe said president Frederick Chiluba ceased to hold office legally when Parliament was dissolved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
