<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136526" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian hotel stocks boom as confidence returns.</title>
<headline>Croatian hotel stocks boom as confidence returns.</headline>
<byline>Davor Huic</byline>
<dateline>POREC, Croatia 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first successful tourist season after four years of war in the region and good long-term prospects have made hotels on Croatia's Istrian coast the hit of the season on the Zagreb bourse, analysts said.</p>
<p>Shares of five major hoteliers from the peninsula, located in the northern corner of the Adriatic, have surged between 100 and 230 percent since August. Investors started cashing in some gains last week, but analysts believe shares will now stabilise at about double the level they had started from.</p>
<p>Market watchers attribute part of the success to small domestic investors speculating on a foreign listing of hoteliers after the take-over in August of two of the biggest, Jadranturist Rovinj and Istraturist Umag, by the country's top commercial bank, Zagrebacka Banka.</p>
<p>But the key factor, analysts say, is the return of investor confidence in what was once the flagship of Croatia's economy, bringing in $4 billion in hard-currency earnings a year before the country gained independence from former Yugoslavia in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;There is definitely a medium to long-term potential for profitability in tourist companies,&quot; said Wolfgang Rigler, director of Raiffeisen Investment in Zagreb.</p>
<p>The 1996 season already showed a strong gain in overnight stays, and analysts said it will get better still. &quot;The inflow of tourists will grow, that is foreseeable,&quot; said Rigler.</p>
<p>Major Istrian hoteliers recorded an average increase of 52 percent in the number of guests this summer, with Laguna Porec leading the way with 1.2 million overnight stays in the first nine months, up 74 percent from the previous year.</p>
<p>Overall, the Croatian government forecasts this year's tourism revenue to reach about $2 billion.</p>
<p>Local brokers say Istrian hotels are top on investors' minds since they were among the first to recover financially and reduce their crippling debt burden.</p>
<p>While many tourist facilities on the southern Adriatic coast accumulated large debts because of war damage and the cost of providing shelter for refugees, Istrian hotels kept working throughout the four years of war, albeit at reduced capacity.</p>
<p>Loreto Radojkovic, a manager at Laguna, said the company would finish the season on the positive side. &quot;It is going to be a small profit, but still a profit,&quot; he said. His colleague at Jadranturist expects a net profit of 800,000 kuna ($150,000) this year.</p>
<p>Like most other hotels in the region, both firms had large losses in 1995. Laguna lost 28.6 million kuna and Jadranturist 61.6 million, on revenue of 142.5 and 239 million respectively.</p>
<p>While Jadranturist's losses stemmed mostly from a major right-off of non-liquid assets, those at Laguna were due to ambitious infrastructure investments made in 1994 and 1995. But returns were swamped by the renewed outbreak of fighting in the region in the summer of last year.</p>
<p>Both managers said they expect the number of guests to rise between 10 and 30 percent next year, defying the negative effects of the country's hard local currency, the kuna.</p>
<p>But analysts warn long-term growth could only be secured by the supply of fresh capital to help Croatian hotels meet the requirements of a fast-changing global tourist industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Profitability in the long run will depend on the ability to adapt to new global trends in the industry, and to invest in restructuring and upgrading,&quot; Rigler said. ($1=5.4654 kuna)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POREC, Croatia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
