<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136504" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOLDOVA: Moldova plans private placement, Eurobond.</title>
<headline>Moldova plans private placement, Eurobond.</headline>
<dateline>CHISINAU 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moldova will make its first dollar private placement through Merrill Lynch in four or five weeks, in preparation for a Eurobond by the middle of next year, a senior Finance Ministry official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In line with talks held recently in London, the prominent finance company Merrill Lynch will act as the agent of Moldova's government, floating the placement among several large Western investors,&quot; Victor Cibotaru, head of the ministry's external debt department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Cibotaru, said it was too early to give details of the placement, but the issue would total some $20 million. Another Finance Ministry official talked of $25 million.</p>
<p>&quot;This private placement is very important for Moldova as the first stage before the proper issue of its own Eurobonds,&quot; Cibotaru said.</p>
<p>Shortly after the placement experts of two international rating agencies will arrive in Moldova to define the country's sovereign rating, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that after that Eurobonds could be issued in the first half of 1997,&quot; Cibotaru said.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides a possibility for the state to borrow more credit resources abroad, Eurobond issues and Moldova's own rating will open our country to international financial markets, and this could help attract more direct private investment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Officials say Moldova's regular issues of Treasury bills, which have several maturities running from 28 days to one year, have already attracted some foreign investors.</p>
<p>--Dmitry Solovyov, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOLDV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHISINAU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOLDOVA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
