<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136537" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian Duma slams government on budget, taxes.</title>
<headline>Russian Duma slams government on budget, taxes.</headline>
<byline>Julie Tolkacheva</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian State Duma, the lower house of parliament, on Wednesday asked ministers to clamp down on tax evasion and condemned the government's inability to meet its 1996 budget plans.</p>
<p>The Duma, dominated by communists and their allies, unanimously passed a resolution criticising the government. But its vote has no legal force under the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;The financial system of the Russian Federation is functioning in an unstable, extremist way,&quot; the resolution said.</p>
<p>&quot;The clampdown on inflation is carried out against a background of falling gross domestic product and investment and the worsening of companies' financial situations which is deepening the economic crisis further.&quot;</p>
<p>The Duma has already rejected the government's 1997 budget plans, criticising as unrealistic revenue forecasts and as inadequate funding for investment and social protection. It is unhappy about the fulfillment of the 1996 budget as well.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Alexander Livshits told the Duma that the government had received only 71.3 percent of planned taxes or 172.9 trillion roubles ($31.79 billion), in the first nine months of 1996.</p>
<p>Government spending was about 233 trillion roubles, or 74.6 percent of targeted levels, taking the nine-month federal budget deficit to 3.61 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Presidential chief-of-staff Anatoly Chubais said on Tuesday the government expected to collect only 45 percent of targeted taxes in October. &quot;We must fully reverse the situation,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>The budget provides for a deficit of 3.85 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>The Duma resolution asked the government to cancel customs and tax privileges, prepare a list of federal property, including property abroad and work out measures to stimulate tax collection.</p>
<p>It also recommended that the government attract foreign funds to finance the budget deficit and start declaring tax dodgers bankrupt -- an aim shared by the government and a new commission it has set up to rake in extra cash.</p>
<p>The VChK tax commission shares the initials of the feared Soviet-era secret police of Felix Dzerzhinsky and many Russians expect it to impose a draconian clamp down on tax evaders.</p>
<p>Ministers have already said Russia will start bankruptcy proceedings against four big corporate tax debtors.</p>
<p>The Duma also compiled a list of 73 of Russia's biggest corporate tax dodgers and said their total debt to the budget amounted to 26.30 trillion roubles on September 1.</p>
<p>The list includes Russia's national power grid RAO United Energy System  EESR.RTS, utility Irkutskenergo  IRGZ.RTS, Sidanko's main production unit Varyoganneftegaz  VJGZ.RTS and Yukos main production unit Yuganskneftegaz  YFGA.RTS.</p>
<p>The Duma asked the government to sequester 1996 budget expenditures and report back on its action before December 1.</p>
<p>Fulfilment of the 1996 budget and satisfactory spending plans for 1997 hold the key to Russia receiving money from the International Monetary Fund, which is backing Moscow's economic reforms with a three-year $10 billion loan.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Yevgeny Yasin said on Tuesday that talks with the IMF were tough, but he hoped the fund would not delay payment of the next tranche of the loan.</p>
<p>&quot;If we take as a base the formal requirements it is clear that this is possible, but in the situation which Russia is in I think it would be a very unjust thing,&quot; Yasin told Reuters during a visit to Milan.</p>
<p>Officials close to the talks say the IMF is more worried about revenue levels than about the size of the deficit.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520 ($1=5439 Rouble)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
