<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136552" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish Prime Minister asks parliament to cut taxes.</title>
<headline>Polish Prime Minister asks parliament to cut taxes.</headline>
<byline>Marcin Grajewski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz on Wednesday called on parliament to lower income tax levels next year despite an earlier decision to keep the taxes unchanged because of higher-than-planned budget spending.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz told the Sejm, lower house, the government had almost finished work on the 1997 budget draft, which envisaged higher real spending for many vital areas but would not require giving up tax cuts because additional sources  of financing had been found.  </p>
<p>&quot;After additional analyses of the state's financial potential I can declare with full responsibility that it is possible to implement this difficult budget also along with lower the income tax as the government had proposed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government originally proposed to shed one point from personal income tax levels to 20, 32 and 44 percent next year but parliamentary committees recommended keeping this year's rates in 1997 and to lower them only in 1998.</p>
<p>The original proposal, abandoned earlier this month under pressure parliamentarians, also provided for lowering the corporate tax level to 38 percent from the current 40 percent.  </p>
<p>Cimoszewicz did not give any details of the government's new proposals. It was also not immediately clear whether the proposals would allow to cut the 1997 budget deficit to 2.6 percent of gross domestic product from this year's planned deficit of 2.8 percent, as proposed by the finance ministry.</p>
<p>But he stressed the 1997 budget would allow to boost real-term term spending for education by nearly six percent, for health care by nearly six percent, for judicial system by nearly seven percent, for internal security and agriculture by five percent, for university education and science by 7.5 percent while for culture by 8.3 percent.</p>
<p>Government spokeswoman Aleksandra Jakubowska told Reuters Cimoszewicz would present details of the government's tax proposals in his speech in parliament expected at 1400 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister will propose income tax cuts both for individuals and firms and will give details in his speech ...and I think this proposals stands a good chance of being approved by parliament,&quot; Jakubowska said.</p>
<p>After Cimoszewicz's motion, parliament decided to vote on next year's tax levels on Thursday rather than on Wednesday. If the debate on his proposal proves long, the vote may take place on Friday. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
