<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136554" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Oct 23.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Government officials said  SAFI Invest SA, administrator of troubled FMOA unit trust, failed to declare some 3.5 billion lei in its six-month revenues , breaching profit tax rules.</p>
<p>- Foreign investors are waiting for November's elections and a new government to speed up reforms, said Obbie Moore, head of Romanian-American Investment Fund.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Daewoo Securities Co Ltd eyes $25 million investment in planned Romanian-Korean bank.</p>
<p>- Control over the leu-dollar exchange rate is not good for the protection of the national currency, said Anthony van der Heijden, head of Romanian branch of ING Bank.</p>
<p>-  Alcatel Network Systems Romania won a tender bid to supply equipment for GSM mobile telephone network in Slovakia.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Government set maximum retail prices for milk and dairy produce.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- State Ownership Fund holds tender on November 13 to sell its stake in 14 companies involved in construction, textiles, footwear and leather.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>-  Casa de Economii si Consemnatiuni savings bank will give loans under new law allowing young people to get long-term housing credits at 15 percent interest rate.</p>
<p>- Romanian Securities Companies Association is due to decide on first group of companies whose shares will be traded on the over-the-counter market.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The newspaper prints speech by opoposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc's presidential contender Emil Constantinescu at CDR national conference.</p>
<p>- CDR challenged the proposals for presidents of Bucharest polling stations made by the ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR), saying they violate the electoral law, which bars those officials from being party members.</p>
<p>- The National Broadcasting Board (CNA) ordered a private television station stop a live broadcast of the CDR conference.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- The ruling PDSR wants to control the elections, rather than simply take part in the polls, editorial says.</p>
<p>- Opposition CDR and President Ion Iliescu are potential winners of the November 3 polls, newspaper says on the results of a CURS opinion poll. CDR leads with 31.4 percent of support followed by PDSR with 27.2 percent. Iliescu gets 33.5 percent of voting support, to Constantinescu's 27, the poll shows.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Most people who got rich after the revolution are members of former Prime Minister Petre Roman's opposition Democratic Party (PD) and of the opposition CDR alliance, President Iliescu said during his campaign tour in southern Romania.</p>
<p>- Mircea Moldovan, CNA president, says in interview he never intervened to suspend private television broadcasts.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Report on almost 1,000 Romanians living in Denmark.</p>
<p>- Young Romanians earn little money as prostitutes in Berlin, says newspaper report.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- Opinion polls are a mockery for parties, presidential candidates and voters, as polling institutions are involved in politics, newspaper says about the conflicting results of three opinion surveys issued this week.</p>
<p>- The November 5 presidential elections in the U.S. will be broadcast live on Romanian state television.</p>
<p>DIMINEATA</p>
<p>- The ruling PDSR, with 31 percent of voter support and President Iliescu, with 36 percent, are far ahead of the CDR's and Constantinescu's 21 percent, shows an IRSOP opinion poll.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- The government approved an extra 26 billion lei ($7.8 million) for the November polls. ($=3,312 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
