<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136538" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Moscow rejects CIA report of weak nuclear controls.</title>
<headline>Moscow rejects CIA report of weak nuclear controls.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian officials on Wednesday rejected a U.S. intelligence report that Moscow's control over its nuclear arsenal had been weakening.</p>
<p>&quot;This does not correspond to the truth,&quot; said Georgy Nasonov, a spokesman for Russia's atomic energy ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;Russian and American specialists are working hand in hand in the field of the military use of nuclear energy and our American colleagues have expressed no reservations,&quot; he said, speaking by telephone.</p>
<p>The Central Intelligence Agency report, quoted in a U.S. newspaper on Tuesday, concluded that controls had become less strict because of dramatic social change in Russia and accompanying economic problems and low morale in the military.</p>
<p>But it said the chance of an unauthorised launch or blackmail remained low. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Washington believed Russia had control over its nuclear force.</p>
<p>&quot;There can be no doubt about the control over strategic missile forces,&quot; said a spokesman for the Russian military organisation which oversees controls of the nuclear arsenal.</p>
<p>&quot;An inspection group from the United States is arriving today, and tomorrow they will be checking how our strategic forces are controlled. We are ready for this check,&quot; said the official, from the National Centre for Reduction of Nuclear Danger.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
