<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136515" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Ageing veterans mark Hungary '56 anti-Soviet revolt.</title>
<headline>Ageing veterans mark Hungary '56 anti-Soviet revolt.</headline>
<byline>Michael Roddy</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary on Wednesday marked the 40th anniversary of a doomed 1956 uprising against Soviet rule and President Arpad Goncz handed a &quot;flame of freedom&quot; to youth.</p>
<p>Young people generally stayed away from a day of events laden with significance for veterans of the October 23 revolt but which underscored current divisions in Hungarian society.</p>
<p>&quot;Our generation is handing over this flame to the next generation in the spirit of freedom,&quot; Goncz said in light rain outside Parliament at a new 1956 monument topped by a flame.</p>
<p>The event drew only a few hundred people, including ageing veterans of the 1956 revolution that posed the biggest challenge up to that time to Soviet hegemony in Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We are dwindling but you are going to build the future,&quot; Goncz, imprisoned for life for his role in 1956, told technical university students who accepted the honour of safeguarding the flame.</p>
<p>Apart from the students, young people were little in evidence in the generally small crowds celebrating the uprising, in which 25,000 people were killed.</p>
<p>Although poorly armed Hungarians drove the powerful Soviet army out of Budapest, the West failed to provide support and Soviet troops returned in crushing strength in November.</p>
<p>Regina Szanto, a 23-year-old psychology student who attended a wreath-laying ceremony near Parliament for Hungary's executed uprising prime minister, Imre Nagy, said the day's events were too politicised, especially by the right-wing.</p>
<p>&quot;The nation needs a celebration but it can't always be so dramatic,&quot; she said. &quot;We need to get on...we need to get all the nation together.&quot;</p>
<p>New York Governor George Pataki, a third generation Hungarian-American who flew here for the anniversary, said one of his vivid childhood memories was seeing on U.S. television the Soviet tanks invading Budapest.</p>
<p>&quot;Today Hungary is very exciting,&quot; he told Reuters after the wreath-laying ceremony. &quot;Transition is difficult but certainly the freedom is there...and the fact there is a clear commitment to democracy and the free exchange of ideas is exciting.&quot;</p>
<p>At the renovated Corvin Cinema, heavily damaged during battles in which Hungarians armed with guns and petrol bombs fought Soviet tanks, almost as many people, mostly young, lined up to see the movie &quot;Independence Day&quot; as attended a ceremony.</p>
<p>Jozsef Szabo, a veteran of the fierce fighting at the cinema, gave one of the most political speeches of the day, saying that while communism finally was defeated with the change to democracy in 1989, Hungary was still suffering.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1989, just the coat of arms and methods of exploitation changed, but exploitation has continued,&quot; Szabo said.</p>
<p>&quot;The majority of politicans, regardless of their political colour, serve the interests of those who try to destroy the country,&quot; he said, referring to the economic plight of many Hungarians, losing social benefits provided by communism while wages have dropped due to high inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Fortunate are those of our comrades who died during the fighting or were executed because they at least have been left with the illusion the struggle was not in vain,&quot; Szabo said.</p>
<p>Other speakers were more conciliatory, among them Balint Nemeth, head of a 1956 association, who said Hungary was healing the rift between those who fought against Soviet rule and communists who returned to power after the Soviet victory.</p>
<p>&quot;The importance of this event is shown by the fact that even those who for 40 years have denigrated the memory of 1956 are here to celebrate with us,&quot; Nemeth said at Szena Square, another battleground.</p>
<p>&quot;This is our celebration of the '56 generation but also of those who will take over our heritage,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Several 1956 associations had said members of Hungary's ruling socialist party, comprised largely of former communists, would not be welcome.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Prime Minister Gyula Horn, parliament Speaker Zoltan Gal and Defence Minister Gyorgy Keleti, all former communists, attended the ceremony at Parliament and were expected to attend a reception there in the evening, ending the commemoration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
