<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136522" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Joint stock firm to build Russia-Greece oil route.</title>
<headline>Joint stock firm to build Russia-Greece oil route.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria, Russia and Greece plan to establish a joint stock company, Trans-Balkan Pipeline, for the construction of a planned oil route supplying Russian crude to the Balkans, Bulgarian senior officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The experts' meeting of the three countries was successful...and a plan on the structure of a joint stock company consortium will be worked out,&quot; Construction Minister Doncho Konakchiev said.</p>
<p>&quot;My wish is to set up the organisation structures by the end of the year,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Konakchiev said there was agreement in principle on stakes in the joint company, with 50 percent to Russia, while Bulgaria and Greece would have 25 percent each.</p>
<p>The three countries plan a tanker route from the Russian Black Sea port of Novorossiisk to Bourgas in Bulgaria, from where a pipeline will carry the Russian crude to Alexandroupolis in Greece.</p>
<p>Last week experts from the three countries signed a protocol in Sofia confirming close positions in their technical and economic studies of the project, which is expected to cost some $600-$700 million.</p>
<p>The experts decided to set up a working group, which will unite and coordinate the feasibility studies and the financial plans of the three sides and the procedure for the assignment of a pipeline's final and detailed plan, expected to cost $10 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no significant differences which hamper the realisation of the project,&quot; Konakchiev said.</p>
<p>Konakchiev, who is also a deputy prime minister, said the route was now being considered as a part of a greater regional project linking the Black Sea to Caspian Sea oilfields.</p>
<p>He said Bulgaria had no problems with funding its stretch of a new underground pipeline, which would carry Russian crude from Bourgas to Greece. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>&quot;We will call tenders (for the pipeline construction) and (only) licensed firms would be able to bid as the construction is very specific,&quot; Konakchiev told a news conference.</p>
<p>But if companies submitted equal bids, Bulgarian firms would be preferred, he said.</p>
<p>Deputy construction minister Nikolay Grigorov said by the end of November the three countries' working group would unify some methodological and legislative norms, which were different in Russia, Bulgaria and Greece.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, +359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
