<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136546" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria parliament amends deposit guarantee law.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria parliament amends deposit guarantee law.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament on Wednesday passed amendments to a deposit guarantee law which will delay compensation payments for personal and company deposits in bankrupt banks, the official news agency BTA said.</p>
<p>The Socialist majority in parliament overturned a presidential veto on the amendments, which were first passed by parliament three weeks ago.</p>
<p>Under the amendments, citizens' lev deposits in insolvent banks will be fully repaid by the state no sooner than 30 days after the court declares the banks insolvent and companies will be able to draw lev deposits from insolvent banks 60 days after the ruling.</p>
<p>So far, compensation payments have begun immediately after the central bank filed an insolvency suit to the courts.</p>
<p>&quot;It is wrong to think that handing out money straight away will solve people's problems,&quot; said Socialist deputy Fidel Kosev.</p>
<p>Zhelev sent the amendments back to parliament last Friday, saying that blocking accounts for an indefinite period violated the legal right of depositors to access their funds and could cause insolvency in small companies.</p>
<p>&quot;People badly need this money during the winter, not in June or July,&quot; said Muravei Radev, a deputy of Zhelev's Union of Democratic Forces.</p>
<p>The law provided for a 100 percent state guarantee on personal savings in bankrupt banks and 50 percent coverage of companies' deposits.</p>
<p>Under the new amendments, personal foreign exchange deposits in bankrupt banks will be compensated in four semi-annual tranches, but the first instalment will be paid six months after the court rules on those banks' insolvency.</p>
<p>Under the law, the government issued treasury bonds worth a total of 80 billion levs and $100 million, which were placed with the State Savings Bank and the state-owned Bulgarian Post Bank to guarantee payments to depositors in the five banks.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) has filed insolvency suits against five local banks since May in line with bank stabilisation pledges made to multilteral lenders.</p>
<p>The BNB placed a further nine banks in receivership last month aiming to evaluate their financial state and then decide which of them should seek insolvency.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
