<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136529" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian trade unions to strike on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Slovenian trade unions to strike on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenia's trade unions said on Wednesday they will stage a two-hour general strike on Thursday to press employers not to reduce workers' benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Employers are wrong if they expect to ensure another 35,000 jobs by cutting social benefits. They act as if they do not need workers,&quot; Rajko Lesjak, secretary of the Association of Free Trade Unions, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the unions would continue to exert pressure on employers after Thursday's strike.</p>
<p>But Chamber of Economy president Jozko Cuk said that the strike action was illegal because unions had refused to enter negotiations over the dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been pushing for negotiations on the issue since September, 1995,&quot; Cuk told a news conference.</p>
<p>Early this month employers said they wanted to amend a collective agreement introduced in 1990 and renewed in 1993.</p>
<p>With effect from April next year they plan to reduce holiday pay, sick pay, strike compensation pay, redundancy pay and daily allowances for workers at financially troubled companies.</p>
<p>Slovenia was hit by a wave of pay strikes over the summer and the government gave in to many demands. Analysts say that unrestrained growth in Slovanian wages could fuel inflation and endanger economic stability.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
