<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136541" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland's Kwasniewski to press NATO case in Britain.</title>
<headline>Poland's Kwasniewski to press NATO case in Britain.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's President Aleksander Kwasniewski, buoyed by a U.S. pledge to enlarge NATO by 1999, set off on Wednesday for a visit to Britain to map out his vision of a Warsaw role in the pact.</p>
<p>A key point of the two-day London trip will be a speech to the Royal Institute of International Affairs, when Kwasniewski will argue the benefits of Polish NATO entry for European security, his spokesman Antoni Styrczula told reporters.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski, an ex-communist who replaced former Solidarity leader Lech Walesa as president after winning elections last year, has hailed U.S. President Bill Clinton's campaign speech on Tuesday pledging that NATO would admit new members by 1999.</p>
<p>In Detroit Clinton gave 1999, the 50th anniversary of the alliance, as a target date.</p>
<p>&quot;This conforms with Polish expectations, which I have repeatedly expressed to our Western partners,&quot; Kwasniewski said in a statement issued after Clinton's speech.</p>
<p>All principal political parties in Poland including the ruling ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) see full, fast entry into NATO as a key policy goal and have pressed for member states to issue a clear timetable.</p>
<p>Poles worry that Russian opposition to the pact's expansion, denounced by Moscow as a threat to its security, could leave Poland -- which threw off communist rule in 1989 -- in a grey zone of European security.</p>
<p>&quot;President Clinton, and (Republican contender Robert) Dole, if he wins the elections, cannot now withdraw from a declaration made in such a way,&quot; Poland's Gazeta Wyborcza newspaper said in an editorial welcoming Clinton's speech.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular there cannot now be any effective blackmail from the side of Russia,&quot; it said, adding that Clinton's pledge was a historic success for successive Polish governments.</p>
<p>During the trip to NATO member Britain, Kwasniewski, accompanied by Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati, planned talks with Prime Minister John Major and opposition leaders.</p>
<p>One of his goals is to further confirm Britain's support for fast preparations to expand the alliance, which is generally expected first to include Poland, the Czech Republic and Hungary.</p>
<p>In his speech, Clinton did not give a date for a NATO summit next year to issue invitations to the first candidate countries to begin formal talks on joining.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski is also to visit Queen Elizabeth who came to Poland in March.</p>
<p>The delegation includes several business leaders, who are scheduled along with Kwasniewski to attend a meeting at the major employers' group the Confederation of British Industry.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
