<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138966" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP CIVIL LIBERTIES COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</title>
<headline>EP CIVIL LIBERTIES COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Civil Liberties and Internal Affairs [[ Wednesday 30 October 1996 ]] 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.955 ) ===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 2. Chairman's announcements 3. Report by the Commission on the possible application of Article K.9 of the T reaty on European Union (T04284) (T04284) COS0337 COM(95)0566 C4-0560/95 + LIBE Fond R LAMBRAKI Irini. (PSE) (PE217.132/A ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 4. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (T04556) BUD0074 SEC(96)1677 C4-0515/96 + LIBE Avis A HAARDER Bertel. (ELD) (PE218.457/DEF) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE219.043 ) 4.1 Implementation of the 1996 budget - Section III - draftsman: Hartmut NASSAUER 5. Schengen: assessment, inclusion in Community law, forms of cooperation with third countries, etc. (T04613) (T04613) INI0468 INI0468 + LIBE Fond R VAN LANCKER A. (PSE) (PE218.950 ) - Exchange of views Exchange of views on the basis of working documents 6. Annual debate on progress in JHA in 1996 (T04969) (T04969) INI0891 INI0891 + LIBE Fond LINDEPERG Michele. (PSE) (PE218.469 ) - Exchange of views Further exchange of views ===] 5.30 p.m. (at the latest) 7. Coordinators' meeting (with interpretation) ===] Thursday 31 October 8. Results of the coordinators' meeting 9. Combating terrorism in Europe (T04131) INI0435 INI0435 + LIBE Fond R REDING Viviane. (PPE) (PE218.454 ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 10. Measures to protect minors in the European Union (T03927) (T03927) INI0421 INI0421 + LIBE Avis A LAMBRIAS Panayotis. (PPE) (PE215.278/REV) + LIBE Avis LAMBRIAS Panayotis. (PPE) (PE215.278/REV) + LIBE Avis F JURI Fond R ZIMMERMANN Wilmya. (PSE) (PE213.154/REV) - Exchange of views Exchange of views on the basis of a revised text - Deadline for tabling amendments 11. Improving the adoption laws (T03928) (T03928) INI0420 INI0420 + LIBE Avis A REDING Viviane. (PPE) (PE218.949 ) + LIBE Avis A F JURI Fond R CASINI Carlo. (PPE) (PE215.242/A ) - Exchange of views 12. Respect for human rights in the European Union in 1995 (T04366) (T04366) INI0440 INI0440 + LIBE Fond R ROTH Claudia. (V ) - Exchange of views 13. European Union and the External Dimension of Human Rights Policy: from Rome to Maastricht and beyond (T04255) (T04255) COS0339 COM(95)0567 C4-0568/95 + LIBE Avis A ANDREWS Niall. (UPE) (PE218.952 ) F POLI Fond R ROUBATIS Ioannis. (PSE) - Exchange of views 14. Convention on computerization in the field of customs (T04119) (T04119) COS0274 LET 8406/95 C4-0248/95 + LIBE Fond R SCHULZ Martin. (PSE) (PE215.793 ) - Exchange of views Further exchange of views 14.1 Convention on the European Information System (T04120) (T04120) COS0275 12029/94 C4-0249/95 + LIBE Fond R TERRON I C. (PSE) (PE215.800 ) - Exchange of views Further exchange of views 15. Any other business 16. Date of next meeting - 11 November 1996 in Strasbourg - 20 November (afternoon) and 21 November (whole day) ===] 11.30 a.m. to 12.30 p.m. 17. Restrictions on freedom of expression on computer networks (T04909) (T04909) INI0510 INI0510 + LIBE Fond R PRADIER Pierre. (ARE) - DEMONSTRATION OF THE INTERNET - LEO 0A50 - FIN - 5 END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
