<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138967" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP YOUTH COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</title>
<headline>EP YOUTH COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Culture, Youth, Education and the Media [[ Monday 28 October 1996 ]] 0. 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.969 ) 2. Statement by Colettre FLESCH, Director-General in DG X of the Commission, on the Council meeting in Galway. (VIS0153 ) - Monday 28 October at 5 p.m. 3. Statement by Mr Bernard ALLEN, Irish Minister of State at the Department of Education (VIS0146 ) - Wednesday 30 October, 11 a.m. - 12.30 p.m. 4. Pursuit of television broadcasting activities (amendment of Directive 89/552 /EEC) (T03172) COD95074 COM(96)0200 C4-0 G. (PPE) (PE219.40 4//A ) - Adoption of draft recommendation - - The amendments will be considered on Tuesday 29 October at 9 a.m. - The vote will be held on Tuesday 29 October at 3 p.m. 5. The Commission's report on the consideration of cultural aspects in European Community action (T04825) (T04825) COS0414 SEC(96)0686 C4-0249/96 + JEUN Fond R ESCUDERO LOPEZ J. (PPE) - Consideration of draft report 6. Islam and the European Averroes Day (T04689) INI0490 INI0490 + JEUN Fond R MOHAMED ALI A. (GUE) (PE219.405/DT ) - Consideration of working document 7. Measures to protect minors in the European Union (T03927) (T03927) INI0421 INI0421 + JEUN Avis A SEILLIER Francoise. (EDN) (PE216.162 ) + JEUN Avis F JURI Fond R ZIMMERMANN Wilmya. (PSE) (PE213.154/REV) - Adoption of draft opinion 8. Universal service for telecommunications in the perspective of a fully liber alized environment (T04802) (T04802) COS0399 COM(96)0073 C4-0205/96 + JEUN Avis A DASKALAKI Katerina. (UPE) F ECONn of draft opinion 9. Participation in the institutional system of the EU and IGC by social repres entatives and other citizens (T04618) (T04618) INI0474 INI0474 + JEUN Avis L (PE219.409 ) F INST Fond R HERZOG Philippe. (GUE) (PE218.253/A ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 10. Situation of foreign teachers at Italian universities (PET0055 ) - Adoption of oral question Adoption of oral question with debate, pursuant to r ule 40 11. Commission study on convergence - Adoption of motion for a resolution Adoption of motion for a resolution to win d up the debate on the oral question to the Commission pursuant to Rule 40 12. Commercial communications in the Internal Market - Green Paper (T03907) (T03907) COS0430 COM(96)0192 C4-0365/96 + JEUN Avis A ARRONI Aldo. (UPE) F ECON Fond R LARIVE Jessica E. (ELD) - Initial exchange of views 13. Restrictions on freedom of expression on computer networks (T04909) B4-0224/94 B4-0224/94 + JEUN Avis A PEX Peter. (PPE) F LIBE Fond R PRADIER Pierre. (ARE) - Initial exchange of views 14. Services of general interest in Europe (Commission communication) (T04993) (T04993) COS0459 COM(96)0443 C4-0507/96 + JEUN Avis A (PSE) F ECON Fond - Initial exchange of views 15. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 16. Chairman's announcements 17. Any other business 18. Date of next meeting (PE/XII/OJ/96-22 ) 18.0 19. The COM and SEC documents mentioned will be available on request at the mee ting. 20. THE ORDER IN WHICH ITEMS ARE TAKEN WILL BE DECIDED WHEN THE AGENDA IS ADOPT ED. - FIN - j END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
