<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138974" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-30.</title>
<headline>EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-30.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Agriculture and Rural Development [[ Tuesday 29 October 1996 ]] PUBLIC MEETING 0.1 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.618 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meeting of: - 16/17 September 1996 (PE218.450 ) ===] In the presence of the Commission 3. Common organization of the market in bananas (amendment of Regulation 404/93 ) (T04785) CNS96080 COM(96)0082 C4-0233/96 + AGRI Fond R SANTINI Giacomo. (UPE) (PE217.833 ) - Adoption of draft report 4. Support system for producers of certain arable crops - Council regulation am ending Regulation 1765/92 (T04914) CNS96167 COM(96)0175 C4-0389/96 + AGRI Fond R HALLAM David J. (PSE) (PE218.447 ) - Adoption of draft report 5. Specific measures for live plants and floricultural products (proposal for a Council regulation) (T04899) CNS96155 COM(96)0261 C4-0390/96 + AGRI Fond R FILIPPI Livio. (PPE) (PE218.442 ) - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 6. A support system of producers of certain arable crops (durum wheat) (amendment of Regulation 1765/92) (T04960) CNS96221 COM(96)0361 C4-0496/96 + AGRI Fond R BALDARELLI Francesco (PSE) - Exchange of views 7. Agricultural relations between the EU and the associated countries in view o f their future accession (T03913) COS0365 CSE(95)0607 C4-0023/96 + AGRI Fond R REHDER Klaus. (PSE) (PE218.441 ) - Further consideration of draft report 8. The legal protection of biotechnological inventions (T04629) COD95350 COM(95)0661 C4-0063/96 + AGRI Avis A GRAEFE ZU B. (V )</p>
<p>(PE217.836 ) F JURI Fond R ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE218.021 ) - Further consideration of draft opinion 9. Geographical indications &amp; designations of origin for agricultural products &amp; foodstuffs - Amend. Reg.EEC 2081/92 (T04927) CNS96159 COM(96)0266 C4-0439/96 + AGRI Fond R FANTUZZI Giulio. (PSE) - Consideration of draft report (possibly) 10. System for the identification and registration of bovine animals (proposal for a Council regulation) (T05011) CNS96228 COM(96)0460 C4-0545/96 + AGRI Fond R (PPE) - Exchange of views 10.1 Labelling of beef and beef products (proposal for a Council regulation) (T0 5010) CNS96229 COM(96)0460 C4-0546/96 + AGRI Avis A (PPE) F ENVI Fond - Exchange of viewficiency of agricultural structures and product marketing (T04783) CNS96044 COM(96)0058 C4-0234/96 CNS96045 COM(96)0058 C4-0235/96 CNS96046 COM(96)0058 C4-0236/96 + AGRI Fond R (PPE) + AGRI Fond (PPE) - Exchange of views 12. Forests: protection against atmospheric pollution and fires (T04463) CNS96185 COM(96)0341 C4-0476/96 CNS96186 COM(96)0341 C4-0477/96 + AGRI Avis A WEBER Jup. (ARE) + AGRI Avis F ENVI Fond - Exchange of views 13. Confirmation of the calendar of meetings from January to December 1997 (PE219.616 ) 14. Decision on procedure 15. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure (possibly) 16. Any other business 17. Date of next meeting in BRUSSELS (PE/II/OJ/96-24 ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
