<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138969" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP LEGAL AFFAIRS COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</title>
<headline>EP LEGAL AFFAIRS COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</headline>
<text>
<p>- Adoption of draft opinion 19. The rights of the disabled (T04780) (96/106) (T04780) INI0498 INI0498 + JURI Avis A ULLMANN Wolfgang. (V ) (PE219.393 ) F PETI Fond R BANOTTI Mary. (PPE) - Consideration of draft opinion - Decision on procedure 20. Worker information and consultation (T04264) (95/142) (T04264) COS0331 COM(95)0547 C4-0538/95 + JURI Avis A ODDY Christine M. (PSE) (PE216.341 ) F ASOC Fond R MENRAD Winfried. (PPE) (PE218.630/DT ) - Adoption of draft opinion 21. Takeover bids - 13th Council Directive (T04736) (96/032) COD95341 COM(95)0655 C4-0107/96 + JURI Fond R FONTAINE Nicole. (PPE) (PE216.817/DT ) - Exchange of views on the basis of a working document 22. The relationship between international public law, Community law and nation al constitutional law (T04599) (95/076) INI0455 + JURI Fond C ALBER Siegbert. (PPE) (PE219.606/CM ) - Statement by Mr ROTHLEY on the 17th FIDE CONGRESS (9-12 October 1996) in Berli n - Statement by Mr KRARUP on the Danish Supreme Court's judgment of 12 August 199 6 - followed by an exchanrning 23. (96/115) Judicial Organization of the European Communities - the Parliament' s position in the CIG (PE219.608/CM ) - Member responsible - Willi ROTHLEY - Exchange of views with the participation of Mr GARZON CLARIANA, Jurisconsult 24. Agreements between the EC and Israel on procurement by government and telco mmunications operators (T04821) (96/090) (T04821) CNS96104 COM(96)0148 C4-0323/96 + JURI Avis SIERRA GONZ uLEZ A. (GUE) (PE219.607/CM ) F RELA F ond R DE CLERCQ W. (ELD) (PE218.552 ) - Examination of the legal basis 25. Quality of drinking water intended for human consumption (Directive 80/778) (T02663) (96/112) **I (T02663) SYN95010 COM(94)0612 C4-0199/95 + JURI Avis SIERRA GONZ uLEZ A. (GUE) F ENVI Fond R COLLINS Kenneth D. (PSE) (PE218.671 ) - Examination of the legal basis 26. Any other business 27. Date of next meeting (PE/VII/OJ/19-96 ) 27.1 Deadline for texts for translation before the next meeting (reminder) - Wednesday, 30 October 1996 A N N E X I ===] APPOINTMENT of RAPPORTEUR on - 1. Protocol on Privileges and Immunities and procedure for applying tax (amendm ent of Regs 549/69 and 260/68) (T04973) (96/105) (T04973) CNS96214 COM(96)0400 C4-0534/96 + JURI Fond - Rapporteur - Group - Points - 1.1 * * * ===] APPOINTMENT of DRAFTSMAN on - 2. A common system of VAT - a programme for the Single Market (T03833) (96/101) (T03833) COS0446 COM(96)0328 C4-0458/96 + JURI Avis F ECON Fond R RANDZIO-PLATH Christ (PSE) - item held over from meeting of 23-25/9/96 - Draftsman - Group - Points - adoption expected on 2 December 1996 - part-session - JANUARY I 1997 3. Sale of consumer goods and associated guarantees (proposal for a directive) (T04955) (96/100) (T04955) COD96161 COM(95)0520 C4-0455/96 + JURI Avis F ENVI Fond R KUHN Annemarie. (PSE) - Draftsman - Group - Points - no timetable for adoption yet 4. Protection against effects of application of certain third-country legislati on (Helms-Burton Act) (T04951) (96/116) (T04951) CNS96217 COM(96)0420 C4-0519/96 + JURI Avis F RELA Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE218.828/DEF) - Draftsman - Group - Points -. following a request for urgent procedure in October, the REX committee expe cts to adopt its draft report on - 22 October 1996 in Strasbourg - part-session NOVEMBER I 1996 - the 'HUGHES' procedure will be proposed A N N E X II ===] Rule 45 motion referred to the committee as the committee responsible at th e part-session of 16-20 September - Decision on procedure (Rule 45(2)) - attach the motion to other motions or reports - or deliver an opinion, possibly in the form of a letter - or decide to draw up a report, for which authorization will have to be obtaine d from the Conference of Presidents 20. Establishing a European Mediation and Arbitration Tribunal (B4-0709/96) ( (96/104) ) - Rapporteur - Group - Points - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
