<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138998" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-ALLENBY CROSSES GLOBE FOR JUST ONE SHOT.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ALLENBY CROSSES GLOBE FOR JUST ONE SHOT.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>VALDERRAMA, Spain 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Injured Robert Allenby travelled 19,000 km from his native Melbourne to dribble a single shot 35 yards down the first fairway at the Volvo Masters on Thursday.</p>
<p>In a farcical episode, the Australian stood quietly on the tee chatting to onlookers while waiting for fog to lift, then took out his three-wood and off a backswing of no more than 18 inches, eased the ball off the tee.</p>
<p>He then announced he was withdrawing from the tournament because of the fractured sternum he suffered in a car accident four weeks ago, and pledged the money he earned for the stroke -- which could be as much as $117,000 -- to charity.</p>
<p>Allenby needed to hit one shot to satisfy a European Tour requirement that he played in the competition to qualify for the bonus money he would earn after the event. He is currently third on the money list and will collect the extra prize if his position remains unchanged after the event.</p>
<p>The Australian looked embarrassed as he sat through the 45-minute delay at the Valderrama course before teeing off.</p>
<p>Afterwards he promised his earnings would go to two children's charities -- the Challenge Cancer Support Network at home and the Teenager Cancer Trust.</p>
<p>&quot;They are wonderful charities. Kids with cancer and blood disorders deserve every chance,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This was not for the money,&quot; he insisted, defending himself against charges of greed. &quot;I just wanted to preserve my position on the money list and I felt I deserved the money for the way I have played this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Allenby, who won the French and English Opens and the British Masters on his way to earning $730,000 prize money this year, denied he made the trip simply to qualify for several more lucrative events next year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am already in the U.S. Open and PGA, the British Open and the World Series. I'm probably also in the U.S. Masters, although their criteria are not as firm,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not ridiculous, though it may seem funny to many people that I came so far to hit just one shot,&quot; he said. &quot;The rules are there in black and white. They can't be broken for one person,&quot;.</p>
<p>Allenby suffered his chest injury, along with cuts to his head and his upper lip that required 21 stitches, in a car crash in Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;I still have sharp pains in my chest, like someone has planted an axe in there,&quot; he said. &quot;The only cure is rest. My knees and lower legs are sore too and it hurts to sneeze, breath, or laugh.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his earliest return would be at Australian Open in late November, but even that might be too soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The sternum could snap if I did too much, then I'd be out for six months to a year,&quot; he said. &quot;I know a man who broke his sternum 10 years ago and he still has pain.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALDERRAMA, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
