<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138956" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Patten tells China to relax over Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Patten tells China to relax over Hong Kong.</headline>
<byline>James Forrester</byline>
<dateline>EDINBURGH 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong can remain one of the world's great cities in the next century under Chinese rule, the territory's British governor Chris Patten said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;All China needs to do is relax about Hong Kong,&quot; Patten told a conference of Scottish business leaders in Edinburgh.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact of Hong Kong's present success is not in question. The question is, will it continue after the return to Chinese sovereignty in the middle of next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We've done our best to give Hong Kong the best possible chance for the future. It would take spectacular incompetence to destroy that success,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Patten said doubts remained about the future but Britain was doing everything possible to preserve Hong Kong's way of life.</p>
<p>&quot;Independence was never an option,&quot; he said. &quot;We are handing a free society to a society that has a different concept of freedom.&quot;</p>
<p>Patten told the conference, entitled &quot;Hong Kong, 1997 and beyond&quot;, that important guarantees were given in the Joint Declaration in which Britain and China agreed on the handover.</p>
<p>They were not just guarantees for the survival of capitalism in Hong Kong but of the context in which it flourished, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've taken them seriously and tried to make them stick.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there had been disagreements with China on such things as human rights and the rule of law but these had not damaged Hong Kong's economic progress.</p>
<p>The chairman of Hong Kong's stock exchange said China could be trusted to nurture financial markets after the territory was handed over to Beijing next year.</p>
<p>&quot;China has extensive commercial interests in Hong Kong...it can be trusted to behave pragmatically,&quot; Edgar Cheng Wai-Kin told the conference.</p>
<p>But he said pro-democracy groups could disrupt harmony after China takes over from Britain at midnight on June 30 and warned his compatriots not to antagonise Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;China needs strong government. Hong Kong must also have strong government...the control of existing pressure groups is one of the key tests for the future,&quot; Cheng said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong has the sixth largest foreign exchange market in the world and its stock market is the eighth largest -- the biggest in Asia after Japan.</p>
<p>The task was to maintain the integrity of existing regulatory institutions, now run by Hong Kong people who would be staying on after the handover, Cheng said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDINBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
