<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138990" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-FOURTEEN-YEAR-OLD TEST PLAYER RAZA STARTS IN STYLE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-FOURTEEN-YEAR-OLD TEST PLAYER RAZA STARTS IN STYLE.</headline>
<dateline>FAISALABAD, Pakistan 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hasan Raza, at 14</p>
<p>years and 227 days easily the youngest to play test cricket,</p>
<p>began in sparkling style with four boundaries to ensure Pakistan</p>
<p>remained well on top of Zimbabwe on the opening day of the</p>
<p>second test on Thursday.</p>
<p>Raza shared in an unbroken 47-run fourth wicket partnership</p>
<p>with opener Saeed Anwar in the closing session to make sure</p>
<p>Pakistan did not waste the earlier fast bowling efforts of</p>
<p>captain Wasim Akram who took six wickets as Zimbabwe were</p>
<p>dismissed for 133.</p>
<p>Pakistan also began their first innings inauspiciously,</p>
<p>losing their first two wickets with only 10 on the board and</p>
<p>their third when they reached 67.</p>
<p>Raza entered to loud cheers from the small crowd and</p>
<p>apparantly unfazed by the occasion, and opened his account with</p>
<p>an exquiste late cut off leg-spinner Paul Strang.</p>
<p>By the close, Raza was 20 not out and Anwar unbeaten on 69</p>
<p>as Pakistan reached 114 for three, only 19 behind Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Anwar, dropped at 49 and 51, brought up his 12th half</p>
<p>century in his 19th test in 88 minutes off 59 balls with nine</p>
<p>fours. He has so far struck 13 fours after 130 minutes at the</p>
<p>crease.</p>
<p>Raza beat the previous record for the youngest test player,</p>
<p>held by current Pakistan team manager Mushtaq Muhammad who made</p>
<p>his debut at the age of 15 years and 124 days against West</p>
<p>Indies in Lahore in 1958-59.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe would hardly have objected to Raza gaining all the</p>
<p>attention as they collapsed miserably after winning the toss and</p>
<p>opting to bat first on a lively grass-top pitch at Faisalabad's</p>
<p>Iqbal Stadium.</p>
<p>Their plight would have much worse but for a fighting 61 by</p>
<p>left-hander Andy Flower. He was last out after batting for 174</p>
<p>minutes and hit seven fours from 143 balls.</p>
<p>Openers Grant Flower (15) and Mark Dekker (19) were the only</p>
<p>other batsmen to reach double figures.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, 88 for five at luch, continued to decline in the</p>
<p>afternoon session, losing the last five wickets for just 45 runs</p>
<p>to be all out on the stroke of tea.</p>
<p>Akram finished with six for 48, his best figures against the</p>
<p>visitors, surpassing his five for 43 at Bulawayo in 1994-95. It</p>
<p>was Zimbabwe's lowest total by one run on Pakistani soil.</p>
<p>It continued an amazing series for the Pakistan captain who</p>
<p>made 257 in the drawn first test and shared in a world record</p>
<p>eighth wicket stand of 313.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAISALABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
