<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138994" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-SHEARER FACES SURGERY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SHEARER FACES SURGERY.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>England captain Alan Shearer, the world's most expensive footballer, could be out of soccer for up to eight weeks.</p>
<p>The striker needs an operation on a persistent groin problem.</p>
<p>Shearer was transferred for 15 million pounds ($24 million) from Blackburn Rovers to Newcastle just before the start of the season and his absence will be a major blow to his new club.</p>
<p>The English league leaders are attempting to win the title for the first time since 1927.</p>
<p>Shearer has been in fine form and last Sunday scored in Newcastle's crushing 5-0 triumph over current champions Manchester United.</p>
<p>But the injury flared up and ruled him out of the 1-0 victory over Oldham in the League Cup fourth round on Wednesday. He will also miss next week's UEFA Cup second round return leg at home to Ferencvaros, who lead 3-2.</p>
<p>Shearer has scored eight goals for his club this season and developed a formidable striking partnership with fellow England international Les Ferdinand.</p>
<p>Shearer has also netted three times in England's two World Cup qualifiers against Moldova and Poland, but will be out of the reckoning for the game in Georgia on November 9.</p>
<p>He had a similar operation at the end of last season before England's Euro 96 campaign, returning to training after four weeks.</p>
<p>Shearer said: &quot;The original operation in May was on my left groin.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt some twinges around three or four weeks ago and visited the specialist, who confirmed that I had a similar problem with my right groin, which apparently is not unusual in these cases.</p>
<p>&quot;The pain has been getting worse in recent games and was really bad during and after the Manchester United game.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks likely that I will miss four Premiership games and the international in Georgia.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
