<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138989" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-HASAN RAZA MISSES SCHOOL TO MAKE TEST MATCH HISTORY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-HASAN RAZA MISSES SCHOOL TO MAKE TEST MATCH HISTORY.</headline>
<dateline>FAISALABAD, Pakistan 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a story straight</p>
<p>out of a boy's comic, Pakistan's Hasan Raza stepped into test</p>
<p>cricket on Thursday at the tender age of 14 years and 227 days</p>
<p>to steer his side out of a tricky situation.</p>
<p>The Karachi-born schoolboy easily beat the previous record</p>
<p>for the youngest test player, set by Pakistan's current manager</p>
<p>Pakistan's Mushtaq Muhammad, who was 15 years and 124 days on</p>
<p>his debut against West Indies in 1958-59.</p>
<p>Although not exactly staring defeat in the face, Pakistan</p>
<p>had made an uncertain start to their innings to be 67 for three</p>
<p>in reply to Zimbabwe's first innings 133 on the opening day of</p>
<p>the second test.</p>
<p>Enter Hasan Raza, and any fears of a collapse disappeared.</p>
<p>He promptly played an exquisite late cut off leg-spinner</p>
<p>Paul Strang and went on to hit three more boundaries in an</p>
<p>unbeaten 20 by the close as he and opener Saeed Anwar shared in</p>
<p>an unbroken 47-run partnership for the fourth wicket which took</p>
<p>Pakistan to only 19 runs behind Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>&quot;I am just thrilled to be playing for my country. It is</p>
<p>indeed a great honour, more so when I have become the youngest</p>
<p>test cricketer,&quot; Raza said shyly after stumps were drawn.</p>
<p>He said he felt he had improved his chances for selection</p>
<p>after scoring heavily in Pakistan's Under-19 championship and</p>
<p>after making 58 for a Combined XI against Zimbabwe.</p>
<p>Raza was introduced to the game as a seven-year-old when he</p>
<p>joined Karachi's Nazimabad Sports Club, and came to prominence</p>
<p>when he played in the Under-15 World Cup in England earlier this</p>
<p>year.</p>
<p>&quot;I enjoyed playing in England and especially the final</p>
<p>against India at Lords,&quot; the slender batsman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Raza, a ninth class student at the Government Boys Secondary</p>
<p>School, Karachi, showed his talent in the Under-19 Championship,</p>
<p>in which he scored 791 runs, including four centuries.</p>
<p>His 134 against Lahore in the final attracted the attention</p>
<p>of the national selectors, who picked Raza for the opening match</p>
<p>of Zimbabwe's tour. He went to the wicket with the Combined XI</p>
<p>in deep trouble at 110 for four, but soon transformed the game</p>
<p>with a lusty 58 from 55 balls, including two sixes and five</p>
<p>fours.</p>
<p>Raza, the son of a businessman who has six children, says</p>
<p>education, not cricket, must take priority at the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;Education is very imperative. I know I can't play cricket</p>
<p>all my life and that is why I want to complete my education</p>
<p>before turning to cricket on a whole-time basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;My great ambition is to play the next World Cup in England</p>
<p>in 1999 and by that time I should have gained more experience.&quot;</p>
<p>By that time he will be a hardened veteran of 17.</p>
<p>Raza said he had modelled his hard-hitting style on that of</p>
<p>compatriot Basit Ali, now out of form and out of the test side.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAISALABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
