<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138973" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP ECONOMIC COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-31.</title>
<headline>EP ECONOMIC COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Economic and Monetary Affairs and Industrial Policy [[ Tuesday 29 October 1996 ]] P U B L I C M E E T I N G 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.840 ) - the order of business will be decided when the agenda is adopted - a draft timetable may be obtained from the secretariat or at the meeting 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 25-27 June 1996 in Brussels (PE219.512 ) - 8-9 July 1996 in Brussels (PE218.926 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Report by the chairman of the Subcommittee on Monetary Affairs 5. Consideration and adoption of the committee's calendar of meetings for 1997 (PE219.508/REV ) 6. Exchange of views with Mr BRUTON, Irish Minister for Enterprise and Employme nt - Exchange of views on employment policy in the EU - Mr BRUTON will attend on Tuesday 29 October 1996 from 3.10 pm 7. Hearing of Mr DUISENBERG, candidate for the Presidency of the European Monet ary Institute - the hearing of Mr DUISENBERG will take place on Wednesday 30 October 1996 from 9 am; - the hearing will be in public; following the hearing a meeting of the politica l groups will be held in camera; (PE219.999 ) - Mr DUISENBERG's written answers will be treated as confidential until the hear ing; (PE219.520 ) - they will be distributed to members of the Committee on Economic and Monetary Affairs 24 hours before the hearing. 8. Exchange of views with Sir Brian UNWIN, President of the European Investment Bank - Exchange of views on the lending policy priorities, annual balance sheet and f uture developments of the EIB - Sir Brian UNWIN will attend on Wednesday 30 October 1996 from 4.15 pm 9. Hearing on 'SMEs and the craft sector, keys to employment' - the hearing will take place on Thursday 31 October 1996 from 10 am to 12.30 pm; the programme will be available separately (PE219.842 ) 9.1 The craft industry and small enterprises: keys to growth and employment in E urope (second SME conference in Berlin) (T04245) COS0326 COM(95)0502 C4-0503/95 + ECON Fond R TORRES MARQUES H. (PSE) 9.2 Coordination of activities in favour of SMEs and the craft sector (T04734) COS0380 COM(95)0362 C4-0120/96 B4-0030/96 B4-0030/96 + ECON Fond R GAROSCI Riccardo. (UPE) 10. Maximum design speed of wheeled agricultural or forestry vehicles (amendmen t of 23 directives) (T04891) COD96129 COM(96)0196 C4-0301/96 + ECON Fond R HAUTALA Heidi. (V ) (PE219.504 ) - Adoption of draft report 11. Report on convergence (T04762) ATT1183 + ECON Fond R METTEN Alman. (PSE) (PE219.495 ) - Adoption of draft report 12. The changeover to the single currency (report by the European Monetary Inst itute) (T04566) COS0336 C4-596/95 C4-0559/95 + ECON Fond R HOPPENSTEDT Karsten (PPE) (PE218.194/REV) - Adoption of draft reonomy in the context of p reparation for the third stage of EMU (T03572) INI0316 + ECON Fond R HARRISON Lyndon. (PSE) (PE217.495/AM ) - Adoption of draft report 14. Report on employment in Europe (T04700) COS0472 COM(96)0485 C4-0553/96 + ECON Avis CASSIDY Bryan M. (PPE) (PE219.834 ) F ASOC Fond WOLF Friedrich. (V ) (PE219.490/A ) - Adoption of draft opinion 15. Scope of the codecision procedure (Commission report under Article 189b(8)) (T04963) COS0449 SEC(96)1225 C4-0464/96 + ECON Avis L (PE218.934 ) F INST Fond</p>
<p>(PE219.530 ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 16. Legal status of Euro (T04343) ATT0961 + ECON Fond HERMAN Fernand H. (PPE) (PE219.844 ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 17. Stability Pact - Convergence in Stage 3 of EMU (T04987) COS0448 SEC(96)1489 C4-0461/96 + ECON Fond R CHRISTODOULOU Efthym (PPE) (PE219.841 ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 18. Universal service for telecommunications in the perspective of a fully libe ralized environment (T04802) COS0399 COM(96)0073 C4-020 ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 19. The strengthening of Fiche d'Impact (B4-0120/96) - rapporteur: Mr Graham MATHER - Consideration of draft report (PE219.838 ) - Deadline for tabling amendments 20. Any other business 21. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 22. Date of next meeting in Brussels: (PE/IV/OJ/96-24 ) - an extraordinary meeting will be arranged in Strasbourg on Tuesday 12 November 1996 from 5.30 to 7 pm. - at that meeting the committee will adopt the HERMAN, CHRISTODOULOU and TORRES COUTO reports scheduled for November II END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
