<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138984" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-EU STUDYING SATELLITE DEAL WITH ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-EU STUDYING SATELLITE DEAL WITH ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>European competition commissioner Karel Van Miert said in a radio interview on Thursday he wants to probe a four-year exclusive deal between satellite broadcaster BSkyB and the English Football Association (F.A.).</p>
<p>But in Brussels, Van Miert said a distinction had to be made between formal investigations and the need to monitor all such deals. No formal investigation was underway involving BSkyB, he said.</p>
<p>In the interview broadcast on BBC radio, Van Miert said: &quot;We have to look into the (BSkyB-F.A.) deal and also the duration of the contract.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked by the programme if he would intervene in the deal he replied, &quot;We certainly will. We certainly will. And what should not happen is that those acquiring the rights will be in such a dominant position that they are going to impose the rules.&quot;</p>
<p>BSkyB sealed a 670 million pound ($1.07 billion) contract in June to buy the rights to transmit live all English premier league soccer matches for the next four years.</p>
<p>Last month Van Miert signalled his concern over long-term deals involving ever-larger sums of money in submissions to the European Parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;There is this trend which seriously worries us that increasingly a few large groups can buy such (sports broadcasting) rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In August the Commission launched a probe into a plan by the Dutch soccer association KNVB to give a new TV channel called Sport 7, which it partly owns, exclusive rights for seven years over premier and first division matches.</p>
<p>In a statement issued in Brussels commenting on the BBC report Van Miert drew a distinction between KNVB and BSkyB.</p>
<p>&quot;...a formal investigation is presently underway as to the Dutch sports channel, especially as regards the seven-year duration of the contract, and not as far as the BSkyB-premier league is concerned.</p>
<p>&quot;As to the BSkyB-premiership contract, Mr Van Miert said that this is part of a more general monitoring exercise related to the overall phenonomenon of exclusive rights on sports events,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>No one was immediately available at BSkyB.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
