<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138963" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP RULES OF PROCEDURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</title>
<headline>EP RULES OF PROCEDURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on the Rules of Procedure, the Verification of Credentials and Immunities [[ Wednesday 30 October 1996 ]] 0.1 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.648 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meeting of: - 9 and 10 September 1996 (PE219.208 ) 2.1 VERIFICATION OF CREDENTIALS 3. Verification of credentials (DVR0368 ) - by Mrs Marie-Arlette CARLOTTI (PE219.207 ) - by Mr Alfonso NOVO BELENGUER (PE219.640 ) 3.1 INTERPRETATION 4. Rules 46, 92 and 94 - procedure for presenting Council recommendations in pl enary (T04874) REG0070 + REGL Fond DONNELLY Brendan P. (PPE) (PE219.212 ) - Consideration of a draft interpretation 5. Rule 92(2) - presentation of oral amendments to recommendations not availabl e in all languages (T04875) REG0071 + REGL Fond DONNELLY Brendan P. (PPE) - Exchange of views 6. Possibility of Parliament delivering an opinion on an amendment to a text th at it has already officially approved (T04744) T REG0064 + REGL Fond R FABRE-AUBRESPY Herve (EDN) (PE216.261 ) - Consideration of working document 7. Rule 150 - Interpretation of Rule 124(6) on oral amendments tabled in commit tee (T04919) REG0073 + REGL Fond GUTIERREZ DIAZ A. (GUE) - Initial exchange of views 8. Rule 141: membership of subcommittees (T04926) REG0074 + REGL Fond DELL'ALBA Gianfranco (ARE) (PE218.150 ) - Consideration of working document 9. Rule 12 - Brief statement by the oldest Member (DVR0424 ) - Appointment of rapporteur 9.1 MODIFICATION 10. Rule 49 - annual legislative programme (T04903) REG0072 + REGL Fond MANZELLA Andrea. (PSE) (PE218.583/REV) - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 11. The statute for Members (T04621) INI0477 + REGL Fond FAYOT Ben. (PSE) - Consideration of amendments - Adoption of a draft working document 12. Cooperation between committees responsible and committees asked for their o pinions (DVR0425 ) - Appointment of rapporteur 13. Action to be taken on the coordinators' proposals (1) 14. Calendar of committee meetings in 1997 - Consideration and possibly adoption (PE219.642 ) 15. Any other business 16. Date of next meeting (PE/XVIII/OJ/96-13 )</p>
<p>[FOOTNOTES]1. ) A coordinators' meeting will be held at 5.30 p.m. or after the meeting. A N N E X 0.1 0.2 COORDINATORS' MEETING 0.3 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.648/ANN ) 2. Deferred resignations - Proposal for the appointment of a rapporteur 3. Temporary committees of inquiry - presence of members and presentation of fi nal report (DVR0435 ) - Proposal for action to be taken - Possibly, proposal for the appointment of a rapporteur - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
