<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138970" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP EXTERNAL ECONOMIC RELATIONS COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</title>
<headline>EP EXTERNAL ECONOMIC RELATIONS COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on External Economic Relations [[ Wednesday 30 October 1996 ]] P U B L I C M E E T I N G ===] Wednesday 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.456 ) 2. Chairman's announcements ===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 3. Information from the Commission on work in progress 4.1 Amendment of Regulation 40/94 on the Community trade mark (Protocol on the I nternational Registration of Trade Marks) (T03826) (T03826) CNS96198 COM(96)0372 + RELA Avis A VALDIVIELSO DE C. (PPE) (PE218.826 ) F JURI Fond R MEDINA ORTEGA M. (PSE) (PE219.017 ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 4.2 EC accession to the Madrid Protocol on the International Recognition of Mark s (proposal for a decision) (T04948) (T04948) CNS96190 COM(96)0367 + RELA Avis A VALDIVIELSO DE C. (PPE) (PE218.827 ) F JURI Fond R MEDINA ORTEGA M. (PSE) (PE219.018 ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 5. Towards a new maritime strategy (T04818) (T04818) COS0405 COM(96)0081 C4-0237/96 + RELA Avis A WAAL Leen v. (EDN) (PE219.458 ) F TRAN Fond R DANESIN Alessandro. (UPE) (PE218.415 ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 6.1 Amendment of the basic decision relating to the SOCRATES programme to includ e Turkey among the beneficiary countries (T04863) (T04863) COD96130 COM(96)0199 C4-0293/96 + RELA Avis A SCHWAIGER Konrad. (PPE) F JEUN Fond R HEINISCH Renate C. (PPE) - Exchange of views 6.2 Amendment of the basic decision on the Youth for Europe programme to include Turkey among the beneficiary countries (T04864) (T04864) COD96131 COM(96)0199 C4-0294/96 + RELA Avis A SCHWAIGER Konrad. (PPE) F JEUN Fond R HEINISCH Renate C. (PPE) - Exchange of views 6.3 Amendment of the basic decision relating to the Leonardo programme to includ e Turkey among the beneficiary countries (T04865) **I (T04865) SYN96132 COM(96)0199 + RELA Avis A SCHWAIGER Konrad. (PPE) F ASOC Fond R (ELD) - Exchange of views 7. Framework procedure for implementing Article 366a of the Lome Convention (T04769) (T04769) AVC96050 COM(96)0069 + RELA Avis A SMITH Alex. (PSE) (PE217.862 ) F DEVE Fond R AELVOET Magda G. (V ) (PE218.074 ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 8. Linking relief, rehabilitation and development (LRRD) (T03955) (T03955) COS0419 COM(96)0153 C4-0265/96 + RELA Avis A SMITH Alex. (PSE) F DEVE Fond R FASSA Raimondo. (ELD) (PE218.768 ) - Exchange of views ===] Coordinators' meeting at the end of the meeting 8.2 - oOo-===] Thursday 9. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure (see addendum) 10. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 11 December 1995 (PE218.820 ) - 12 December 1995 (PE218.824 ) - 18-19 December 1995 (PE218.822 ) 11. Agreements between the EC and Israel on procurement by government and telco mmunications operators (T04821) CNS96104 COM(96)0148 C4-0323/96 + RELA Fond R DE CLERCQ W. (ELD) (PE218.552 ) - Adoption of draft report 12. Reciprocal recognition of approval for motor vehicle equipment and parts - EC accession to 1958 Agreement (T04728) AVC96006 COM(95)0723 C4-0186/96 + RELA Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE217.860 ) - Adoption of draft report 13. Conclusion of a partnership agreement with Chile (T04468) (T04468) ACC96149 COM(96)0259 C4-0450/96 + RELA Fond R MIRANDA DE L. (PSE) - Exchange of views 14. Implementation of the action plan annexed to the Barcelona Declaration (T04510) (T04510) COS0436 7987/96 C4-0414/96 + RELA Avis A DIMITRAKOPOULOS Geor (PPE) F POLI Fond R SAKELLARIOU Jannis. (PSE) (PE218.799/A ) - Exchange of view Transatlantic trade and economic relations (T04596) INI0452 + RELA Fond R MANN Erika. (PSE) - Exchange of views 16. Cooperation in the peaceful uses of nuclear energy between the EAEC amd the USA (T03117) COS0418 C4-264/96 C4-0264/96 + RELA Avis A BERES Pervenche. (PSE) (PE219.454 ) F ENER Fond R AHERN Nuala. (V ) - Exchange of views 17. International fisheries agreements (T04619) B4-0126/96 B4-0126/96 + RELA Avis A NOVO Honorio. (GUE) (PE218.568 ) F PECH Fond R CRAMPTON Peter D. (PSE) - Exchange of views 18. Any other business 19. Date of next meeting (PE/VI/OJ/96-25 ) ===] 3 p.m. 19.2 Information from the Commission on the PHARE and TACIS programmes (see separate programme) (PE219.457 ) - FIN - u END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
