<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138978" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-MORRISON RETURNING TO RING NEXT MONTH.</title>
<headline>BOXING-MORRISON RETURNING TO RING NEXT MONTH.</headline>
<dateline>TULSA, Oklahoma 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>HIV-infected former heavyweight contender Tommy Morrison will return to the ring next month in Tokyo in a bout to raise money for children stricken with AIDS.</p>
<p>Morrison, who retired eight months ago after testing positive for the virus that causes AIDS, is fighting undistinguished boxer Anthony Cooks on the undercard of the George Foreman-Crawford Grimsley card on November 3.</p>
<p>Morrison said he hopes to raise $500,000 to benefit the Knockout AIDS Foundation.</p>
<p>&quot;The main objective has always been to finance the Foundation and this is the most effective, fast way to do it,&quot; Morrison said of his decision to return.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't really miss boxing,&quot; said Morrison. &quot;I'm doing this strictly for the foundation, that is my sole purpose. I made a lot of promises to these kids and I want to live up to my end of the bargain and boxing is what I do best.&quot;</p>
<p>Morrison, 45-3-1, has not fought since being stopped by Briton Lennox Lewis in the sixth round 12 months ago, but is not worried about his fitness for the scheduled 10-round bout against Cooks, 9-5-0.</p>
<p>&quot;I always work out and I've been been in the gym about three weeks,&quot; said Morrison, who expects to weigh near his usual 225 pounds (102 kg) for the fight. &quot;I've been doing a little sparring for two weeks so everything is going fine.&quot;</p>
<p>Though he has plans to fight just this one time, Morrison would not rule out more fights under the right circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;If the opportunity presents itself that would be beneficial to the foundation we will do it,&quot; Morrison said.</p>
<p>Morrison said the concerns of him infecting others in the ring are unfounded.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel very comfortable with it, I don't think there is anything wrong with somebody fighting someone with HIV positive as long as the other person knows,&quot; said the 27-year-old Morrison.</p>
<p>&quot;The risks are much higher to get a brain contusion than HIV in the ring. Once they see it happen (the fight), it won't be frowned upon so much.&quot;</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Morrison has agreed to certain rule changes for the fight.</p>
<p>&quot;If I suffer an uncontrollable cut, I will automatically stop the fight and whoever is ahead on the scorecards wins the fight,&quot; Morrison said. &quot;It has to be a very bad cut.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TULSA, Oklahoma"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
