<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138972" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP ENERGY COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</title>
<headline>EP ENERGY COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 30-31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Research, Technological Development and Energy [[ Wednesday 30 October 1996 ]] ===] Wednesday, 30 October 1996 at 3 pm 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.378 ) ===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 2/3 September 1996 in Brussels (PE216.084 ) - 17 September 1996 in Strasbourg (PE219.373 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Any other business 5. Improving energy efficiency: continuation of the SAVE programme after 1995 ( CO2 strategy) (T03884) **II (T03884) SYN95131 COM(96)0195 C4-0375/96 + ENER Fond R BLOCH von B. (V )</p>
<p>(PE218.601 ) - Consideration of draft recommendation and amendments 6. Trans-European networks in the energy sector (amendment of Decision 1254/96/ EEC) (T04947) (T04947) COD96203 COM(96)0390 C4-0429/96 + ENER Fond R ADAM Gordon J. (PSE) (PE219.372/A ) - Further consideration of draft report - Consideration of amendments 7. Reduction of CO2 emissions from motor vehicles (T03141) (T03141) COS0358 COM(95)0689 C4-0015/96 + ENER Avis A HOLM Ulf. (V ) (PE218.592 ) F ENVI Fond R IVERSEN John. (GUE) - Further consideration of draft opinion - Consideration of amendments 8. Universal service for telecommunications in the perspective of a fully liber alized environment (T04802) (T04802) COS0399 COM(96)0073 C4-0205/96 + ENER Avis A MANN Erika. (PSE) (PE218.587 ) F ECON Fond R BERES Pervenche. (PSE) - First consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 9. Armenia: negotiation of the Partnership and Cooperation Agreement (T04117) (T04117) AVC96093 COM(96)0136 C4-0319/96 + ENER Avis A BLOCH von B. (V ) (PE218.590 ) F POLI Fond R LA MALFA G. (ELD) (PE218.133 ) - First consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments ===] Coordinators' meeting ===] Thursday, 31 October 1996, 9 am 10. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 11. Improving energy efficiency: continuation of the SAVE programme after 1995 (CO2 strategy) (T03884) **II SYN95131 COM(96)0195 C4-0375/96 + ENER Fond R BLOCH von B. (V ) (PE218.601 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation 12. Trans-European networks in the energy sector (amendment of Decision 1254/96 /EEC) (T04947) COD96203 COM(96)0390 C4-0429/96 + ENER Fond R ADAM Gordon J. (PSE) (PE219.372/A ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 13. Reduction of CO2 emissions from motor vehicles (T03141) COS0358 COM(95)0689 C4-0015/96 + ENER Avis A HOLM Ulf. (V )</p>
<p>(PE218.592 ) F ENVI Fond R IVERSEN John. (GUE) - Vote on and adoption of draft opinion 14. An industrial competitiveness policy for the European chemical industry: a model (T04842) COS0422 COM(96)0187 C4-0273/96 + ENER Avis A HEINISCH Renate C. (PPE) (PE218.584 ) F ECON Fond R LANGEN Werner. (PPE) - Further consideration of draft opinion - Consideration of amendments - Vote on and adoption of draft opinion 15. Common rules for the internal market in electricity (T02229) (T02229) COD0384 COM(93)0643 C4-0457/96 + ENER Fond R DESAMA Claude. (PSE) (PE219.379 ) - Consideration of draft recommendation - Deadline for tabling amendments 16. Prospects for European research and technology in the 21st century (T04591) (T04591) INI0447 COM(96)0332 INI0447 C4-0491/96 + ENER Fond R DESAMA Claude. (PSE) (PE219.376/A ) - Further consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 17. The European Union and Latin America: the present situation and prospects f or closer partnership, 1996-2000 (T04237) (T04237) COS0321 COM(95)0495 C4-0489/95 + ENER Avis A ESTEVAN BOLEA M. (PPE) (PE219.380 ) F POLI Fond R BERTENS Jan W. (ELD) (PE218.999 ) - First consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 18. Date of next meeting Tuesday, 12 November 1996, from 5.30 - 7 pm, Strasbour g - FIN - l END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
