<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138968" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP TRANSPORT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30, EP ENVIRONMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-30.</title>
<headline>EP TRANSPORT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30, EP ENVIRONMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 29-30.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Transport and Tourism [[ Monday 28 October 1996 ]] MEETING OPEN TO THE PUBLIC 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.913 ) ===] In the presence of the Commission 2. Third pan-European transport conference (T04008) INI0406 INI0406 + TRAN Fond R LUTTGE Gunter. (PSE) (PE218.425 ) - Adoption of amendments (Am. 1-5) - Adoption of compromise amendments (Comp.Am. 6-9) - Adoption of draft report 3. A strategy for revitalizing the Community's railways (T04954) COS0442 COM(96)0421 C4-0452/96 + TRAN Fond (PPE) - Statement by Mr KINNOCK, - Commissioner responsible for Transport - Exchange of views - (Monday, 28 October 1996 at 3.30 pm.) ===] Coordinators' meeting Monday, 28 October 1996 at 5.30 pm 3.2 ===] Tuesday, 29 October 1996 at 9 am 4. Internal Business 4.1 Chairman's announcements (PE219.910 ) 4.2 Decision on procedure - Annex (PE219.913/ANN) - Notice to members (PE219.914 ) 5. Eighth European Parliament and Council directive on summertime arrangements (T04829) COD96082 COM(96)0106 C4-0252/96 + TRAN Fond R BELLERE S. (NI ) (PE218.712 ) - Adoption of amendments - Adoption of draft report 6. White Paper on an air traffic management (Freeing Europe's airspace) (T03915) COS0394 COM(96)0057 C4-0191/96 B4-0305/96 B4-0305/96 + TRAN Fond R CORNELISSEN Petrus A (PPE) (PE219.349 ) - Consideration of draft report 7. Green Paper: Towards fair and efficient pricing in transport - internalizing the external cost of transport (T04560) COS0349 COM(95)0691 C4-0610/95 + TRAN Fond SCHMIDBAUER Barbara. (PSE) (PE218.428 ) - Consideration of draft report 8. Public services and state aid for transport (T04009) INI0407 INI0407 + TRAN Fond CASTRICUM Frits. (PSE) (PE219.909 ) - Consideration of draft report 9. Implementation in 1991-92 of Regulation (EEC) No 3820/85 on harmonizing soci al legislation concerning road transport (T04658) COS0370 COM(95)0713 C4-0065/96 + TRAN Fond R SCHLECHTER Marcel. (PSE) (PE218.714 ) - Consideration of draft report ===] Tuesday, 29 October 1996 from 3.00-5.00 pm 9.3 H E A R I N G 10. Towards a new maritime strategy (T04818) (T04818) COS0405 COM(96)0081 C4-0237/96 + TRAN Fond R DANESIN Alessandro. (UPE) (PE218.415 ) - Notice to members - Statement by experts - Exchange of views 10.1 o o o 11. Safe transport of radioactive material/3rd report of the Working Group on t he Safe Transport of Radioactive Material (T04822) (T04822) COS0409 COM(96)0011 C4-0241/96 + TRAN Fond R MILLER Bill. (PSE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 12. Defining a Community aviation safety improvement strategy (T04934) COS0438 SEC(96)1083 C4-0423/96 + TRAN Fond R McINTOSH Anne C. (PPE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 13. Road transport: framework regulation on road taxes (T04401) ATT1025 + TRAN Fond R JARZEMBOWSKI Georg. (PPE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 14. Air transport: briefs for negotiations with the countries of Central and Ea stern Europe (T03731) ATT0635 SEC(95)0328 + TRAN Fond - GONZ uLEZ TRIVINO A. (ARE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 15. Topical debate 15.1 Council meeting of 3-4 October 1996 (Transport) 15.2 Financing of Trans-European Transport Networks (Kinnock Group) 15.3 Telematics in Transport (STOA study - 3rd Annual World Congress on Intellig ent Transport Systems in Orlando, Florida) (PE165.894 ) - Statement by Mr CORNELISSEN, chairman and - Mr STOCKMANN, rapporteur - Statement by Mr FINN, managing director of the ETTS (European Transport Telema tic Systems) on behalf of STOA on the - telematics applications in urbain and public transport - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 16. Limitation of the operation of aeroplanes - Proposal for a Council directiv e amending Directive 92/14/EEC (T04975) **I SYN96209 COM(96)04 Fond - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 17. Commission report on the Single Market in 1995 (T04759) COS0389 COM(96)0051 C4-0146/96 + TRAN Avis A WAAL Leen v. (EDN)</p>
<p>(PE218.718 ) F ECON Fond R SECCHI Carlo. (PPE) (PE218.182/DEF) - Adoption of draft opinion 18. The European Union and Latin America: the present situation and prospects f or closer partnership, 1996-2000 (T04237) (T04237) COS0321 COM(95)0495 C4-0489/95 + TRAN Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.719 ) F POLI Fond R BERTENS Jan W. (ELD)</p>
<p>(PE218.999/B ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 19. Framework trade and cooperation agreement between the EC and the Republic o f Korea (T03506) (T03506) CNS96098 COM(96)0141 + TRAN Avis A VICECONTE Guido. (UPE) (PE218.720 ) F RELA Fond R PORTO Manuel. (ELD) - Adoption of draft opinion 20. Competitiveness of the shipping industry (T04389) (T04389) COS0402 COM(96)0084 C4-0211/96 + TRAN Avis A BELLERE S. (NI )</p>
<p>(PE218.716 ) F ECON Fond R KATIFORIS Georgios. (PSE) (PE219.836/DT ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Adoption of draft opinion (possibly) 21. Alpine Transit - Adoption of oral question with debate (PE219.341 ) - Adoption of oral question (PE219.342 ) 22. Any other business 23. Date of next meeting (PE/X/OJ/96-18 ) A N N E X ===] In the presence of the Commission 1. EC 1997 work programme, political priorities and legislative initiatives. Implementation of 1996 programme (COS0475 ) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter (possibly) ===] Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure ===] CONSULTATIONS ===] - Responsible 2. Safety at sea: minimum level of training for seafarers (amendment of Directi ve 94/58/EC) (T05012) **I SYN96240 COM(96)0470 C4-0550/96 + TRAN Fond - Appointment of rapporteur ===] RULE 45 MOTIONS FOR RESOLUTIONS ===] - Responsible 3. Establishment of a European compensation fund for transport accident victims (B4-0968/96) - - Include in future report on road safety ===] - Opinion 4. Promoting inter-regional cooperation between the Canaries, the Azores and Madeira (B4-0721/96) - Include in future report on White Paper on Tourism ===] DOCUMENTS RECEIVED FOR INFORMATION ===] - Responsible 6. Vendor control systems applied by the Member States (COM(96)0245) - Appointment of rapporteur l END OF DOCUMENT [[ Monday 28 October 1996 ]] MEETING OPEN TO THE PUBLIC ] In the presence of the Commission 2. Third pan-European transport conference (T04008) INI0406 INI0406 + TRAN Fond R LUTTGE Gunter. (PSE) (PE218.425 ) - Adoption of amendments (Am. 1-5) - Adoption of compromise amendments (Comp.Am. 6-9) - Adoption of draft report 3. A strategy for revitalizing the Community's railways (T04954) COS0442 COM(96)0421 C4-0452/96 + TRAN Fond (PPE) - Statement by Mr KINNOCK, - Commissioner responsible for Transport - Exchange of views - (Monday, 28 October 1996 at 3.30 pm.) ===] Coordinators' meeting Monday, 28 October 1996 at 5.30 pm 3.2 ===] Tuesday, 29 October 1996 at 9 am 4. Internal Business 4.1 Chairman's announcements (PE219.910 ) 4.2 Decision on procedure - Annex (PE219.913/ANN) - Notice to members (PE219.914 ) 5. Eighth European Parliament and Council directive on summertime arrangements (T04829) COD96082 COM(96)0106 C4-0252/96 + TRAN Fond R BELLERE S. (NI ) (PE218.712 ) - Adoption of amendments - Adoption of draft report 6. White Paper on an air traffic management (Freeing Europe's airspace) (T03915) COS0394 COM(96)0057 C4-0191/96 B4-0305/96 B4-0305/96 + TRAN Fond R CORNELISSEN Petrus A (PPE) (PE219.349 ) - Consideration of draft report 7. Green Paper: Towards fair and efficient pricing in transport - internalizing the external cost of transport (T04560) COS0349 COM(95)0691 C4-0610/95 + TRAN Fond SCHMIDBAUER Barbara. (PSE) (PE218.428 ) - Consideration of draft report 8. Public services and state aid for transport (T04009) INI0407 INI0407 + TRAN Fond CASTRICUM Frits. (PSE) (PE219.909 ) - Consideration of draft report 9. Implementation in 1991-92 of Regulation (EEC) No 3820/85 on harmonizing soci al legislation concerning road transport (T04658) COS0370 COM(95)0713 C4-0065/96 + TRAN Fond R SCHLECHTER Marcel. (PSE) (PE218.714 ) - Consideration of draft report ===] Tuesday, 29 October 1996 from 3.00-5.00 pm 9.3 H E A R I N G 10. Towards a new maritime strategy (T04818) (T04818) COS0405 COM(96)0081 C4-0237/96 + TRAN Fond R DANESIN Alessandro. (UPE) (PE218.415 ) - Notice to members - Statement by experts - Exchange of views 10.1 o o o 11. Safe transport of radioactive material/3rd report of the Working Group on t he Safe Transport of Radioactive Material (T04822) (T04822) COS0409 COM(96)0011 C4-0241/96 + TRAN Fond R MILLER Bill. (PSE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 12. Defining a Community aviation safety improvement strategy (T04934) COS0438 SEC(96)1083 C4-0423/96 + TRAN Fond R McINTOSH Anne C. (PPE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 13. Road transport: framework regulation on road taxes (T04401) ATT1025 + TRAN Fond R JARZEMBOWSKI Georg. (PPE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 14. Air transport: briefs for negotiations with the countries of Central and Ea stern Europe (T03731) ATT0635 SEC(95)0328 + TRAN Fond - GONZ uLEZ TRIVINO A. (ARE) - Statement by the Commission - Exchange of views 1</p>
<p>Committee on the Environment, Public Health and Consumer Protection [[ Tuesday 29 October 1996 ]] 0.1 ===] Tuesday, 29 October 1996, 3.00pm 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.419 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 24/25/26 September 1996 (PE219.417 ) - 8/9 October 1996 (PE219.418 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Consideration of common positions (possibly) 5. Oral question n. 20/95 by Messrs Lucas Pires and Florenz on the protection of waterways in Spain and Portugal (DVR0404 ) 6. Community strategy for waste management and a proposal for a Council resolut ion on waste policy (T04952) COS0443 COM(96)0399 C4-0453/96 + ENVI Fond R JENSEN Kirsten. (PSE) (PE219.422 ) - Consideration of draft report 7. Implementation of Community environmental law (T04482) ATT1107 + ENVI Fond R COLLINS Kenneth D. (PSE) - Consideration of working document 8. White Paper on an air traffic management (Freeing Europe's airspace) (T03915) (T03915) COS0394 COM(96)0057 C4-0191/96 + ENVI Avis L (PE219.872 ) + ENVI Avis</p>
<p>(PE219.872 ) F TRAN Fond R CORNELISSEN Petrus A (PPE) (PE218.713 ) - Consideration and possibly - Adoption of draft opinion in a form of a letter ===] Wednesday, 30 October 1996, 9.00am 9. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 10. Assessment of the effects of certain public and private projects on the env ironment - amendment of 85L0337 (T02659) **II (T02659) SYN94078 COM(95)0720 C4-0371/96 + ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) (PE219.111 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation 11. The legal protection of biotechnological inventions (T04629) (T04629) COD95350 COM(95)0661 C4-0063/96 + ENVI Avis A SANDB K Ulla. (EDN) (PE219.413 ) F JURI Fond R ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE218.021 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 12. Complementary (or non-conventional) medicine (T03525) (T03525) INI0330 INI0330 + ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) (PE216.066 ) - Adoption of draft report 13. Encrypted radio broadcasting: Green Paper (T03911) (T03911) COS0395 COM(96)0076 C4-0190/96 + ENVI Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.543 ) F JURI Fond R ANASTASSOPOULOS Geor (PPE) (PE217.902/DT ) - Adoption of draft opinion in a form of a letter 14. An industrial competitiveness policy for the European chemical industry: a model (T04842) (T04842) COS0422 COM(96)0187 C4-0273/96 + ENVI Avis L (PE219.112 ) F ECON Fond R LANGEN Werner. (PPE) - Consideration of draft opinion and possibly - Adoption of draft opinion in a form of a letter 15. Any other business 16. Date of next meeting - 12 November 1996 in Strasbourg (joint meeting with the Committee on Budgets) - -19/20/21 November 1996 in Brussels</p>
<p>[FOOTNOTES]1.) Coordinators' meeting to be held on Tuesday, 29 October 1996 at 6.00pm CORRIGENDUM 0.1 ===] MODIFICATIONS TO DRAFT AGENDA 0.3 Items 5 and 12: postponed 0.4 Item 14 to be taken on 29.10 instead of 30.10 (after item 8) 0.5 Add the following item after item 13: 13.1 Forests: protection against atmospheric pollution and fires (T04463) (T04463) CNS96185 COM(96)0341 C4-0476/96 + ENVI Fond</p>
<p>(PE219.873 ) - Consideration of draft report A N N E X ===] Item 9 of the agenda ===] Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure ===] CONSULTATIONS ===] - Responsible 1. Acquaculture animals and products: health conditions and combating fish dise ase (proposal for a directive) (T04908) (T04908) CNS96157 COM(96)0279 C4-0394/96 + ENVI Fond R BALDI Monica S. (UPE) + ENVI Fond BALDI Monica S. (UPE) - reconsideration 2. Forests: protection against atmospheric pollution and fires (T04463) (T04463) CNS96185 COM(96)0341 C4-0476/96 + ENVI Fond</p>
<p>(PE219.873 ) 3. Limitation of the operation of aeroplanes - Proposal for a Council directive amending Directive 92/14/EEC (T04975) **I (T04975) SYN96209 COM(96)0413 C4-0541/96 + ENVI Fond 4. Health protection of individuals against the dangers of ionizing radiation i n medical exposures (directive) (T04998) CNS96230 COM(96)0465 C4-0548/96 + ENVI Fond 5. Labelling of beef and beef products (proposal for a Council regulation) (T05010) (T05010) CNS96229 COM(96)0460 C4-0546/96 + ENVI Fond ===] - Opinion 6. System for the identification and registration of bovine animals (proposal f or a Council regulation) (T05011) (T05011) CNS96228 COM(96)0460 C4-0545/96 + ENVI Avis F AGRI Fond R (PPE) *** A N N E X 2 *** ===] COMMITOLOGY ===] Decision on procedure 1. Tables on packaging and packaging waste (94/62/EC) (PMC0165 ) (document available in all languages) 2. System of identifying packaging materials (Article 8(2) of Directive 94/62/E C) (T04554) (document available in all languages) PMC0187 XI/492/95RE3 + ENVI Fond S</p>
<p>(PE215.733 ) 3. Maximum concentrations of contaminants in foodstuffs (PMC0359) (document available in all languages)</p>
<p>[FOOTNOTES]1.) The documents mentioned may be consulted in the secretariat (IP2 E/33 or LEO 4 C 59) END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
