<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138988" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-AMES LEADS WHILE ALLENBY HITS SINGLE SHOT FOR CHARITY.</title>
<headline>GOLF-AMES LEADS WHILE ALLENBY HITS SINGLE SHOT FOR CHARITY.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>After travelling 19,000 km (12,000 miles) to hit a golf ball, ailing Australian Robert Allenby struck it 35 metres for charity before pulling out of the Volvo Masters on Thursday.</p>
<p>As Stephen Ames of Trinidad took the first round lead later in the day with a four-under-par 67, Allenby, his fractured sternum still throbbing with pain, was already on his way home via the United States after fulfilling a European Tour requirement that he play in the season-ending tournament to be eligible for his bonus.</p>
<p>At third place on the money list, his share of a 600,000 pounds ($960,000) end-of-season kitty would be 73,000 pounds ($117,00), 53,000 pounds ($85,000) if, as likely, he falls to fourth place.</p>
<p>Whatever the amount, Allenby will donate it to two children's charities, the Teenage Cancer Trust UK and the Challenge Cancer Support Network in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not here for the money. I merely wanted to protect my position on the money list for the year because I think I deserve it,&quot; said the 25-year-old winner of the French and English Opens and the British Masters this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll probably hit a shot like a five-year-old,&quot; Allenby, who flew from his Melbourne home on Wednesday, said when he arrived at the Valderrama course on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>As a morning fog lent a surreal air to an already farcical situation, Allenby did just that, his shot with a three wood looking more like a putt as it trickled down the fairway a mere 35 yards.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt a sharp pain on the follow-through,&quot; he said of the injury that he sustained in car crash in the nearby town of Estepona four weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It hurts when I sneeze, laugh or breath. It feels like there's an axe in there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Allenby had no quarrel with the rule that led to what was almost a cameo appearance, though Ryder Cup captain Seve Ballesteros said he felt it was unfair a player had to travel so far to hit just one shot.</p>
<p>Ballesteros offered no solution to the situation though he seemed to agree with a suggestion from Colin Montgomerie on Wednesday that the bonus money be made part of the tournament prize fund instead of being offered separately.</p>
<p>Ames, winner of the Benson and Hedges International in May, was surprised with his 67 after taking three weeks off because of repeated problems with his swing.</p>
<p>&quot;I just wanted to come here and enjoy the game, accept what I shot and hopefully play four rounds,&quot; said Ames, who dropped out after three rounds of his only previous Masters appearance in 1993.</p>
<p>Four birdies over the back nine helped him to a one-stroke lead over Britons Gordon Brand jnr, who holed a 95-yard wedge shot for an eagle three at the 535-yard fourth, and Paul Curry.</p>
<p>Irishman Padraig Harrington aced the 173-yard third hole with a seven iron on the way to a two-under-par 69 and a share of fourth place with Britons Jim Payne and Paul Lawrie and Costantino Rocca of Italy.</p>
<p>Rocca could displace Allenby from third spot on the money list with a fifth placing or better finish.</p>
<p>The big names did not fare well. Montgomerie, whose opening shot assured him of the number one position for a fourth successive year, carded a level-par 71. &quot;And I was very fortunmate to do that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ian Woosnam, second on the list, carded a 76 after accidentally breaking his putter following a birdie four at the fourth. He putted with a one iron for the rest of the round.</p>
<p>Ballesteros, still suffering from a heavy cold, had a three-over par 74 that included a triple bogey six at the tough 212-yard 12th, where he sliced his first shot 50 yards to the right, out of play.</p>
<p>Bernhard Langer, needing a victory to extend his record of winning at least one tour title every year to 17 years, shot 73.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TRTO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
