<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138993" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-WORLD CUP SEASON TO START WITHOUT TOMBA.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-WORLD CUP SEASON TO START WITHOUT TOMBA.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Pontieri</byline>
<dateline>SOELDEN, Austria 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alpine skiing will have to make do without its biggest drawcard -- Alberto Tomba -- when the World Cup season opens in Austria this weekend.</p>
<p>The Italian had already ruled himself out of the giant slalom on the Soelden glacier when he fell heavily during training in northern Italy on Wednesday. The crash forced him to take a three-week break from skiing.</p>
<p>This weekend's race was one of many World Cup events Tomba has scrapped from his schedule this season. He has not said when and where he will make his first World Cup appearance.</p>
<p>Instead, &quot;La Bomba&quot;, who considered retiring after winning two world championship gold medals in Spain last February, will concentrate his efforts on the 1997 event in Sestriere.</p>
<p>The three times Olympic champion, who trains separately from other Italian skiers, badly bruised his left knee and right wrist in the accident at Passo del Tonale.</p>
<p>Italian doctors said he was lucky not to tear a cruciate knee ligament.</p>
<p>&quot;Thank God the injuries are not that serious and will not completely ruin my season,&quot; the sport's number one showman said. &quot;But it does complicate my life because I have a lot of promotional appointments.&quot;</p>
<p>His absence from Sunday's men's race turns attention on Michael Von Grueningen, giant slalom title-holder.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be nice to win the giant slalom World Cup again, but it will be difficult to repeat my good performance from last winter,&quot; said the Swiss, winner of five giant slaloms and two championship medals last winter.</p>
<p>He said his form was still not up to scratch because of poor weather conditions at the resorts chosen by the Swiss team for summer training.</p>
<p>Blue skies are forecast for Soelden and the weather is not expected to be problematic.</p>
<p>Swiss Urs Kaelin, Norwegian Lasse Kjus and overall World Cup title-holder Kjetil Andre Aamodt are expected to be Von Gruenigen's main challengers.</p>
<p>Although Aamodt failed to impress last winter following a series of injuries, he won the final giant slalom of the season in Lillehammer. Coaches said he is currently in top form.</p>
<p>The Austrian team's training sessions were overshadowed by the death of Richard Kroell, a giant slalom and super-G veteran killed in a road accident this month.</p>
<p>Home skiers to watch include 1994 overall giant slalom winner Christian Mayer, Hans Knauss, who won his first World Cup race on the circuit's most demanding giant slalom piste at Alta Badia last season, and Mario Reiter, fit again after a recent operation.</p>
<p>Guenther Mader's participation in Soelden is uncertain and will be decided later on Thursday. Austria's most consistent skier for the past decade and runner-up in the overall World Cup in 1995 and 1996 is suffering from back trouble.</p>
<p>Germany's Martina Ertl, the dominant figure in women's giant slalom competition last winter, misses Saturday's race because of a knee injury.</p>
<p>Instead, German hopes rest with Katja Seizinger, in pursuit of a second consecutive World Cup crystal trophy.</p>
<p>Other women to watch are Italians Deborah Compagnoni, a double Olympic champion, and Isolde Kostner, a super-G world champion in Spain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOELDEN, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
