<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138983" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-AGASSI FACES &quot;ULTIMATE TEST&quot; AGAINST SAMPRAS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-AGASSI FACES &quot;ULTIMATE TEST&quot; AGAINST SAMPRAS.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>STUTTGART, Germany 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andre Agassi's bid to qualify for next month's tennis world championship stepped up a gear on Thursday when he booked a mouth-watering quarter-final showdown with Pete Sampras in the Stuttgart Open.</p>
<p>Agassi, currently ninth in the world, needs to improve his ranking by one place to compete in the prestigious season-ending championship in Hanover.</p>
<p>The former world number one boosted his chances with a comfortable 6-4 6-2 third-round victory over compatriot Richey Reneberg to earn a clash with Sampras who swept aside promising Spaniard Felix Mantilla 6-1 6-4.</p>
<p>In recent months the pair have had television viewers glued to their sets with some intriguing matches played in London's Trafalgar Square and on an American downtown street.</p>
<p>But these were only commercials, whereas Friday's clash will be the real thing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the ultimate challenge in tennis to beat Sampras,&quot; Agassi said. &quot;We are meeting a little earlier than we usually do but I hope it is a great match and we walk off the court feeling good.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampras added: &quot;It is always a bit different when I see him across the net. He is one of the best players on the Tour. When he gets going he is tough to play. He is very dangerous.&quot;</p>
<p>Agassi, at one stage top of the rankings early in the year, has 2,292 points, 111 behind eighth-placed South African Wayne Ferreira.</p>
<p>Sampras is sure of making it to Hanover but is looking to confirm his leading position in the sport by finishing the year at the top of the rankings.</p>
<p>Sampras, 25, and Agassi, 26, have clashed in three major grand slam finals -- the last in 1995 when Sampras won the U.S. Open in four sets.</p>
<p>Their first top-class professional meeting took place in Rome on clay in 1989 when Agassi won easily 6-2 6-1. But just over a year later Sampras beat Agassi in the U.S. Open final to become the youngest men's champion ever at 19.</p>
<p>Agassi defeated three-times Wimbledon champion Sampras to win last year's Australian Open final but his rival leads their head-to-head statistics 10-8.</p>
<p>World number six Boris Becker, another player needing good results to make sure of a place at the world championship, looked in impressive form in the third round with a 6-4 7-5 victory over Swede Thomas Enqvist which took just 80 minutes.</p>
<p>Becker, who is trying to get back to his best after suffering a serious wrist injury at this year's Wimbledon, said it was one of his best performances for months.</p>
<p>&quot;That was my best match since Wimbledon,&quot; the three-times Wimbledon champion said. &quot;It shows I have broken through the problems with the wrist...I surprised myself how well I played.&quot;</p>
<p>In the quarter-finals Becker faces Swede Magnus Gustafsson who beat Australian Mark Woodforde 6-7 6-2 7-6. Dutchman Jan Siemerink faces big-serving Goran Ivanisevic in another quarter-final.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
