<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138965" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP DEVELOPMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</title>
<headline>EP DEVELOPMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - OCT 28-30.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Development and Cooperation [[ Monday 28 October 1996 ]] Coordinators' meeting on Tuesday 29 October, 9 - 9.30 a.m. 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.747 ) ===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 2. Chairman's announcements 3. Meeting with Mr Marin, Vice-President of the Commission (1) 4. Meeting with the Delphi Forum (2) 5. Meeting with the NGO Rugmark (3) 6. Announcements by the Commission 7. Sition in Zambia 10. Aid for uprooted people (refugees, displaced persons and returnees) in Asia n and Latin American developing countries (T03810) **II (T03810) SYN95162 COM(96)0234 C4-0374/96 + DEVE Fond R HOWITT Richard S. (PSE) (PE218.765 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation 11. HIV/AIDS related operations in developing countries (T03804) **II (T03804) SYN95164 COM(95)0293 C4-0372/96 + DEVE Fond ANDRE-LEONARD Anne. (ELD) (PE218.762 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation 12. Environmental measures in developing countries in the context of sustainabl e development (T03808) **II (T03808) SYN95161 COM(95)0294 C4-0373/96 + DEVE Fond TAUBIRA-DELANNON Chr (ARE) (PE218.769 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation 13. Conclusion of the agreement amending the fourth ACP-EC Convention (T04172) (T04172) AVC96023 COM(95)0707 C4-0278/96 + DEVE Fond R WURTZ Francis. (GUE) (PE219.748 ) - Deadline for tabling amendments 14. Strategy in respect of Central America (T04498) (T04498) COS0392 COM(95)0600 C4-0102/96 + DEVE Avis A DURY Raymonde M. (PSE) (PE218.767/REV) F POLI Fond R CARNERO GONZ uLEZ C. (GUE) (PE219.805/B ) - Consideration of draft opinion Consideration of revised draft opinion 15. European Union and the External Dimension of Human Rights Policy: from Rome to Maastricht and beyond (T04255) (T04255) COS0339 COM(95)0567 C4-0568/95 + DEVE Avis A PONS GRAU J. (PSE)</p>
<p>(PE218.070 ) F POLI Fond R ROUBATIS Ioannis. (PSE) - Adoption of draft opinion 16. Conclusion of a partnership agreement with Chile (T04468) (T04468) ACC96149 COM(96)0259 C4-0450/96 + DEVE Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.770 ) F RELA Fond R MIRANDA DE L. (PSE) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 17. Fisheries agreement between the EC and Mauritania (T04905) (T04905) AVC96210 COM(96)0417 + DEVE Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.758 ) F PECH Fond R GIR tO PEREIRA J. (UPE) (PE219.274 ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 18. EC-Angola fisheries agreement for the period from 3 May 1996 to 2 May 1996 (proposal for Council regulation) (T04931) (T04931) CNS96176 COM(96)0323 C4-0475/96 + DEVE Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.755 ) F PECH Fond R CUNHA Arlindo. (ELD) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 19. Special system of assistance to traditional ACP suppliers of bananas (amend. Reg. 2686/94) (T04732) **II (T04732) SYN96028 COM(96)0033 C4-0529/96 + DEVE Fond R CASTAGNEDE Bernard. (ARE) - Exchange of views Exchange of views on the common position 20. Complementarity between the Community's development policy and that of the Member States (T04051) (T04051) COS0258 COM(95)0160 C4-0178/95 + DEVE Fond R McGOWAN Michael. (PSE) (PE219.745 ) - Consideration of draft report 21. Work of the ACP-EU Joint Assembly in 1996 (T05006) (T05006) INI0893 + DEVE Fond BALDI Monica S. (UPE) - Exchange of views 22. Improving the effectiveness of Community aid (T03954) (T03954) INI0356 INI0356 + DEVE Fond R GOERENS Charles. (ELD) - Exchange of views 23. Framework agreement with Cambodia (T03794) (T03794) ATT0696 + DEVE Fond PETTINARI Luciano. (GUE) - Exchange of views 24. Framework agreement with Laos (T03790) (T03790) ATT0692 + DEVE Fond CASTAGNEDE Bernard. (ARE) - Exchange of views 25. Cocoa and chocolate products for human consumption - Proposal for EP and Co uncil Directive (T04894) (T04894) COD96112 COM(95)0722 C4-0303/96 + DEVE Avis A MAIJ-WEGGEN Johanna (PPE) (PE218.763 ) F ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) - Consideration of draft opinion 26. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (T04556) BUD0074 SEC(96)1677 C4-0515/96 + DEVE Avis A GUNTHER Maren. (PPE) (PE218.754/DEF) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE219.043 ) - Current situation - Use of appropriations under B7-661 (anti-personnel mines) 27. International fisheries agreements (T04619) + DEVE Avis A KOUCHNER Bernard. (PSE) F PECH Fond R CRAMPTON Peter D. (PSE) - Exchange of views 28. Transfer of appropriations 34/96 - 34/C/96 - Compulsory expenditure - 34/D/96 - Compulsory and non-compulsory expenditure - 34/E/96 - Non-compulsory expenditure - Committee's view (Responsible: CONT) 29. The legal protection of biotechnological inventions (T04629) (T04629) COD95350 COM(95)0661 C4-0063/96 + DEVE Avis F JURI Fond R ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE218.021 ) - Appointment of draftsman - Exchange of views 30. Amendment of the Financial Regulation applicable to the general budget of t he European Communities (SEM 2000) (T04961) (T04961) CNS96189 COM(96)0351 C4-0497/96 + DEVE Avis F CONT Fond - - Appointment of draftsman 31. Protocol to the Fourth ACP-Lome Convention, following the accession of Aust ria, Finland and Sweden (T04995) (T04995) AVC96225 COM(96)0447 + DEVE Fond - Decision on procedure 32. Promoting RTD cooperation with the world's emerging countries - Commission communication - (T04981) (T04981) COS0456 COM(96)0344 C4-0494/96 + DEVE Avis F ENER Fond R POMPIDOU Alain. (UPE) - Decision on procedure 33. Any other business 34. Date of next meeting (in BRUSSELS) (PE/XIII/OJ/96-12 ) 34.1 *************************************************************** 34.2 N.B. The VOTES will be held on 29 October at 3 p.m. 34.3 ***************************************************************</p>
<p>[FOOTNOTES]1. ) 29 October at 9.30 a.m. 2. ) 30 October at 9 a.m. 3. ) 30 October at 10.30 a.m. - FIN - r END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
