<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139000" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-RAZA YOUNGEST TEST PLAYER AT 14.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-RAZA YOUNGEST TEST PLAYER AT 14.</headline>
<dateline>FAISALABAD, Pakistan 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hasan Raza became the youngest test cricketer on Thursday when he appeared for Pakistan in the second test against Zimbabwe at the age of 14 years and 227 days.</p>
<p>The schoolboy and middle-order batsman from Karachi broke the existing record of current Pakistan team manager Mushtaq Muhammad who made his debut aged 15 years and 124 days against West Indies in Lahore in 1959.</p>
<p>Hasan Raza was in the field as Pakistan reduced Zimbabwe to 88 for five at lunch on the first day.</p>
<p>Pakistan captain Wasim Akram led the attack with three for 38 from nine overs after Zimbabwe had won the toss and batted on a firm and grassy pitch at the Iqbal Stadium.</p>
<p>Akram, who took just one wicket in the drawn first test at Sheikhupura, struck in the seventh over, clean bowling Grant Flower for 15 with the total at 22.</p>
<p>The next wicket went to Waqar Younis, who trapped Craig Wishart leg before for nought with the score at 32.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe's problems troubles deepened when Akram sent David Houghton's leg stump flying with a lethal inswinger after the veteran batsman had added just one run to the total.</p>
<p>Captain Alistair Campbell Pakistan was the next to go, caught behind by Moin Khan for nine off a sharply turning delivery from Saqlain Mushtaq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAISALABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
