<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139004" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FEATURE - CRUMBLING ST PETERSBURG DREAMS OF OLYMPIC GLORY.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - CRUMBLING ST PETERSBURG DREAMS OF OLYMPIC GLORY.</headline>
<byline>Alastair Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>ST PETERSBURG, Russia 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>When International Olympic Committee (IOC) inspectors went to St Petersburg last month to review the Russian city's bid for the 2004 Games they found the former tsarist capital falling to pieces -- literally.</p>
<p>The sprawling canal-etched metropolis on the Baltic may have fallen from centre of a great empire to faded second city of an ex-superpower, but it is one of the world's man-made marvels.</p>
<p>Yet both its classical masterpieces and the postwar high-rise blocks where most of its five million people live are in a state of disrepair that must raise doubts about the wisdom, if not the very feasibility, of staging the Olympics here.</p>
<p>The Russian establishment, from President Boris Yeltsin to the city fathers, is nevertheless pulling out all the stops to win next year's bidding contest among 11 would-be venues.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin flew to Lausanne this month to convince the IOC that holding the Olympics would bestow world recognition on Russia's move to democracy.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, preparing for open heart surgery, asked his friend German Chancellor Helmut Kohl to support the bid for the Games.</p>
<p>Few St Petersburg residents seem to think spending nearly $10 billion -- equal to Russia's latest three-year loan from the International Monetary Fund -- is a waste of cash. Officials say most of the money will be spent whether the Games come or not.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be a good way to attract funds to the city,&quot; lecturer Yevgeny Golovanov suggested hopefully as he protested on the main Nevsky Prospekt against cuts that have left his college without power, sanitation and wages for months.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand there is a mass of problems,&quot; deputy city governor Valery Malyshev told Reuters. &quot;But Russia, including St Petersburg, needs extraordinary measures to develop the city and the country...The Games will attract investment and tourism.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet St Petersburg's world-famous Hermitage and Russian Museum art galleries, the Mariinsky Theatre, home of the Kirov ballet, and a host of other cultural treasures cannot pay their bills. As the bitter Baltic winter approaches, heating has been cut off and the museums and theatres plan a day of action.</p>
<p>The end of the Cold War undermined a local economy dependent on the navy and defence research and on manufacturing. If Russia has any signs of an economic boom, it is 600 km (370 miles) away in Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been sitting in lectures with no heating,&quot; said Oxana, a 21-year-old languages student at St Petersburg State University. &quot;I wish they'd sort that out before talking about the Olympics.&quot;</p>
<p>She is a relative rarity, however.</p>
<p>Anton Getman, director of the Philarmonic concert hall, said he expected the investment to bring dividends. &quot;We see the Olympic Games as a very real help to culture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mikhail Piotrovsky, director of the Hermitage art gallery, also backs the bid: &quot;St Petersburg doesn't need the Olympics for economic reasons. But the Olympics need St Petersburg.&quot;</p>
<p>Echoing a key selling point of the bidding committee, the city's cultural wealth, he noted: &quot;The original Olympics were a religious festival. There should be more of the spiritual side, a move to cultural venues. This city could do that.&quot;</p>
<p>St Petersburg has inherited facilities for virtually every sport from heavily subsidised Soviet days.</p>
<p>But a number of major installations would have to be built from scratch and others would need major repairs.</p>
<p>The city on the Neva lacks a rowing lake, a baseball stadium and a new swimming pool as well as an Olympic village which could then be used for private accommodation.</p>
<p>Alexander Kozlovsky, vice-president of the Russian Olympic Committee, believes the cultural argument, plus commitment from the Kremlin, can fend off the challenges of favourites Rome, Cape Town and Stockholm and seven others -- Istanbul, Athens, Seville, Rio de Janeiro, San Juan, Buenos Aires and Lille.</p>
<p>A short list of four or five will be announced in March and the final choice made next September.</p>
<p>&quot;The commitment of the government is obvious. It's very, very appealing,&quot; he added, saying this year's Games in Atlanta had shown up problems with largely privately organised events.</p>
<p>Recalling Chernomyrdin's remark that winning the Olympics was a &quot;political question&quot; that would confirm Russia had become a &quot;normal, civilised society&quot;, Kozlovsky said the Games would rally the Russian people behind the free market and democracy.</p>
<p>IOC President Juan Antonio Samaranch, who was once Spain's ambassador in Moscow, understood that, Kozlovsky said.</p>
<p>That state involvement, though, is not without its ironies.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a purely Soviet idea,&quot; said protesting lecturer Yevgeny Golovanov. &quot;To decide at the top to hold the Games. And, like in Soviet times, I'm sure everything would be done very well and the city would get the funds it needs.&quot;</p>
<p>Cynical St Petersburg citizens, who took a lead in dumping Soviet ways when they changed the city's name back from Leningrad, say they doubt they have a chance of winning the Games.</p>
<p>But the bid may at least focus wealthy Moscow's attention -- and money -- on the problems of the capital's poor relation.</p>
<p>Local people say that if the IOC chose St Petersburg next September it would force the federal government to honour a commitment to channel more than $7 billion into the city's infrastructure by 2003, its 300th anniversary.</p>
<p>That spending plan, independent of the bid, underpins Russian claims that staging the Olympics would cost very little.</p>
<p>A new airport, motorways around the city, hotels and sports complexes are all planned for the tercentenary, Olympics or no.</p>
<p>The Kirov Stadium, a gigantic earthwork thrown up on the edge of the Gulf of Finland by World War Two German prisoners would be refurbished as the centrepiece of the Games.</p>
<p>The city centre would be unspoiled, though beach volleyball near the Winter Palace might raise eyebrows. Along the beach are grim cells that housed generations of political prisoners.</p>
<p>Kozlovsky dismisses complaints about shortcomings at the Goodwill Games held in St Petersburg in 1994, when the ice rink melted and swimmers refused to race in the dubiously soupy pool.</p>
<p>He argued Russia's economic problems peaked that year. The 2004 Games would be staged in a new-look city rebuilt by a new-look Russian economy, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST PETERSBURG, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
