<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139003" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-YANKS WIN IN 10TH ON BASES-FULL WALK TO EVEN SERIES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKS WIN IN 10TH ON BASES-FULL WALK TO EVEN SERIES.</headline>
<byline>Gary Hill</byline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steve Avery walked in the go-ahead run as the New York Yankees came back from a 6-0 deficit to beat the Atlanta Braves 8-6 in 10 innings and even the World Series at two games apiece on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Jim Leyritz's three-run homer in the eighth inning tied the game at 6-6 and Wade Boggs drew the walk that provided the go-ahead run in a victory that ensured the best-of-seven series will return to New York after Thursday's Game 5 here.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think he's hit a bigger home run in his life,&quot; New York manager Joe Torre said of Leyritz.</p>
<p>&quot;Coming back from six runs down against anybody, let alone the Atlanta Braves, is a huge lift,&quot; said Torre. &quot;We feel pretty good about ourselves right now and we know we're going to New York.&quot;</p>
<p>Both Yankee rallies in the eighth and 10th innings used the &quot;little ball&quot; -- advancing runners one base at a time -- that Torre says they must rely on against the defending champions.</p>
<p>In the 10th, with two outs, Tim Raines walked and Derek Jeter singled. Atlanta manager Bobby Cox then told Avery to intentionally walk Bernie Williams and load the bases -- putting the go-ahead run just 90 feet away from the plate.</p>
<p>Cox defended the move as the &quot;smart thing to do,&quot; asking: &quot;Why not? He's the best hitter they've got.&quot;</p>
<p>Torre then brought on Boggs to pinch-hit for little-used Andy Fox, who had been inserted in the ninth as a pinch-runner. The veteran Boggs, known for his accurate eye, drew the walk from Avery -- after a checked-swing ball 2 on a 1-2 count that drew howls from the crowd.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the biggest walk in my life,&quot; said Boggs.</p>
<p>New York added an insurance run when Ryan Klesko -- just inserted in a double switch when relief pitcher Brad Clontz came on -- could not handle Charlie Hayes's low bloop to first base.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of things went wrong for us tonight,&quot; said Cox. &quot;We'll bounce back.&quot;</p>
<p>Australian Graeme Lloyd got the win, facing two batters and throwing nine pitches to get the ever-dangerous Fred McGriff to hit into a double play in the bottom of the ninth and a strikeout to begin the 10th.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely it's the biggest thing that ever happened in my life,&quot; said Lloyd, who even had an at-bat in a game that saw seven Yankee pitchers and six for Atlanta.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't sure at first that I was going to bat,&quot; said Lloyd. &quot;They were talking about a pinch hitter. To stand out there in the 10th inning of the World Series, it was amazing.&quot;</p>
<p>Lloyd, who as an American Leaguer had never batted in the major leagues before, looked surprisingly adept in grounding out to shortstop.</p>
<p>John Wetteland got the save for the last two outs of the game, which followed a pattern of the Yankee starting pitching not matching up to Atlanta's but New York's relievers outperforming the Braves'.</p>
<p>Atlanta starter Denny Neagle in five innings yielded three runs, two of them earned. New York starter Kenny Rogers gave up five runs in two-plus innings. After McGriff homered in the second to make it 1-0, Rogers seemed to crumble.</p>
<p>&quot;It looked like he just changed,&quot; said Torre, adding that he was concerned for the left-hander's &quot;psyche.&quot;</p>
<p>The Braves immediately used some &quot;small ball&quot; of their own, adding three runs on two walks, a Jeff Blauser bunt on which Yankee second baseman Mariano Duncan failed to cover first, another bunt and Marquis Grissom's double to make it 4-0.</p>
<p>In the third, a Chipper Jones bloop single and a McGriff single knocked Rogers out of the game. Brian Boehringer yielded a Javier Lopez sacrifice fly to make it 5-0.</p>
<p>In the fifth, after two walks, Andruw Jones hit one down the third base line that Hayes at third had bounce off his glove into foul territory, allowing Chipper Jones to score Atlanta's sixth run.</p>
<p>The Yanks began their comeback in the sixth when Atlanta right fielder Jermaine Dye let a Cecil Fielder single get by him, allowing Jeter, who singled, and Williams, who walked, to score. Hayes, who went 3-for-5 with an RBI and a run scored, singled home Fielder to cut the lead to 6-3.</p>
<p>After Darryl Strawberry walked, putting Yankees on first and second with no outs, Cox brought in right-hander Mike Bielecki, who appeared to stem the tide by striking out the next three batters.</p>
<p>But in the eighth, facing Atlanta closer Mark Wohlers, Hayes hit a trickler down the third-base line that just would not roll foul for Chipper Jones. Darryl Strawberry then delivered a single to left and one out later, Leyritz hit a 2-2 slider for his second homer of the Series.</p>
<p>&quot;He hung the slider and fortunately I hit it good enough to get it out,&quot; said Leyritz, who came in after Paul O'Neill pinch-hit for starting catcher Joe Girardi in the sixth.</p>
<p>Leyritz hit a 15th-inning homer in Game 2 of last year's divisional playoffs to give the Yankees a dramatic win in the rain at Yankee Stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;I had the same feeling,&quot; said Leyritz.</p>
<p>The Yankees are now a record 7-0 on the road in this post-season.</p>
<p>At four hours and 17 minutes it was the longest World Series game ever.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
