<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142521" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-LANGER HAS CHANCE OF EXTENDING RECORD.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LANGER HAS CHANCE OF EXTENDING RECORD.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bernhard Langer gave himself the chance of extending one of golf's most illustrious records when he fired a two-under-par 69 in the Volvo Masters second round on Friday.</p>
<p>The German has won at least one full European Tour event every year for 16 seasons -- but not in 1996.</p>
<p>The Volvo Masters represents his last attempt at stretching his run.</p>
<p>Langer captured the title here in 1994 when he also set the nine-under-par course record of 62 but he has not shown the form lately to suggest any achievements of that calibre.</p>
<p>He came into the tournament with sore shoulders and a sore finger, plus the putting problems that have bedevilled him for several months. He is now using a long-handled putter.</p>
<p>His 69 following an opening 73 left him level par and well within striking distance of the pacesetters.</p>
<p>&quot;My shoulders feel much better and I played well today,&quot; he said. &quot;I hit a lot of irons close and with a bit of luck it could have been a good round.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm working hard on it but I wish I could have done two or three better because it was on for me to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm still not making enough putts to be at the top of the leader board.</p>
<p>&quot;But at least I'm giving myself chances and that's fun.&quot;</p>
<p>He said his worst miss was from nine feet at the first hole, &quot;but I'm not making enough in the 10-15 foot range&quot;.</p>
<p>He did sink putts of 15 feet at the 10th and 12 feet at the third and he made a good par-saving putt of 15 feet at the watery 17th.</p>
<p>His second shot with a five-wood was right at the pin but it hit the slope and rolled back into the water.</p>
<p>&quot;That green is tough and not even the third shot if you play safe is easy,&quot; Langer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
