<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142523" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: CRICKET-SOUTH AFRICA PULL OFF FOURTH TITAN CUP VICTORY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-SOUTH AFRICA PULL OFF FOURTH TITAN CUP VICTORY.</headline>
<dateline>FARIDABAD, India 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa seized their fourth consecutive triumph in the Titan Cup triangular limited overs tournament when they beat Australia by two wickets at the Nahar Singh Stadium on Friday.</p>
<p>South Africa, chasing Australia's 215 all out from 47.3 of their 50 overs, won at 218 for eight with 16 balls left.</p>
<p>With four victories in as many outings, South Africa head the standings, followed by India with one victory from three matches. Australia have not won a game.</p>
<p>All of Australia's top-order batsmen reached double figures but only Stuart Law managed to convert his start into a half-century. He was run out for 52.</p>
<p>Fast bowler Allan Donald ripped apart Australia's lower order, claiming four for 31 from 8.3 overs.</p>
<p>South Africa's batsmen stumbled midway in their chase but an unbeaten 71 by Daryll Cullinan carried them to victory.</p>
<p>Cullinan faced 115 balls, struck six boundaries and shared a 65-run fourth-wicket partnership with Jonty Rhodes.</p>
<p>South Africa made a poor start when in-from batsman Gary Kirsten was bowled by Damien Fleming for one.</p>
<p>Andrew Hudson (32) and Pat Symcox (26) indulged in some lusty hitting before Reiffel, who claimed four for 35, had Symcox caught by Michael Bevan at point. Mark Waugh then scored with a direct hit to run out Hudson to bring together Cullinan and Rhodes.</p>
<p>South Africa were coasting towards an easy victory when Reiffel returned to claim the wickets of Rhodes and skipper Hansie Cronje off successive balls.</p>
<p>Cullinan watched another three partners head back to the pavilion but patiently stroked the winning runs with more than two overs to spare.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARIDABAD, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
