<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142531" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: CYCLING-RAIN FORECAST IS CLOUD ON MUSEEUW'S WORLD CUP HORIZON.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-RAIN FORECAST IS CLOUD ON MUSEEUW'S WORLD CUP HORIZON.</headline>
<dateline>UTSUNOMIYA, Japan 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forecasts of possible rain cast a cloud on Friday over Belgian Johann Museeuw's hopes of retaining cycling's World Cup road race title in the torturous Japan Cup on Sunday.</p>
<p>Needing to either finish better than eighth, or see his two nearest rivals fail to win the last race of the circuit, Museeuw can ill afford the dangers of a slippery road.</p>
<p>There is only an outside chance of rain at this stage in the course area, a hilly nature reserve about 100 kms north of Tokyo.</p>
<p>But at this time of the year in northern Japan the weather is unpredictable and squalls can sweep in quickly from the nearby coast.</p>
<p>The 179.5-km race, involving 12 circuits of 14.10 km and a final one of 10.30 km, is less testing than most of the 10 previous races in the 11-contest World Cup.</p>
<p>The greatest challenge -- and danger in wet weather -- is a an abrupt 200 metre high hill just one kilometre after the start of the circuit.</p>
<p>&quot;That hill, particularly in wet weather, could throw even the most experienced cyclist,&quot; said a Japan Cup spokeswoman.</p>
<p>Museeuw, winner of the world road race title in Lugano, Switzerland, two weeks ago on his 31st birthday, has 162 World Cup points.</p>
<p>His Italian rivals for the title, Andrea Ferrigato on 126 points and Michele  Bartoli on 124, need the 50 points from a first place finish to have any chance of beating Musseuw.</p>
<p>Even then, a high place finish by the Belgium would still deny them the title.</p>
<p>Museeuw has won only one World Cup race this year, the prestigious Paris-Roubaix in April, but with 65 race victories since turning professional in 1988, he has the experience to protect his lead.</p>
<p>It will be the first and last time a World Cup race will be held in Japan as the 11th race of the series, traditionally staged in Asia, will be scrapped from next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UTSUNOMIYA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
