<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142519" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-CHAMPION SEIZINGER LOOKS FOR REPEAT.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-CHAMPION SEIZINGER LOOKS FOR REPEAT.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Pontieri</byline>
<dateline>SOELDEN, Austria 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The girl who can happily claim &quot;I've already won everything&quot; begins her bid for an encore in Saturday's opening World Cup race, a giant slalom in Soelden.</p>
<p>Germany's Katja Seizinger assures opponents she is fully motivated in pursuit of a second successive overall title.</p>
<p>Although she specialises in speed disciplines, her giant slalom performances last winter were impressive, with victories at Maribor and Lillehammer.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be difficult to repeat such a good season,&quot; she says. &quot;Everything starts from zero again. But that's what makes ski racing fun.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I am embarking on a second career. I have already won everything, but I can imagine it would be just as nice to win everything a second time,&quot; said Seizinger, 24.</p>
<p>Although she adds that her preparation may have been affected by inappropriate weather conditions at practice venues used by the German team, she points out that all top alpine squads were plagued with similar troubles this summer.</p>
<p>Forecasts for the season's opener promise blue skies. Organisers said the Austrian slope could be prepared perfectly following recent snowstoms at the resort in the Oetz valley.</p>
<p>Seizinger's toughest opponents in Soelden are expected to be Italian two-time Olympic champion Deborah Compagnoni, Sweden's Pernilla Wiberg and Austrian veteran Anita Wachter.</p>
<p>Compagnoni, who like compatriot Alberto Tomba trains apart from the Italian team, is overjoyed about having survived her first summer without major injuries or illnesses.</p>
<p>&quot;I am so happy I could train the whole summer. It makes me feel like one of the young racers. It's so difficult to start in the middle of the season,&quot; said the 26-year-old who missed the first half of last season due to a knee injury.</p>
<p>Swedish team coaches said Wiberg, twice Olympic and three times world champion, left many of the men from the strong Norwegian team trailing during Scandinavian training camps this summer.</p>
<p>Austria's new technical coach Sepp Hanser said Wachter, the 1993 overall World Cup winner, was in great shape.</p>
<p>&quot;She is already a big step ahead of all of her teammates. I don't have a good feeling yet about the others, they need more training.</p>
<p>&quot;But Wachter is simply an exceptional athlete,&quot; Hanser said about Austria's most consistent woman skier of the past decade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOELDEN, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
