<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142511" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PSG CRASH TO FIRST DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PSG CRASH TO FIRST DEFEAT.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rennes striker Stephane Guivarc'h, on loan from champions Auxerre where he could not command a regular place, struck twice to send Paris Saint-Germain crashing 2-1 on Friday, their first league defeat of the season.</p>
<p>Monaco crushed Lille 4-1 away and Auxerre, who travel to Grasshopper Zurich in the European Champions' League next week, thrashed 10-man Lyon 7-0 at home to throw the French first division title race wide open.</p>
<p>Guivarc'h, leading scorer in the French first division, took his tally to 12 with a 73rd-minute penalty and another goal 11 minutes later as Rennes dominated an off-colour PSG who replied through Patrice Loko two minutes from time.</p>
<p>Rennes failed to score earlier only because of brilliant goalkeeper Bernard Lama, back after a six-week absence through injury and who had not previously conceded a goal this season.</p>
<p>&quot;The championship still has a long way to go,&quot; said PSG's assistant manager Joel Bats, whose side have drawn one and lost two of their last three matches, including the 4-2 defeat at Galatasaray in the European Cup Winners' Cup.</p>
<p>&quot;You would have thought there were 15 of them and seven of us. Rennes wanted this victory more than us from the start.&quot;</p>
<p>Monaco, who have scored four goals in each of their last three matches, ended Lille's unbeaten home record as they climbed to just three points behind PSG in second place. </p>
<p>Brazilian Anderson and Nigeria's Victor Ikpeba continued in their scoring vein with a goal apiece after hitting two and four each in the 4-1 home win over Nice and the 4-2 away victory over Borussia Moenchengladbach in the UEFA Cup last week.</p>
<p>Auxerre, whose Algerian midfielder Moussa Saib struck twice in their biggest victory in 17 years in the first division, are third, one point behind Monaco.</p>
<p>Striker Thomas Deniaud, who has scored all three of Auxerre's European Cup goals, hit his first ever first division goal in the fourth minute, but missed the second half with an ankle injury that might keep him out of the Zurich clash.</p>
<p>Lyon defender Florent Laville was sent off in the 45th minute for a second bookable offence with the score 1-0.</p>
<p>Former European champions Marseille slumped to their second successive home defeat, 1-0 to Nantes, and were jeered off by their own fans, some demanding the head of coach Gerard Gili, who steered them back to the top flight last season.</p>
<p>A small group of fans tried to get into the dressing rooms to take their frustrations out on the players but were forced away by police.</p>
<p>Marseille played nervously after defeat at home to Caen and a 0-0 draw away to Nancy, both in the bottom three, in their previous two matches.</p>
<p>The club's acting president Jean-Michel Roussier said: &quot;I saw a team paralysed. We must react. It's clear some things have to change and I'm not ruling out sanctions.&quot;</p>
<p>Roussier said he understood the reaction of the fans, many of whom did not back the team during the match, adhering to a &quot;support strike&quot; called for by leading supporters' groups.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not by chance that (Bulgaria's Yordan) Lechkov and (captain Xavier) Graveliane are the butt of the crowd. Like the rest of the players, it's not their technical qualities that are in question, rather a mental attitude incompatible with the first division,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As Marseille slumped to seventh from bottom, Strasbourg leapt to fourth with a 3-1 win over Nancy.</p>
<p>Jean-Pierre Papin and Argentine striker Claudio Biaggio, with his first goal in France, both scored as Bordeaux won 3-1 at home to Montpellier on Thursday. They are fifth after Bastia lost 1-0 to Lens, their first home defeat of the season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
