<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142528" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-HARFORD QUITS BLACKBURN UNDER MOUNTING PRESSURE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HARFORD QUITS BLACKBURN UNDER MOUNTING PRESSURE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ray Harford surrendered to increasing pressure when he resigned as manager of English premier league club Blackburn Rovers on Friday.</p>
<p>Blackburn, who won the championship in 1995, are bottom of the table without a win this season, and on Tuesday fans demonstrated after they were knocked out of the League Cup by second division strugglers Stockport County.</p>
<p>It has been a difficult, 16-month stint for Harford since he was promoted from coach to succeed Kenny Dalglish, who resigned as manager to become director of football after the championship was secured, leaving the club completely this year.</p>
<p>The 51-year-old Harford, much respected within the game for his coaching qualities but who lacks charisma, declined to be bitter about his exit.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;I have always tried to put the club first and I hope the decision can do some good. The supporters have been brilliant. I have no complaint with the attitude of the players and have had the full support of the board.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a big decision that's taken a lot of thought, but the performance and result against Stockport the other night was the final straw.&quot;</p>
<p>Blackburn chairman Robert Coar said: &quot;We have negotiated a settlement with Ray in view of his five years stout, sterling and loyal service.</p>
<p>&quot;We wish him and his wife Maureen all the best for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Harford, a nomadic player of little signifance whose career included 161 appearances for lowly Lincoln City, had his managerial acumen fully stretched by long-term injuries to defender Graeme Le Saux and midfield player Jason Wilcox.</p>
<p>Blackburn under Harford had been ridiculed when Le Saux and team mate David Batty fought each other on the pitch away to Moscow Spartak during an unsuccessful European Cup Champions' League campaign.</p>
<p>The departure in the close season of England striker Alan Shearer to rivals Newcastle United for a world record 15 million pounds sterling ($23 million) was a heavy blow, both on the pitch and to the club's morale.</p>
<p>Harford joined Blackburn in 1991, having previously managed Wimbledon and Luton, where he won the League Cup in 1988, beating Arsenal in the final.</p>
<p>Backed by the money of multi-millionaire benefactor Jack Walker, a lifelong fan and former steel works owner, he and Dalglish immediately lifted the Lancashire club from the old second division into the inaugural premier league for the 1992-93 season.</p>
<p>Walker's wealth and Dalglish's record as one of soccer's great achievers ensured Blackburn a flow of big name players, including Shearer.</p>
<p>Their enterprise was rewarded with the championship they had last won in 1914. Now the club is threatened by a crash as rapid as was their spectacular rise.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
