<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142532" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-PAKISTAN TIGHTEN GRIP IN SECOND TEST.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PAKISTAN TIGHTEN GRIP IN SECOND TEST.</headline>
<dateline>FAISALABAD, Pakistan 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fast bowlers Wasim Akram and Waqar Younis made early inroads into Zimbabwe's second innings after Pakistan took a 134-run first innings lead in the second and deciding test on Friday.</p>
<p>Akram trapped Grant Flower lbw with his second delivery and Younis claimed Mark Dekker's wicket in a similar fashion with his first ball to leave the touring side nine for two at tea on the second day.</p>
<p>Pakistan were earlier all out for 267 in their first innings in reply to Zimbabwe's 133.</p>
<p>The home side added 32 to their lunch score of 235 for seven before losing their last wicket 40 minutes before tea.</p>
<p>Starting the day at 114 for three, Pakistan lost Saeed Anwar (81), Hasan Raza (27), Wasim Akram (35) and Mohammad Hussain (0) in the morning session.</p>
<p>Anwar, 69 overnight, smashed three more boundaries before he chased a wide delivery from paceman Everton Matambanadzo and edged an easy catch to Andy Flower behind the stumps.</p>
<p>His partner Raza, the youngest player to appear in a test match at the age of 14 years and 227 days, added seven runs to his overnight 20 before he edged a catch to David Houghton at first slip off leg-spinner Paul Strang.</p>
<p>Moin Khan failed to add to his lunchtime score of 58 but Waqar Younis hit 23 with five fours to put his side into a strong position.</p>
<p>Left-arm seamer Bryan Strang finished with three for 53.</p>
<p>At the tea interval David Houghton was on nine and Craig Wishart on nought.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAISALABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
