<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142527" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>spain: GOLF-WOOSNAM CONSULTING SURGEON, CEJKA STRUGGLES.</title>
<headline>GOLF-WOOSNAM CONSULTING SURGEON, CEJKA STRUGGLES.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ian Woosnam said on Friday he would consult his surgeon next week to discuss the type of back operation he will need to guarantee his playing future.</p>
<p>The 38-year-old Briton was speaking after keeping alive his chance of a fifth victory of the year with a battling two-under-par 69 in the second round of the Volvo Masters at Valderrama.</p>
<p>But defending champion Alexander Cejka of Germany all but conceded his hopes despite a two-over 73.</p>
<p>Woosnam, who carded a first round 76, said his back felt better than last week when he was beaten by Colin Montgomerie in the first round of the World Matchplay championship in England.</p>
<p>&quot;Last week it felt like someone had cut it open with a knife,&quot; said the Welshman, who suffers from spondylosis, a degeneration of the discs in his back.</p>
<p>&quot;Two vertebrae are sticking out and if he (the surgeon) decided he could shave them off, I would not be away from the game too long. But if he decided to fuse them together, I would be out longer,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Woosnam still has three events left on his schedule after this season-ending European Tour event.</p>
<p>Next month he plans to play a skins game in Asia, a tournament in Japan and the Million Dollar Challenge in South Africa.</p>
<p>Woosnam, second on the European money list after four victories this year, cannot catch runaway leader Montgomerie but could be caught by fourth-placed Costantino Rocca this week for the runner-up place.</p>
<p>Australian Robert Allenby, who hit his one shot for charity on Thursday despite a fractured sternum, is in third place.</p>
<p>Despite breaking his putter on Thursday, Woosnam used the same club with a new shaft on Friday and putted well with four birdies and a one-under-par back nine of 35.</p>
<p>Cejka, who has struggled with his game while trying to divide his time between the U.S. and European Tours this year, added a 73 to an opening 78.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not feeling like last year and this is a tough golf course when you are struggling,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have not been playing well the last couple of months. Yes, I think the title is gone. But you never know in golf. Maybe I will shoot a 62.&quot;</p>
<p>Tournament leader Stephen Ames of Trinidad was due to start his round later on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
