<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142506" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, OCT 28 - SUNDAY, NOV 3.</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, OCT 28 - SUNDAY, NOV 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - EU foreign ministers meet (Monday-Tuesday); Helms-Burton and d'Amato legislation, signature of a framework agreement with the Republic of Korea, Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa attends 10th Session of the Cooperation Council with Egypt (Monday); structured dialogue with central and eastern European countries (Tuesday).</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - EU agriculture ministers meet (Monday-Tuesday); main discussions focus on the situation on the beef sector.</p>
<p>FINLAND - Palestinian President Yasser Arafat meets Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari; followed by a visit to Dublin (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee holds plenary session (Wednesday-Thursday); European Commission President Santer and European Commissioner Brittan attend (Thursday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (Wednesday); article 85: rules on competition applying to undertakings, European Commissioner Wulf-Mathies holds news conference on structural funds.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU institutions closed for All Saints Day holiday (Friday).</p>
<p>Please note that the European Court of Justice is closed for All Saints holiday from Monday October 28 to Friday November 1.</p>
<p>MONDAY, OCTOBER 28</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - General Affairs Council (and Tuesday).</p>
<p>- (0930/0830 GMT) EU-US relations: Helms-Burton and D'Amato legislation. The action aims at completing the protection of the regulation in so far as effects of the Helms-Burton and D'Amato legislation go beyond trade, investment and related activities. It foresees that each member state shall take the measures it deems necessary to protect the interests of persons affected by the extraterritorial application of these laws.</p>
<p>- The Council will hear an oral communication from European Commissioner Marin about the state of play of the negotiations for a Euro Mediterranean Associations Agreement with Egypt.</p>
<p>- Preparation for the structured dialogue meeting with the associated central and eastern European countries foreign ministers on October 29.</p>
<p>- European monitoring center for racism and xenophobia.</p>
<p>- Situation in the Middle East. The Council will concentrate on the question of the appointment of a special EU-envoy as envisaged by the European Council.</p>
<p>- The Council will examine the problems in former Yugoslavia, and in particular in Bosnia-Hercegovina, and will be informed on the latest developments by the High Representative Carl Bildt: adjournment of the municipal elections, first meeting of the collective Presidency, situation in Mostar, etc. The Council may also consider the situation in eastern Slavonia and EU-Former Yugoslavia relations.</p>
<p>- OSCE: EU objectives for the December 2-3 Lisbon Summit.</p>
<p>- Joint action in support of the transition to democracy in Zaire and the situation in the Great Lakes area. The Belgian delegation proposed a draft joint action containing the following elements: the implementation of an EU assistance programme for the preparation and the monitoring of the elections; the possibility for the Union to cease its support at any moment, should the Zairian authorities fail to respect agreed obligations; the establishment of a European Electoral Support Unit in Kinshasa. On request of the Belgian Minister the Council will discuss the situation in the region of the Great Lakes and more specifically the new outbreak of violence in eastern Kivu/Zaire close to the border of Rwanda and Burundi and the consequences for the refugees in the area.</p>
<p>- (1130/1030 GMT) Signature of a framework agreement with the Republic of Korea. The framework agreement is intended in particular to develop and diversify trade and establish commercial cooperation to the parties' mutual advantage; establish economic cooperation in areas of common interest, including scientific and technological cooperation and industrial cooperation; promote cooperation between undertakings of the two parties by facilitating investment on either side and encouraging better mutual understanding.</p>
<p>- (1230/1130 GMT) 10th Session of the Cooperation Council with Egypt. Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa attends.</p>
<p>- (1600/1500 GMT) Inter-governmental conference (IGC).</p>
<p>- Exchange of views with the EP President Klaus Haensch assisted by MEPs Elmar Brok and Elisabeth Guigou, on the subjects featured on the agenda. This subject is the external action of the Union under three headings: Common Foreign and Security Policy; external economic relations; security and defence.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - Farm Council (1500/1400 GMT) (and Tuesday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Bovine sector:</p>
<p>- Modification of WTO in beef meat;</p>
<p>- Modification of support measures to certain arable crops producers;</p>
<p>- Modification of aid regime for the improvement of agricultural structures.</p>
<p>- Consequences of the beef crises on the producers' revenues.</p>
<p>- Labelling identification:</p>
<p>- Proposal for regulation establishing an identification and registration system for beef;</p>
<p>- Proposal for regulation on beef meat labelling and beef meat based products.</p>
<p>- European veterinary inspection and plant health agency.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(1500/1400 GMT) Budget;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Regional Policy;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Instiutional Affairs;</p>
<p>Petitions.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Brittan meets European Investment Bank (EIB) Chairman Brian Unwin.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Bureau of International Recycling holds bi-annual recycling convention (and Tuesday). Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Isabelle Adam, Bureau of International Recycling (322) 514 2180.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Second European forum for social partners on services of general interest (and Tuesday). Agenda includes: role and missions of services of general interest in achieving the goals of the EU and guaranteeing the fundamental rights of its residents and citizens; role of the actors (public authorities, operators, consumers, employees); subsidiarity, regulation, control, evaluation; globalisation and European strategy towards third countries. Venue: Palais des Congres. Contact: First &amp; Top Travel - L'Universelle Travel Group (322) 647 4935.</p>
<p>BUDAPEST - Association of European Journalists (AEJ) hold XXXIV international congress on &quot;Central and eastern Europe: on the threshold of the EU&quot; (and Tuesday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Opening address by Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn.</p>
<p>- (0945/0845 GMT) Hungarian Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs gives address.</p>
<p>First panel: &quot;Central and Eastern Europe: political problems arising from full membership in the EU&quot;.</p>
<p>Slovak Vice-President Katarina Tothova gives address. - (1500/1300 GMT) Hungarian National Bank President Gyoergy Surani, Portuguese Environment Minister Elisa Maria Ferreira, Hungarian Environment Minister Ferenc Baja give address.</p>
<p>Second panel: &quot;Central and Eastern Europe: economical problems arising from full membership in the EU&quot;.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, OCTOBER 29</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (NEW ITEM) - General Affairs Council (second of two days).</p>
<p>- (0930/0830 GMT) Preparation for the WTO ministerial conference in Singapore: draft Council conclusions, negotiation mandate on the information technology agreement, report on telecommunications negotiations.</p>
<p>- (1130/1030 GMT) Structured dialogue with central and eastern European countries devoted to the evaluation of the progress made in the implementation of the pre-accession strategy; report on the inter-governmental conference (IGC) and current international issues.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Farm Council (second of two days).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0800 GMT) Budget;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs</p>
<p>Regional Policy;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Development - European Commissioner Marin attends;</p>
<p>Institutional Affairs;</p>
<p>Petitions;</p>
<p>(1500/1400 GMT) Foreign Affairs;</p>
<p>Agriculture;</p>
<p>Economic;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Women's Rights.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Business Environment Europe (BEE) holds conference on &quot;Farmers and environmentalists: the land we share&quot; (to Thursday). Speakers include: European Commissioners Fischler and Bjerregaard. Venue: Eurovillage Hotel. Contact: BEE (322) 230 8360.</p>
<p>LOUVAIN-LA-NEUVE, Belgium - Louvain Catholic University Rector Marcel Crochet and European Studies Institute Chairman Michel Dumoulin host meeting on &quot;An emerging international identity: external relations of the EU&quot; (2015/1915 GMT). European Commissioner Brittan gives address. Venue: Socrate Auditorium, 10 place Cardinal Mercier.</p>
<p>FINLAND (NEW ITEM) - Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on official visit; meets Finnish President Martti Ahtisaari. Palestinian President Yasser Arafat will continue his visit to Dublin where he will meet Irish President Mary Robinson, Prime Minister John Bruton and Foreign Minister Dick Spring (and Wednesday).</p>
<p>BUDAPEST - Association of European Journalists (AEJ) hold XXXIV international congress on &quot;Central and eastern Europe: on the threshold of the EU&quot; (second of two days).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Third panel: &quot;Central and eastern Europe: Problems related to foreign policy and common security arising from full membership in the EU&quot;.</p>
<p>Hungarian Defence Minister Gyoergy Keleti, Romanian Defence Minister Gherogh Tinca, Estonian Defence Minister Andrus Oovel give address.</p>
<p>- (1300/1200 GMT) News conference: VIIIth conference of the culture ministers of the Council of Europe.</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) EP President Klaus Haensch gives address.</p>
<p>Fourth Panel: &quot;Central and eastern Europe: minorities and migrations&quot;</p>
<p>- (1630/1530 GMT) Hungarian President Arpad Goencz gives address.</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Philip Morris Institute and the Insitute of European Affairs hold conference on &quot;Europe of the Regions - The future of regional policy&quot; (0915/0915 GMT) (and Wednesday). Main discussions include: the political role of European regions; the new economic challenges; the cultural dimension. Speakers include: Irish Prime Minister John Bruton. Venue: Royal Hospital Kilmainham. Contact: Alwyn Fitzgerald, Project Planning International (353) 1 661 3788.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 30</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (0930/0830 GMT).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Article 85: rules on competition applying to undertakings.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Monti communication on the efficiency of the single market.</p>
<p>- Report on economic and social cohesion.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Wulf-Mathies communication on structural funds - followed by a news conference.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) Foreign Affairs;</p>
<p>Agriculture;</p>
<p>Economic;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Women's Rights;</p>
<p>(1500/1400 GMT) Economic;</p>
<p>Civil Liberties;</p>
<p>Rules of Procedure;</p>
<p>Women's Rights;</p>
<p>Energy;</p>
<p>External Economic Relations.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (1430/1330 GMT) (and Thursday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Settlement finality and collateral security COM(96)193.</p>
<p>- Market implications of legislation and regulations necessary for transition to the single currency.</p>
<p>- Green paper on financial services and consumer expectation COM(96)209.</p>
<p>- Maximum speed of wheeled agricultural or forestry tractors COM(96)196.</p>
<p>- Control of concentrations between undertakings COM(96)313.</p>
<p>- Industral competitiveness for the European chemical industry COM(96)187.</p>
<p>- Integrated programme for SMEs and the craft sector COM(96)329.</p>
<p>- Towards fair and efficient pricing in transport COM(95)691.</p>
<p>- Communication on the new maritime strategy COM(96)81.</p>
<p>- White paper on freeing Europe's airspace COM(96)57.</p>
<p>- Public service obligations in the energy.</p>
<p>- Honey, coffee, chicory, preserved milk and cocoa for human consumption COM(95)722.</p>
<p>- Animal health conditions - aquaculture animals and products of certain fish diseases COM(96)279.</p>
<p>- Relations between EU and Cuba.</p>
<p>- Relations between EU and Canada.</p>
<p>- International trade and environment.</p>
<p>- The global challenge of international trade: a market access strategy for the EU COM(96)53.</p>
<p>- Action for employment in Europe - a confidence pact.</p>
<p>PARIS - Euroforum holds conference on &quot;Gas and electricity '96 - deregulation: what is the impact?&quot; (and Thursday). Venue: Pavillon Royal, Bois de Boulogne. Contact: Alexandra Galeza (33) 1 44 88 14 98.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, OCTOBER 31</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0800 GMT) Economic;</p>
<p>Energy;</p>
<p>External Economic Relations - European Commissioner Marin attends;</p>
<p>Civil Liberties;</p>
<p>Rules of Procedure.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (second of two days). European Commission President Santer and European Commissioner Brittan attend.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - GTE Directories Corporation holds fifth annual conference on &quot;Inside the yellow pages Europe 1996&quot; (0900/0800 GMT). Venue: Sheraton Brussels Airport. Contact: GSE (322) 702 8200.</p>
<p>MARRAKESH, Morocco - Prometheus-Europe holds conference on &quot;Articulate the Euro-Mediterranean partnership and decentralised cooperation&quot; (and Friday). Agenda includes: the Euro-Mediterranean partnership; the functioning of the EMP - circuits of decision-making, financial control and the MEDA regulation; the functioning of Euro-Mediterranean programmes in the context of decentralised cooperation. Contact: Euro-Med (33) 1 43 43 03 07.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 1</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU institutions closed for All Saints Day holiday.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 2</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 3</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
