<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142515" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-CAGLIARI'S PANCARO APOLOGISES FOR SPITTING.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CAGLIARI'S PANCARO APOLOGISES FOR SPITTING.</headline>
<dateline>CAGLIARI, Sardinia 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cagliari defender Giuseppe Pancaro apologised to Inter Milan's Gianluca Pagliuca on Friday for spitting in the former international goalkeeper's face during their Italian Cup tie on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We both insulted each other, I reacted and I want to apologise to Pagliuca for that,&quot; Pancaro told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody saw what I did on television. I was totally out of line,&quot; Pancaro added.</p>
<p>Pancaro was sent off in the 2-2 draw after the altercation in which the 'keeper appeared to butt him.</p>
<p>Seconds earlier Pancaro had pulled a goal back for Cagliari with an 85th-minute penalty.</p>
<p>Dario Silva equalised two minutes from time to complete a remarkable night for veteran coach Carlo Mazzone, in charge of his first game at Cagliari since the sacking of Gregorio Perez.</p>
<p>Mazzone said he had accepted Pancaro's apology but also pointed the finger at Pagliuca.</p>
<p>&quot;Both (Pancaro and Pagliuca) were guilty of poorly representing this sport on television. I hope nothing like this happens again,&quot; the former Roma trainer told reporters. &quot;They are ugly incidents that hurt soccer's image.</p>
<p>Pagliuca said on Friday he had been in the wrong as well.</p>
<p>&quot;My reaction was definitely improper,&quot; he told reporters in Milan. &quot;But nothing like that had ever happened to me. I think I would have preferred a punch in the face.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAGLIARI, Sardinia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
