<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142517" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-CURRY EDGES AHEAD IN VOLVO MASTERS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-CURRY EDGES AHEAD IN VOLVO MASTERS.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>SOTOGRANDE, Spain 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paul Curry nosed ahead of overnight pacesetter Stephen Ames into a one shot second round lead at the Volvo Masters on Friday.</p>
<p>The Briton carded a two-under-par 69 to take over at the top as Trinidadian Ames compiled a level-par 71.</p>
<p>Andrew Oldcorn recorded the best score of the first two rounds with a five-under-par 66 to grab a share of third place with Carl Suneson of Spain.</p>
<p>Mark McNulty of Zimbabwe, round in 69, shared fifth place with Jose Coceres of Argentina and giant Briton Russell Claydon, who both shot 70.</p>
<p>Bernhard Langer, trying to extend his record of winning a full Tour event at least once a season for 16 years, made 69 to stand on level par, along with four others including New Zealanders Frank Nobilo and Greg Turner.</p>
<p>Colin Montgomerie, confirmed as number one in Europe when he struck his first shot in the opening round, trailed nine shots off the lead after adding a 75 to his opening 71.</p>
<p>&quot;I developed a hook, struggled against it and did not putt well either,&quot; said Montgomerie, 1993 winner and third last year.</p>
<p>The course showed its teeth despite a second day of very little wind.</p>
<p>&quot;It was defenceless yet five under is leading and only seven players are under par. That shows what a good course it is,&quot; said Ames of the venue for next year's Ryder Cup.</p>
<p>Curry, whose only European Tour victory was in the 1994 Jersey Open, said he did not think he had ever led halfway through a tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say this course really suits me, but if you manage to keep the ball in play you can score well.</p>
<p>&quot;But the course can jump up and bite you at any time. I'm generally one who never takes golf courses apart, certainly not here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His only bogey after earlier birdies from 15, 12 and five feet came at the long 17th, where he hit his third over the green, chipped and then missed from five feet.</p>
<p>Ames felt things he has been working on to correct his swing faults are bearing fruit after a three-week break.</p>
<p>He was superb from tee to green, &quot;but I just didn't make any putts.&quot;</p>
<p>Except, that is, from 20 feet at the seventh and 35 feet at the 12th for birdies that offset a double bogey five at the short sixth.</p>
<p>&quot;I can see the light at the end of the tunnel with my swing,&quot; he said. &quot;The ball is coming off the club better and penetrating more.&quot;</p>
<p>Oldcorn's best-of-the-week 66 was the only bogey-free round of the day.</p>
<p>The Scot feels he has had three chances to win tournaments this year without converting any of them, particularly the Irish Open where he double-bogeyed the final hole to lose to Montgomerie by a shot.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think I've ever broken par here before today,&quot; said Oldcorn, who shot 74 in the opening round.</p>
<p>&quot;I read just a couple days ago that Alexander Cejka shot 74- 66 in the first two rounds last year and went on to win,&quot; he added. &quot;Maybe I can too. But I'll just be keeping my mind on each hole and not be looking too far ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>Sunesson, a diabetic who eats a lot of bananas during his rounds to keep his blood sugar level up, had six birdies and four bogeys.</p>
<p>Ryder Cup captain Seve Ballesteros, still nursing a cold, soared to 76 for a 150 total but Ian Woosnam, second to Montgomerie on the money list, managed a 69. He was three-over.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOTOGRANDE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
