<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142529" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-FIS INTRODUCES EMERGENCY SAFETY MEASURES.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-FIS INTRODUCES EMERGENCY SAFETY MEASURES.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Pontieri</byline>
<dateline>SOELDEN, Austria 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Ski Federation (FIS) said on Friday it would introduce emergency safety measures in alpine skiing to provide more protection for racers following a spate of accidents.</p>
<p>Plates fitted to skis to enable racers to corner faster had introduced new risks into the sport said FIS, hinting they could have contributed to the tragic death in 1994 of double world champion Ulrike Maier of Austria.</p>
<p>FIS said it would enforce a new rule at the 1996/97 season's opening World Cup races in Soelden this weekend, restricting the size of the metal plates used under bindings -- the connection between ski and ski boot.</p>
<p>Chairman of the FIS Alpine committee Toni Sailer said skiers would be disqualified if the fitting of plates increased the distance between the bottom of the ski and the highest point of the binding to more than 60 mms.</p>
<p>The distance would be restricted further to a maximum of 55 mms for the 1997/98 season, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The height given by these plates combined with the new format of skis -- of being wider at the top and bottom and narrower in the centre -- leads to new risks we didn't know of before,&quot; said FIS president Marc Hodler, adding that a number of universities had begun investigating the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;Suddenly accidents have started occurring on relatively flat parts of the slope where accidents shouldn't happen, for example when a skier is going straight and suddenly loses control of his or her ski.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw this with (German Markus) Wasmeier in Wengen and it could have been the case in a bad women's accident some years ago, although we cannot be certain,&quot; Hodler said in a clear reference to Maier's death.</p>
<p>Maier was killed from neck injuries sustained in a fall during a World Cup downhill at Garmisch-Partenkirchen, Germany, in 1994, when she suddenly lost control of her right ski.</p>
<p>FIS will also begin checking the size of the sole of the ski boot to ensure racers do not compensate the height lost from the plate by building up the sole. However, this rule will only come into force at the November races in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;As the equipment improves, skiers can take curves better and the races get faster and faster,&quot; said Sailer. &quot;Course-setters don't know how to construct a safe course anymore. This is why we need more control.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOELDEN, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
