<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142516" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-MIDDLESBROUGH DUO BARMBY AND FJORTOFT FOR SALE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MIDDLESBROUGH DUO BARMBY AND FJORTOFT FOR SALE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Middlesbrough manager Bryan Robson confirmed on Friday he is ready to sell England striker Nick Barmby -- just 14 months after signing him for 5.25 million pounds ($8.38 million).</p>
<p>Speculation is mounting that Barmby, who joined Middlesbrough from Tottenham, could join Leeds in a swap deal that would take Lee Sharpe to Middlesbrough where he would link up with Robson, a former Manchester United team mate.</p>
<p>Sharpe only joined Leeds in the close-season for 4.5 million pounds ($7 million).</p>
<p>Robson said he had decided the balance of his team was not right with Barmby and Brazilian international Juninho having similar roles.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I could play the two behind the striker but it has not worked out. We have been overpowered too many times in too many games,&quot; said Robson.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Barmby has a big future in the game. He is a top player and a good professional. I have looked at the situation and a Barmby move is best for both parties.</p>
<p>&quot;Barmby has been linked with a number of clubs but so far I have received no offers. If I get a good offer that will further his career I will look at the situation,&quot; said Robson.</p>
<p>Barmby was the club's leading scorer last season but has only scored once this season.</p>
<p>Robson is also prepared to listen to offers for Norwegian international Jan-Aage Fjortoft, who has not played in the premier league this season.</p>
<p>Fjortoft said: &quot;This has been a frustrating season for me, especially as I have lost my international place.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot complain about that because I have not been playing first-team football. I must get back on the big stage before I can play for my country again.&quot;</p>
<p>Robson said that first division Portsmouth had made several inquiries for Fjortoft without putting in an offer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
