<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142524" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CYCLING-TOUR DE FRANCE RETURNS TO FAMILIAR TERRITORY.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-TOUR DE FRANCE RETURNS TO FAMILIAR TERRITORY.</headline>
<byline>Francois Thomazeau</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1997 Tour de France, starting in Rouen in honour of the late five-times winner Jacques Anquetil, returns to its roots with an almost entirely French itinerary announced on Friday.</p>
<p>Rouen, birthplace of Anquetil, will mark the 10th anniversary of the great Frenchman's death and 40th anniversary of his first Tour triumph in 1957 with the prologue on July 5.</p>
<p>The 1997 Tour will then head down the western side of France, including Brittany which missed out this year, embarking on an anti-clockwise reverse swing to the 1996 race won by Bjarne Rijs.</p>
<p>The Dane said on Friday he liked the look of the new course.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not say this course has been designed for me, but I like it very much,&quot; he said. &quot;I will start the race to win it again even though there's a long way to go.&quot;</p>
<p>There are just two individual time trials apart from the prologue, the first over 55 kms at St Etienne -- the 12th stage on July 18 after the only rest day and before the tough climb to Alpe d'Huez.</p>
<p>There is a second on the penultimate stage, like this year, over 62 kms at Disneyland before the traditional run-in to the Champs Elysees in Paris on July 27.</p>
<p>Five of the opening seven stages are longer than 200 kms as the Tour makes for Bordeaux and the traditional crossing of the Landes before hitting the Pyrenees ahead of the Alps.</p>
<p>The itinerary does not appear to favour time trial specialist Miguel Indurain of Spain, who is rumoured to be seeking a change of team in a bid for a record sixth tour victory that escaped him this year.</p>
<p>For the first time in years, the Spaniard did not attend the Tour presentation.</p>
<p>He would no doubt have preferred the dreaded Alps before his favoured Pyrenees where the ninth stage on July 14 includes the mountain passes of Soulor, Tourmalet, Aspin and Val-Louron.</p>
<p>The next day the riders hit the highest point in the Tour at Envalira -- 2,407 metres -- and then head for Andorra-Arcalis, first of three uphill finishes.</p>
<p>The others are at Alpe d'Huez -- left out of the 1996 race -- in the 13th stage and the new climb to Courchevel (14th).</p>
<p>The 16th stage takes the riders into the Swiss town of Fribourg with the return into France through the Alsace and the 19th stage which ends at Dijon, another traditional tour stop.</p>
<p>In all, 27 mountain passes will be on the Tour's menu compared to 21 last summer, which suits 1995 and 1996 king of the mountain Richard Virenque.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a Tour that suits me better than the last,&quot; said the Frenchman, who finished third in July.</p>
<p>&quot;What I like above all is that all the mountain stages plus one of the time trials will be concentrated within seven days. It'll make it even harder,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
