<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142522" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-HOUGHTON AND CAMPBELL LEAD ZIMBABWE FIGHTBACK.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-HOUGHTON AND CAMPBELL LEAD ZIMBABWE FIGHTBACK.</headline>
<dateline>FAISALABAD, Pakistan 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Houghton and Alistair Campbell, past and present captains respectively, led a Zimbabwe fightback with a century stand in the second and final test against Pakistan on Friday.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe, 134 behind on first innings, were reeling at 23 for three in their second innings when Houghton and Campbell joined forces.</p>
<p>By the close of the second day, Houghton had stroked 74 not out and Campbell was unbeaten on 51, their unbroken third wicket partnership of 113 having lifted Zimbabwe to 136 for three.</p>
<p>Fast bowlers Wasim Akram and Waqar Younis rocked the start of the touring side's second innings, each taking a wicket in their first over.</p>
<p>Akram had Flower lbw and Waqar had Mark Dekker leg before, both failing to score.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe plunged into further trouble when Waqar had Craig Wishart (7) caught by Salim Malik in the slips with the total 23.</p>
<p>The innings was given impetus by 39-year-old Houghton, the oldest player among the two sides. He has so far struck nine fours and a six from 110 balls in his second successive half century of the series, while Campbell has six fours in his 83-ball knock for his eighth 50 in 20th test.</p>
<p>Pakistan, starting the day at 114 for three in reply to Zimbabwe's first innings of 133, and were all out 40 minutes before tea for 267.</p>
<p>Saeed Anwar, overnight 69, slammed three blistering fours, before chasing a wide delivery from paceman Everton Matambanadzo to Andy Flower behind the stumps.</p>
<p>Anwar's attractive 81 contained 16 fours and he faced 97 balls and was at the wicket for 138 minutes.</p>
<p>His colleague Hasan Raza, the youngest test player in the game's history at 14 years and 227 days, went next at 141, falling to left-arm seamer Bryan Strang after adding seven to his overnight 20.</p>
<p>Akram and Moin Khan put on 53 for the sixth wicket before the Pakistan captain was bowled by Mbangwn for a fluent 35 off 47 balls. Moin went on to make 58.</p>
<p>The first test was drawn.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAISALABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
