<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145534" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: HORSE RACING-STORM SONG CHARGES TO VICTORY AT BREEDERS' CUP.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-STORM SONG CHARGES TO VICTORY AT BREEDERS' CUP.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Storm Song came from mid-pack at the quarter pole to chase down and roar past Love That Jazz and win the 1-1/16-mile Juvenile Fillies, the opening race of the Breeders' Cup on Saturday.</p>
<p>Storm Song, an 8-5 favourite in the race for two year olds, had plenty of run left at the finish line, winning by four lengths going away.</p>
<p>Critical Factor was third and Minister's Melody was fourth.</p>
<p>Storm Song, bought for $100,000 earlier this year, won $520,000. Second place was worth $200,000 and third $120,000.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a terrific filly. She put her last two races behind her and got it all together,&quot; said winning jockey Craig Perret, referring to Storm Song losing her last two races. &quot;She's the queen.&quot;</p>
<p>Love That Jazz broke quickly to take the lead going into the first turn and opened up a two-length lead by the 1/4 mile pole and lengthened that margin to three lengths at half a mile. Love That Jazz was attempting to become the first to win the Breeders' Cup juvenile filly wire to wire.</p>
<p>But Storm Song, fifth at the 3/4 pole, made her move at the top of the stretch and breezed past Love That Jazz for her fourth win in seven outings this year.</p>
<p>It was the first Breeders' Cup victory for veteran trainer Nick Zito.</p>
<p>Critical Factor's trainer Myung Kwon Cho said of his horse: &quot;She almost fell down at the gate. I never though we'd have any problem there because she has enough speed. But we're very proud of the way she finished.&quot;</p>
<p>Celebrated trainer D. Wayne Lukas, had three horses in the race but was shut out.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
