<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145533" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: HORSE RACING-NAKATANI GIVES HIS MURDERED SISTER CREDIT FOR WIN.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-NAKATANI GIVES HIS MURDERED SISTER CREDIT FOR WIN.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jockey Corey Nakatani rode with guts and a sure touch in winning two Breeders' Cup races on Saturday, but he said he was really guided by &quot;an angel on my shoulder&quot; -- his murdered sister.</p>
<p>Nakatani, who had been 0-12 in Breeders' Cup races, won the Sprint aboard Lit de Justice and the Distaff with Jewel Princess.</p>
<p>&quot;I was thinking about my sister,&quot; said an obviously happy but somewhat subdued Nakatani. &quot;All of this was for Dawn. She does a lot of things for me. I just hope she is in a better place and that she is in peace now.&quot;</p>
<p>Nakatani's 21-year-old sister Dawn was found October 1 near death in her apartment, apparently after being strangled. She died later that day in the hospital.</p>
<p>In the Sprint, Nakatani was 13th at the 1/4 pole and moved up to 10th at the half-mile mark as Lord Carson set the pace with early speed.</p>
<p>By the top of the stretch, Nakatani had Lit De Justice fourth as a tiring Lord Carson tried to hang on to the lead.</p>
<p>As Lord Carson faded, Nakatani had Lit De Justice skimming along the rail like a gray ghost.</p>
<p>Then he veered to his right, splitting Paying Dues and Honour and Glory for the victory, tying the 23-year-old record at Woodbine racetrack for 6 furlongs with a time of 1:08 and 3/5 seconds.</p>
<p>In the 1-1/8-mile Distaff, Nakatani had Jewel Princess comfortably within stirking distance throughout the race.</p>
<p>Serena's Song was stalking Top Secret, the leader from the 1/4 mile pole to the stretch. That's when Serena's Song made her move to take the lead as they made the final turn.</p>
<p>But Jewel Princess kept coming on and sneaked by on the inside to win, giving Nakatani his second consecutive victory.</p>
<p>Different was third.</p>
<p>In the Juvenile Fillies race, the first event of the $11 million, seven-race extravaganza, Storm Song came from mid-pack at the quarter pole to chase down and roar past Love That Jazz to win the 1-1/16-mile race.</p>
<p>Storm Song, an 8-5 favourite in the race for two year olds, had plenty of run left at the finish line, winning by four lengths going away.</p>
<p>Critical Factor was third and Minister's Melody was fourth.</p>
<p>Storm Song, bought for $100,000 dollars earlier this year, won $520,000. Second place was worth $200,000 and third $120,000.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a terrific filly. She put her last two races behind her and got it all together,&quot; said winning jockey Craig Perret, referring to Storm Song's recent losses. &quot;She's the queen.&quot;</p>
<p>Love That Jazz broke quickly to take the lead going into the first turn and opened up a two-lenth lead by the 1/4-mile pole. That margin became three lengths at half mile as Love That Jazz attempted to become the first to win the juvenile filly wire to wire.</p>
<p>But Storm Song, fifth at the 3/4 pole, made her move at the top of the stretch and breezed past Love That Jazz, giving veteran trainer Nick Zito his first Breeders' Cup victory.</p>
<p>Boston Harbour led wire-to-wire to win the Juvenile by a neck ahead of a rapidly-closing Acceptable. Ordway, the favourite, was third.</p>
<p>It seemed Boston Harbour would easily win, until Acceptable made a tremendous run down the stretch but ran out of track.</p>
<p>The 1-1/2-mile Turf was all-Ireland. Pilsudski came on with a great stretch run to beat Singspiel with Swain finishing third.</p>
<p>Pilsudski's jockey Walter Swinburn, who won his first Breeders' Cup race in 14 attempts, was wiping tears from his face while jogging Pilsudski to the winner's circle.</p>
<p>&quot;I just kicked his butt home,&quot; Swinburn said.</p>
<p>In the Mile, Da Hoss began moving up patiently at the 1/4, was third at the stretch and chased down Kiridashi to win by 1-1/2 lengths. Spinning World was second and Same Old Wish third.</p>
<p>Kiridashi, who had led the race for 3/4 of a mile finished fourth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
