<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145531" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: HORSE RACING-CIGAR LOSES BREEDERS' CUP CLASSIC IN VALIANT BID.</title>
<headline>HORSE RACING-CIGAR LOSES BREEDERS' CUP CLASSIC IN VALIANT BID.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The great Cigar, struggling mightly, could not make up enough ground from the outside and finished third behind upset winner Alphabet Soup in the $4 million Breeders' Cup Classic on Saturday.</p>
<p>Preakness Stakes winner Louis Quatorze finished second.</p>
<p>Cigar had won 17 of his last 19 races, including a storied 16 consecutive victories that tied the legendary Citation before losing last August.</p>
<p>But Saturday the six-year-old Cigar, who won the Classic last year, showed why this was in all liklihood his last race.</p>
<p>Cigar left from the seventh postion and after finding no room to break through the pack on the inside, he was forced to go wide.</p>
<p>While he ran his heart out down the stretch, closing the gap on the leaders, Cigar was unable to find that final kick that had made him a horse racing legend around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;The first turn was fine and going into the backstretch was fine, but we had nowhere to go inside from there,&quot; said Cigar's jockey, Jerry Bailey, who had won four of the previous five Classics.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a long year -- two years actually -- going to Dubai and all the races,&quot; said Bailey, referring to Cigar's victory in the Middle East last June over 1-1/8 miles after a grueling trip.</p>
<p>&quot;Cigar is still a champion to do what he's done this year. He never quit. He never gave up; he just never quit. It's great he is still around.&quot;</p>
<p>Alphabet Soup did not quit either, fending off a strong challenge down the stretch.</p>
<p>He gave away some steps in what turned into a three-horse finish and seemed to be on the verge of faltering. But he put on a final burst to beat Louis Quatroze by just a nose. Cigar finished a 1/2 length back.</p>
<p>&quot;This horse has a heart as big as all outdoors,&quot; said Alphabet Soup jockey Chris McCarron. &quot;What a thrill, it was a great trip.&quot;</p>
<p>Three-year-old Yanks Music, who was aiming to become the first filly to win the Classic, was scratched minutes before the race with an inflamed leg.</p>
<p>The first Japanese horse to run in the Breeders' Cup, five-year-old Taiki Blizzard, finished last of 13 horses.</p>
<p>First prize for the Classic was $2,080,000, second $800,000, third $480,000, fourth $224,000 and fifth $80,000.</p>
<p>The Breeders' Cup series, which was staged outside the United States for the first time, served up another dramatic storyline Saturday with two victories by Corey Nakatani, who posted his first Breeders' Cup victory in the Sprint aboard Lit De Justice and then won the Distaff with Jewell Princess.</p>
<p>Nakatani, whose parents were interned in a California concentration camp at, of all places Santa Anita racetrack, during World War II, dedicated his victories to his murdered sister.</p>
<p>&quot;I was thinking about my sister,&quot; said an obviously happy but somewhat subdued Nakatani. &quot;All of this was for Dawn. She does a lot of things for me. I just hope she is in a better place and that she is in peace now.</p>
<p>&quot;She was an angel on my shoulder,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nakatani's 21-year-old sister Dawn was found October 1 near death in her apartment, apparently after being strangled, and died later that day in the hospital.</p>
<p>In the Sprint, Nakatani was 13th at the 1/4 pole, but moved up to skim the rail. Down the stretch he split Paying Dues and Honour and Glory to take the lead. Paying Dues was second and Honour and Glory finished third.</p>
<p>In the 1-1/8-mile Distaff, Nakatani had Jewel Princess comfortably within stirking distance throughout the race. He sneaked his horse by on the inside past Serena's Song, who finished second. Different was third.</p>
<p>In the Juvenile Fillies, the first event of the $11 million, seven-race extravaganza, Storm Song came from mid-pack at the quarter pole to chase down and roar past Love That Jazz for victory in the 1-1/16-mile race.</p>
<p>Critical Factor was third and Minister's Melody was fourth.</p>
<p>Storm Song, bought for $100,000 earlier this year, won $520,000. Second place was worth $200,000 and third $120,000.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a terrific filly. She put her last two races behind her and got it all together,&quot; said winning jockey Craig Perret of his mount's recent losses. &quot;She's the queen.&quot;</p>
<p>Boston Harbour led wire-to-wire to win the Juvenile by a neck over rapidly-closing Acceptable. Ordway, the favourite, was third.</p>
<p>The 1-1/2-mile Turf was all-Ireland. Pilsudski came on with a great stretch run to nip to Singspiel with Swain finishing third.</p>
<p>Pilsudski's jockey Walter Swinburn, who won his first Breeders' Cup race in 14 attempts, was wiping tears from his face while jogging Pilsudski to the winner's circle.</p>
<p>&quot;I just kicked his butt home,&quot; Swinburn said.</p>
<p>In the Mile, Da Hoss moved up patiently from the 1/4 pole, took third at the stretch and chased down Kiridashi to win by 1/12 lengths.</p>
<p>Spinning World was second and Same Old Wish third. Kiridashi, who had led the race for 3/4 of a mile, finished fourth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
