<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145532" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-DELVECCHIO DELIVERS &quot;MIRACLE GOAL&quot; FOR ROMA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DELVECCHIO DELIVERS &quot;MIRACLE GOAL&quot; FOR ROMA.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Second half substitute Marco Delvecchio grabbed an equaliser deep in injury time on Saturday as Roma drew 1-1 with Italian league leaders Juventus in a memorable serie A match at the Olympic Stadium.</p>
<p>The draw was the second in a week for European champions Juventus -- they were held by third division Nocerina in the Italian Cup on Wednesday -- and left them open to being overtaken when the other clubs play on Sunday.</p>
<p>Juventus have 14 points from seven games, with champions Milan behind on 12 and Inter and Roma both on 11.</p>
<p>The almost 70,000 strong crowd exploded in delight as Delvecchio, who came on in the 62nd minute, scored after about three minutes of stoppage time being added on.</p>
<p>Tireless Argentine attacker Abel Balbo hit the crucial through ball for Delvecchio to knock in right-footed and maintain Roma's record of being unbeaten by Juventus in the league at the Olympic Stadium since 1990-91.</p>
<p>&quot;We made the huge mistake of taking the win for granted,&quot; said angry Juventus coach Marcello Lippi, whose team play Rapid Vienna in a home Champions' League match next Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what was going through the minds of some of them in that 93rd or 94th minute. We dominated the match and it makes me mad that we assumed we had won and paid the price.&quot;</p>
<p>Juventus had taken the lead through Michele Padovano in the 59th minute and seemed to have the win all sewn up after outplaying Roma in almost every area of the game.</p>
<p>Croat striker Alen Boksic, who played home matches at the stadium for three years with Roma's city rivals Lazio, set up the goal with a cross from the edge of the area.</p>
<p>Padovano was ironically the only Juventus player on the field to have previously scored against Roma while playing for the Turin club -- he hit the 71st minute equaliser in last season's 2-2 draw -- and he kept the record intact.</p>
<p>The player, with the rest of the Juventus team making his first appearance at the stadium since winning the European Cup there in May, gave young goalkeeper Giorgio Sterchele absolutely no chance with a strong, straight shot.  </p>
<p>Juventus could have gone ahead as early as the eighth minute when Yugoslav midfielder Vladimir Jugovic had a header tipped just over the bar by Roma's Giorgio Sterchele.</p>
<p>Roma, humiliated by lowly Verona last weekend and beaten 3-0 by Karlsruhe in a UEFA Cup first leg match earlier in the month, desperately needed a positive result to ease the pressure on Argentine coach Carlos Bianchi.</p>
<p>Bianchi said later that the draw was something of a miracle and praised his team for never giving up.</p>
<p>But he reserved most of the accolades for his opponents, saying that they had been in a different class.</p>
<p>Balbo said that Juventus were the best team Roma, who beat Milan 3-0, had come across this season. &quot;If they play like this all the time they will win the title easily,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Roma's best chance came in the final minute of the first half when Juventus goalkeeper and captain Angelo Peruzzi, who used to play for Roma, fumbled a shot by Balbo and dived desperately to recover the ball on the goal line.</p>
<p>Otherwise Roma offered few touches of class, looking disjointed and often vainly chasing high balls while Juventus commanded the midfield and made the running.</p>
<p>The clash was brought forward one day to give Roma time to prepare for their second round, second leg UEFA match against Germany's Karlsruhe in Rome on Tuesday.</p>
<p>That match could end Roma's European ambitions this season but Bianchi promised to go down fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to take the game to them,&quot; he promised.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Roma - 12-Giorgio Sterchele; 3-Marco Lanna, 4-Enrico Annoni (7-Francesco Moriero, 71), 6-Aldair (captain), 8-Francesco Statuto (24-Marco Delvecchio, 62), 9-Abel Balbo, 13-Fabio Petruzzi, 15-Luigi Di Biagio, 17-Francesco Totti, 18-Damiano Tommasi, 19-Massimiliano Cappioli</p>
<p>Juventus - 1-Angelo Peruzzi (captain), 2-Ciro Ferrara, 3-Moreno Torricelli, 4-Paolo Montero, 22-Gianluca Pessotto (13-Mark Juliano, 71), 18-Vladimir Jugovic, 7-Angelo Di Livio, 14- Didier Deschamps, 9-Alen Boksic, 21-Zinedine Zidane, 11-Michele Padovano (10-Alessandro del Piero, 70).</p>
<p>Referee: Livio Bazzoli</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
