<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145896" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: ALPINE SKIING-LOCHER AND SEIZINGER OPEN WITH A FLOURISH.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-LOCHER AND SEIZINGER OPEN WITH A FLOURISH.</headline>
<byline>Adriana Pontieri</byline>
<dateline>SOELDEN, Austria 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steve Locher and Katja Seizinger made flying starts to the World Cup ski season at the weekend.</p>
<p>Locher continued the Swiss domination of giant slalom by clocking the fastest times in both runs for a combined two minutes 3.20 seconds to edge out compatriot and defending champion Michael von Gruenigen.</p>
<p>Von Gruenigen, who won five of last winter's nine giant slaloms, recorded 2:03.51 and was trailed by 1994 overall World Cup champion Kjetil Andre Aamodt of Norway.</p>
<p>Seizinger's giant slalom victory on Saturday ahead of Italy's Olympic and world champion Deborah Compagnoni was a great beginning to her defence of the overall World Cup title.</p>
<p>Men's overall title holder Lasse Kjus of Norway had a disappointing start when he crashed out of the second run after having posted a superb third quickest time in the first descent.</p>
<p>Germany's Seizinger kept her usual cool to deliver a near-perfect second run for a combined 2:11.81 on a demanding and slippery Rettenbach piste, which was shrouded by thick fog.</p>
<p>But Sunday's men's race on the Austrian glacier above 3,000 metres altitude was blessed with clear, blue skies and perfect hard slope conditions.</p>
<p>Locher, a 29-year-old veteran, is better-known in his home country as the man who claimed Switzerland's only medal at the 1992 Olympics when he clinched a combined gold.</p>
<p>&quot;I struggled so hard over the past two years to get back to the top of the field. Last year I could not place better than fourth so this victory comes as a huge surprise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The victory was Locher's third World Cup win and second in giant slalom. His previous win in the discipline dates back to 1993 when he sensationally defeated Alberto Tomba at Alta Badia in Italy.</p>
<p>Seizinger was surprised she was able to defeat Compagnoni.</p>
<p>&quot;I wasn't expecting this victory. Beating Compagnoni in her best discipline is an achievement. It makes me feel mentally stronger than ever and gives me a lot of confidence,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I went into this race without any pressure. I have already won the overall World Cup and I don't really need to prove myself by defending it.&quot; She now has 25 World Cup victories, four in giant slalom.</p>
<p>Both Locher and Seizinger said their goal for the season was to gain a medal at the world championships in Sestriere, Italy in February. Locher has never managed a podium finish at previous championships but Seizinger took super-g gold in 1993.</p>
<p>The World Cup season now takes a one month break and resumes with slalom and giant slalom races for men and women in Park City, Utah from November 21 to 24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOELDEN, Austria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
