<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145895" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-BECKER SURPRISES HIMSELF WITH WIN OVER SAMPRAS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-BECKER SURPRISES HIMSELF WITH WIN OVER SAMPRAS.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>STUTTGART, Germany 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>No-one was more surprised than Boris Becker by his victory over world number one Pete Sampras in the Stuttgart Open final on Sunday.</p>
<p>He delighted his fanatical home fans by coming from behind to end Sampras's 21-match unbeaten run with a 3-6 6-3 3-6 6-3 6-4 victory.</p>
<p>Becker, whose Wimbledon campaign this year was destroyed by a wrist injury, said: &quot;I am surprising myself every day. Three months ago I was in plaster and now I am beating the top players in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't ask me how I've done it.</p>
<p>&quot;This is like a dream. I hope I don't wake up tomorrow...This is one of my best victories ever. It is one of the highlights of my career. This kind of thing doesn't happen every week and it is even greater because of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Sampras was looking for his fourth consecutive tournament victory after winning the U.S. Open last month but was thwarted by a resurgent Becker who had played some superb tennis on his way to the final.</p>
<p>&quot;It is always tough to play Boris in Germany,&quot; said Sampras. &quot;I played well enough to win. He just got the important points today.&quot;</p>
<p>Becker is now almost certain to qualify for next month's season-ending world championship on his home turf in Hanover where he is the defending champion.</p>
<p>Sunday's contest was not all serve-and-volley despite the swift surface. Both were also prepared to play longer, tactical rallies from the baseline.</p>
<p>The 7,000 crowd roared every point Becker won. He played with their nerves before serving them up a victory.</p>
<p>Becker made a perfect start, breaking Sampras's serve in the opening game when the American volleyed into the net.</p>
<p>But Sampras bounced back with a break in the sixth game and effectively clinched the set with another break in the eighth game when Becker struck a forehand into the net to give the American a 5-3 lead.</p>
<p>Becker started the second set confidently again, taking a 3-0 lead after an early break. This time, despite pressure from Sampras, he managed to hold on to his serve and clinch the set 6-3 with an ace.</p>
<p>Sampras, who beat Andre Agassi on his way to the final, had the better touch and rhythm in the third which he also clinched with an ace.</p>
<p>But Becker is never more dangerous than when under pressure. He forced the match into a deciding set when he broke Sampras's serve to lead 5-3 in the fourth when his opponent netted a volley and then served out the next game.</p>
<p>Becker then had the psychological edge.</p>
<p>At times he dived across the court as acrobatically as he did in his younger days. Becker made the most important break of the match in the third game of the final set and held serve, eventually clinching the match with an ace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STUTTGART, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
