<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145897" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ZAMORANO STRIKES TWICE AS INTER GO JOINT TOP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ZAMORANO STRIKES TWICE AS INTER GO JOINT TOP.</headline>
<byline>Chris Endean</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's Ivan Zamorano struck twice as Internazionale fought back from conceding a goal in the opening minute to beat Parma 3-1 at the San Siro on Sunday and join Juventus at the top of serie A.</p>
<p>Argentine Hernan Crespo shocked Inter fans with a superb volleyed goal on his league debut for Parma.</p>
<p>But Zamorano took just three minutes to level the scores with a powerful header while Argentine Javier Zanetti's 20-metre shot ensured Inter reached the interval a goal up.</p>
<p>Former Real Madrid striker Zamorano added a third in the 54th minute to leave Juventus regretting Roma's injury-time equaliser in their 1-1 draw at the Olympic stadium on Saturday.</p>
<p>Inter are now tied with Juve on 14 points after seven matches, one ahead of unfancied Vicenza, 2-0 winners over Cagliari, playing their first match under manager Carlo Mazzone.</p>
<p>Reigning champions Milan dropped to fourth after stumbling to their third league defeat of the season -- going down to an 83rd minute goal by Anselmo Robbiati at Fiorentina.</p>
<p>Victory for Inter takes the pressure off English coach Roy Hodgson, severely criticised after his expensively assembled side were outclassed by Juventus last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We were 2-0 down after a minute,&quot; joked Hodgson after Sunday's match. &quot;First the media criticism, then Crespo's goal.&quot;</p>
<p>But relief for Hodgson has only added to the pressure on Parma's manager Carlo Ancelotti.</p>
<p>The former Milan midfielder, who took over at the club in the summer, was banished from the bench in the 55th minute for protesting. After three successive defeats that have caused Parma to plunge to 11th in the table, his job is now at risk.</p>
<p>In a rare show of soccer solidarity, Hodgson embraced his counterpart after he was shown the red card.</p>
<p>Vicenza's climb to second place in the table owes much to the markmanship of Uruguayan Marcelo Otero and on Sunday he broke the deadlock with his sixth goal of the season.</p>
<p>With Cagliari still struggling despite the arrival of Mazzone, Roberto Murgita added a second in the 62nd minute.</p>
<p>Fiorentina are fast becoming Oscar Tabarez's bogey team.</p>
<p>Since taking over from Fabio Capello, the Uruguayan has met the Florentine side twice -- and lost both times.</p>
<p>His official debut on the Milan bench was ruined when Fiorentina carried off the Italian Supercup at the San Siro before the start of the league season.</p>
<p>In Sunday's vital warm-up for next week's crucial European Cup match with Gothenburg, Milan had midfielder Stefano Eranio sent off for a crude foul on Massimo Orlando.</p>
<p>Then, with 10-man Milan three minutes away from a hard-earned point, Robbiati claimed a late winner for Fiorentina.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
