<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149297" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oil prices lead commodity indexes lower.</title>
<headline>Oil prices lead commodity indexes lower.</headline>
<byline>Harry Milling</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices fell Tuesday as traders bet that low inventories of heating oil were finally starting to rise ahead of winter. Coffee and silver prices also fell.</p>
<p>The Knight Ridder Commodity Research Bureau index of 17 futures prices ended 2.22 points lower at 241.11.</p>
<p>Heating oil prices tumbled on expectations the American Petroleum Institute (API) would show a build-up in stocks of heating oil and diesel fuels in weekly oil inventory data.</p>
<p>Heating oil for November delivery fell 1.63 cents to 69.83 cents a gallon at the New York Mercantile Exchange. November unleaded gasoline fell 1.20 cents to 69.10 cents a gallon and December crude oil lost 51 cents to $24.34 a barrel.</p>
<p>Record low heating oil inventories had sent heating oil and crude prices to new post-Gulf War highs this month, but the belief that heating oil stocks were being replenished has been pushing oil prices lower the past two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a change in psychology in the market with the effort by refiners to build stocks,&quot; said ING Derivatives analyst Tom Bentz. &quot;Heat was hit because people are expecting the stats to show a bearish build.&quot;</p>
<p>After the close of trading, the API said that distillate stocks grew 3.6 million barrels in the week ended Oct. 25, a bigger buildup than the 1 million- to 3 million-barrel rise traders had expected.</p>
<p>Crude stocks fell 2.5 million barrels compared with an expected drop of up to 2 million barrels. Gasoline stocks fell 3.8 million barrels, a sharper drop than the expected decline of up to 3 million barrels.</p>
<p>Coffee futures closed lower in volatile trading as speculators ignored record low warehouse stocks and instead concentrated on central and South American supplies expected to arrive soon.</p>
<p>December coffee fell 2.75 cents to 116.35 cents a pound at the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange after trading as high as 123 cents a pound during the day, the highest in a month.</p>
<p>On Monday the exchange reported warehouse stocks of coffee suitable for delivery against futures fell 4,036 132-pound bags in the week ended Oct. 25 to just 1,547 bags, the lowest since the exchange began tracking inventories in 1980.</p>
<p>But traders said new crop from Colombia should start to flow soon into the market following the end of a 12-day truckers' strike on Thursday.</p>
<p>And many Central American countries, which have had difficulty getting their beans to port due to flooding and heavy rains, should begin exporting in coming weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are eventually going to see a buildup in stocks,&quot; said Dean Witter analyst Steve Platt. &quot;It seems to undercut each rally attempt.&quot;</p>
<p>Precious metals also fell sharply as the rally in the stock and bond markets drew money from other investments.</p>
<p>December silver at the COMEX division of the New York Mercantile Exchange fell 11 cents to $4.82 an ounce after hitting $4.81, the lowest price since late 1994.</p>
<p>December gold lost $3 to $381.60 an ounce.</p>
<p>The rally in stock and bond markets after wage and consumer confidence data pointed to tame inflation discouraged buying in precious metals, traditionally an inflation hedge for investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The breakout in the U.S. 30-year bond futures to multi-month highs encouraged more fund selling,&quot; Friedberg Mercantile Group's Toronto-based trader Jeff Kowal said.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed rumours of further European central bank selling of gold reserves as countries sought to meet the 1999 single-currency criteria also depressed sentiment, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
