<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149293" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY FOR NOV 4 - DEC 31, 1997.</title>
<headline>REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY FOR NOV 4 - DEC 31, 1997.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>LISBON - Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) holds annual summit (To December 3).</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (December 9-13).</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Irish Presidency European Council of heads of state and government (December 13-14).</p>
<p>December 31, 1996 - Irish EU presidency ends. The Netherlands takes over to June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>EARLY 1997 - NATO holds summit to formally decide new members and approve a charter defining the alliance relationship with Russia - date to be set later.</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Dutch presidency hosts European Council of heads of state and government (June 16-17).</p>
<p>NOVEMBER</p>
<p>- Irish presidency hosts conference on &quot;Local employment initiatives&quot;. Date and venue to be announced.</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 4</p>
<p>EUROPEAN UNION - 1996 European Telework week begins (To November 11). The aim is to raise awareness of business and work opportunities presented by telework and to provide opportunities to understand and use telework technologies. Contact: Horace Mitchell (44) 1 635 253 802.</p>
<p>VIENNA - Third European assembly on telework and new ways to work (To November 6). Main topics discussed are: getting people to work; training for life in the information society and working towards sustainability. Contact: Josef Hochgerner (43) 1 4950 442 42.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Tourism Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Commission report on the evaluation of Community's action plan to assist tourism (1993-1995).</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council decision on a first multiannual programme to assist European tourism (1997-2000) &quot;PHILOXENIA&quot;.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Report by the Commission on the situation regarding travel guides and ski instructors in the EU.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Entente International Communication organises &quot;European employment week '96&quot; conference (1000/0900 GMT) (To November 7). Main issues discussed: new technology and job creation; social and urban innovations for job creation; more undertakings and small firms-more jobs. Speakers include: European Commissioner Flynn. Contact: Laurence Fontaine, Entente International Communication (322) 502 1558.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IBC Legal Studies and Services Ltd. hold third annual conference on &quot;EC Competition law&quot; (0845/0645 GMT) (To November 6). Venue: Radisson SAS Hotel. Contact: Holly Barton, IBC Legal Studies and Services Ltd. (44) 171 637 4383.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Transport Safety Council (ETSC) holds conference on &quot;Low-cost/high-return engineering measures for road accident reduction&quot;. Contact: ETSC (322) 230 4106.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - CENELEC holds conference on &quot;Standards on trial: case studies in European standardisation&quot; (To November 6). Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Annick Colman, CENELEC (322) 519 6889.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting. (possibly) Commission due to release bi-annual economic forecasts.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - EP President Klaus Haensch meets EP bureau and political group leaders in order to decide on a certain number of measures to reform the EP members allowance system. Contact: Angelina Hermanns (33) 3 88 17 4082.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 7</p>
<p>BORDEAUX, France (NEW ITEM) - Franco-British summit meeting (To November 8).</p>
<p>LONDON (NEW ITEM) - Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring reviews Ireland's EU presidency.</p>
<p>CORK, Ireland - European Commission hosts European conference on &quot;Rural development&quot; (To November 9). Discussions will focus on the future perspectives for the Union's rural development policy. This policy seeks to address the challenges faced by rural areas in a way that considers all economic sectors and aspects of rural life and builds on their strengths.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Voice holds conference on &quot;What future for industrial liberalisation in Europe?&quot; (0915/0815 GMT). Main topics discussed: European Commissioner Van Miert addresses on &quot;The future of competition policy in Europe&quot;; Commissioner Bonino addresses on &quot;Implications of liberalisation for consumers&quot;; discussions on how companies are facing up to a liberalised single market and debate on industrial liberalisation and competition. Venue: SAS Radisson Hotel. Contact: IBC technical Services (44) 171 453 2700.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Trade Union Confederation (ETUC) holds conference on &quot;Social protection&quot; (To November 8). Contact: ETUC (322) 224 0411.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 8</p>
<p>CHICAGO - Transatlantic Business Dialogue (TABD NEWS) holds conference (To November 9) to discuss transatlantic trade relations and develop creative solutions to remaining barriers to transatlantic trade. Speakers are: US Commerce Secretary Mickey Kantor, European Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and European Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann. Contact: Stephen Johnston, EU Contact Point (322) 548 0693.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 10</p>
<p>LJUBLJANA (NEW ITEM) - Slovenian general elections; poll is Slovenia's third multi-party election and second since the country declared independence from the former Yugoslav federation in 1991.</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation for December 13-14 Dublin European Council:</p>
<p>- EMU;</p>
<p>- Employment;</p>
<p>- Report on taxation;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Banking and financial directives;</p>
<p>- Taxation issues.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To November 15).</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Health Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for an EP and Council decision adopting a programme of Community action on the prevention of drug dependence within the framework for action in the field of public health.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision adopting a programme of Community action on health monitoring in the context of the action in the field of public health.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive on the approximation of the laws, regulations and administrative provisions of the member states relating to the advertising of tobacco products.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council creating a network for the epidemiological surveillance and control of communicable diseases in the European Community.</p>
<p>- Setting-up of an EU-U.S. task force to develop and implement a global early warning system and response network for communicable diseases.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies (TSE).</p>
<p>- Blood safety/self sufficiency.</p>
<p>- State of health in the EU.</p>
<p>- Health protection requirements in Community policies.</p>
<p>- European health card.</p>
<p>- Pollution-related diseases:</p>
<p>- Rare diseases;</p>
<p>- Accidents/injuries.</p>
<p>- Statement by presidency on Alzheimers Disease conference (November 21-22, 1996).</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 13</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (To November 14).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce launches the business of adding value, an analysis of European retail and distribution based on a study by London economics, and the EuroCommerce recommendations for future policy in recognition of the vital importance of this sector to the European economy (1030/0930 GMT) (To November 14). Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5 874.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Agra Europe holds third annual European grain conference (To November 14). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>TILBURG, Netherlands (NEW ITEM) - Former German President Richard von Weizsaecker gives address on Culture of European Union (2000/1900 GMT). Venue: Brabant Catholic University.</p>
<p>ROME - U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation holds world food summit (To November 17). European Commissioner Fischler meets U.S. Department of Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman.</p>
<p>GENEVA - WTO holds conference with 48 poorest countries (To November 15).</p>
<p>PARIS - European Radiocommunications Office holds conference on &quot;Regulation and legislation in a liberalised market&quot; (1000/0900 GMT) (To November 15). Venue: Hilton Hotel. Contact: European Radiocommunications Office (45) 35 25 0300.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 14</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Industry Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes</p>
<p>- Steel:</p>
<p>a) State aids code;</p>
<p>b) Sixth monitoring report on state aids in steel sector;</p>
<p>c) (possibly) Future of ECSC Treaty.</p>
<p>- Competition:</p>
<p>a) State aids;</p>
<p>b) Merger regulation;</p>
<p>c) Agreement with Canada.</p>
<p>- Shipbuilding:</p>
<p>- (possibly) State of ratification procedure - OECD agreement.</p>
<p>- SMEs:</p>
<p>a) Proposal for a Council decision on a third multiannual programme for small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) in the European Union (1997-2000);</p>
<p>b) Report on integrated programme.</p>
<p>- Competitiveness policy:</p>
<p>a) Commission's first report on the competitiveness of European industry;</p>
<p>b) A European policy for quality promotion;</p>
<p>c) Benchmarking;</p>
<p>d) Standards.</p>
<p>- Merger regulation:</p>
<p>- Review of regulation 4064/89 on the control of concentrations between undertakings.</p>
<p>- Automobile industry.</p>
<p>- Chemicals industry.</p>
<p>- Textiles:</p>
<p>- Communication from the Commission on the competitiveness of subcontracting in the textile and clothing industry in the European Union.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Recycling industry and environmental technology.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Space industry.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Cooperation with third countries.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Commision and EP host &quot;European film forum&quot; (To November 20). Venue: EP. Contact: Daniele Blin, DCB Productions (33) 1 42 768 82 14.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Europe's 500 - the association for dynamic entrepreneurs hold international think-tank (To November 16). Venue: Conrad Hotel. Contact: Europe's 500 (322) 716 4838.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce holds conference on &quot;The business of adding value - European retailing and distribution&quot;. Main discussions focus on commerce in the cashless society and the challenges of multimedia (second of two days). European Commission President Jacques Santer attends. Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5874.</p>
<p>PARIS (NEW ITEM) - Foreign ministers of countries involved in Bosnia discuss plans for two-year civilian peace consolidation programme in Bosnia; countries meeting include members of the contact group on former Yugoslavia of Western allies and Russia, and the Arab contact group.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - The Edmond Israel Foundation and the Cedel Group hold &quot;Vision for Europe&quot; award ceremony (1800/1700 GMT). Participants include: Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene and European Commission President Santer. Venue: European Centre, rue du Fort Thungen.</p>
<p>NEHGELO, The Netherlands - European Ostrich Association (EOA) holds world congress (To November 15). Venue: Expo Centre. Contact: EOA (31) 546 81 3677.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 15</p>
<p>PRAGUE (NEW ITEM) - Elections to Czech senate (newly-created senate to be mostly an advisory body with limited legislative power) (To November 16).</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 17</p>
<p>QATAR - European Commission DG XVII and the Cooperation Council for the Arab States of the Gulf (GCC) hold joint conference on &quot;EU-GCC: extending partnership to natural gas&quot; (and 18/11).</p>
<p>MOLDOVA (NEW ITEM) - Presidential election; if no candidate wins a majority in a first round, a second round will be held on the first Sunday of December and the winner will be inaugurated on January 15.</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 18</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To November 19). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>OSTEND, Belgium (NEW ITEM) - The Belgian Presidency of the WEU holds council of ministers (To November 19). Venue: Media Centre Ostend.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 19</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Budget Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Draft Community budget for 1997 (second reading).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Euro-Mediterranean Committee for the Barcelona process meets (To November 20).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Forum Europe holds conference on &quot;Europe's competitive edge&quot; (0845/0645 GMT). Agenda includes: assessing the state of EU competitiveness; an agenda for future action. Speakers include: European Commissioner Bangemann, Irish Enterprise and Employment Minister Richard Bruton, Irish Congress of Trade Unions General Secretary Peter Cassells, DG V Director General Allan Larsson, DG III Director General Stefano Micossi, Amcham Chairman William Seddon-Brown, UNICE Chairman Francois Perigot, MEP Irene Slotwedel-Schefer, DG XIII Director General Robert Verrue. Venue: Concert Noble. Contact: Forum Europe: (322) 736 1430.</p>
<p>STOCKHOLM (NEW ITEM) - Conference on NATO enlargement, organised by U.S. embassy in Sweden.</p>
<p>LONDON - Agra Europe holds ninth annual European and international dairy conference &quot;Dairy '96&quot; (To November 20). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 20</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - The Karolinska Institute, WHO and Volvo hold joint conference on &quot;Traffic safety, communication and health&quot; (To November 21). Sessions include: traffic safety and health; traffic safety in developing countries; traffic safety, mobility and health; transportation networks; traffic safety and environmental impact; human factors and human machine interaction in traffic safety. Contact: Volvo (46) 31 54 57 23.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 21</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Education/Youth Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on TEMPUS II.</p>
<p>- Conclusions on school effectiveness.</p>
<p>- European year of lifelong learning.</p>
<p>- Green paper on obstacles to mobility in higher education.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a recommendation concerning the assessment of quality in higher education.</p>
<p>- White paper on teaching and learning: towards the learning society.</p>
<p>- In-career development for teachers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) &quot;SOCRATES&quot; programme: draft decision amending the Socrates decision.</p>
<p>- Quality of higher education.</p>
<p>- General assessment of first and second level education systems.</p>
<p>- Commission proposal for a Council recommendation on the transferability of grants.</p>
<p>- Preparation of the structured dialogue with counterparts from central and eastern European countries.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Club de Bruxelles holds conference on &quot;The future of the West African Economic and Monetary Union (WAEMU) - The role of business and the European institutions in the context of regional integration and economic development of the countries of the WAEMU&quot; (0900/0800 GMT) (To November 22). Speakers include: European Commission President Santer; Commissioners Pinheiro and de Silguy; MEP Martens; Burkina Faso President Blaise Compaore; African Development Bank President Omar Kabbaj. Venue: Palais des Congres. Contact: Club de Bruxelles (322) 743 1520.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 22</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Development Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- First ministerial exchange of views on ACP/EU relations post-Lome IV (Commission green paper).</p>
<p>- Further exchange of views on relief, rehabilitation and development.</p>
<p>- Resolution on the forestry sector.</p>
<p>- Adoption of a common position on the regulation on north/south cooperation in the fight against drugs.</p>
<p>- Adoption of a common position on the regulation on aid for population policies and programmes.</p>
<p>- Approval after EP second reading of the regulations on rehabilitation and construction in developing countries, refugees in Asia and Latin America, environmental measures in developing countries and HIV/AIDS related operations in developing countries.</p>
<p>- Horizon 2000 - coherence, complementarity and coordination.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Fisheries Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulations (EC) fixing:</p>
<p>- The guide prices for the fishery products listed in Annex I (A), (D) and (E) of Regulation (EEC) No. 3759/92 for the 1997 fishing year;</p>
<p>- The guide prices for the fishery products listed in Annex H to Regulation (EEC) No. 3759/92 for the 1997 fishing year;</p>
<p>- The Community producer price for tuna intended for the industrial manufacture of products falling within CN code 1604 for the 1997 fishing year.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) temporarily suspending totally or partially the autonomous duties of the Common Customs Tariff for certain fishery products (1997).</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council Regulation laying down (new) technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council decision on MAGP IV.</p>
<p>- Commission report on third countries' activities in Community waters.</p>
<p>- Proposals for a Council regulation on the conclusion of the protocol establishing the fisheries rights and financial compensation provided in the agreement between the European Economic Community and the government of Senegal.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Conclusion of new fisheries agreements with:</p>
<p>a) Certain countries of South America;</p>
<p>b) South Africa;</p>
<p>c) Namibia;</p>
<p>d) Mozambique.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT (NEW ITEM) - Chancellor Helmut Kohl and various representatives from politics and the banking community attend the Frankfurt European Banking Congress 1996, opens 0630 GMT.</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 25</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council (To November 26). In margins of the Council, EU/African Unity Organisation ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation for Dublin European Council.</p>
<p>- Transatlantic relations.</p>
<p>- Preparation for December WTO ministerial meeting.</p>
<p>- Middle East.</p>
<p>- Mediterranean policy:</p>
<p>- Status report on contacts with Syria;</p>
<p>- Middle East (post-Cairo summit).</p>
<p>- Albania: decision to sign a new accord.</p>
<p>- Relations with Turkey.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign trade and cooperation agreement with FYROM.</p>
<p>- Nigeria: renewal of sanctions.</p>
<p>- Biological and toxin weapons convention: approval of statement on the opening of the fourth review conference.</p>
<p>- Ratification of chemical weapons convention: statement welcoming ratification.</p>
<p>- Determination of EU position for structured dialogue with Cyprus and Malta.</p>
<p>- Conclusion of negotiations on framework agreement with Australia.</p>
<p>- Relations with central and eastern European countries:</p>
<p>- Approval of conclusion of Europe agreements with Baltic States;</p>
<p>- Approval of interim protocols to Europe agreements.</p>
<p>- Russia: review of action plan.</p>
<p>- Food aid for Central Asian Republics.</p>
<p>- Status of negotiations with South Africa.</p>
<p>- Preparation for OSCE conference, Lisbon.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Consumers Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Commission proposal on access to justice (injunctions).</p>
<p>- Commission communication on access to justice (settlement).</p>
<p>- Directive amending existing consumer credit directives.</p>
<p>- Commission green paper on commercial communications in the internal market.</p>
<p>- Commission green paper on financial services meeting consumers' expectations.</p>
<p>- Guarantees and after sales services.</p>
<p>- Consumer protection within the information society.</p>
<p>- Protection of vulnerable and disadvantaged consumers.</p>
<p>- Continuation of consumer education theme.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission hosts conference on &quot;Investment and trade cooperation between India and the EU&quot; (To November 26). Speakers include: European Commissioner Marin. Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Euro Synergy Network (322) 510 2463.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Brussels institute for management of the environment (IBGE), European federation of regional energy and environment agencies (FEDARENE) and Eurocities hold joint conference on &quot;Plans and strategies for waste management on regional and local level&quot; (0900/0800 GMT). Venue: General de Banque auditorium. Contact: IBGE by fax (322) 775 7679.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 26</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Internal Market Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (possibly) 1996 study of the impact and effectiveness of single market legislation.</p>
<p>- Simpler legislation for the internal market (SLIM).</p>
<p>- Directive on legal protection of designs and industrial models.</p>
<p>- (possibly) 16th amendment of the directive 76/769/EEC on the marketing and use of certain dangerous substances and preparations.</p>
<p>- Citizens First initiative.</p>
<p>- Directive concerning the free movement of lawyers.</p>
<p>- European company statute.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Directive concerning the free movement of doctors.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive amending directive 93/7/EEC concerning the return of cultural objects unlawfully removed from the territory of a member state.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a directive on the supplementary supervision of insurance undertakings in an insurance group.</p>
<p>- Amendments to directive 89/398/EEC - dietary foods:</p>
<p>a) Vertical directives;</p>
<p>b) Temporary authorization;</p>
<p>- Amendments to directive 2/95/EEC - miscellaneous additives:</p>
<p>a) Prohibition of use in traditional products;</p>
<p>b) Classification of processed euchema seaweed.</p>
<p>- Amendment to sweeteners directive 94/35/EEC.</p>
<p>- In-vitro medical diagnostic devices.</p>
<p>- Amending public procurement directives following the adoption of G.P.A.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Green paper on public procurement.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - European Commission DG XI hosts standing conference on &quot;Health and safety in the nuclear age: informing the public on European radiation standards&quot; (1030/0930 GMT) (and 27/11). Topics include: major changes in the Euratom basic safety standards directive. Venue: Jean Monnet building, room M6. Contact: Mrs Eisen, DG IX (352) 4301 33 164.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;Managing consumer credit in the EU&quot; (0845/0745 GMT). Main issues discussed are the economic environment; market developments in the EU; the regulatory environment in the EU and the U.S. Venue: CEPS. Contact: Isabelle Tenaerts, CEPS (322) 229 3956.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (to 28/11).</p>
<p>DUBLIN - European Finance Convention holds tenth anniversary meeting (To November 30). Contact: (44) 171 381 9291.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 27</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (To November 28).</p>
<p>VENICE - Second ministerial conference on the management of fish stocks in the Mediterranean (To November 29).</p>
<p>THE HAGUE (NEW ITEM) - Portuguese Prime Minister Antonio Guterres on official visit in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 28</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Justice and Home Affairs Council (To November 29). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Telecoms Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Telecommunications terminal and satellite earth station equipment.</p>
<p>- TENs: Proposal for a European Parliament and Council decision on a series of guidelines for trans-European telecommunications networks.</p>
<p>- Data protection: modified proposal for a directive of the European Parliament and of the Council concerning the processing of personal data and the protection of privacy in the telecommunications sectors, in particular in the integrated services digital network (ISDN).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Numbering.</p>
<p>- (possibly) ONP voice telephony.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council decision on inter-administration telematic networks for statistics relating to the trading of goods between member states (EDICOM).</p>
<p>- Proposal for a European Parliament and Council directive on interconnection in telecommunications.</p>
<p>- Update of framework and leased lines directives on open network provision (ONP).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission and the Indian government hold joint forum on trade and investment in India.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Institute for Asian Studies (EIAS) hold conference on &quot;EU-Asia cooperation in the WTO context&quot; (To November 29). Main discussions focus on how and to what extent Asians and Europeans can cooperate in opening up markets within the WTO. Speakers include: European Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan. Contact: EIAS, Kerstin Bergloef (322) 230 8122.</p>
<p>BRUGES, Belgium - European Society of Transport Institutes (ESTI) holds conference on &quot;The citizens' network&quot; (and 29/11). Topics discussed include: the implications of external costs principles on urban transport; the network benefits principles; the modernising of the regulatory framework in public transport. Venue: Castle Prinsenhof. Contact: Laetitia Hoste, ESTI (322) 230 0514.</p>
<p>LEIPZIG, Germany - Verband Saechssicher Bildungsinstitute hold conference on &quot;Education 2000&quot; (To November 30). Topics include: the European education market; training in the latest skills; multimedia ability for both suppliers and users; innovation through personal development. Contact: Verband Saechssicher Bildungsinstitute, Dieter Webner (49) 341 490 5910.</p>
<p>LONDON - Agra Europe holds fifth annual European sugar, sweetners and starch conference (to November 29). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 29</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament hosts conference on &quot;Europe and its nations - before Maastricht II&quot;. Participants include: European Commission President Jacques Santer and Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene.</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 2</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation for December 13-14 Dublin European Council:</p>
<p>- Commission report on the coordination of the Community's economic and structural policies.</p>
<p>- EIB loans to third countries.</p>
<p>- Taxation issues.</p>
<p>- SEM 2000 (sound and efficient management) final report of personal representatives group.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Protection of the financial interests of the Community:</p>
<p>- Monitoring of national measures;</p>
<p>- Extension of administrative controls and sanctions.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Social Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Follow-up of the Essen European Council: draft single report to the European Council of Dublin.</p>
<p>- Directive proposal on posting of workers in the framework of services.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive on the burden of proof in sex discrimination cases.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive modifying directive 76/207/EEC (Kalanke European Court of Justice judgment).</p>
<p>- Amendment to regulation on civil servants and students (social security for migrant workers).</p>
<p>- Proposed regulation on modification of regulations (EEC 1408/71 and 574/72) (social security of migrant workers: beneficiaries of pre-retirement benefits).</p>
<p>- Proposed regulation on various modifications of the regulations on social security for migrant workers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposed regulation on codification of the regulations on social security for migrant workers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Draft resolution on lifelong learning.</p>
<p>- Draft resolution on the future of social protection.</p>
<p>LONDON - Financial Times holds conference on &quot;World telecoms - New alliances for a new era&quot; (To december 3). Venue: Inter Continental Hotel. Contact: Financial Times (44) 171 896 2626.</p>
<p>LISBON (NEW ITEM) - Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) holds annual summit. Main discussions will focus on an architecture of European security outlining its main principles and parameters (To December 3).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Transport Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- External relations:</p>
<p>- Relations with the United States in the field of air transport.</p>
<p>- Recommendation for a Council decision authorising the Commission to open negotiations on air transport agreements between the Community and Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Slovakia.</p>
<p>- Negotiations between the European Community and Switzerland on land and air transport.</p>
<p>- Other measures:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to green paper on the citizens' network.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to green paper on internalisation of external costs.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for an European Parliament and Council directive on summer time arrangements.</p>
<p>- Surface transport:</p>
<p>a) Rail transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to the white paper on the future of the railways.</p>
<p>b) Road transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Access to the road haulage profession.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Taxation of goods vehicles to replace directive 93/89/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down the conditions under which non-resident carriers may operate national road passenger transport services within a member state.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council directive and regulation on recording equipment in road transport.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation (EEC) No 684/92 on common rules for the international carriage of passengers by coach and bus.</p>
<p>- Air transport:</p>
<p>- Follow-up to white paper on air traffic management.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to high level group on air safety.</p>
<p>- Proposal for the establishment of a single European authority for air safety.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal on airport charges.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation on air carrier liability in case of accidents.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Revision of regulation on slot allocation.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposals to update rules on denied boarding compensation and passenger protection.</p>
<p>- Maritime transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Licensing regime for roll-on roll-off ferry operations.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Compiling lists of passengers on roll-on roll-off ferries.</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council directive setting up a harmonised safety regime for fishing vessels of 24 metres in length and over.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission strategic document.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal to amend Council directive 94/58/EC on the minimum level of training of seafarers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal to amend Council directive 93/75/EEC concerning minimum requirements for vessels bound for or leaving Community ports and carrying dangerous or polluting goods.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Shipping agreements with third countries, especially China and India.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Report on competition in the multimodal sector.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, DECEMBER 13</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Irish presidency hosts European Council of heads of state and government (To December 14).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Council report on the development of tax systems within the Union, taking into account the need to create a tax environment that stimulates business and the creation of jobs and promotes a more efficient environmental policy.</p>
<p>- Commission and European Monetary Institute (EMI) report on progress in stage three of European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>- Commission report on subsidiarity.</p>
<p>- Presentation of draft revision of the treaties, addressing in particular:</p>
<p>* Bringing the Union closer to its citizens;</p>
<p>* Strengthening and enlarging the scope of the Union's common foreign and security policy;</p>
<p>* Assuring, in view of enlargement, the proper functioning of the institutions while respecting their balance of powers and the efficiency of the decision-making process;</p>
<p>* Simplification of the treaties.</p>
<p>- Commission report on appropriate initiatives for reinforcing regional cooperation in Europe.</p>
<p>- Report on the evolution of the trade policies and the preferential agreements of the Community in relation to the World Trade Organisation (WTO).</p>
<p>- Final European Commission report on the mutually beneficial effects of greater coordination of the Union's economic and structural policies.</p>
<p>- Review of December 1995 Madrid summit recommendations on fighting unemployment and on application of multiannual employment programmes.</p>
<p>- Joint ECOFIN/Social Affairs Council annual employment monitoring report.</p>
<p>- Review of progress in application of Madrid December 1995 drug experts group report on the fight against drugs.</p>
<p>- Territorial pacts for employment within the framework of the confidence pact for employment.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, DECEMBER 15</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - Council of Europe holds symposium on &quot;Medically-assisted procreation and the protection of the human embryo&quot; (To December 18).</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 16</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To December 17). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Culture Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Debate on European funds promoting cinema and television production.</p>
<p>- Directive amending the television without frontiers directive.</p>
<p>- Decision establishing an audiovisual guarantee fund.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive harmonising rules on media concentrations.</p>
<p>- Decision on Ariane programme.</p>
<p>- Decision on Raphael programme.</p>
<p>- First Commission report on consideration of cultural aspects of EU action.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on rules concerning the European city of culture after the year 2000.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Green paper on new audiovisual services.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive amending directive 93/7/EEC concerning the return of cultural objects unlawfully removed from the territory of a member state.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Transport Safety Council (ETSC) holds conference on &quot;Increasing survivability in aircraft accidents&quot; (0930/0830 GMT). Speakers include: MEP Mark Watts. Venue: Dorint Hotel. Contact: ETSC (</p>
<p>322) 230 4106.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, DECEMBER 17</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Economic and Social Committee (ECOSOC) holds plenary session (To December 19).</p>
<p>TUESDAY, DECEMBER 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Energy Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive concerning common rules for the internal market in electricity.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive concerning common rules for the internal market in gas.</p>
<p>- White paper on energy: Community strategy on renewables.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on ALTENER II.</p>
<p>- White paper on energy: proposal for a decision on analysis and forecasts.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on SAVE II programme.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive on energy efficiency requirements for households: electric refrigerators, freezers and combinations thereof.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a regulation on a SYNERGY programme.</p>
<p>- Report on the situation of oil supply, refining and markets in the European Community.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive to introduce rational planning techniques in the electricity and gas distribution sectors.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on the conclusion of the Energy Charter Treaty.</p>
<p>- Euro-Mediterranean conference.</p>
<p>- Revision of Community law in the energy sector.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, DECEMBER 4</p>
<p>LONDON (NEW ITEM) - Britain hosts international conference on peace consolidation in Bosnia in 1997. Meeting will be attended by some 50 countries and international agencies as well as by newly-elected Bosnian leaders (To December 5).</p>
<p>LONDON - Financial Times (FT) holds conference on &quot;Venture '96 Europe&quot; (To December 6). Main topics discussed: overview of venture capital and buyouts markets in Europe; update on eastern Europe; fund raising for European investments; technology-a hot investment sector; mezzanine and senior debt-a look at availability and terms; managing the European portfolio; deal flow channels; exit and IPO markets in Europe. Contact: FT conferences (44) 171 896 2626.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Research Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Financial supplement to the fourth framework programme/task force.</p>
<p>- Action plan on follow-up to the green paper on innovation.</p>
<p>- Fifth RTD framework programme.</p>
<p>- Presidency initiative on the contribution of research to drug detection and prevention of abuse.</p>
<p>- International cooperation in the RTD field:</p>
<p>- Science and technology cooperation strategy with central and eastern European countries;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Bilateral science and technology agreements with several third countries.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on the EU and space.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on agronomic research for development.</p>
<p>- SMEs.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Fusion:</p>
<p>- ITER;</p>
<p>- Evaluation report from the Commission on the fusion programme.</p>
<p>- High flux reactor (HFR) programme.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Environmental Bureau (EEB) hold seminar on &quot;Ecolabel sells?&quot;. Venue: Borschette centre. Contact: EEB (322) 539 0037.</p>
<p>CASABLANCA - Euro-Mediterranean summit of industrial federations.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, DECEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation of Dublin European Council.</p>
<p>- Discussion of 53rd U.N. Commission on human rights (including definition of EU position on China).</p>
<p>- Approval of policy document on peacekeeping operations.</p>
<p>- Submission of report on European armament policy.</p>
<p>- Adoption of common position on U.N. register of conventional arms.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Middle East.</p>
<p>- Mediterranean policy:</p>
<p>- Report on the follow-up to the Barcelona Conference;</p>
<p>- Algeria and Egypt: decision to sign agreements;</p>
<p>- Syria: Commission proposal for a negotiating mandate.</p>
<p>- Preparation of EEA ministerial council.</p>
<p>- Internal financial regulation on ACP.</p>
<p>- Radiation protection of persons undergoing medical examination or treatment.</p>
<p>- Negotiating directives for a nuclear cooperation agreement between EURATOM and Japan.</p>
<p>- Approval of mandate to negotiate an agreement on wine with Slovakia, Slovenia and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>- Agreement on steel with central and eastern European countries.</p>
<p>- Approval of negotiating mandate for a partnership and cooperation agreement with Turkmenistan.</p>
<p>- Asia:</p>
<p>- Decision to sign a protocol relating to the accession of Vietnam to ASEAN;</p>
<p>- Preparation for EU-ASEAN ministerial (February 1997);</p>
<p>- Follow-up to Bangkok ASEM and preparation for Singapore ministerial.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign framework agreement with Australia.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign mutual recognition agreements with Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>- Decision on signature of free trade agreement with South Africa.</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 9</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (To December 13).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Brittan presents report on integrating multilateral clothing and textile pacts under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</p>
<p>- Review of the implementation of Uruguay Round commitments.</p>
<p>- Endorsement of results of negotiations on services.</p>
<p>- Report from the committee on trade and environment.</p>
<p>- Any other trade-related issues.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Environment Council (To December 10).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council on the review of the European Community programme of policy and action in relation to the environment and sustainable development &quot;towards sustainability&quot;.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 90/219/EEC on the contained use of genetically modified micro-organisms.</p>
<p>- Auto oil:</p>
<p>a) Draft directive relating to the quality of petrol and diesel fuels;</p>
<p>b) Draft directive on measures against air pollution by emissions from motor vehicules - amendment of directives 70/229//EEC and 70/156/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive concerning the quality of water intended for human consumption.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on waste policy.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council regulation (EEC) No 3254/91 prohibiting the use of leghold traps in the Community and the introduction into the Community of pelts and manufactured goods of certain wild animal species originating in countries which catch them by means of leghold traps or trapping methods which do not meet international humane trapping standards.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation establishing common rules and procedures to apply to the shipments to certain non-OECD countries of certain types of waste.</p>
<p>- Follow-up to the conference on climate change.</p>
<p>- Fifth session of the Commission on sustainable development.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To December 13).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 19</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Fisheries Council (To December 20).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation fixing, for certain fish stocks and groups of fish stocks, the total allowable catches for 1997 and certain conditions under which they may be fished.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council regulation (EEC) No. 3074/95 fixing, for certain fish stocks and groups of fish stocks, the total allowable catches for 1996 and certain conditions under which they may be fished.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation laying down certain rules for the access to Community waters of research vessels for scientific purposes.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Commission proposal on the financing of collection of scientific data.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) amending regulation (EEC) No. 2847/93 establishing a control system applicable to the common fisheries policy (establishment of a Community catch-reporting data-base).</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council decision on MAGP IV.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council regulations</p>
<p>a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of Norway;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, certain catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in the Norwegian exclusive zone and the fishing zone around Jan Mayen.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council regulations:</p>
<p>a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of the Faroes;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, certain catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Faroese waters.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation allocating, for 1997, Community catch quotas in Greenland waters.</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulation allocating, for 1997, certain catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Icelandic waters.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council regulations:</p>
<p>a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of Estonia;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Estonian waters.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council regulations:</p>
<p>a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of Latvia;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Latvian waters.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council regulations</p>
<p>a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of Lithuania;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Lithuanian waters.</p>
<p>- a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of Poland;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Polish waters.</p>
<p>- a) laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of the Russian Federation;</p>
<p>b) allocating, for 1997, catch quotas between member states for vessels fishing in Russian waters.</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulation laying down, for 1997, certain conservation and management measures for fishery resources in the regulatory area as defined in the Convention on future multilateral cooperation in the North West Atlantic Fisheries.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down, for 1997, certain measures for the conservation and management of fishery resources applicable to vessels flying the flag of certain non-member countries in the 200-nautical-mile zone off the coast of the French Department of Guiana.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) NAFO: New STACFAC regulations.</p>
<p>- Proposals for Council decisions:</p>
<p>a) Authorising the Kingdom of Spain to extend the agreement on mutual fishery relations with the Republic of South Africa;</p>
<p>b) Authorizing the Portuguese Republic to extend the agreement on mutual fishery relations with the Republic of South Africa.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Executive committee of Schengen group on free movement of people meets at ministerial level under Luxembourg presidency. The agreements with the five nordic countries should be signed. Venue: Kirchberg conference centre.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, DECEMBER 23</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU institutions closed for Christmas holidays until January 2.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, DECEMBER 31</p>
<p>- Irish EU presidency ends. The Netherlands takes over to June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>EARLY 1997 - NATO holds summit to formally decide new members and approve a charter defining the alliance relationship with Russia - date to be set later.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, JANUARY 7</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Fisheries Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JANUARY 13</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To January 17).</p>
<p>MONDAY, JANUARY 20</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council (To January 21). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To January 21). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JANUARY 27</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - (possibly) ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 29</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To January 30).</p>
<p>FRIDAY, JANUARY 31</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Informal Transport Council (To February 1). No agenda yet available,</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 29</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To January 30).</p>
<p>FRIDAY, JANUARY 31</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Informal Transport Council (To February 1). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, FEBRUARY 5</p>
<p>NOORDWIJK, The Netherlands - Informal Justice and Home Affairs Council (To February 6). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, FEBRUARY 14</p>
<p>ROTTERDAM - Informal Social Affairs Council (To February 15). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, FEBRUARY 17</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To February 18). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To February 21).</p>
<p>MONDAY, FEBRUARY 24</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council (To February 25). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, FEBRUARY 28</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Informal Development Council (To March 2). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MARCH 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Environment Council (To March 4). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>ROTTERDAM - Informal Education Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, MARCH 4</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Environment Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, MARCH 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Telecoms Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MARCH 10</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Internal Market Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To March 14).</p>
<p>TUESDAY, MARCH 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Transport Council (To March 12). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, MARCH 15</p>
<p>APELDOORN, The Netherland - Informal General Affairs Council (To March 16). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MARCH 17</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To March 19). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MARCH 24</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council (To March 25). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, APRIL 4</p>
<p>NOORDWIJK, The Netherlands - Informal ECOFIN Council (To April 6). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, APRIL 7</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To April 11).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, APRIL 10</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Consumers Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, APRIL 14</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Fisheries Council (To April 15). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, APRIL 17</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Social Affairs Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, APRIL 18</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Informal Environment Council (To April 20). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, APRIL 21</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Farm Council (To April 22). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, APRIL 23</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - ACP-EU Council (To April 24). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To April 24).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, APRIL 24</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Industry Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, APRIL 29</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - General Affairs Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MAY 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - (possibly) General Affairs Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MAY 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Farm Council (To May 13). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To May 16).</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, MAY 14</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Research Council (To May 15). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, MAY 20</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Internal Market Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - World Fuels Conferences hold conference on &quot;Fuel quality and vehicle technology&quot; (To May 22). Venue: Conrad Hotel. Contact: Worl Fuel Conferences (1) 703 812 0902.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, MAY 25</p>
<p>VENUE TO BE CONFIRMED - EU foreign ministers hold Inter-governmental conference (IGC) conclave ahead of European summit (To May 26).</p>
<p>DOMBURG, The Netherlands - Informal Farm Council (To May 27). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, MAY 26</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Energy Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, MAY 27</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Justice and Home Affairs Council (To May 28). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, MAY 28</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To May 29).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, MAY 29</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Telecoms Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JUNE 2</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - General Affairs Council (To June 3). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, JUNE 5</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Health Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Development Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JUNE 9</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Farm Council (To June 10). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To June 13).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, JUNE 12</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Social Affairs Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JUNE 16</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Dutch presidency hosts European Council of heads of state and government (To June 17).</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Transport Council (To June 18). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, JUNE 19</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Fisheries Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JUNE 23</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Environment Council (To June 24). No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - (possibly) ECOFIN Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, JUNE 25</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To June 26).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, JUNE 26</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Education Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JUNE 30</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - General Affairs Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Culture Council. No agenda yet available.</p>
<p>- Dutch EU presidency ends. Luxembourg takes over to December 31, 1997.</p>
<p>MONDAY, JULY 14</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (to July 18).</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 15</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To September 19).</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 1</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To October 2).</p>
<p>MONDAY, OCTOBER 20</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To October 24).</p>
<p>WEDENESDAY, NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To November 6).</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 17</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To November 21).</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, DECEMBER 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament holds mini session (To December 4).</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 15</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament holds plenary session (To December 19).</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
