<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15547" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US appeals court stays Lloyd's injunction.</title>
<headline>US appeals court stays Lloyd's injunction.</headline>
<byline>Greg Baumann</byline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. appeals court gave Lloyd's of London a reprieve Tuesday in its multibillion-dollar reorganization, throwing out an injunction that the insurance giant said could have led to its collapse.</p>
<p>The three-judge panel ruled that the injunction issued Friday by a U.S. district judge in Virginia should be dismissed, clearing the way for Lloyd's to give formal approval Thursday to its reorganization.</p>
<p>In its ruling, the court noted that the plaintiffs, 93 U.S. investors in Lloyd's, had agreed to litigate any disputes in England, an indication of the court's reluctance to take jurisdiction in the case.</p>
<p>The U.S. investors, known as Names, are likely to appeal the court's decision and will continue to pursue litigation in other U.S. courts, said Kenneth Chiate, a U.S. Name and a chief negotiator for the American Names Association.</p>
<p>&quot;My prediction is that the Names will appeal,&quot; Chiate said. &quot;At this point it is a sufficiently important decision that I'm confident that they will appeal.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But to say that they definitely will would be premature until we determine what the exact basis for the court's ruling is,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Immediately after the ruling was issued, Lloyds issued a statement in London saying it extended the deadline for its investors to accept the agreement. The deadline had been for 8 a.m. EDT Wednesday but was extended indefinitely.</p>
<p>Lloyd's also said 82 percent of its investors, or Names as they are known at Lloyd's, had accepted the proposed $2.2 billion settlement. But it said only 53 percent of the 2,700 U.S. names had accepted it.</p>
<p>&quot;Since we won the appeal, faxes have been flooding in from U.S. Names accepting the settlement offer,&quot; a Lloyd's spokesman said by telephone.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very pleased,&quot; said Lloyd's Chairman David Rowland. &quot;I have believed for a long time that what we are doing is in the interest of the whole society (Lloyd's).&quot;</p>
<p>The reorganization plan was thrown into uncertainty Friday, when U.S. District Judge Robert Payne in Richmond, Va., ruled that Lloyd's sold securities to U.S. Names in violation of U.S. securities laws.</p>
<p>Payne granted the injunction and ordered Lloyd's to provide more information to the U.S. investors by Sept. 23.</p>
<p>Lloyd's argued in its appeal before the U.S. 4th Circuit Court of Appeals sitting in Baltimore that such a delay could cause the 300-year-old insurance market to collapse since it would be unable to meet the deadline to pass solvency tests in the United Kingdom and the United States.</p>
<p>The appeals court subsequently sent the case back to the district court with instructions to dismiss it.</p>
<p>During the hearing Tuesday, appellate Judge Paul Niemeyer said, &quot;If we find the whole market is subject to American security laws, we could be looking at rescission (rescinding) of up to $2.2 billion in obligations.&quot;</p>
<p>A Lloyd's spokesman said the ruling had removed the last major legal obstacle to Lloyd's recovery plan, aimed at ending years of turbulence triggered by huge liabilities.</p>
<p>But several U.S. legal actions are still pending against Lloyd's.</p>
<p>Colorado Attorney General Gale Norton said her office last week told Lloyd's it was considering a new legal action against Lloyd's based on allegations of consumer fraud.</p>
<p>&quot;We have notified them of our concerns and asked them to give us a response,&quot; Norton said.</p>
<p>In addition, an appeal of a lawsuit filed by some 600 Names in California is still pending, Chiate of the American Names Association said.</p>
<p>That lawsuit, which seeks rescission and restitution, was dismissed in U.S. district court and now is pending before the 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, Chiate said.</p>
<p>Lloyd's hopes the support shown by Names will be enough to declare the plan unconditional when its ruling council meets Thursday. The plan still has to be approved by Britain's Department of Trade and Industry.</p>
<p>Lloyd's problems began in the 1980s when a fatal combination of negligent underwriting, poor investment advice and a sequence of unexpected natural disasters conspired to bring about losses of several billion dollars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
