<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15554" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Lamfalussy says EMU likely to begin on time.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Lamfalussy says EMU likely to begin on time.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's planned currency union is likely to begin on time at the end of the decade even though a series of issues still needs to be tackled before the start, a senior European monetary official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Alexandre Lamfalussy, President of the European Monetary Institute (EMI), the forerunner to Europe's central bank, told a business group, &quot;I am reasonably confident that (European Economic and Monetary Union) will start in 1999.&quot;</p>
<p>Lamfalussy based his optimism on the fact that European nations were showing the necessary political will to meet prescribed entry criteria, having already made considerable progress on paring back inflation rates.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a clear determination on behalf of governments to meet the criteria,&quot; Lamfalussy said, adding, &quot;nations have said they would do so and they are doing so.&quot;</p>
<p>But Lamfalussy also warned that more work lay ahead, especially as nations were having difficulties meeting the criteria on public finances.</p>
<p>To join the currency union, nations must show their budget deficits do not exceed three percent of gross domestic product and that debt does not exceed 60 percent of GDP, or at least convince their peers they are heading towards these levels.</p>
<p>Even as nations scramble to get their budgets in order on time, Lamfalussy said it was clear that not all 15 European member nations could join the union at the beginning.</p>
<p>&quot;Not all nations will participate at the beginning, that is an understatement,&quot; Lamfalussy said, declining however to hint at which nations were likely to pass the test.</p>
<p>Privately, EMI officials said the final decision on who would participate, to be reached officially by governments in the spring of 1998 after 1997's economic data are compiled, would come as no surprise to anyone.</p>
<p>Periodic EMI reports detailing nations' progress as well as ongoing feedback to member nations should give sufficient preliminary information on nations' developments, ruling out the chance for last minute upsets, they said.</p>
<p>The next status report will be published in November.</p>
<p>By January the EMI, charged with drawing up a blueprint of instruments the future European central bank (ECB) will use to formulate policies, will also have completed the final catalogue of instruments to be used by the ECB.</p>
<p>While the issue of using minimum reserves, something Germany is lobbying for very heavily, remains open, Lamfalussy said general agreement had been reached on implementing instruments like securities repurchase agreements.</p>
<p>Lamfalussy added that the legal status of the Euro, the new common currency, in the changeover time between 1999 and the time when it is expected to be widely used in 2002 should be formalised before the end of this year.</p>
<p>Meanwhile questions regarding those nations who do not meet the requirements and are relegated as the so-called &quot;outs&quot;, will be discussed at several meetings in Dublin this year with Lamfalussy arguing a revised European exchange rate mechanism, ERM II, should be put in place.</p>
<p>The ERM holds currencies within fixed bands around a a known central rate. Currencies which fluctuated beyond these limits were then entitled to help from the other members and liable to drastic policy changes if they failed to work. The ERM still operates in name.</p>
<p>Once the currency union is underway, Lamfalussy said it was essential to have a mechanism that ensured nations do not relax fiscal vigilance, and spend much more than they take in tax.</p>
<p>He therefore welcomed the idea of a stability pact which would trigger automatic sanctions punishing those who lapse.</p>
<p>But Lamfalussy stressed that the EMI was in no way involved with advising on how to set up such a plan. &quot;It is up to the finance ministers to concoct that, but we are in favour of such a pact.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
