<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15553" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Eurobourses end mixed but London recovers.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Eurobourses end mixed but London recovers.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses closed mixed on Tuesday with London clawing back most of the day's losses despite an unsteady start on wall Street, hit by inflation worries.</p>
<p>The dollar weakened during the day with many dealers sidelined because of uncertainty over Tokyo's monetary direction ahead of the important Japanese Tankan economic survey out on Wednesday. But it recovered at the close of trade.</p>
<p>Stocks in London started the week badly after a three-day weekend, slipping 0.3 percent, but bargain-hunters later moved in and the FTSE index recovered most of the lost ground to end only just in negative ground.</p>
<p>Tuesday's patchy showing in London followed a string of records last week, culminating in Friday's trading high of 3,911, fuelled by a wave of European interest rate cuts. The London bourse drew little help from the unsettled morning on Wall Street, which slipped in and out of positive ground after a stronger-than-expected August consumer confidence report refuelled inflation fears, pulling U.S. Treasuries back from their early peaks.</p>
<p>Shortly after the report appeared showing the confidence index rising to 109.4 in August from a revised 107.0 in July, Wall Street relinquished virtually all its morning gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Treasuries remain very sensitive to any indication of a strong economy and we're still in that summer doldrum period of light trading,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, market strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co. &quot;Consequently, stocks and bonds are both subject to rapid swings.&quot;</p>
<p>Frankfurt was the one bright spot in Europe. Floor trading ended up 0.25 percent and the computerised IBIS index climbed nearly 0.4 percent, given a push by the performance of chemical shares. &quot;The market is trading 100 percent on fundamentals at the moment as interest rate fantasy disappears -- it's all company news,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>French shares ended slightly down amid growing unease about a difficult autumn for the government which also weighed on the franc, dealers said.</p>
<p>Bond prices were weaker and the franc was quoted at 3.4210 per mark for the first time since August 13 as worries about the government's autumn budget and a weak U.S. currency lifted the mark and squeezed French investments.</p>
<p>The dollar, which dropped sharply on Monday because of jitters over the Japanese Tankan survey, weakened further in quiet trading but regained losses to end the day close to Monday's levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Besides the Tankan, there's nothing really until the U.S. jobs numbers next week,&quot; said a UK bank corporate dealer. &quot;There is still the summer malaise hanging over the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign exchange markets regard the Tankan report as an important indication of the country's future monetary policy direction. If it points to weakness in the economy, the report will help the dollar regain some lost ground as speculation of a near-term rise in Japanese interest rates will evaporate.</p>
<p>The Japanese discount rate is currently at a record low of 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>The dollar was also pressured by the mark's strength against European currencies amid renewed concerns over Europe's economic and monetary union (EMU) timetable.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4788 marks and 107.74 yen at the close of European trading compared with 1.4789 marks and 107.55 yen on Monday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares ended 1.8 points lower at 3,905.7.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index finished down 2.43 at 2,017.99.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed up 6.48 at 2,558.84.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold closed at $388.55 an ounce, compared with Monday's close of $388.75 on international markets. Silver ended up one cent $5.24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
