<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15552" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French teachers lead autumn challenge to Juppe.</title>
<headline>French teachers lead autumn challenge to Juppe.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>French teachers' unions warned on Tuesday of protests including a likely strike over job cuts expected in the centre-right government's austerity budget but said they would meet again before deciding what action to take.</p>
<p>The unions said in a statement after a meeting that they were &quot;working to achieve the broadest possible unity&quot; on action over the coming weeks with a view to striking in late September or early October and that they would meet again on September 3.</p>
<p>As public sector unions prepare their response to planned budget cuts, Nicole Notat, head of the country's biggest union, the CFDT, also warned on Tuesday of &quot;tension and conflicts&quot; when the French return from their summer holidays.</p>
<p>One teachers' union called in advance of the Tuesday meeting for members to protest against the job cuts in education which are expected under the government's 1997 spending-cut budget.</p>
<p>The Federation Syndicale Unitaire (FSU) union made the call to action as it met representatives from the SE-FEN teachers union as well as education branches of the national unions CFDT and FO, to decide what action to take against the budget.</p>
<p>It said conditions were ripe to prepare a national strike by the start of October. French schools re-starts next week.</p>
<p>Tuesday's meeting kicks off a series opposing Prime Minister Alain Juppe's budget, which is expected to axe between 2,000 and 2,500 teachers' jobs -- the first teaching cuts in 15 years -- under a plan to shed 6,500-7,000 civil service jobs.</p>
<p>Juppe has said the 1997 budget would freeze spending at 1996 levels, implying a spending cut of 60 billion francs ($11.89 billion), to reduce the state deficit to three percent of gross domestic product in order to join the single European currency in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be tension and conflicts when people go back to work,&quot; Notat told the daily Le Monde, citing anger among staff at ailing property lender Credit Foncier, state-owned bank Credit Lyonnais, film studio SFP and appliance maker Moulinex.</p>
<p>The CFDT would take part in union action, she said. The Socialist-led CFDT, France's biggest union with some 650,000 members, is expected to announce its plans on September 27.</p>
<p>Credit Foncier is being gradually wound down after making a 1995 net loss of 10.8 billion francs, while Credit Lyonnais is shedding jobs in a bid to make good losses totalling 21 billion francs racked up between 1992 and 1994.</p>
<p>Some 667 jobs could go out of a total 1,056 at SFP if sold to businessman Walter Butler, while Moulinex is axing posts as part of a recovery plan.</p>
<p>Former conservative prime minister Edouard Balladur, also in Le Monde, said France was suffering from a &quot;lingering decline&quot; and called for big cuts in income tax, local taxes and value added tax to boost consumer demand. Reducing government spending was necessary but not sufficient, he said.</p>
<p>Communist Party leader Robert Hue said on Monday the spirit of public sector strikes which brought France to a virtual standstill for 24 days in November and December last year was &quot;still alive in the hearts and minds&quot; of the French people.</p>
<p>The Communist-led CGT union will unveil on Wednesday its plans to mobilise opposition to the budget, which is due to be discussed in cabinet around September 10, along with proposals for tax and social security reform.</p>
<p>The executive committee of the Force Ouvriere union will meet on September 3 and is expected to draw up its oppostion plans, a spokesman said. ($1=5.046 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
