<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15563" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MFS WorldCom seen as European upmarket threat.</title>
<headline>MFS WorldCom seen as European upmarket threat.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Newly merged MFS-WorldCom Inc seems well placed to win high profits from the most lucrative section of Europe's telecommunications market, the corporate sector, experts said Tuesday.</p>
<p>The $14.4. billion merger of MFS Communication Co Inc and WorldCom Inc, announced Monday, owes its conception to recent U.S. deregulation legislation.</p>
<p>&quot;This merger is really driven by the need to strengthen themselves in their newly opened-up home market,&quot; said John Matthews, for high-technology research consultancy Ovum.</p>
<p>The merged company will have sales of about $5.4 billion a year, with more than 500,000 business customers throughout North America, Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>But the merger will have big repurcussions in Europe, where some national telephone monopolies, due to expire in 1998, present a tempting combination of bloated prices and workforces and complacent management.</p>
<p>MFS-WorldCom is also seen as a powerful competitor which could even take business away from some of the big, global groupings. These comprise Global One - with Deutsche Telekom AG , France Telecom and Sprint Corp of the U.S. - British Telecommunications Plc and MCI Communications Corp's Concert, and the Unisource partnership led by ATT T.</p>
<p>But in Europe, experts say the combination of MFS, with its burgeoning networks of fibre optic cables in major financial centres, allied with WorldCom's expertise in long-distance services will give it powerful leverage at the top end of the market.</p>
<p>This is the corporate market, where the management of giant companies telecommunications and data processing is big business.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking large corporate clients in large financial centres and shipping their traffic around the world is superior cream skimming - clotted cream skimming really, attacking the highest value market,&quot; said David Roffey, who leads PA Consulting's telecommunication strategy team.</p>
<p>Roffey said the fit between MFS and WorldCom makes sense. MFS has local networks, particularly in the U.S., and WorldCom has expertise in long-distance line leasing.</p>
<p>In Europe the new combination will be taking aim at the currently protected and over-priced national markets which become liberalised in 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;Some European telephone costs are huge and so are the price discrepancies. A medium volume private high-speed circuit in Italy is 17 times more expensive than in Sweden. That sort of range - and even a price level of twice is probably unsustainable - won't last when competition like MSF-WorldCom gets going,&quot; Roffey said.</p>
<p>Matthews, principal consultant at Ovum, said this threat to the least efficient European operators could be exaggerated, while profits at the top end of the market are themselves being held back by increasing competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly there will be losers after deregulation. The smaller and weaker national companies that relied on monopoly over 100 years in some cases, but they were threatened anyway by the opening of the market,&quot; Matthews said.</p>
<p>And the top of the market is not necessarily still a license to print money.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very true five years ago, but high end customers are being saught by so many, they're not as profitable as they used to be,&quot; Matthews said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
