<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15565" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London precious metals firmer but cautious after holiday.</title>
<headline>London precious metals firmer but cautious after holiday.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metals prices had turned higher on Tuesday when London-based dealers returned after their late summer holiday weekend.</p>
<p>But they were cautious about whether or not the new levels would last now that the market was back to full strength.</p>
<p>&quot;Moves made when part of the market is on holiday tend to give up the ghost pretty quickly,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $389.00 per ounce, its highest since August 5 and compared with $387.50 on Friday. Bullion's $389.45 late close in New York on Monday largely held during the Asian trading day although markets in both time zones were quiet.</p>
<p>&quot;The Australians were doing some buy-backs (of gold sold previously) in New York but they were sellers again this morning in Tokyo,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The market's reaction to the expiry of the current over-the-counter (OTC) options on Wednesday would be key to gold's short-term direction, dealers said.</p>
<p>Options give their owner the right but not the obligation to buy a commodity at a fixed price, called the strike price, at a given time, known as the expiry date.</p>
<p>Current gold and silver prices suggested the $390.00 and $5.30 strike price respectively could be the targets come the expiry at 1330 GMT, dealers said.</p>
<p>There were mixed views on the how capable the markets were of building on their new price levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold does not look overbought. It has had an orderly move and has built a good foundation but I would be cautious about silver at these numbers,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;When people start talking about prices in the $5.30s and $5.50s, they tend not to happen,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Technical analysts, who chart previous prices to predict future trends, were more positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver's rounding base is completing now. There is resistance at 530 cents but the aim seems to be 540 cents where the downtrend comes in,&quot; said Elli Gifford at Investment Research of Cambridge.</p>
<p>Silver was quoted at $5.28, up five cents.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium were also mildly firmer -- platinum fixed at $401.00, its highest since August 9 -- and palladium's fixing of $125.50 was a couple of dollars above its 2-1/2 year low struck last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
