<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15566" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British regulator suspends three ex-Barings staff.</title>
<headline>British regulator suspends three ex-Barings staff.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's key markets regulator the Securities and Futures Authority (SFA) said on Tuesday it had disciplined three more former directors of Barings, the British merchant bank which collapsed in February 1995.</p>
<p>In a statement the SFA said the three -- George Maclean, head of the banking group of Baring Investment Bank, Anthony Hawes, group treasurer of Baring Investment Bank and Anthony Gamby, director of settlements for Baring Investment Bank -- had failed to act with due skill, care and diligence.</p>
<p>In March the SFA, which grants the licences vital to do business in London's financial district, said it had started disciplinary action against an unspecified number of unnamed individuals in connection with the collapse of Barings.</p>
<p>Nick Leeson, the trader blamed for stacking up $1.4 billion of unauthorised trading losses which crippled the bank, is serving a six-and-a-half year jail sentence in Singapore.</p>
<p>Barings was rescued by Dutch financial services group ING following its collapse.</p>
<p>In May, the SFA banned Peter Norris, former chief executive of the failed bank, and former head of group finance at Baring Investment Bank Geoffrey Broadhurst.</p>
<p>The regulator was criticised, though, for failing to take tough action against the two men at the top of Barings -- chairman Peter Baring and his deputy Andrew Tuckey.</p>
<p>Maclean has been reprimanded and his SFA registration as a director suspended for two years, the regulator said. He must also pay 10,000 pounds ($15,590) towards the SFA's costs.</p>
<p>Hawes was removed from the SFA's registers of directors and managers and required to pay 10,000 pounds towards costs.</p>
<p>Gamby's registration as a director has been suspended for a year from March 15, 1996 and he has been required to pay 5,000 pounds costs, the SFA said. ($1=.6415 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
