<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="155612" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, NOV 4 - SUNDAY, NOV 10.</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, NOV 4 - SUNDAY, NOV 10.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>EUROPEAN UNION - 1996 European Telework week (from Monday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commissioner Fischler holds news conference on rural development (Monday).</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - European Commissioner de Silguy attends European Monetary Institute Council (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (Wednesday). Agenda includes adoption of bi-annual economic forecasts.</p>
<p>BORDEAUX, France - French President Jacques Chirac and British Prime Minister John Major meet to discuss the future of the EU and other topical matters (Thursday-Friday).</p>
<p>LONDON - Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring reviews Ireland's EU presidency (Thursday).</p>
<p>LJUBLJANA - Slovenian general elections (Sunday).</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 4</p>
<p>EUROPEAN UNION - 1996 European Telework week begins (To November 11). The aim is to raise awareness of business and work opportunities presented by telework and to provide opportunities to understand and use telework technologies. Contact: Horace Mitchell, European Telework Development (44) 1 635 253 802. Also in VIENNA, third European assembly on telework and new ways to work (to Wednesday). Main topics discussed are: getting people to work; training for life in the information society and working towards sustainability. Contact: Josef Hochgerner (43) 1 4950 442 42.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Fischler holds news conference on rural development at 1215/1115 GMT. Venue: European Commission Breydel building, press room.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission DG IA hosts conference on &quot;Achievements, problems and challenges of reforms in social security in the central and eastern European countries&quot; (to Wednesday). News conference on Tuesday at 1815/1715 GMT. Venue: Palace Hotel. Contact: Helene Bourgade (322) 675 2626.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committee meets:</p>
<p>(1500/1400 GMT) Inquiry into Fraud in Transit.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Cooperation Committee for Tool Industries holds news briefing on &quot;Pre trans-Atlantic business dialogue&quot; (1030/0930 GMT). Venue: Brussels-Europe liaison bureau, 63 avenue d'Auderghem. Contact: Hill and Knowlton, George Ellis Ruano (322) 640 0495.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Renewable Energy Centers Agency (EUREC) holds news conference on &quot;Renewable energy means business&quot; (1100/1000 GMT). Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: Geert Palmers, EUREC (32) 16 281 522.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG (MODIFIED ITEM) - Tourism Council has been CANCELLED. No other date available yet.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner van den Broek and MEPs Leo Tindemans and Simone Veil hold joint news conference on the publication of &quot;Unfinished peace&quot; (1215/1115 GMT). Venue: European Commission Breydel building, press room.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner de Silguy attends European Monetary Institute Council.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Entente International Communication organises &quot;European employment week '96&quot; conference (1000/0900 GMT) (to Thursday). Main issues discussed: new technology and job creation; social and urban innovations for job creation; more undertakings and small firms - more jobs. Speakers include: European Commissioner Flynn and Commission President Santer. Contact: Laurence Fontaine, Entente International Communication (322) 502 1558.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - The European Association of Aerospace Industries (AECMA) holds conference on &quot;The future of the European aerospace industry&quot; (0900/0800 GMT). Agenda includes: aerospace and defence; the aerospace industry: a vital contribution to Europe's mobility; the role of space for Europe's development; aerospace: a technology driver; summary: EU policy for aerospace. Speakers include: European Commission President Santer and European Commissioner Bangemann. Venue: EP, Espace Leopold. Contact: European Service Networks (ESN) (322) 646 4020.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IBC Legal Studies and Services Ltd. hold third annual conference on &quot;EC Competition law&quot; (0845/0745 GMT) (and Tuesday). Venue: Radisson SAS Hotel. Contact: Holly Barton, IBC Legal Studies and Services Ltd. (44) 171 637 4383.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Transport Safety Council (ETSC) holds conference on &quot;Low-cost/high-return engineering measures for road accident reduction&quot; (0930/0830 GMT). Venue: Dorint Hotel. Contact: ETSC (322) 230 4106.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - CENELEC holds conference on &quot;Standards on trial: case studies in European standardisation&quot; (0900/0800 GMT) (and Wednesday). Venue: Sheraton Hotel. Contact: Annick Colman, CENELEC (322) 519 6889.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (0930/0830 GMT). Commission due to release bi-annual economic forecasts.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EP President Klaus Haensch meets EP bureau and political group leaders in order to decide on number of measures to reform the allowance system for MEPs. Contact: Angelina Hermanns (322) 284 3926.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 7</p>
<p>CORK, Ireland - European Commission hosts European conference on &quot;Rural development&quot; (to Saturday). Discussions will focus on the future prospects for the Union's rural development policy. This policy seeks to address the challenges faced by rural areas in a way that considers all economic sectors and aspects of rural life and builds on their strengths.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(1430/1330 GMT) Budget;</p>
<p>Institutional.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Gabon Economic and Social Committee President Okemvele Nkogho holds news conference at 1200/1100 GMT. Venue: ACP House, 451 avenue Georges Henri. Contact: ACP House (322) 743 0600.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Voice holds conference on &quot;What future for industrial liberalisation in Europe?&quot; (0915/0815 GMT). Main topics discussed: European Commissioner Van Miert speaks on &quot;The future of competition policy in Europe&quot;; Commissioner Bonino speaks on &quot;Implications of liberalisation for consumers&quot;; discussions on how companies are facing up to a liberalised single market and debate on industrial liberalisation and competition. Venue: SAS Radisson Hotel. Contact: IBC technical Services (44) 171 453 2700.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Trade Union Confederation (ETUC) holds conference on &quot;Social protection&quot; (and Friday). Venue: ETUC. Contact: ETUC (322) 224 0411.</p>
<p>BORDEAUX, France (EXPANDED ITEM) - French President Jacques Chirac and British Prime Minister John Major meet (and Friday); main discussions focus on the future of the EU, the situation in Bosnia and other topical subjects.</p>
<p>LONDON - Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring reviews Ireland's EU presidency.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 8</p>
<p>MOSCOW (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner van den Broek attends official visit to Russia with Troika of foreign ministers from past, present and future EU presidencies.</p>
<p>CHICAGO - Transatlantic Business Dialogue (TABD NEWS) holds conference (and Saturday) to discuss transatlantic trade relations and develop creative solutions to remaining barriers to transatlantic trade. Speakers are: US Commerce Secretary Mickey Kantor, European Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and European Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann. Contact: Stephen Johnston, EU Contact Point (322) 548 0693.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 9</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 10</p>
<p>LJUBLJANA - Slovenian general elections; poll is Slovenia's third multi-party election and second since the country declared independence from the former Yugoslav federation in 1991.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
