<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15560" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain &quot;surprised&quot; by U.S. open skies rebuff.</title>
<headline>Britain &quot;surprised&quot; by U.S. open skies rebuff.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain said it was surprised by a U.S. decision on Tuesday to call off &quot;open skies&quot; talks on freeing up competition in the transatlantic airline market, but it left the way open for a new meeting to be arranged.</p>
<p>The future of the talks are critical to the proposed alliance between British Airways and American Airlines since an open skies agreement to free up transatlantic competition is a necessary condition for approving their tie-up.</p>
<p>British Airways said it believed the breakdown was only temporary and a deal would be cut sooner or later.</p>
<p>&quot;We are sure that the delay is only temporary,&quot; a company spokesman said. &quot;Both sides are committed, on the right terms, to deliver an open skies agreement. It's a bold and imaginative objective and inevitably given the scale of what is being attempted some complications were inevitable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The U.S. side has a longstanding request for all U.S. airlines to have access to London Heathrow, Europe's busiest and most popular landfall.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite surprised at their reaction to our proposals which we thought went quite a long way towards opening access to Heathrow...But both sides remain in touch,&quot; said a British Department of Transport spokeswoman.</p>
<p>Previous efforts at getting open skies have foundered on the Heathrow issue and a demand by Britain for the U.S. to lift its 25 percent ceiling on foreign ownership of its airlines.</p>
<p>But airline industry sources said on Tuesday that it was believed a U.S. demand for onward &quot;fifth freedom&quot; rights for its airlines to fly from Britain to third countries was proving to be a major hurdle in talks this time.</p>
<p>They also said there may have been some confusion over what this week's meeting was expected to achieve.</p>
<p>Earlier the U.S. Department of Transportation (DoT) said it had called off the meeting due to be held in Washington on Wednesday and Thursday after disappointment with the latest British proposals which it received last Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK proposal that was provided fell so far short of providing the essential elements of an open skies agreement, it did not provide the basis for discussion,&quot; a DoT spokesman said.</p>
<p>But he said the two sides remained in touch and that the United States was ready to resume negotiations if &quot;the basis for productive talks can be developed.&quot;</p>
<p>Various airline sources said this week's meeting was first billed as an interim session focusing on technical issues but last week U.S. negotiators were then led to believe the meeting would explore possibilities for a compromise on the main deal.</p>
<p>According to the sources this was because British officials made a request that their U.S. counterparts should not brief their airlines on how the talks were going, as they normally do, and said it would make some constructive proposals.</p>
<p>But in the event none were forthcoming when officials got Britain's proposed agenda for the meeting last Friday, which the sources said focused on trying to agree ways of policing an open market to ensure fair competition for smaller carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. side had hoped for a compromise proposal so when it (the agenda) arrived they were disappointed...It all looked rather stale,&quot; a source with a U.S. airline said.</p>
<p>Britain's Department of Transport routinely declines to comment on the progress of the talks, arguing that it would be tantamount to negotiating through the media.</p>
<p>BA's domestic long-haul rival Virgin Atlantic said on Tuesday that it was disappointed the talks had broken down but it deplored the idea that this week's meeting might have had a hidden agenda to discuss substantive issues in secret.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks this week were going to be conducted behind closed doors when we were told they were merely procedural,&quot; said Virgin's chief spokesman, Will Whitehorn.</p>
<p>&quot;We have always said that negotiations affecting so many British and American consumers should be conducted in an open forum,&quot; he said. &quot;It is our belief that all airlines and the public in general should be kept informed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
