<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15567" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Most Euro bourses down, led by London.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Most Euro bourses down, led by London.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most European bourses declined in early trade on Tuesday, weighed down by a poor performance on Wall Street, with London falling the most after a hitting a new peak last Friday.</p>
<p>New York's negative close on Monday also unsettled the dollar, already hit by uncertainty over Tokyo's monetary direction ahead of an important survey Japanese economic survey out on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Stocks in London started the week badly after a three-day weekend, slipping 0.3 percent. The bourse hit a string of records last week, culminating in Friday's trading high of 3,911.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people are still away... A lot of positions might have been unwound over the weekend. It was the squeeze that kept it going last week and on Friday it was quite evident that a lot of people were trying to level their books,&quot; said a senior trader.</p>
<p>A lack of scheduled economic and company news is likely to cap activity in a traditionally slack holiday period.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average slipped nearly 29 points to 5,694 in one of the slowest trading days of 1996 as U.S. Treasuries again came under pressure.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, German shares were unsettled by Wall Street's close and investors lacked direction in the absence of any major indicators to guide the market.</p>
<p>Floor trading fell at the start then struggled just into positive territory later. Stocks on the computerised IBIS index were slightly down. Dealers hoped volumes would pick up after reaching a year's low on Monday because of London's closure.</p>
<p>French shares opened weaker for the second day running amid growing unease about a difficult autumn for the government which also weighed on the franc, dealers said.</p>
<p>Bond prices were weaker and the franc was quoted at 3.4210 per mark for the first time since August 13 as worries about the government's autumn budget and a weak U.S. currency lifted the mark and squeezed French investments.</p>
<p>The dollar, which dropped sharply on Monday because of jitters over the Japanese survey, weakened further against the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;The weakness of the dollar is, as ever, boosting the mark in Europe and this will be exacerbated by budget concerns as negotiations get underway in several European countries,&quot; said Klaus Baader, senior currency economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell. Foreign exchange markets are awaiting the The Bank of Japan's Tankan report on future business expectations, considered an important pointer to the country's monetary policy stance. If it points to weakness in the economy, the report will help the dollar regain some lost ground as speculation of a near-term rise in Japanese interest rates will evaporate.</p>
<p>The Japanese discount rate is currently at a record low of 0.5 percent. The mark was firming against European currencies as worries about forthcoming budgets undermined currencies such as the French franc, down at 3.4213 per mark from Monday's 3.4155.</p>
<p>The Swedish crown was down at 4.4645 per mark against 4.4510 late Monday with the Riksbank cutting its repo rate by 15 basis points to 5.25 percent.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.4742 marks and 107.75 yen compared with 1.4789 marks and 107.55 yen at the London close on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The London stock market was down 11.1 points to 3896.4.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 3.11 points to 2,017.31.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was up 1.96 points at 2,554.32.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold opened stronger at $389.35 an ounce, compared to Monday's close of $388.75 on international markets. Silver was up five cents at $5.28.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
