<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15575" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: HD-YUGOSLAVIA-PRIVATISATION.</title>
<headline>HD-YUGOSLAVIA-PRIVATISATION.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Filipovic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian media say the government is preparing to sell off parts of the state post and telecommunications company but officials have yet to issue any public statement outlining their plans.</p>
<p>Belgrade newspapers are full of speculation that Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic has promised that advisers from NatWest Markets of Britain would help launch the privatisation of some parts of the company.</p>
<p>A spokesman for NatWest Markets in London declined to confirm this. All he said was that his company was an adviser to the government and that the general subject of privatisations was being examined.</p>
<p>&quot;Natwest Markets, as advisers to the government, are looking into potential privatisations,&quot; the spokesman said without detailing which possible privatisations were being studied.</p>
<p>An analyst familiar with the company told Reuters in Belgrade on Tuesday &quot;Something has started moving and it is certain that the PTT is about to restructure. But when and in what way nobody in the PTT knows.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Only some parts of telecommunications could be privatised. But not strategic sectors, such as the fibre optic cable network, which is a reliable source of budget income,&quot; said the analyst, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Serbia's ruling Socialists have been reluctant so far to join the rest of Eastern Europe in privatising state-run monopolies, and economists cautioned it was unlikely any sweeping change was on the horizon.</p>
<p>Before any division of the PTT could be sold off, Serbia first needed to adopt laws on telecommunications and specific rules for foreign investors, he added.</p>
<p>Experts from Belgrade's CES-Mecon economic institute, with the help of NatWest Markets, are preparing a study on privatising the PTT, analysts said.</p>
<p>The government has also selected CES-Mecon and Price Waterhouse to conduct an audit of the Serbian PTT, which would take at least two months, they said.</p>
<p>The director of CES-Mecon declined to comment on the project which has been shrouded in secrecy.</p>
<p>Several prominent economic institutes in Belgrade have been chosen to study privatising two other infrastructure giants -- the oil and power monopolies, analysts said.</p>
<p>Mila Korugic of EKI Rating said privatising the PTT was a daunting task and probably could not be carried out anytime soon.</p>
<p>&quot;But if it happened, it would signal that Yugoslavia is also close to a deal with commercial creditors of the so-called London club on refinancing its debt and that the country is about to get its first credit rating,&quot; Korugic said.</p>
<p>Independent economists accuse the Serbian government of taking an overly secretive and cautious approach to privatisation which will fail to generate the foreign capital necessary to revive the ruined economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Serbia has the necessary legal environment but it lacks a an aggressive policy by the ruling Socialist party using new models of privatisation,&quot; said Aleksandar Vlahovic, management consulting director of the Belgrade-based Economic Institute.</p>
<p>Serbia adopted its first law on the &quot;transformation of ownership&quot; in August 1991 but has failed to make any real progress since.</p>
<p>Officials say it is still too early to talk about speeding up the process, but sources close to the ministry of industry say the government will discuss unspecified amendments to the law on ownership transformation this week.</p>
<p>Belgrade economists say the government should consider privatising large chunks of the state-owned economy instead of a few tentative steps in major industries.</p>
<p>Privatisation is crucial for cash-starved Serbian companies to obtain working capital and kick-start idle production capacities, local and Western analysts say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
