<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15572" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadians take issue with world fastest man title.</title>
<headline>Canadians take issue with world fastest man title.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Canadian newspaper publisher is mounting a campaign to strip U.S. sprinter Michael Johnson of his title as the world's fastest man.</p>
<p>Ian Oliver, publisher of the Oakville Beaver near Toronto, said on Tuesday he would start publishing ads in the USA Today newspaper to push his view that Canadian runner Donovon Bailey is actually the fastest man alive.</p>
<p>Bailey, who comes from Oakville, wowed Canada with his record-smashing victory in the 100-meter race at the Atlanta Olympics. Johnson, from Dallas, won the 200- and 400-meter races, setting a new record in the 200-meter competition.</p>
<p>Oliver said he became angry when NBC television commentators began calling Johnson the world's fastest man, a title he said traditionally goes to the winner of the 100-meter race.</p>
<p>&quot;I was getting angry at the way NBC was covering the Olympics,&quot; he said. &quot;The way anybody who wasn't American didn't really count.&quot;</p>
<p>Oliver said so far he has received C$7,000 (U.S. $5,147) in donations and thousands of calls and letters in support of the campaign. The first advertisement will run in the Dallas edition of USA Today this week, with another in the New York regional edition next week.</p>
<p>The bill for both advertisements will be about $48,000 (U.S. $35,112) but Oliver said he was sure the mounting donations would cover the cost.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
