<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15576" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak premier sacks three key ministers - agency.</title>
<headline>Slovak premier sacks three key ministers - agency.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovakia's Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar sacked three key ministers on Tuesday, the news agency CTK reported.</p>
<p>It said Slovak President Michal Kovac had accepted the firing of the economics, foreign affairs and interior ministers, and named replacements for the three.  </p>
<p>Tikhomirov said troops would resume pulling out of Grozny on Wednesday after halting at the weekend when a group of soldiers had their weapons taken. Withdrawal from some southern districts of Chechnya would be completed on Tuesday, he said. A final army withdrawal from the region would be the subject of new talks in the future, he added.</p>
<p>Tikhomirov said that over the next four days a system of joint Russian-Chechen police patrols would get under way in Grozny, much of it in rebel hands since an August 6 offensive. The two sides would also begin work on exchanging prisoners.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be no more obstacles to the continuation of our task,&quot; Tikhomirov said following the final agreement on what he called the &quot;practical implementation of the Lebed plan&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We gave each other our word that no provocations would become grounds for a breakdown of negotiations,&quot; Maskhadov said. &quot;Somehow in the end we got around to really acting on creating peace.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
