<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15577" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Audit says Hungary telecom selloff irregular-press.</title>
<headline>Audit says Hungary telecom selloff irregular-press.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The privatisation of Hungary's MATAV telecommunications company lacked vision and was irregular, the State Audit Office said according to newspaper reports.</p>
<p>The privatisation was inadequately planned and failed to consistently represent the state's interests, the Hungarian daily Nepszabadsag said on Tuesday in an article about the audit office's report, which has not yet been published.</p>
<p>State privatisation agency APV Rt officials were not immediately available for comment while the State Audit Office confirmed the report's existence but said it is not finished.</p>
<p>&quot;The report is confidential and has yet to be completed and submitted to the parliament,&quot; said Peter Divinyi of the Audit Office's press department.</p>
<p>According to the newspaper, the report says that after the first stage of MATAV's privatisation when German-American consortium MagyarCom acquired a 30 percent stake in the company for 87.5 billion forints ($580.5 million) , the state ploughed another 40 billion forints into it, giving the buyers a more valuable company.</p>
<p>In addition, the minority owner had rights normally reserved to majority owners.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom and Ameritech own 50 percent each of the joint venture MagyarCom.</p>
<p>The drive for immediate state income led to a closed second round of privatisation, when instead of a bourse listing and an open tender, the minority owners could buy a further 37 percent stake in MATAV, the report said.</p>
<p>The majority owner is registered in the Cayman Islands, but Hungarian corporate law does not recognise off-shore consortiums. Thus, it is unclear how the company will repay the state-guaranteed loans.</p>
<p>As Hungary's biggest telecommunications company, MATAV is obliged by law to meet some national security requirements. These seemed to have been overlooked during privatisation, the report said.</p>
<p>MATAV, the monopoly holder of national cable telecommunications, could also lose some 20 billion forints as a result of its investments in loss-making local telecommunications companies, the report said.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 266 2410 ($ = 150.7 Hungarian Forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
