<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15578" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miss. Chemical to buy First Miss unit.</title>
<headline>Miss. Chemical to buy First Miss unit.</headline>
<dateline>YAZOO CITY, Miss. 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mississippi Chemical Corp. said Tuesday it agreed to acquire First Mississippi Corp.'s fertiliser operations in a deal valued at about $297 million, including debt.</p>
<p>Mississippi Chemical said it will acquire FirstMiss Fertiliser, which operates through its AMPRO Fertiliser subsidary, and a 50 percent interest in Triad Chemical.</p>
<p>Mississippi Chemical already owns the remaining 50 percent stake in Triad, which owns an anhydrous ammonia plant in Louisana.</p>
<p>Mississippi Chemical said it will also acquire a 50 percent stake in an ammonia storage terminal in Pasadena, Texas, and a 50 percent stake in a partnership which owns 11 ammonia barges.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of First Mississippi's fertiliser operations is of great strategic importance to Mississippi Chemical,&quot; said Mississippi Chemical Chief Executive Charles Dunn. &quot;The consolidation of the AMPRO and Triad facilities creates one of the premier nitrogen complexes in North America.&quot;</p>
<p>Mississippi Chemical said the acquisition of the remaining 50 percent of Triad will double its urea sales to 560,000 tons a year.</p>
<p>FirstMiss Fertiliser posted fiscal 1996 operating income of about $65 million on sales of about $224 million.</p>
<p>Under the acquisition agreement, First Mississippi will spin off its non-fertiliser operations to its shareholders. Mississippi Chemical will then merge with First Mississippi's fertiliser operations in a tax-free deal that is expected to close in December.</p>
<p>Each share of First Mississippi common stock will be exchanged for about 0.335 shares of Mississippi Chemical common stock. At that ratio, First Mississippi shareholders will be issued about 6.9 million Mississippi Chemical shares, or about 25 percent of the combined company.</p>
<p>FirstMiss Fertiliser has an equity value of about $147 million, and will have about $150 million in outstanding debt at the deal's closing, Mississippi Chemical said.</p>
<p>The deal remains subject to shareholder and regulatory approval.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YAZOO CITY, Miss."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
