<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15580" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cow's milk not linked to childhood diabetes-report.</title>
<headline>Cow's milk not linked to childhood diabetes-report.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fears that giving cow's milk to infants increases the risk of the child developing diabetes are probably unfounded, a study published on Tuesday said.</p>
<p>Researchers at the University of Colorado at Denver found babies under the age of three months who consumed proteins found in cow's milk were not more likely to develop a type of autoimmune disorder that is an early predictor of diabetes.</p>
<p>The authors of the study, which was published in this week's Journal of the American Medical Association, said it disputed previous reports that showed a 60 percent increased risk of diabetes from cow's milk.</p>
<p>The Colorado researchers screened 253 children from 171 families identified to be at risk for insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. No connection was found between cow's milk and the 18 cases of B-cell autoimmunity that were uncovered, study author Jill Norris said.</p>
<p>Scientists do not understand what triggers autoimmune diseases, believing it to be an interaction of several genes and the environment, University of Florida pathologists Desmond Schatz and Noel Maclaren wrote in an accompanying editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;Cow's milk has many valuable nutrients and forms a critical part of the diet of many infants and children throughout the world. Thus, feeding practices that exclude cow's milk should not be adopted without a strong scientific indication. In our opinion, such an opionion has not been clearly established,&quot; they wrote.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
