<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15589" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ingram Micro names Jerry Stead chairman.</title>
<headline>Ingram Micro names Jerry Stead chairman.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ingram Micro Inc., the world's largest distributor of microcomputer products, Tuesday named Jerre Stead chairman and chief executive, effective immediately.</p>
<p>Stead is the former chairman and chief executive officer of Legent Corp. before its acquisition by Computer Associates International Inc. and of AT&amp;T Corp.'s Global Information Solutions (NCR Corp.).</p>
<p>Stead replaces Lindwood Lacy, who left in May due to &quot;irreconcilable differences&quot; over how the $1.8 billion company would be run in its final months before a planned spin-off from its parent, Nashville-based Ingram Industries Inc.</p>
<p>The company said plans for the spin-off, which will come through a 20 million-share initial public offering of stock, are unchanged. The shares are expected to sell for $14 to $16 each. Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. Inc. is the lead underwriter.</p>
<p>Ingram is awaiting a favourable ruling from the Internal Revenue Service on whether the spin-off would be tax-free. Once the IRS ruling is received, plans for the offer will be finalised, the company said.</p>
<p>Industry experts believe the initial public offering, which will likely come in September, will be well received and that Stead's naming as chief executive should boost expectations for the offering by soothing management concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term, it helps,&quot; said Manish Shah, publisher of IPO Maven, a leading research publication. &quot;but the company will still have to prove itself in the market every day.&quot;</p>
<p>Stead, 53, brings a solid background in the computer and electronic information industries to Ingram Micro. He helped guide Legent's $1.8 billion sale in 1995 to Computer Associates, a top rival in mainframe software development.</p>
<p>He also led several of AT&amp;T's units. including the $8.5 billion Global Information Solutions unit and the Global Business Communications Systems group, which he turned into a profitable unit after it was a money loser for years.</p>
<p>But some industry experts question whether his skills in leading manufacturing companies will transfer well to Ingram Micro's focus on computer distribution and wholesale markets.</p>
<p>Under Lacy's 11 years of leadership, Ingram Micro grew to one of the world's largest distributors of computer products with annual sales of $8.6 billion and net income of $84.3 million in 1995. By contrast, in 1991 the company generated net sales of $2.0 billion and income of $30.2 million.</p>
<p>With the slowdown in the growth of computer product sales this year, however, some market experts believe investors may initially stay away from Ingram Micro's shares until they can judge the health of the company from its Christmas sales.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
