<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15594" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lumber, cotton, grains close higher.</title>
<headline>Lumber, cotton, grains close higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lumber prices rose to the highest level in nearly 2-1/2 years and cotton prices jumped Tuesday on worries that Hurricane Edouard may hit the East Coast and parts of the southeastern United States in coming days.</p>
<p>In other markets, grains also rose on crop worries but coffee and crude oil prices fell. The Commodity Research Bureau index of 17 futures fell 0.57 point to 249.76.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Mercantile Exchange September lumber closed $3.00 higher at $413.90 for 1,000 board feet after rising to a $414.50, the highest futures price since March 11, 1994.</p>
<p>Prices for plywood and other lumber materials have climbed this week on concern that hurricanes in the Atlantic Ocean such as Edouard will damage East Coast buildings and lead to more construction activity, fuelling demand for wood.</p>
<p>&quot;Hurricanes are stacked up like bowling balls out there,&quot; said Jim Elrod, a trader with Pacific Futures Trading.</p>
<p>Edouard, packing winds of up to 130 miles an hour, was 1,200 miles east of Miami on Tuesday. The storm was heading north of the Leeward Islands in the Caribbean but forecasters said it was too early to say if Edouard would hit land.</p>
<p>&quot;It is simply too early to predict whether this storm will make landfall along the East Coast,&quot; said Smith Barney meteorologist Jon Davis.</p>
<p>But prices jumped at the New York Cotton Exchange on worries that Edouard's impact could damage the big cotton crop now maturing in southeastern states. Cotton for December delivery rose 2.31 cents to 76.76 cents a pound.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point everyone is just being cautious,&quot; said Sharon Johnson, an analyst with Frank Schneider and Co Inc. &quot;I don't see any other reason the market should be up.&quot;</p>
<p>Grain prices were led higher by soybeans, which is planted and harvested later than corn and faces a greater threat from frost if weather turns colder next month. The summer has already been one of the coolest on record.</p>
<p>November soybeans rose 6-1/4 cents to $7.95-3/4 a bushel at the Chicago Board of Trade, and December corn rose one cent to close at $3.48-3/4 as bushel.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a message here and the message is: the crop is not as big as some think,&quot; said grain analyst Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>At the Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York, coffee futures tumbled after a rise in warehouse stocks was reported. December coffee lost 6 cents to 119.20 cents a pound.</p>
<p>Late on Monday the exchange reported domestic stockpiles rose 4,797 132-pound bags in the week ended Aug. 23 to 39,313 132-pound bags, a small but encouraging sign that supply tightness may be easing up.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices fell, shrugging off possible new delays in the sale of Iraqi crude oil under a deal with the United Nations this summer.</p>
<p>October crude oil lost 6 cents to $21.56 a barrel at the New York Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>Relatively high prices for oil have surpised investors and analysts who had predicted weakness given record output and the prospect of more supplies when some $2 billion in Iraqi exports come back in coming months under the U.N. plan.</p>
<p>After months of negotiations, the agreement was signed on May 20 but has been delayed as the two sides work out the details.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, an Iraqi diplomat at the United Nations accused the United States of hindering implementation of the accord.</p>
<p>September heating oil rose 0.10 cent to 61.13 cents a gallon and September gasoline fell 0.41 cent to 61.21 cents a gallon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
