<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15597" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil price rally stalls after hitting 4-month high.</title>
<headline>Oil price rally stalls after hitting 4-month high.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices fell slightly on Tuesday as traders mulled over their next move after a month-long rally which has taken prices to four-month highs.</p>
<p>On London's International Petroleum Exchange, which was closed for a holiday on Monday, October futures for North Sea benchmark Brent Blend crude shed 38 cents to $20.04 a barrel.</p>
<p>London's declines follow a similar slide on Monday on the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) where profit-takers pushed crude lower. On Tuesday, October NYMEX crude futures lost just six cents to $21.56 per barrel.</p>
<p>Traders said a downward correction was probably needed after the sharp gains posted so far in August. Brent is hovering about $4 above levels seen this time last year, and so far this year has averaged $2 more than 1995's average $16.94.</p>
<p>&quot;The prices are quite amazing. Especially (in heating oil) which are $36 (a tonne) above last year,&quot; said Mari Buglass, senior energy analyst at Smith, Barney.</p>
<p>The relatively high oil price has stunned many analysts who had predicted price weakness given record-high oil output and the prospect of more supplies when Iraqi oil exports return under a United Nations plan allowing Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to pay for food and medicines.</p>
<p>After months of negotiations, the agreement was signed on May 20 but has been delayed as both sides work out the details. On Tuesday, an Iraqi diplomat at the United Nations accused the United States of hindering the implementation.</p>
<p>Unexpected demand increases and fears that low stocks of heating oil in both the United States and Europe might fall short of winter demand have thwarted any big sell-off despite expectations that Iraqi exports would hit the market in weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I think heating oil will save the day both here and in the United States,&quot; Buglass said.</p>
<p>Traders will be studying the latest weekly oil stocks data from the United States released after the close of trading on Tuesday to see if the stock deficit remains.</p>
<p>In last week's American Petroleum Institute report, U.S. stocks of distillate fuel, which includes diesel and heating oil, were 18.5 million barrels below one year ago.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Aug 27	 Aug 26</p>
<p>						    (close)	(close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $20.25	 N/A</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$20.04	 N/A</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)     $21.56	 $21.62</p>
<p>Note: Brent prices from August 26 not available as London markets were closed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
