<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15590" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton proposes national literacy campaign.</title>
<headline>Clinton proposes national literacy campaign.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WYANDOTTE, Mich. 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Tuesday proposed a $2.75 billion literacy campaign for children and said he would pay for it in part by eliminating billions of dollars in tax breaks for multinational corporations.</p>
<p>White House aides said that during his speech on Thursday accepting the Democratic re-nomination, Clinton also planned to propose at a $3.4 billion package to get jobs for people on welfare, fleshing out legislation he signed last week.</p>
<p>In addition, Clinton will propose a $2 billion environmental programme on Wednesday to help clean up poor urban areas, the aides said.</p>
<p>The welfare jobs plan, centrepiece of his Chicago speech and a top priority of a second Clinton term, would encourage &quot;creating jobs in an effort to make welfare reform a success,&quot; said White House spokesman Mike McCurry.</p>
<p>Other aides said the package is expected to include tax breaks for businesses that create jobs in inner city areas.</p>
<p>The president has taken a lot of heat from liberal Democrats for signing legislation that ended the federal goverment's 61- year guarantee of welfare assistance for poor children.</p>
<p>Churning through the election battleground state of Michigan aboard his whistlestop train, Clinton announced in the blue-collar factory town of Wyandotte the latest in a series of proposals aimed at generating popular enthusiasm as he makes his way to the Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</p>
<p>On the third day of his four-day train ride, Clinton went to Bacon Memorial Public Library to say he wanted to lead a national effort to ensure that &quot;all America's children&quot; can read on their own by the third grade, or about age eight.</p>
<p>With national reading scores lagging behind recent advances in math and science, Clinton said many children needed individualized attention and called for a &quot;citizen's army&quot; of one million volunteers to help 30,000 reading specialists and volunteer coordinators who would be hired.</p>
<p>&quot;Every single, tired night a parent spends reading a book to a child is a night well worth it. Every dollar we spend bringing in people to help these kids after school with personal tutoring is a dollar well worth it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Later, the Clinton train passed through Rust Belt urban decay around Detroit, and stopped in Royal Oak for a rally. He spoke to a large, enthusiastic crowd gathered at a railroad crossing in town and accepted the endorsement of the National Association of Police Organisations, the country's second largest police union with 185,000 members.</p>
<p>The reading programme, which would require congressional approval, would spend $2.75 billion over five years, most of it to hire the specialists to help communities provide extra reading help before and after school for 3 million children at 20,000 schools.</p>
<p>Some $1 billion of the total would go to Clinton's national service programme, AmeriCorps, which the Republican-led Congress tried but failed to kill last year as an example of wasteful government spending.</p>
<p>Lest he be accused by Republicans as a big-spending Democrat, Clinton aides said he would propose $8.4 billion in budget cuts to pay for the reading programme as well as other initiatives he will announce this week.</p>
<p>But of course that did not stop the campaign of Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole from attacking the idea.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of pursuing fundamental reform -- by confronting the teachers' unions and embracing school choice -- Bill Clinton announces a new government programme and a new pot of money for the unions,&quot; Dole's deputy press secretary Christina Martin said.</p>
<p>Putting some bite into frequent administration threats to reduce so-called &quot;corporate welfare,&quot; Clinton would raise $5.3 billion over six years by limiting export-related tax breaks for multinational corporations, aides said.</p>
<p>For 70 years, multinationals that export products abroad have been able to declare half of their export profits as income from foreign sales and therefore eligible for U.S. tax breaks. Clinton would eliminate this.</p>
<p>&quot;None of these things will be popular, a lot of these things will have people who will be unhappy, but this is the real world of paying for specific savings,&quot; said Clinton economic adviser Gene Sperling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WYANDOTTE, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
