<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15599" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Volkswagen defends Saxony subsidy decision.</title>
<headline>Volkswagen defends Saxony subsidy decision.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>DRESDEN, Germany 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ferdinand Piech, management board chairman of German carmaker Volkswagen, on Tuesday defended the decision by the Saxony government to pay subsidies to the company in defiance of a European Union ban.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the decision by the premier of Saxony to grant subsidies to Volkswagen is a decision for the people and for jobs in Saxony. This is also how we view our decision to invest in this location,&quot; Piech told journalists.</p>
<p>The group was introducing its new Passat vehicle.</p>
<p>Saxony and the European Commission locked horns in June when the Commission approved only 540 million marks ($366 million) of a proposed 780 million marks in subsidies for Volkswagen to build two plants in the formerly communist east German state.</p>
<p>Saxony Premier Kurt Biedenkopf decided to hand over all the money anyway, saying 23,000 jobs depended on it.</p>
<p>&quot;Volkswagen has created jobs with a future in Saxony, a step that leads the way for the entire region,&quot; Piech said.</p>
<p>He added the subsidies, which Volkswagen will use for expansion at plants in the region, will create around 3,000 new jobs. &quot;We have got the money and we are going to invest the money,&quot; Piech said.</p>
<p>These investments &quot;will help bring this region back into line with its past,&quot; Piech added. Saxony was one of the most industrialised regions in Germany before World War Two, but suffered under the communist East German government.</p>
<p>Already investment in Saxony had resulted in the creation of some 20,000 jobs, Piech said, adding Volkswagen has been the leading private investor in the five east German states.</p>
<p>By the end of 1997 Volkswagen will have invested the entire scheduled investment volume of 3.5 billion marks, Piech said.</p>
<p>Piech said that the company was not breaking laws by investing the subsidies.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel that we are doing the right thing in legal terms, our legal expects have confirmed that we are doing the right thing, we are going by the book,&quot; Piech said.</p>
<p>He also reaffirmed comments by Saxony's premier Kurt Biedenkopf that the government did not feel blackmailed by VW's statements that the carmaker would look elsewhere to invest if it did not receive the subsidies.</p>
<p>Biedenkopf said on Tuesday he could not accept the suggestion by EU Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert that the subsidies be paid in escrow until the matter is settled.</p>
<p>Piech added, &quot;We have carried out this project as friends with people who deserve this investment in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said earlier on Tuesday he saw signs that tensions between Germany and the EU were easing over the matter.</p>
<p>He expressed support for Saxony and VW saying, &quot;The German government stands on the side of Saxony and Volkswagen, which deserves to get the full allotment of subsidies.&quot; ($1=1.4747 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DRESDEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
