<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15598" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: First two Canadian banks post solid Q3 profits.</title>
<headline>First two Canadian banks post solid Q3 profits.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two of Canada's six major banks kicked off a rush of quarterly bank earnings reports with better-than-expected profits on Tuesday, justifying recent gains in their stock prices.</p>
<p>Bank of Montreal, Canada's third-largest bank, posted net income of C$300 million ($219 million U.S.), or  C$1.07 (78 cents) per share, in its third fiscal quarter vs. C$264 million, or 91 cents Canadian (67 cents) per share in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Scotiabank, the fourth-biggest, reported a profit of C$275 million ($201 million), or C$1.04 (76 cents U.S.) per share vs. C$165 million, or 86 cents Canadian (63 cents) per share, in the third fiscal quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>In both cases, the numbers were ahead of expectations. According to the I.B.E.S. service, the consensus forecast for Bank of Montreal was 97 cents Canadian (71 cents) per share while analysts were expecting Scotiabank to post C$1.00 (73 cents) per share.</p>
<p>Canada's fifth-biggest bank, Toronto-Dominion Bank, and the smallest, National Bank of Canada, report on Thursday.</p>
<p>The country's top two banks, Royal Bank of Canada and Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, are scheduled to report their results Sept. 5.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market has been indicating that the banking earnings are going to be solid,&quot; said Dunnery Best, vice president of Canadian equities at Richardson Greenshields of Canada Ltd.</p>
<p>Investors sold off both Bank of Montreal and Scotiabank immediately after their earnings' releases. Bank of Nova Scotia dropped 10 cents to C$33.90 in heavy volume at midday while Bank of Montreal fell 15 cents to $33.55.</p>
<p>&quot;(Investors) always sell on news. Also, the banks have been very strong for the last couple of days,&quot; Best said.</p>
<p>Rolie Bradley, a salesman at Maison Placements Canada, said: &quot;Apparently the results that have come out so far are being received by the market with a big yawn.&quot;</p>
<p>Scotiabank cut its 1996 loan loss provision to an estimated C$380 million ($278 million) from last year's provision of C$560 million ($410 million). Bank of Montreal also revealed a rosier view of the future, The bank cut its loan loss provisions to C$225 million ($165 million) in 1996 from a year-ago C$275 million ($201 million) due to &quot;superior credit performance.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Bank of Montreal's strategic investments over the last three years involving Burns Fry, Suburban Bancorp and Bancomer are paying off as evidenced by the bank's growth in volumes, improving productivity and contributions to income growth,&quot; Matthew Barrett, chairman and chief executive of Bank of Montreal said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
