<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15595" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stock prices end higher.</title>
<headline>Stock prices end higher.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks gained Tuesday, led by a rebound in technology shares and a bond market rally after three days of weakness.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 17.38 points at 5,711.27. In the broader market, advancing issues beat declines 1,387 to 899 on moderate volume of 306 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury rose 10/32, or $3.125 on a $1,000 bond, lowering its yield to 6.97 percent from 7.00 percent at Monday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonds rallied on bargain-hunting after Monday reaching the critically important seven percent level,&quot; said Philip Orlando, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management.</p>
<p>&quot;But bonds are really counter-intuitive to the data we saw today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bonds rose despite news that suggested that the economy will strengthen in the months ahead, which may encourage the Federal Reserve to raise interest rates to slow economic growth.</p>
<p>The Conference Board, a business research group, reported that its index of consumer confidence rose to a six-year high of 109.4 in August from a revised reading of 107.0 in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Confidence levels about both current and future business conditions are higher now than at any time since early 1990,&quot; said Lynn Franco, associate director of the board's consumer research centre.</p>
<p>The consumers' expectations for the next six months also jumped last month, with the index at 97.7 from a revised 95.0 in July and the current conditions component rose to 126.9 from a revised 125.0 in July.</p>
<p>The index is based on a survey of 5,000 households.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the technology-laden Nasdaq Composite index surged 9.80 points to 1,149.02.</p>
<p>&quot;Regardless of whatever the stage of the economy we're in, smaller-cap earnings are far more volatile than the primary market,&quot; said Scott Bleier, chief investment strategist at Prime Charter Ltd.</p>
<p>Among technology stocks, Microsoft rose 1-7/8 to 124-3.4, ThreeCom rose 2-1/4 to 46 and Intel added 1/4 to 81-1/2, but International Business Machines lost 3/4 to 111-3/4.</p>
<p>The trading interest remained subdued ahead of the long Labour Day holiday weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone has done what they wanted to and is waiting for the holiday,&quot; said Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co. &quot;The fear is that we have seen the low in interest rates and the question now is how far up will they go.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said that stock price fluctuations were mostly isolated to special situations.</p>
<p>Philip Morris extended its rebound, rising 1-5/8 to 91-7/8 in the wake of last Friday's Indiana jury ruling in favour of major tobacco companies in a tobacco liability case.</p>
<p>The giant tobacco company's stock was also boosted by speculation that its board of directors will increase its dividend and split its shares at Wednesday's meeting.</p>
<p>Boeing rose 7/8 to 91-1/4 after the plane maker said it will boost the production rate for its new 777 jet transport to seven airplanes per month from five and analysts expect it to launch the long-awaited stretch version of its 747 jumbo jet next week.</p>
<p>PepsiCo was the most-active NYSE issue, off 1/2 to 31 on trading of 7.6 million shares. Salomon Brothers handled a huge 3 million-share block trade.</p>
<p>Olympic Financial rose 2-1/2 to 26-3/8 after jumping 6-1/4 Monday on news that a possible acquirer had indicated interest in buying Olympic Financial.</p>
<p>WorldCom fell 1-3/4 to 21 after losing 3-5/8 Monday on news of its multibillion-dollar merger pact with MFS Communications. MFS, which climbed 9-15/16 on Monday, lost 3-8/16 to 41-5/16.</p>
<p>Consolidated Freightways rose 1-3/4 to 23-5/8. It announced plans late Monday to spin off some of its long-haul trucking units. New York Bagel rose to 10-3/4 from its initial public</p>
<p>offering of $9 a share in its Wall Street debut.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 2.52 points to 666.40. The American Stock Exchange index rose 1.43 to 562.05.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks gained 1.26 to 357.15. The average share was up 14 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,535.569 up 30.086 or 0.46 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
