<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15608" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak PM Meciar replaces three key ministers.</title>
<headline>Slovak PM Meciar replaces three key ministers.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovak Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar on Tuesday replaced three ministers in a move seen by political commentators as an attempt to improve the country's image abroad as well as its economic performance.</p>
<p>At a news conference in Bratislava, Meciar announced he had accepted the resignations of Economics Minister Jan Ducky and Foreign Minister Juraj Schenk, and had dismissed Interior Minister Ludovit Hudek.</p>
<p>They were replaced by Karol Cesnek, 49, as economics minister, Pavol Hamzik, 42, as foreign minister and Gustav Krajci, 45, as interior minister.</p>
<p>&quot;Schenk himself asked to be replaced for health reasons. There was no other cause for his removal,&quot; Meciar said.</p>
<p>Meciar added that Ducky too had resigned, but gave no reason for the move.</p>
<p>&quot;Ducky will, from now on, be the personal economic advisor to the prime minister,&quot; Meciar said.</p>
<p>He said that Hudek had been sacked because of unrest among the police, adding that a far-reaching reform of the force would take place. &quot;There will be no other changes in the government,&quot; Meciar said.</p>
<p>The moves were widely anticipated following an announcement on Monday that cabinet changes were imminent, coupled with a recent downturn in the country's economic performance.</p>
<p>&quot;They could be expected following the poor performance of the ministries in question,&quot; said Lubomir Fogas, deputy chairman of the opposition Party of the Democratic Left (SDL).</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the new heads of the foreign and economic ministries o bring in a wind of change, and the interior ministry needs a general change of atmosphere,&quot; Fogas said.</p>
<p>Cesnek is a former general director of the state power producer Slovenske Elektrarne, while Hamzik is a career diplomat and currently ambassador to Germany. Krajci is an executive of the Bratislava branch of Meciar's HZDS party.</p>
<p>The three ministers and their replacements were nominated by Meciar's ruling Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS).</p>
<p>Schenk, a sociologist by profession, had been widely criticised for his failure to boost Slovakia's image abroad, particularly in the European Union and the United States.</p>
<p>Both have voiced fears that the country is failing to implement democratic and economic market reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Meciar seems to have admitted that Schenk was not able to represent Slovakia in the field of foreign policy,&quot; said Roman Kovac, deputy chairman of the opposition Democratic Union.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears that the premier had to find a scapegoat for Slovakia's failure to integrate into Western economic and political structures,&quot; Kovac added.</p>
<p>Under Ducky's two-year tenure, the country's trade balance fell from a surplus of almost 2 billion Slovak crowns ($65.59 million) in 1995 to a staggering 31.9 billion crown deficit in the first seven months of 1996.</p>
<p>Hudek's position as interior minister was hit earlier this year over an alleged tape recording in which he and Slovak intelligence service chief Ivan Lexa discussed the sacking of an investigator probing the kidnapping a year ago of the president's son, Michal Kovac Junior.</p>
<p>Kovac Junior was abducted by unknown assailants last August, forced to drink a large amount of alcohol and dumped in neighbouring Austria. ($1=30.49 Slovak Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
