<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15600" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Support grows for Lloyd's rescue, deadline looms.</title>
<headline>Support grows for Lloyd's rescue, deadline looms.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled insurance market Lloyd's of London said on Tuesday that over 82 percent of its worldwide membership had accepted the terms of its 3.2 billion pound ($4.99 billion) rescue plan ahead of Wednesday's crucial deadline.</p>
<p>The announcement came as the market awaited a U.S. appeals court decision due at 1800 GMT which threatens to throw the recovery plan off track, by giving American investors more time to think over the settlement offer.</p>
<p>It also emerged on Tuesday that New York regulators may freeze the insurance market's assets if Britain declares the market insolvent.</p>
<p>With just one day to go until the deadline for its 34,000 investors worldwide -- called Names -- to accept or reject the proposals, Lloyd's is hoping that the support shown by Names will be enough to declare the plan unconditional when its ruling council meets on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am encouraged by the steady flow of acceptances we have received since midday on Saturday. At that time 75 percent of our members had accepted,&quot; Lloyd's chairman David Rowland said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that the acceptance level will have increased yet again by the time our deadline is reached at non tomorrow (1100 GMT),&quot; Rowland added.</p>
<p>But an injunction granted by a judge in Virginia late on Friday granting all 2,700 U.S. Names extra time to consider the plan, under which they would help pay to reinsure billions of pounds of liabilities into a new company called Equitas, means success is less than certain.</p>
<p>New York's insurance regulator said it would move to seize Lloyd's U.S. trust fund assets only if Britain's Department of Trade and Industry declares Lloyd's insolvent.</p>
<p>If the British regulator decides Lloyd's is insolvent and that the reorganisation plan will work, New York will not need to take action, a spokesman for the insurance department told Reuters in New York.</p>
<p>A Lloyd's spokesman declined to comment on whether the funds might be frozen. He said the insurance market was in constant contact with the New York Insurance Department and was keeping it fully informed of developments.</p>
<p>On Monday, its lawyers were preparing for the appeal in Baltimore, Maryland, which could run to Wednesday. The acceptance deadline passes at noon London time (1100 GMT) on Wednesday and Lloyd's will know shortly afterwards if it has enough &quot;yes&quot; votes to declare the recovery plan unconditional.</p>
<p>The insurance market's leaders have constantly emphasised that the August 28 settlement deadline is immutable, because Lloyd's must shortly afterwards pass annual solvency tests both in Britain and the United States.</p>
<p>Rowland is hoping support for the plan will swell to the critical mass of settling litigants and major debtors needed to push it through.</p>
<p>But some form of limited extension should not necessarily be ruled out.</p>
<p>The number of U.S. Names electing to wait while the judge's order remains in force is likely to be a key factor in whether Lloyd's can implement the recovery proposals as planned.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the injunction, which Lloyd's hopes to overthrow, U.S. Names are not barred from accepting the plan.</p>
<p>But Payne has said Lloyd's should provide them with more information by September 23. They have until September 30 to pay funds into an escrow account, after which there remains another month in which to accede finally or not.</p>
<p>Even if the insurance market does succeed in overturning the judge's order, further litigation is still a possibility.</p>
<p>A top legal official in Colorado, which signed an agreement along with 37 other U.S. states in July ending action against Lloyd's in return for extra financial assistance for U.S. Names, said last week that it was working on a new claim. ($1=.6415 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
