<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15603" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Chemical stocks lift German stocks to higher close.</title>
<headline>Chemical stocks lift German stocks to higher close.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares ended the day on Tuesday higher, after a rush by foreign investors to buy chemical stocks helped lift the market in afternoon trade, with volumes higher than Monday's year lows.</p>
<p>Despite the continued weakness of the dollar, the IBIS DAX index, which measures all-day electronic trade in 30 blue-chip German companies, ended up 9.17 points, or 0.36 percent, at 2,563.59 points.</p>
<p>Earlier bourse trade ended with the DAX index, which measures trade in 30 blue-chip German shares, up 6.48 points, or 0.25 percent, at 2,558.84 points.</p>
<p>Chemical shares drove afternoon IBIS gains, with BASF AG ending trade up 65 pfennigs at 44.39 marks, Hoechst AG ended up 1.02 marks at 52.57 marks, Bayer AG was up 56 pfennigs at 54.16 marks and Degussa AG ended up 8.65 marks at 520.85 marks.</p>
<p>Mixed industrial group Linde AG fell after it reported an eight percent increase in 1996 first half profits to 262.1 million marks.</p>
<p>The figure was below analysts' forecasts, which anticipated increases of between 11 and 20 percent. Shares ended bourse down 10 marks at 924 marks and ended IBIS trade down 8.25 marks at 922.75 marks.</p>
<p>Shares in industrial group MAN AG surged after the company reported a 21 percent increase in group net profit in 1995/96 to 330 million marks from 272 million marks in 1994/95.</p>
<p>Dealers said the figures were as good as expected and the shares ended bourse trade up 16.70 marks at 369.50 marks and IBIS trade up 15.30 marks at 368.10 marks.</p>
<p>Tyre-maker Continental AG saw its shares go higher after it announced first half group pre-tax profit of 120 million marks compared to 58 million marks in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Continental shares were up eight pfennigs at 25 marks at the end of bourse trade, off earlier highs, and ended bourse trade up 20 pfennigs at 25.10 marks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
