<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15602" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lloyd's to tell appellate court survival at stake.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's to tell appellate court survival at stake.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London was back in court on Tuesday in a bid to overturn a U.S. court ruling that it claims threatens its reorganization plan.</p>
<p>Lloyd's was set to argue that the court ruling Friday granting a preliminary injunction blocking the plan could eventually lead to the collapse of the 300-year-old insurance market.</p>
<p>A hearing on Lloyd's appeal of the ruling was set to begin Tuesday morning in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit in Baltimore. U.S. Circuit Judge Paul V. Veimeyer said Tuesday the court would issue its ruling in the case at 2 p.m. EDT (1800 GMT).</p>
<p>At issue is Lloyd's plan to reorganize by reinsuring billions of dollars of liabilities into a new company called Equitas.</p>
<p>It is asking its investors -- known as Names -- to help pay for Equitas and has offered to forgive some of their outstanding liabilities in return for an end to litigation and their association with Lloyd's.</p>
<p>Lloyd's says investors must decide whether to accept or reject the plan by Wednesday because its ruling council meets on Thursday to determine whether the plan can be declared unconditional.</p>
<p>Such a declaration is needed because the market must meet solvency tests with British regulators by the end of the month, with the New York insurance department by Sept. 1 and with the U.S. Treasury by Sept. 30, according to Lloyd's motion to appeal.</p>
<p>More than 75 percent of Lloyd's 34,000 investors worldwide have already accepted the offer. But Lloyd's has said the reorganization plan cannot proceed without the consent of its American investors.</p>
<p>If it were to lose the appeal, a Lloyd's spokesman said it would be forced to reconsider its alternatives and consider contingency plans.</p>
<p>It said in its motion that the British government, which regulates Lloyd's, has reviewed the reorganization plan and has concluded that it is critical to Lloyd's survival.</p>
<p>It also said that excluding American Names, or even some of them, from reinsurance into Equitas was not possible.</p>
<p>&quot;Failure to satisfy the solvency tests would lead inexorably to 'run-off,' in which no new policies could be issued and the sole focus of the market would be the settlement of claims made on existing policies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In run-off, administrative expenses would increase, syndicate assets would be frozen and policyholders would file lawsuits, Lloyd's said in the motion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
