<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15601" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FoxMeyer Drug declares bankruptcy after sale falls through. [CORRECTED 20:30 GMT]</title>
<headline>FoxMeyer Drug declares bankruptcy after sale falls through. [CORRECTED 20:30 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS</dateline>
<text>
<p>FoxMeyer Drug Co., the nation's fourth-largest wholesaler of drugs, said Tuesday it filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection after efforts to sell the ailing company fell through.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer Health Corp. said last week it was in final negotiations to sell FoxMeyer Drug to a New Jersey investor group led by William F. Taggart, a turnaround expert, for $25 million in cash and securities.</p>
<p>The subsidiary accounts for most of FoxMeyer Health's $5.5 billion in annual revenue.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer did not say why the sale was terminated.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer Drug also announced the appointment of Robert Peiser as the drug unit's vice chairman and chief executive.</p>
<p>Peiser is the former chief financial officer (Corrects title from chief executive) of Trans World Air Lines and is widely credited with being the architect of that company's restructuring, said Michael Kolbenschlag, a spokesman for FoxMeyer Health.</p>
<p>The company also secured a $775 million financing package arranged by GE Capital Services as part of the bankruptcy filing, under which it will reorganize its finances.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer Drug said that although it was able to reach an agreement in June on a new and expanded credit package, recent restrictions on the terms by its suppliers forced it to file for bankruptcy.</p>
<p>&quot;As we explained in several meetings with a number of our suppliers, we believe that we would have been able to operate successfully outside of Chapter 11 with the continuation of normal trade terms,&quot; said William Estes, president and chief operating officer of FoxMeyer Drug.</p>
<p>&quot;Some suppliers, however, apparently preferred the certainty of a Chapter 11, where they knew that as post-petition suppliers they would receive priority status by the court for any new goods that were purchased,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Dallas-based company said FoxMeyer Drug will operate as usual despite the bankruptcy filing. The action does not affect the parent company.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer Health last week reported a loss of $288.4 million, or $17.27 a share, on revenues of 4 million in the first quarter. The results include a write-down of investment in FoxMeyer Drug of $238.7 million.</p>
<p>The company also faces a class action lawsuit that charges that FoxMeyer and certain of its officers and directors violated securities laws.</p>
<p>FoxMeyer's stock was halted Tuesday, a day after it fell sharply to close at $4.125 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>On Monday, FoxMeyer declined the NYSE's request that the company make a public statement indicating whether there were any corporate developments that may explain its stock activity, the exchange said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
