<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15609" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consolidated Freightways stock jumps on spin off.</title>
<headline>Consolidated Freightways stock jumps on spin off.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stock of Consolidated Freightways Inc. jumped in early trading Tuesday, one day after the transportation company said it plans to spin -off its long-haul, less-than-truckload units.</p>
<p>Consolidated was up $2 to $23.875 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Palo Alto, Calif.-based firm said Monday that the spin-off was due to rapid change in the transportation business that recently caused some of its divisions to compete against each other for the same business.</p>
<p>Consolidated Freightways Inc., which has revenues of $5.7 billion, said it will spin off the new company, to be called Consolidated Freightways Corp., to stockholders in a tax-free transaction expected to close by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The units to be spun off have revenues of $2.1 billion. They include CF MotorFreight and its Canadian operations, including Canadian Freightways Ltd., Epic Express, Milne &amp; Craighead and Canadian Sufferance Warehouses.</p>
<p>Consolidated Freightways also said that it will change its name to CNF Transportation Inc. and will include Emery Worldwide, Con-Way Transportation Services, Con-Way Truckload Services, Menlo Logistics, Road Systems Inc. and VantageParts.</p>
<p>Consolidated will continue to trade on the NYSE under the name CNF Transportation Inc. and will file for a listing for the new company.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley raised its recommendation on Consolidated's stock to outperform from neutral.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
