<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15617" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak PM Meciar replaces three key ministers.</title>
<headline>Slovak PM Meciar replaces three key ministers.</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovakia's Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar on Tuesday sacked three key ministers and immediately named their replacements, the president's office said.</p>
<p>A statement said President Michal Kovac had accepted the firing of economics minister Jan Ducky, foreign minister Juraj Schenk and interior minister Ludovit Hudek.</p>
<p>They were replaced by Karol Cesnek, 49, as economics minister, Pavol Hamzik, 42, as foreign minister and Gustav Krajci, 45, as interior minister.</p>
<p>The three sacked ministers and their replacements were nominated by Meciar's ruling Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS).</p>
<p>No reason has yet been given for the move. But on Monday a president's spokeman said changes to the cabinet were imminent after Meciar had met face to face with Kovac for the first time for more than a year.</p>
<p>Cesnek is a former general director of the Slovak state power producer Slovenske Elektrarne, Hamzik is a career diplomat currently serving as ambassador to Germany, and Krajci is an executive of the Bratislava branch of Meciar's HZDS.</p>
<p>According to the constitution, the president appoints and recalls ministers on the recommendation of the prime minister.</p>
<p>The three parties represented in Meciar's coalition government were shaken in June by bitter squabbling over privatisation and oversight of the secret service. But a full disintegration of the group apparently was avoided after inter-party talks at the end of June.</p>
<p>The new ministers will be sworn-in by Kovac on Tuesday evening.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
