<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15614" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO, Israeli minister meet on economic accord.</title>
<headline>PLO, Israeli minister meet on economic accord.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian Trade Minister Maher al-Masri said on Tuesday that Israel's Finance Minister Dan Meridor promised in a meeting to find ways to ease a crippling closure on the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>But neither Masri nor Meridor gave specifics.</p>
<p>Meridor said the two sides agreed to resume economic cooperation halted since last February by holding monthly meetings of the joint Palestinian-Israeli economic committee.</p>
<p>He added that Israel and the Palestinians would be meeting in the next few weeks to coordinate positions ahead of the September 5 meeting of international donors who have pledged aid to the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Meridor said he would study ways to ease the closure which he said harmed the Palestinians,&quot; Masri told Reuters after the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;On my part, I insisted that Israel stop violating the accord. I said the economic accord must be implemented and the closure must be lifted,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Masri and Meridor met at Israel's Finance Ministry in Jerusalem in the highest level meeting between Israel and Palestinian officials since Foreign Minister David Levy met Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on July 23 in Gaza.</p>
<p>Masri warned that if the problem  of the closure was not solved, &quot;undoubtedly economic hardships will create social problems and will have a derailing of the peace process&quot;.</p>
<p>Israel's previous government, ousted in May 29 elections, signed the 1993 interim peace deal with the Palestinians. The new government opposes trading land for peace, a cornerstone of the deal and Palestinians fear it wants to halt the peace process in its tracks.</p>
<p>Meridor said he and al-Masri had discussed general issues and had not gone into details. He described the meeting as good.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a common interest to improve the economic situation in the territories under Palestinian jurisdiction and we will work together to promote this interest,&quot; Meridor said.</p>
<p>Israel's previous government imposed the closure in reaction to a wave of Islamic militant suicide attacks in February and March.</p>
<p>The government of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, which took office in June, has continued the ban which bars tens of thousands of Palestinian labourers from livelihoods in Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;The closure in itself is a violation of the economic accord,&quot; Masri said.</p>
<p>Masri said there were over 35 Israeli violations of the general peace accord, including economic issues such as obstructing the construction of a Palestinian port and airport in the Gaza Strip self-rule enclave.</p>
<p>PLO officials said as a result of the closure, tens of thousands of Palestinian workers lost their jobs in Israel and unemployment has reached an unprecedented level of 51 percent in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, home to nearly two million Palestinians.</p>
<p>They said some economic sectors were completely paralysed and the obstruction of the movement of goods in and out of self-ruled areas harmed industries and development projects.</p>
<p>Israeli officials said the government eased the closure last month. Some 45,000 Palestinians can now work in Israel. Israel has gradually pared down its Palestinian work force.</p>
<p>Before the outbreak of the Palestinian uprising began in December 1987, some 160,000 Palestinians worked in Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
