<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15618" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia trade surpluses seen promising trend.</title>
<headline>Malaysia trade surpluses seen promising trend.</headline>
<byline>Christina Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two monthly trade surpluses and sharply slowing imports suggest Malaysia may be turning the tide in a battle to stem a current account deficit and win foreign investor affections, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Statistics Department said on Tuesday Malaysia chalked up a trade surplus of 574.1 million ringgit ($230.56 million) in June, following May's 238.5 million ringgit surplus.</p>
<p>&quot;This is generally a good figure for the market,&quot; said Jimmy Koh, an economist at analysts I.D.E.A., who said investors had expected a 200-400 million ringgit deficit for June. &quot;All in all, it should provide some bullish trend for investors to come back to Malaysia.&quot;</p>
<p>Some foreign investors have been put off by Malaysia's burgeoning current account deficit, which surged from 11 billion ringgit in 1994 to 17.8 billion ringgit in 1995 and is expected by the government to stabilise at around 17 billion this year.</p>
<p>But viewing the trade balance performance for the first six months of 1996, economists said it appeared the current account deficit may shrink even below the 14 billion ringgit level projected by private economists for this year.</p>
<p>&quot;At this pace, the current account might turn out to be lower than our forecasts,&quot; said Liew Yin Sze, economist at J.M. Sassoon and Co.</p>
<p>June's trade improvements were led by exports of 16.3 billion ringgit against imports of 15.7 billion ringgit.</p>
<p>Year-on-year, imports fell a stunning 11.5 percent in June, the sharpest decline in about 10 years. The drop was in part amplified by a high base in June 1995, economists said.</p>
<p>Exports rose about 4.4 percent in June 1996 from June 1995.</p>
<p>Economists said the sharp drop in imports was likely linked to a worldwide slump in the electronics industry, a slower pace of Malaysian infrastructure imports and an easing in consumer spending amid tight domestic monetary policies.</p>
<p>The electronics industry in Malaysia uses a high proportion of imported parts, and electronics represents the largest export earner for the country, at 18.8 percent of total export earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;The real surprise was the 11 percent import decline in June,&quot; said Ng Bok Eng, a regional economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>He said that if the trend continued, the full-year trade deficit may be well below official forecasts of 7.1 billion ringgit against the 9.2 billion ringgit gap in 1995.</p>
<p>Malaysian officials have predicted a strengthening of the country's balance of payments this year amid more prudent budgetary and tight monetary policies, encouragement of savings and improvements in its export sector.</p>
<p>In the first six months of 1996, Malaysia registered a trade deficit of 798.4 million ringgit, a sharp improvement over the 5.6 billion ringgit deficit in the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Faster growth in exports of 12.6 percent over the six months versus a 6.6 percent increase in imports accounted for the improvement, the department said.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.49 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
