<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15611" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Continental sees higher profits.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Continental sees higher profits.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's largest tyre maker, Continental AG, on Tuesday said pre-tax profits more than doubled to 120 million marks ($81 million) in the first half of 1996 and its full-year earnings would be clearly higher.</p>
<p>In a letter to shareholders, the world's fourth-largest tyre maker said the surge in profits in the half year was driven by internal cost control measures, increased productivity and a favourable exchange rate environment.</p>
<p>The increase in profits in the half came despite insecurity about Germany's weak economy and profitability improved in all areas of the group's activities, it said.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Hubertus von Gruenberg had forecast a doubling of profits at the group's annual general meeting in June.</p>
<p>Conti, whose fortunes tend to mirror those of the German car industry, said sales in the first half of the year increased to 5.09 billion marks from 5.03 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>The group said it expected sales for the year as a whole to climb by 2.5 percent to 10.5 billion marks.</p>
<p>However, unit sales in the first half of 1996 fell short of their 1995 level.</p>
<p>Earnings in the group's passenger car tyre business saw above average growth. Sales in the sector increased by 1.2 percent to 1.93 billion marks.</p>
<p>The group said profits also improved in its truck tyre division, despite a fall-off in sales of 5.9 percent to 550 million marks.</p>
<p>Sales also fell at Conti's U.S. unit, Continental General Tire, but internal rationalisation measures had improved performance in this division and it also saw a better pre-tax result than in the same half year of 1995.</p>
<p>Conti's passenger car business and rubber products unit, ContiTech, traditionally one of its big revenue earners, reported sales up by 4.6 percent in the half year and contributed 1.54 billion marks to group revenues.</p>
<p>The group had 46,974 employees by the middle of 1996, which marks a 3.6 percent reduction in the payroll from the same period last year. The group was offering 10 percent more apprenticeships than in the previous half year.</p>
<p>Conti is due to be replaced by reinsurer Munich Re in Germany's DAX index of 30 blue-chip shares on September 23.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($1=1.4747 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
