<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15615" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Rexrodt sees some de-escalation in VW case.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Rexrodt sees some de-escalation in VW case.</headline>
<byline>Peter Ehrlich</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>German economics minister Guenter Rexrodt said on Tuesday he sees signs from the European Union of an easing of tensions over disputed subsidies by the state of Saxony to auto maker Volkswagen AG.</p>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's cabinet discussed whether to file a complaint with the European Court of Justice in Luxembourg in the case, but reached no decision at its regular meeting on Tuesday, Rexrodt told Reuters.</p>
<p>The government will continue to prepare its case, but will hold off taking action for now, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The German government stands on the side of Saxony and Volkswagen, which deserves to get the full allotment of subsidies,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Rexrodt said fresh discussions would take place on all levels in the next few days, but that preparatory work on a possible complaint by Bonn would continue. Such a complaint would have to be filed by September 16, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to take advantage of the signals of de-escalation from Brussels,&quot; he said, without getting more specific.</p>
<p>Rexrodt said Bonn and Brussels needed to work out their interpretations of the Treaty of Rome, whose Article 92 says that subsidies are acceptable in regions affected by the former separation of Germany.</p>
<p>Brussels also indicated earlier this week it was preparing to file a complaint. Rexrodt said he hoped such an impasse could be avoided.</p>
<p>The row began in June when the European Commission approved only 540 million marks ($365.5 million) of a proposed 780 million marks in subsidies for VW to build two plants in the formerly communist east German state of Saxony.</p>
<p>Saxony premier Kurt Biedenkopf decided to hand over all the money anyway, because he said 23,000 jobs depended on it.</p>
<p>Saxony filed a complaint in Luxembourg last Friday. Saxony premier Kurt Biedenkopf said on Tuesday he could not accept the suggestion by EU Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert that the subsidies be paid in escrow until the matter is settled.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
