<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15619" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consolidated Freightways to spin off units.</title>
<headline>Consolidated Freightways to spin off units.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transportation company Consolidated Freightways Inc. said Monday it plans to spin part of its long-haul trucking operations into a separate company.</p>
<p>Consolidated said the move was due to changes in the transportation business that recently caused Consolidated units to bid against each other for the same business.</p>
<p>&quot;It has become clear that significant changes in our traditional trucking markets have occurred throughout the freight transportation industry,&quot; said Chairman David Moffitt.</p>
<p>&quot;These changes, which have been especially dramatic in the past 18 months, have increasingly placed our separate and distinct regional and national trucking companies in a position where they are in direct competition with each other,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Moffitt said the two companies would be more competitive as independent companies.</p>
<p>Industry analysts have expected Consolidated to attempt to spin-off or sell CF MotorFreight as the industry for less-than-truckload shippers has seen increased competition, flat yields and an overcapacity of trucks.</p>
<p>CF MotorFreight lost money in the fourth quarter of last year as well as the first two quarters of this year. The move to spin-off the business comes just months after the unit has managed to return a profit.</p>
<p>&quot;They were profitable in June and have been pretty much break-even since then,&quot; said Mark Nelson, spokesman for Consolidated. &quot;For the first couple of quarters this year and in the fourth quarter they were losing money.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is something that's been analysed internally and it makes good sense for both companies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Consolidated, with annual sales of $5.7 billion, said it will spin-off the new company, to be called  Consolidated Freightways Corp., to shareholders in a tax-free transaction expected to close by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The units to be spun off have revenues of about $2.1 billion and include CF MotorFreight and its Canadian operations, including Canadian Freightways Ltd., Epic Express, Milne &amp; Craighead and Canadian Sufferance Warehouses.</p>
<p>The new company will be virtually debt-free, the company said.</p>
<p>Consolidated Freightways Inc. will change its name to CNF Transportation Inc. and will include Emery Worldwide, Con-Way Transportation Services, Con-Way Truckload Services, Menlo Logistics, Road Systems Inc. and VantageParts.</p>
<p>After the spin-off CNF Transportation Inc. will have debt of about $450 million, increasing its debt to equity ratio from about 46 percent to 54 percent, Nelson said.</p>
<p>Consolidated will continue to trade on the New York Stock Exchange and will file for a listing for the new company.</p>
<p>Donald Moffitt will head up CNF Transportation, while W. Roger Curry, president and chief executive officer of CF MotorFreight, will head the new Consolidated Freightways Corp.</p>
<p>Shares of Consolidated rose 50 cents to $21.875 on the New York Stock Exchange. The announcement came after the close of trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
