<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15625" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Closing stock market indices.</title>
<headline>Closing stock market indices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended on Tuesday.</p>
<p>LONDON - Losses in British bank and oil shares, plus weakness in gilts, kept a lid on the FTSE 100, but the leading blue chip index managed to hold the closely-watched 3,900 level, closing 1.8 points lower at 3,905.7.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - German equities slightly higher after a listless session, during which the DAX traded in a range of less than ten points. Sentiment muted by ongoing weakness of the dollar and a lower close on Wall Street overnight, but trade underpinned by stronger German debt market. The 30-share DAX index closed at 2,558.84, up 6.48 points. In post-bourse trade the DAX index stood at 2,563.59.</p>
<p>PARIS - French shares ended fractionally weaker as unease about union unrest slated for the autumn and a weaker franc got the better of a slight rise on Wall Street. The blue-chip CAC-40 index ended 2.43 points or 0.12 percent lower at 2,017.99 after a brief foray into positive territory when the New York stock market opened higher.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares fell back from the day's highs near the end of the session to close virtually unchanged, Swiss Re and Roche were in the limelight, Re's purchase of Mercantile &amp; General Re from Britain's Prudential Corp for around 3.15 billion francs was considered a good deal. The All-share Swiss Performace Index gained 4.01 points or 0.17 percent to close at 2,380.47.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo stocks closed marginally higher, after a rebound in the morning had withered. Turnover was the lightest this year with institutional investors waiting for the Bank of Japan's (BOJ) key &quot;tankan&quot; survey due out on Wednesday. The key Nikkei 225 average finished up 26.53 points or 0.13 percent at 20,910.27.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Renewed fears about rising interest rates pushed Hong Kong stocks to a weaker close, with investors prompted to take profits after recent gains following a rise in the U.S. long bond yield. The Hang Seng index closed 85.71 points lower at 11,338.93.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The Australian sharemarket closed lower with losses steepening in the afternoon as nervous investors trimmed positions ahead of the U.S. opening. The All Ordinaries index closed down 19.8 points at 2,262.3.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - South African Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals' annual meeting address encouraged South African shares, pulling them higher to finish safely up, having nervously awaited the address, the market took heart and extended gains throughout the day. The All-share index was up 58.7 points at 6,616.1, Industrials up 75.2 points to 7,799.5 and Golds lifted 26.6 to 1,785.7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
