<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15629" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK pension funds prefer balanced management - poll.</title>
<headline>UK pension funds prefer balanced management - poll.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The top UK pension funds still prefer a balanced style of fund management but there are more specialist mandates being awarded, a survey of UK pension funds by Phillips &amp; Drew Fund Management (PDFM) shows.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted earlier this year, polled 200 funds of over 100 million stg and 18 funds of under 200 million stg. Most of them were UK-owned corporate schemes but others were local authority-owned or foreign-owned corporate funds.</p>
<p>The survey showed balanced management, where the manager is responsible for a wide range of asset classes and does both asset allocation and stockpicking, remains popular.</p>
<p>&quot;The proportion of funds regarding this as their principal form of investment management remains remarkably steady,&quot; a report with the PDFM survey said.</p>
<p>But large funds (over 500 million stg) which have had their own investment management teams in-house are using specialist managers more -- 30 percent of respondents against 18 percent two years ago. The poll has been done for seven years.</p>
<p>Balanced management is also preferred (70 percent) for the largest proportion of funds under management.</p>
<p>There has been a trend for medium-sized funds (200-500 million stg) to use two balanced managers, down from the three managers customary three years ago. Smaller funds have reduced from two managers to one.</p>
<p>The benchmarks for asset allocation are also shifting away from CAPS or WM towards customised benchmarks which PDFM found &quot;surprising&quot;. &quot;We...would withhold judgement until at least next year,&quot; the report with the survey said.</p>
<p>Last year 11 percent said they expected to change their benchmark during this year and in fact 11 percent did. A similar 11 percent are expecting to change again in the next year.</p>
<p>The poll showed balanced fund managers' performance is commonly judged by survey medians, although some use survey-weighted averages. By far the most popular outperformance target remains one percent or upper quartile.</p>
<p>But specialist managers' targets tend to be higher -- upper quartile or index plus 2.0 percent or 1.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is explained by the declining popularity of the so-called &quot;aggressive&quot; managers, particularly for UK equity portfolios, the use of which has halved to 22 percent from 1993,&quot; PDFM said.</p>
<p>The survey also shows that funds are &quot;churning&quot; managers more -- with 24 percent of respondents parting company with their managers in 1996, up from 18 percent the year before.</p>
<p>There has been a sharp fall in the use of traded options on individual equities by the funds but a strong rise in the use of hedging, which has more than doubled since 1993.</p>
<p>More UK pension funds are using global custodians -- 20 percent from 17 percent last year and 16 percent are to actively consider their custodian arrangements during 1996.</p>
<p>-- Caroline Allen, London Investment desk +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
