<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15624" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Coffee rallies, then pares the gains.</title>
<headline>Coffee rallies, then pares the gains.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>World coffee prices have been trading close around their highest for a year but Tuesday saw signs that the rally could be losing momentum. Torrential rain and gales in the world number two producer, Colombia, had aroused worries about possible damage to the crop.</p>
<p>Of more immediate concern to traders was a shortage of quality coffee available for delivery against the September Arabica grade futures contract in New York. At the New York Coffee Sugar and Cocoa Exchange on Monday, September coffee rose 4.20 cents per pound and closed at 136.45 cents, its highest close since September 6, 1995. But early trading on Tuesday saw a downward correction to around 134.00. British markets were closed for a holiday on Monday and London futures for Robusta coffee had to play catch-up. In the event, however, the market pared early gains, with no solid news out of Colombia to deter the profit-takers.</p>
<p>The London December contract stalled at $1,740 per tonne, which was a gain from Friday of $73, and ended up just $15.00 at $1,700.</p>
<p>Latest U.S. data showed that certified stocks in New York were up by 4,797 (60-kilo) bags as of August 23 to 39,313.</p>
<p>But an open position in the market of 2,089 lots or the equivalent of some 500,000 bags meant that coffee availability may continue to be tight.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the commodity sector, oil prices eased in what brokers called an overdue correction to a recent rally. London October futures for the benchmark Brent Blend crude oil traded just below $20.20 per barrel late on London's Tuesday afternoon. This was down about 20 cents on the day and compared with values above $20.75 last week.</p>
<p>But prices remain some $4 above those of a year ago, supported by strong demand for energy ahead of the northern hemisphere winter and from the booming economies of developing nations.</p>
<p>Little action was seen on Tuesday in most other commodities. London gold closed at $388.55 an ounce, up $1.05 from Friday, boosted by fund and trade buying in New York on Monday.</p>
<p>Some physical buying gave support but bullion dealers doubted if gold was set to break decisively out of its current range below $390. Industrial metals traded on the London Metal Exchange (LME) were flat.</p>
<p>Aluminium dipped as low as $1,470 per tonne at one stage but bargain-hunting emerged so that it ended barely changed from Friday at $1,482. Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) wheat futures held in a range around $4.55 per bushel.</p>
<p>Some key commodity prices at 1600 GMT</p>
<p>						Tuesday	    Friday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			 388.55	    386.95</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Oct)	  20.19	     20.62</p>
<p>(Ldn Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)    1,944.00	  1,948.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			    1,482.00	  1,478.00</p>
<p>(Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Sep)	   1,700.00	  1,685.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Dec)     999.00	  1,019.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Oct)	349.00	    352.50</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
