<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15634" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: S&amp;P affirms Volvo Finance CP ratings.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P affirms Volvo Finance CP ratings.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's said on Tuesday it affirmed its A2 commercial paper rating of Volvo Group Finance Europe BV and Volvo Group Finance Sweden AB, which are guaranteed by Volvo AB.  </p>
<p>&quot;The rating reflects the extent of Volvo's short-term financial flexibility and the group's operational performance during 1995, which was largely driven by the strength of Volvo's truck operations,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>However, as yet the unproven success of Volvo's Car's product strategy persists, as well as the overall increasingly competitive long-term outlook for its passenger car sector, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is of particular concern given Volvo's historically thin passenger car product range and weak geographic diversity in sales, although Volvo is committed to broaden its range and geographical spread in line with its new strategic focus within its automotive related businesses,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Improving Volvo's truck market position, through the modularized FH truck concept, and deepening and strengthening its market position in the passenger car market by expanding into the pre- and post-family segments are key elements of the company revised focus on core automotive activities.</p>
<p>During 1995, Volvo group saw operating profit margins before depreciation and non recurring items decreased to 8.6 percent from 9.3 percent a year earlier, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The major contributor was Volvo's truck operations, benefiting from overall good market conditions as it increased both volume and European market share. Volvo Truck's operating margin before depreciation grew for the full year to 9.9 percent on sales of 51 billion Swedish crowns from 8.8 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;However, quarterly operating income showed a steadily decreasing trend from its peak of 1.5 billion crowns in the first quarter going down to 1.0 billion the fourth quarter,&quot; S&amp;P said. Volvo's passenger car business improved sales did not translate into a better operating performance. Major factors were the negative currency movements in the fourth quarter as well as Volvo's high product development and marketing costs associated with the implementation of Volvo's new product strategy.</p>
<p>During the first half of 1996 Volvo group's sales decreased by nine percent on a comparable basis, excluding the new Construction Equipment division, due to a significant foreign exchange influence. Operating margin before depreciation And non recurring items slipped to 6.4 percent from 9.8 percent. This reduction was largely influenced by Volvo's truck business, which continued to suffer from a significant sales reduction and subsequent operating loss in its second largest market area, North America.</p>
<p>In contrast the European market saw higher sales and positive operating income, but due to increased price pressures, lower margins. Volvo's car business reported income only slightly above break even due to lower sales, lower capacity utilization as well as higher sales organization and product development expenses. Group operating income before depreciation and nonrecurring items declined by 41 percent to 5.0 billion crowns from 8.4 billion crowns, despite the inclusion of Volvo's Construction Equipment business for the first time.</p>
<p>&quot;Ratings continue to be supported by the group's improving financial profile, which will continue to profit from Volvo's ongoing disposal of noncore assets, which should continue into 1997,&quot; S&amp;P</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
