<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15630" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British strikes show unions retain clout -TUC boss.</title>
<headline>British strikes show unions retain clout -TUC boss.</headline>
<byline>Alan Raybould</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A spate of high-profile strikes in Britain this summer has shown that, despite 17 years of hostile government legislation, the trade unions are still a force to be reckoned with, the leader of Britain's unions said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Trade unionism is still around, and still capable of having a scrap,&quot; John Monks, general secretary of the Trades Union Congress (TUC), told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Mail workers have held a series of one-day strikes in a dispute over working arrangements, and London underground railway drivers have staged short stoppages for a better pay and hours deal.</p>
<p>Monks pointed out the private sector had been affected, too, with disputes at British Airways and Peugeot.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is getting better, and there are opportunities, at least for some workers, to say it's about time our interests were taken more into account by employers,&quot; Monks said.</p>
<p>Some experts believe the Labour Party's lead of around 20 points in the opinion polls ahead of an election to be held by mid-1997 has also helped restore union confidence.</p>
<p>Labour leader Tony Blair has reduced the unions' influence over the party and has refused to repeal Conservative anti-union laws enacted since 1979, but he is pledged to the introduction of a minimum wage and industrial relations changes.</p>
<p>Monks said the TUC &quot;genuinely welcomed&quot; Labour's pledge to sign up for the European Union's Social Chapter, which guarantees minimum working conditions, and other promises such as greater union recognition rights.</p>
<p>The TUC will be lobbying for a more positive attitude towards Europe from a Labour government. &quot;We stand unabashed on the pro-European side of the argument, including on the single currency,&quot; Monks said.</p>
<p>Staying outside but shadowing the single currency would mean &quot;you accept all the disciplines without the influence&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Staying outside and floating, on the other hand, would carry high risks. &quot;The likely costs include higher interest rates in this country and probably some kind of surcharge on British exports into the single market,&quot; Monks said.</p>
<p>To the annoyance of some unions, Labour has declined to fix a figure for the national minimum wage, and will instead set up a commission, with union and employer members, to advise on a level after the election.</p>
<p>The TUC holds its annual conference next month and Monks said various figures would be put forward for debate, from 3.70 pounds ($5.77) to 4.26 pounds ($6.64) an hour.</p>
<p>Another source of embarrassment for Labour will be calls for the renationalisation of the railways, or at least of RailTrack, which owns the tracks and stations.</p>
<p>Reluctantly, most unions accept that Labour will have better things to do with scarce public funds than renationalise everything privatised by the Conservatives since 1979.</p>
<p>But Monks said: &quot;There's still a strong feeling in the Congress, and that should be expressed this year, that the railways should be publicly owned, or certainly the track -- the Railtrack part of it -- should be.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We'll be making demands for some renationalisation in the rail industry...A publicly-owned railway is a popular concept and one we hope we could persuade Labour to look afresh at.&quot; ($1=.6415 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
