<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15637" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's yuppies are back on the rampage.</title>
<headline>Britain's yuppies are back on the rampage.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crowds in London wine bars spill onto the streets, raucous laughter interrupted only by the pop of champagne corks and the roar of the latest Porsche.</p>
<p>British yuppies, resplendent in red braces, shoulder pads and designer suits, were almost wiped out by the economic austerity of the early 1990s. But they are making a comeback as the stock market hits record highs, City salaries return to six figures and property prices in London bounce back.</p>
<p>&quot;Bars and restaurants are packed every night again...and the customers seem even younger and richer this time around,&quot; said the manager of a crowded bar in London's financial district.</p>
<p>A product of the 1980s economic boom, yuppies (young upwardly-mobile professionals) flourished under Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher, who encouraged the nouveau riche to flaunt their wealth.</p>
<p>Brash and super-affluent, they made a swift exit with their flash cars and filofaxes when the stock market crashed in 1987, sending City bonuses and house prices tumbling in its wake.</p>
<p>They were much maligned by the Establishment, which scorned &quot;new money' as vulgar and ostentatious. Now older and duller, the 1980s yuppies channel their much reduced salaries into unit trusts and private school fees.</p>
<p>But an arbitrary survey of luxury goods and service companies showed a new generation has succeeded them, every bit as noisy and equally keen to splash their cash in eye-catching ways.</p>
<p>TVR Engineering, British-based makers of the must-have Griffith, Chimaera and Cerbera models which fill the car parks of London's financial district, boast the waiting list for new vehicles is spiralling upward.</p>
<p>&quot;The waiting list has never been as long,&quot; said spokesman Ben Samuelson. &quot;Over the last 12 months we've doubled the size of our factory, we've doubled the workforce over the last few years and you would still have to wait until next summer for a Cerbera.&quot;</p>
<p>But he was horrified at the suggestion that booming orders were proof the yuppies were back. &quot;Driving a TVR is not about the pose. TVRs are something good to drive in... it's not a car to just cruise down the King's Road (in London's Chelsea district) in.&quot;</p>
<p>Porsche, the cars still beloved of yuppie boy-racers, report the same roaring success this year.</p>
<p>The average waiting list for some 911 models is now nine months compared with four last year, and while most mainstream car makers are struggling with flat sales in Britain, Porsche's are up 28 percent on this time last year.</p>
<p>Toasting a return of the good times requires champagne, and sales of bubbly are soaring.</p>
<p>The Champagne Information Bureau, a trade group for growers and producers, reports Britons guzzled over 60 million bottles in the first five months of the year, up 30 percent on 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumption has been growing steadily for more than three years, but it has really taken off since last November,&quot;  said director Francoise Peretti. &quot;People are buying more prestige vintage ... which is a sign they are looking for quality.&quot;</p>
<p>But she had mixed feelings about the return of yuppies. &quot;I think they are defintely back, and I don't know whether to celebrate or commiserate.&quot;</p>
<p>Sharp designer suits and posh frocks are a sartorial must for yuppies and luxury London department store Harvey Nichols is reaping the benefits of the renaissance.</p>
<p>The recently-floated shop, a firm favourite of Princess Diana, reported annual turnover up 16 percent in June and announced plans to open a new store in Leeds and a restaurant in London's National Theatre complex.</p>
<p>Competition for smart houses in prime locations has also intensified and estate agent Savills said this year has seen the return of speculative buying in the capital.</p>
<p>Turnover in central London properties is up 14 percent and a survey of buyers showed 66 percent were buying properties for use as a second home or for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Only one third were buying property for use a main home, less than half the level seen in the last two years.</p>
<p>And, since the work-hard play-hard yuppie needs to get away from it all occasionally, an exotic holiday is de rigueur. According to travel agent Thomas Cook's latest figures, the further away they can get, the better.</p>
<p>While sales of short-haul holidays were down 12 percent by June, those on long-haul routes to yuppie favourites like the Caribbean and Thailand, were up 18 percent.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
