<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15632" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Air fare row grounds Virgin's Swiss launch.</title>
<headline>Air fare row grounds Virgin's Swiss launch.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European cut-price airline Virgin Express said on Tuesday that Swiss objections to its low fares forced it to call off plans for a new Brussels-Geneva service on September 2.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been denied the right to offer the kind of low fares that have been the trademark of this company, Virgin Express chief executive Jonathan Ornstein said in a statement.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Virgin Group, British owner of the Belgian based airline, said Swiss authorities had objected to Virgin proposals to undercut by 50 percent the fares of Swissair and its Belgian affiliate Sabena</p>
<p>&quot;We were hoping to offer a regular one-way fare of 115 Swiss francs ($97) with a special launch offer of 86 francs but the Swiss authorities have utterly refused to let us fly on the basis of that fare,&quot; spokesman Will Whitehorn said.</p>
<p>Instead Virgin has rejected an offer to be allowed to set a limited-availability return fare of 298 francs -- 25 percent of the full-fare price of 1,190 francs listed by Swissair and Sabena -- and vowed to fight for the right to discount more.</p>
<p>&quot;We are certainly not planning to give up yet,&quot; Whitehorn said. &quot;We are going to have to continue negotiating with the Swiss authorities.&quot;</p>
<p>Virgin Express was launched earlier this year after British entrepreneur Richard Branson's Virgin Group bought 90 percent of the Belgian carrier Euro Belgian Airlines in April.</p>
<p>Currently Virgin Express operates from Brussels to Barcelona, Madrid, Nice, Milan, Rome and Vienna.</p>
<p>The company said the Swiss setback would not affect its plans to launch new services between Rome and Madrid and between Brussels and Copenhagen on September 5 because these enjoy the new commercial freedoms of the single European aviation market.</p>
<p>Whitehorn said Virgin also hopes to start flying from Brussels to regional airports in the Britain next year. It does not intend to fly to London because the services would clash head on with the Eurostar Channel Tunnel train service -- in which Virgin also has a stake. ($1=1.1893 Swiss Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
