<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15644" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - &quot;Eco terrorists&quot; target UK builders.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - &quot;Eco terrorists&quot; target UK builders.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ecological warfare has broken out across the British construction industry, striking some of the biggest corporates as activists give up peaceful protests and seek to hit builders where it hurts -- their profit margins.</p>
<p>Described by one British company as &quot;eco-terrorism&quot;, it is seen as the new business risk of the 1990s.</p>
<p>Famous names like Tarmac Plc, Costain Group Plc and ARC, a unit of conglomerate Hanson Plc, have all been targeted.</p>
<p>Activist groups are no longer seen by British firms as a harmless, badly organised ragbag of students and hippies.</p>
<p>&quot;You only have to see them in action at protests,&quot; said David Harding, spokesman at ARC, Hanson's aggregates company. &quot;They walk around with mobile phones and camera equipment, they communicate and gather support for demos via the Internet -- we're talking about a highly sophisticated organisation.&quot;</p>
<p>One road protestor under the codename Steady Eddie told construction journal &quot;Building&quot; earlier this year, &quot;If it comes down to full-scale economic warfare, we will aim to drive them out of business.&quot;</p>
<p>As well as financial threats, companies also emphasise the &quot;terror&quot; tactics used.</p>
<p>Costain's contract to build the controversial Newbury bypass, which runs through a conservation area, has led to violent protests delaying building, bomb threats, staff intimidation and picketing of chief executive Alan Lovell's home.</p>
<p>A Costain spokesman told Reuters:&quot;We've had all sorts of protests at the head office and the chief executive's house. But it's when it gets to the (employee) families -- that it goes across the line.&quot;</p>
<p>Tactics used by some underground groups including the cryptic Berkshire Wood Elves, which distribute leaflets with instructions on home-made explosives, are now the subject of a police investigation.</p>
<p>Other larger activist groups include Earth First, The Land is Ours, Alarm UK and Road Alert.</p>
<p>The groups have targeted specific projects like the Newbury bypass and the M3 motorway through Twyford Down in the southern county of Hampshire.</p>
<p>But they are also campaigning on broader issue such as stopping the government road building programme and out-of-town superstores which they say create more traffic, pollution and damage local communities.</p>
<p>The government has slashed its road-building spending. Although protests may have contributed to the decision it has been seen primarily as economic rather than ecological.</p>
<p>Graham Watts, chief executive of the Construction Industry Council, said :&quot;I don't think many firms involved in tendering for sensitive projects realise the impact environmental activity has on the cost of running a project.</p>
<p>&quot;But they are more alert than they were 3-4 years ago. There's no doubt it's a big issue now.&quot;</p>
<p>He says the damage comes in two forms: &quot;Tangible -- in the form of extra costs, additional security, threats to staff and the more intangible damage caused by negative publicity.&quot;</p>
<p>Watts said the cost of protesting can be heavy once the company is locked into a contract.</p>
<p>&quot;I do often hear on the industry circuit of tales where the company tenders at low margins and the demonstrations which follow means they are running the project at a loss.&quot;</p>
<p>ARC says it's not just contractors in the front line but also suppliers like itself.</p>
<p>Its own quarries came under attack after it emerged that it may be a supplier for the Newbury bypass.</p>
<p>&quot;It was called the &quot;First Battle of the Newbury bypass',&quot; said ARC's Harding.</p>
<p>&quot;We had 300 Earth First protestors invade and occupy our site. Hundreds of thousands of pounds (dollars) of damage was done in one day. Plus there was the knock-on cost of lost production and extra security in future.&quot;</p>
<p>Simon Brown, analyst at investement bank UBS, said this new phenomenon has led to a change in the way the industry evaluates project risk.</p>
<p>&quot;When talking to Tarmac about the M3 link (through Twyford Down) they made it fairly clear that their risk assessment methods have been changed and now involve a very clear environmental risk analysis.&quot;</p>
<p>Harding says others have done the same. &quot;As a result of eco-terrorism we are looking at controversial jobs more closely to see if the profit margins are wide enough to cover things like extra security.&quot;</p>
<p>For an industry already suffering from razor-thin margins, overcapacity and stagnant demand, eco-terrorism is the latest bizarre twist in the construction sector's tale of woe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
