<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158954" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's Arctic diamond mine wins final approval.</title>
<headline>Canada's Arctic diamond mine wins final approval.</headline>
<byline>Roland Semjanovs</byline>
<dateline>YELLOWKNIFE, Northwest Territories</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian government gave final approval Friday to a C$900 million ($677 million) Arctic diamond mine proposed by Australia's Broken Hill Proprietary Co. Ltd. and Canada's Dia Met Minerals Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;This project has the full support of the government of Canada,&quot; said Ron Irwin, the federal minister responsible for the North.</p>
<p>&quot;This diamond mining project is important to northerners and to all of Canada,&quot; he said at a ceremony in Yellowknife, the capital of the Northwest Territories.</p>
<p>The companies plan to build the mine at Lac de Gras, an isolated wilderness of lakes and tundra on the Arctic frontier. They were jubilant over Friday's announcement.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm absolutely delighted. We're raring to go,&quot; said Dia Met President James Eccott. BHP has 51 percent of the project and Dia Met 29 percent.</p>
<p>After the news, Dia Met's Class B stock climbed C$1.50 to C$21.75 in Toronto. BHP's American Depositary Receipts gained 25 cents to $27.125 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Final Canadian government approval was given after BHP made progress in striking agreements with the government of the Northwest Territories and aboriginal groups. The accords cover the sharing of economic benefits and environmental monitoring and protection.</p>
<p>The diamond mine would be Canada's first and the first large-scale commercial one in North America. It is expected to add C$6.2 billion ($4.7 billion) to Canada's gross domestic product over its projected 25-year life and create about 1,000 jobs during mine construction.</p>
<p>&quot;Today we celebrate. This will be the first diamond mine in North America and we look forward to sharing the economic benefits,&quot; said Don Morin, premier of the territory.</p>
<p>Jim Excell, BHP's manager for the project, told reporters after the ceremony that the Lac de Gras mine was scheduled to go into production in the second half of 1998. Preliminary site work has already started and mine construction is expected to move into high gear next spring.</p>
<p>BHP updated the estimated cost of the project to C$900 million ($677 million), compared to a prior estimate of C$860 million ($647 million). A spokeswoman said this reflected more precise cost projections as the mine moved closer to reality.</p>
<p>Analysts forecast the Lac de Gras mine will produce three to five million carats a year. A large part of its production will consist of the most valuable gem-quality stones.</p>
<p>At least two diamond mines are expected to be developed in Canada and analysts anticipate the country will account for 8 percent to 12 percent of the world's rough diamonds by the turn of the century.</p>
<p>This new production is expected to alter the world market for the gems. BHP, which controls the Lac de Gras project, said it expects to make a decision in about a year whether to market its diamonds through the fabled De Beers cartel.</p>
<p>Investors had been eagerly awaiting Friday's announcement after Canada gave approval in principle in August for the mine. Since then BHP has been in intense negotiations with government officials and local groups.</p>
<p>In reviewing progress Friday, the government said an environmental accord had been developed and was undergoing final technical and legal review. Also, a framework understanding for setting aside protected land in the area has been drafted.</p>
<p>Economic agreements give residents of the territory priority in filling jobs at the project. Also an economic benefit-sharing agreement has been signed with one local aboriginal group and progress has been made toward agreements with three other aboriginal groups.</p>
<p>Friday's news was expected to pave the way for a second mine to be proposed in the same area by Aber Resources Ltd. and a unit of British-Australian mining conglomerate RTZ Corp. Plc.-CRA Ltd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YELLOWKNIFE, Northwest Territories"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
