<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158951" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK Telecom 1st-half net seen up modestly.  [CORRECTED 03:45 GMT 4/11]</title>
<headline>HK Telecom 1st-half net seen up modestly.  [CORRECTED 03:45 GMT 4/11]</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Telecommunications Ltd is expected next week to report solid earnings growth for the first half of the 1996/97 fiscal year on improved revenues and lower costs, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>But longer term, the company's key international revenue is under threat from discount service providers, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;New profit in first half 1997 is benefiting from achievements made in second half 1996..., cellular subscribers growth and productivity growth, providing a very favourable year-on-year comparison,&quot; said Fredson Bowers, regional telecommunications analyst at W.I. Carr.</p>
<p>The company's heavy promotion of its cellular services and a voluntary retirement scheme carried out mostly in the second half last year began to bear fruit in the first half this year, he said.</p>
<p>Hongkong Telecom had net profit of HK$4.8 billion (US$615 million) in first half of fiscal 1995/96 (April-March), up 14.8 percent, and HK$9.9 billion for all last fiscal year, up 14.3 percent.</p>
<p>For the six months to September 30, 1996 (Corrects year from 1997), Bowers  forecasts net profit growth of about 15 percent. </p>
<p>Earnings per share will grow a slower 13.5 percent due to an increase in shares after parent Cable and Wireless Plc, which holds about 59 percent of Hongkong Telecom, took its dividend in scrip form last year, he added.</p>
<p>Adam Quinton, first vice president of Merrill Lynch, said in a recent report that he expected the company to report 12.2 percent earnings growth in the first half.</p>
<p>Quinton was also cautiously upbeat on the short-term outlook for domestic revenue and costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe domestic revenues will have proved relatively robust in the first half. However...line growth is running at or below the four percent level seen in fiscal 1996,&quot; Quinton cautioned.</p>
<p>The company raised its local-service tariffs an average of 3.5 percent effective August 1, 1996. But this increase will have minimal impact in the longer term, analysts said.</p>
<p>On the other hand, the growth of callback services are expected to hit the company's international-call revenue, which accounts for about 75 percent of annual net profit, according to analysts estimates. </p>
<p>Hongkong Telecom has a monopoly until 2006 on outgoing international voice telephone services. But callback services, which access a line in a country such as the United States where international dialing rates are lower, allow local users to make outgoing calls at incoming rates.</p>
<p>Hongkong Telecom still controls a small portion of incoming calls.</p>
<p>Due to the growth of callback services, the ratio of incoming to outgoing calls between the U.S. and Hong Kong had risen to seven-to-one in August from a ratio of three-to-one at the start of the year, said Bowers.</p>
<p>Quinton said the company was still likely to have achieved modest growth in international call traffic in the first half.</p>
<p>But analysts noted that the proportion of incoming calls still handled by Hongkong Telecom was unknown, confounding efforts to forecast the company's revenues.</p>
<p>Bowers sounded a cautious note for the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;HKT has to negotiate compensation for its international franchise while there is still value there to be had, because the value of the...franchise will have evaporated long before the 2006 official expiration,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
