<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161648" id="root" date="1996-11-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: TENNIS-KAFELNIKOV MEETS ENQVIST IN PARIS OPEN FINAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-KAFELNIKOV MEETS ENQVIST IN PARIS OPEN FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov, on course to become the first player to hold France's two top tennis titles, will meet Swede Thomas Enqvist in the Paris Open final on Sunday.</p>
<p>Fourth seed Kafelnikov, who will climb to third in the world rankings published on Monday, recovered from one set down to beat qualifier Petr Korda 3-6 6-4 6-2 in Saturday's first semifinal.</p>
<p>Enqvist, the 12th seed whose current form does not augur well for France's hopes in the Davis Cup final in Sweden at the end of the month, crushed compatriot Magnus Gustafsson who was suffering from a pulled leg muscle 6-3 6-2.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt I was playing really well. When you play Magnus, you have to play aggressively so he can't go around and hit his forehand, dictate the point,&quot; Enqvist said.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, I have to say Magnus pulled a muscle this morning, so he wasn't 100 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>The 28th-ranked Gustafsson, struggling with the muscle strain from the middle of the second set, saved three match points before going down in 67 minutes.</p>
<p>He explained: &quot;When I was warming up this morning I pulled a stomach muscle serving. (During the match) I probably made the wrong moves trying to protect my stomach and pulled another muscle in my leg.</p>
<p>&quot;If it had not been a semifinal I probably would not have played. I was only 90, 95 percent and that's not enough for the tennis of today.&quot;</p>
<p>Korda, French Open finalist in 1992, played well until late in the second set.</p>
<p>The match hinged on the failure of Korda, coming back from a long injury layoff and now ranked 37, to convert three break points in the ninth game of the second set that would have enabled him up to serve for the match.</p>
<p>&quot;When it was four all, till 15-40, everything went in. Then it just didn't happen,&quot; Korda said. &quot;I was just starting to get so tired... I just didn't have the energy to finish the match.&quot;</p>
<p>The Russian, also holder of the Lyon title, went on to level the match with the first of three set points, the Czech driving the ball wide.</p>
<p>Kafelnikov never looked back after an early break in the deciding set but said afterwards he had to &quot;play not 100 percent but 150 percent&quot; to beat Korda.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt he was tiring and wanted to win in two sets. Playing in the doubles takes a lot out of him. He finished very late last night,&quot; said Kafelnikov, who lost to Korda in the third round at Bercy in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;At first he was playing out of his mind, hitting winners all the time. I was just trying not to look a fool.&quot;</p>
<p>The semifinal was Korda's 11th match at Bercy since last Saturday, including singles qualifiers and doubles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
