<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162036" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>Italy: SOCCER-INTER SILENCE CRITICS BY GOING TOP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-INTER SILENCE CRITICS BY GOING TOP.</headline>
<byline>Chris Endean</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inter Milan silenced their critics on Sunday by beating Verona 1-0 to open a one-point lead in serie A as rivals Milan and Juventus slipped to surprising home draws.</p>
<p>Roy Hodgson's side, under fire after needing a penalty shootout to eliminate Austria's Graz from the UEFA Cup, had to wait until the 85th minute for Javier Zanetti's superb winner.</p>
<p>The Argentine picked up the ball near the halfway line and made a mazy run down the right before cutting into the Verona penalty area and shooting past goalkeeper Attilio Gregori.</p>
<p>The last-gasp win took full advantage of Juventus's 1-1 draw at home to Napoli and Atalanta's courageous performance at the San Siro, where champions Milan needed a second-half penalty from Demetrio Albertini to salvage a point.</p>
<p>Inter now lead serie A with 17 points from eight matches, one ahead of unfancied Vicenza and two clear of Juve.</p>
<p>In a late night match, Parma halted a run of two successive defeats with a scoreless draw at home to Fiorentina.</p>
<p>Vicenza have never gone better than runners-up in Serie A in 92 years but, until Zanetti's late goal for Inter, they briefly threatened to go top with their 2-0 win at Lazio.</p>
<p>With Lazio reeling from UEFA Cup defeat at Tenerife, the visitors went ahead in the 35th minute through Roberto Murgita.</p>
<p>The home side then hit the woodwork three times before Giampiero Maini sealed three points with a late second.</p>
<p>Despite Lazio's low position - fifth from bottom - president Sergio Cragnotti gave coach Zdenek Zeman a vote of confidence.</p>
<p>Juventus coach Marcello Lippi blamed his side's indifferent performance at Turin on fatigue.</p>
<p>The European champions struggled to break down Napoli's defence in the first half, relying on a mistake from goalkeeper Giuseppe Taglialatela for Zinedine Zidane's opener in the 43rd minute -- the Frenchman's second goal in three league matches.</p>
<p>After the break a visibly tired Juve looked a shadow of the side who overwhelmed Austria's Rapid Vienna in the European Cup and Alfredo Aglietti claimed a deserved equaliser.</p>
<p>Roberto Mancini, the most prolific striker in serie A with 130 goals, celebrated his 400th and possibly last match for Sampdoria with two goals in a 3-0 home win over Piacenza.</p>
<p>After the match, fans angrily confronted club president Enrico Mantovani, accusing him of selling their top players.</p>
<p>Mancini is rumoured to be on the verge of signing for Inter while, on Sunday, the club announced they had reached agreeent with Barcelona for the sale of France's Christian Karembeu.</p>
<p>If he does decide to go, after 14 year's service, at least Mancini is leaving Sampdoria high in the table -- level third with Milan and Bologna, 3-2 winners over Roma.</p>
<p>Gianluigi Lentini arrived at Milan in 1992 as the world's most expensive player but left this year never having fulfilled his potential after almost losing his life in a car accident.</p>
<p>On Sunday Lentini reminded Milan of what they are missing by setting up Felippo Inzaghi's shock 21st-minute opener -- his seventh goal of the season -- with a fast break from defence.</p>
<p>One down at halftime, Milan coach Oscar Washington Tabarez brought on Christophe Dugarry and the Frenchman responded by winning the penalty from which Albertini struck the equaliser.</p>
<p>At Bologna, Renzo Ulivieri was dismissed from the bench for protesting but that did nothing to blunt his tactical acumen.</p>
<p>With Roma threatening a late comeback after Abel Balbo's 64th-minute penalty had made the score 2-1, Ulivieri, sitting in the stands, brought on striker Pierpaolo Bresciani. Within minutes Bresciani struck a crucial third goal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
