<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162031" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada union warns strike possible in Ford talks.</title>
<headline>Canada union warns strike possible in Ford talks.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian Auto Workers union has warned that talks with Ford Motor Co.'s  Canadian arm should not be underestimated and a strike over differences is possible.</p>
<p>The union says it is still waiting for a response to a host of issues it has thrown on the bargaining table since talks began in earnest last Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We could end up in a strike,&quot; said Bob Such, chairman of the CAW's Ford master bargaining committee. &quot;We've given the company a full set of our demands, which reflect the pattern and issues specific to Ford.&quot;</p>
<p>The CAW, which represents 11,690 unionized Ford workers in Canada, has set a strike deadline of 7 P.M. EST (midnight GMT) on Nov. 6 for Ford.</p>
<p>Contract talks between Ford and Canada's largest private sector union continued at a downtown Toronto hotel just one week after a deal was reached to end a 20-day strike by 26,000 CAW members at General Motors Corp.'s  Canadian operations.</p>
<p>CAW President Buzz Hargrove told reporters he intends to hold North America's second-largest automaker to the pattern agreement forged during talks with Chrysler Corp. begrudgingly accepted by GM.</p>
<p>&quot;I outlined the terms of the pattern settlement at Chrysler that was agreed to by General Motors and informed (Ford lead negotiator, Donald) McKenzie that we expected to do no less here,&quot; Hargrove said. &quot;We hope we can do that without a strike.&quot;</p>
<p>The two sides are expected to face off over work standards and health and safety issues.</p>
<p>The CAW entrenched minimum employment standards, including the right to refuse unsafe work, in the pattern agreement reached with Chrysler in an effort to block changes in workplace law by Ontario's Conservative government.</p>
<p>Ford Canada has said it would like to see a narrowing of the circumstances in which an employee has the right to refuse work, to prevent what it sees as a misuse of the clause.</p>
<p>McKenzie declined to specify when or where Ford was experiencing the problem, but said it arose from workers &quot;using the right to refuse for issues that are really not health and safety issues, (rather as) attempts to frustrate productivity improvements.&quot;</p>
<p>He said issues that held up a settlement at GM, including contracting out work, or outsourcing, were less of an issue at Ford.</p>
<p>Hargrove said he was surprised by the tough stand taken by McKenzie against the pattern deal.</p>
<p>Ford Canada's major operations include a Windsor, Ontario, plant that supplies truck engines for the bulk of Ford's North American operations, a truck and van assembly plant in Oakville, Ontario, and a car assembly plant in St. Thomas, Ontario.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
