<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162033" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-NOBILO KEEPS SARAZEN WORLD OPEN TITLE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-NOBILO KEEPS SARAZEN WORLD OPEN TITLE.</headline>
<dateline>BRASELTON, Georgia 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kiwi Frank Nobilo successfully defended a title for the first time in his impressive career when he won the $1.9 million Sarazen World Open by four strokes Sunday.</p>
<p>Nobilo began the final round four strokes behind Scott Hoch, but he was on the good end of an eight-shot swing as he reeled off six birdies in a bogey-free six-under-par 66 in crisp, cool conditions at Chateau Elan.</p>
<p>&quot;My focus was brilliant,&quot; said Nobilo, who finished at 16-under 272. He received $342,000, as well as a trophy from tournament host Gene Sarazen, one of golf's all-time greats.</p>
<p>Hoch (74) limped home in second place on 276, while fellow Americans Craig Stadler (71) and Payne Stewart (70) tied for third on 278.</p>
<p>Nobilo, 36, was upset after a mediocre third round 72 on Saturday, but it spurred him on in the final round.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I was determined to play my way into the round,&quot; he continued. &quot;The last six holes I played great.&quot;</p>
<p>He did not catch Hoch until the 12th hole, which Hoch bogeyed. Nobilo birdied the next two holes to go two strokes ahead, and doubled his margin when Hoch double-bogeyed the par-four 17th.</p>
<p>Nobilo has little time to celebrate his victory. He will have tests in nearby Atlanta on Monday on both of his shoulders, which have troubled him for months.</p>
<p>A specialist examined him before the final round, and offered a positive assessment of the problem, which appears to be some sort of nerve damage.</p>
<p>Nobilo says it is possible he will pull out of some of his remaining scheduled events this year, but he intends to keep his commitment to play in the Taiheyo Masters in Japan starting Thursday.</p>
<p>Hoch, meanwhile, lamented what might have been. &quot;I didn't have it at all today,&quot; he said. &quot;I didn't play well. I was lucky to keep it close as long as I did.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASELTON, Georgia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
