<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168484" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: EU forecasts heighten Spain EMU entry debate. [CORRECTED 13:05 GMT 7/11]</title>
<headline>EU forecasts heighten Spain EMU entry debate. [CORRECTED 13:05 GMT 7/11]</headline>
<byline>Manuel Maria Ruiz</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commission 1997 forecasts published on Wednesday have done little to resolve the debate on whether Spain will meet the criteria necessary for entry into a single currency in 1999, analysts said.</p>
<p>Spanish stock and bond markets have surged in recent months amid a growing conviction that Spain, whose chances have long been seen as poor, would indeed meet the stringent requirements to join the single currency launch in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) according to the report, we will not achieve the criteria on debt or on inflation,&quot; said Juan Antonio Mielgo, economist at the Bank of America. &quot;I don't find the report very optimistic.&quot;</p>
<p>The Commission forecast that Spain's outstanding stock of debt would be around 67.1 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) in 1997, above the 60 percent demanded by the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>In addition, the Commission forecast inflation at 2.9 percent, 0.2 points above the average of the three nations with the lowest inflation rates plus 1.5 points.</p>
<p>The ratio of deficit to GDP, although low in 1996, remains high and the ratio of debt to GDP has continued rising, said the Commission's report on Spain.</p>
<p>More optimistic observers believe the debt criteria will be relaxed, considering the difficulties that the majority of countries --including Germany and France -- will have to satisfy the requirements for single currency participation.</p>
<p>Others believe the average of the best three inflation rates will exceed the 1.2 percent forecast the local press attributed to the Commission but which it did  not publish, (corrects source). This would give Spain the leeway to meet the  criteria.</p>
<p>The Commission was more upbeat about Spain's capacity to meet the annual public deficit criteria of 3.0 percent of GDP in 1997. It forecast Spain's public deficit would be in line at 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's positive that with forecast growth of 2.7 percent, the EC foresees a deficit (for Spain) of three percent,&quot; said Carmen Alcaide, analyst at Banco Bilbao Vizcaya.</p>
<p>&quot;These forecasts are positive for Spain and open the way for entry into European economic and monetary union (EMU),&quot; she added.</p>
<p>For many analysts, however, the problem lay more in inflation targets. But with strong fiscal discipline Spain may be able to reach its target on this measure, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;CPI could be around 2.5 percent by the end of the second quarter of 1997 making it possible to achieve 2.8 percent by the end of the year, a level which we consider sufficient to complete the criteria on inflation,&quot; said Beta Capital.</p>
<p>BBV's Alcaide were less optimistic. She expected the EC would be less flexible when it comes to the inflation targets.</p>
<p>&quot;Failing to complete the inflation target will be inexcusable, while the interpretation of the deficit criteria will be more flexible,&quot; Alcaide said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the progress so far (on inflation) is not totally out of line, it's still not sufficient given that other countries have maintained a tendency to reduce the rise in prices,&quot; said a monthly research report from Caixa de Catalunya.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2154</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
