<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168480" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Loewen sues insurers over U.S. lawsuits.</title>
<headline>Loewen sues insurers over U.S. lawsuits.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Loewen Group Inc is suing two insurance companies for refusing to reimburse it for costs incurred in two U.S. lawsuits, court papers showed Wednesday.</p>
<p>A writ filed by Loewen in British Columbia Supreme Court does not specify damages but the insurance policies were for a total C$10 million. The insurance companies were Continental Insurance Co of Canada, Lombard General Insurance Co of Canada and Continental Insurance Co. Loewen, a funeral home operator, claims the insurers &quot;wrongfully refused&quot; to indemnify it for costs arising from lawsuits settled earlier this year in Mississippi and Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Loewen has held talks with the insurers in hope of settling its claim out of court.</p>
<p>Loewen lost a breach of contract case brought by Gulf National Insurance Co and related parties in Mississippi last year. A US$500 million damage award pushed Loewen to the brink of bankruptcy in January before it settled out of court for US$175 million in cash and stock.</p>
<p>Loewen settled a separate breach of contract case brought by Provident American Corp of Pennsylvania in February for cash and stock. Loewen valued the after-tax cost of the deal at US$18.9 million. </p>
<p>In an unrelated case, Loewen and its top executives are also suing insurer Chubb Corp's Chubb Insurance Co of Canada over Loewen's US$25 million executive liability policy.</p>
<p>In the case launched in April, Loewen accuses Chubb of wrongfully refusing to cover costs and potential damages arising from three U.S. shareholder class action lawsuits. The shareholders claim Loewen and its officials misrepresented the lawsuits against it. Chubb, in a statement of defense filed with the court, said the policy did not cover any action arising from matters pending before May 1992. It said both the Mississippi and Pennsylvania case were pending at that time.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
