<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175047" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, NOV 11 - SUNDAY, NOV 17 (PAGE 1/4 - MONDAY).</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, NOV 11 - SUNDAY, NOV 17 (PAGE 1/4 - MONDAY).</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU finance ministers meet (Monday); main discussions focus on preparation for third stage of EMU.</p>
<p>CAIRO - The Troika of EU foreign ministers goes to Middle East; meets Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak (Monday), Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy on the margins of the Middle east conference (Tuesday).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - EP committee on inquiry into BSE meets (Monday-Thursday).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (Monday-Friday); report on television without frontiers directive (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU health ministers meet (Tuesday); main discussions focus on draft Council conclusions on Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commissioner Brittan holds news conference on access strategy to markets (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commissioner Flynn holds news conference on the Court of Justice judgment on the work time directive (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commissioner Liikanen holds news conference on the Court of Auditors' annual report (Tuesday).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (Wednesday); orientation debate on whether the EU should continue to subsidise tobacco farmers; European Commissioners Gradin and Papoutsis hold joint news conference on sex tourism.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (Wednesday-Thursday); European Commissioner Wulf-Mathies gives address on the cohesion report (Thursday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ACP ministers hold council (Wednesday-Thursday).</p>
<p>GENEVA - WTO holds conference with 48 poorest countries (Wednesday-Friday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU industry ministers meet (Thursday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission President Santer meets Uzbekistan President Islam Karimov (Thursday).</p>
<p>PARIS - Foreign ministers of countries involved in Bosnia discuss plans for two-year civilian peace consolidation programme in Bosnia (Thursday).</p>
<p>CORK, Ireland - EU youth ministers hold informal meeting (Friday).</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - ECOFIN Council (1000/0900 GMT).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Commission presentation of the report of the Personal Representatives Group on sound financial management (SEM 2000 - stage III).</p>
<p>- Preparation for Dublin European Council - Council recommendation based on article 109J stating that a majority of member states do not fill the conditions necessary for the adoption of the single currency and that therefore the Community will not enter the third stage of EMU in 1997 and that the procedure laid down in art. 109J will be applied as early as possible in 1998.</p>
<p>- Review of work in progress with a view to the European Council on the preparation of stage III of EMU. As for the &quot;stability pact&quot;, the Monetary Committee will seek guidance from ministers for its further work on questions still open in view of a final ministerial discussion at the next ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>- Commission report on the development of tax systems in the EU. It is expected to underline the need for further work on this issue, setting it in the wider context of the Union's strategic objectives, notably those in the conclusions of the Florence summit: stimulate enterprises, promote employment and a more efficient environment policy.</p>
<p>- (over lunch):</p>
<p>- European Loan Insurance Scheme for Employment (ELISE). This proposal is aimed at facilitating access for SMEs to bank loans by providing bank guarantees from the European Investment Fund (EIF) in order to ensure that their potential for job creation is exploited in full.</p>
<p>- Discussion on the progress made in the inter-governmental conference (IGC).</p>
<p>- (possibly) Discussion on the design of the Euro bank note;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Discussion evoking the question of the abolition in 1999 of tax free sales in airports;</p>
<p>- Finally VAT rate for newspapers may be raised.</p>
<p>- Other business:</p>
<p>- EIB lending mandates;</p>
<p>- Ministers are expected to address the question of the need for further macro-economic assistance to Ukraine.</p>
<p>CAIRO (NEW ITEM) - The Troika of EU foreign ministers (Italy, Ireland and The Netherlands) on official visit to Middle East; meets Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Parliament plenary session (first of five days).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1700/1600 GMT) Andrea Manzella report on EP article 49.</p>
<p>- Richard Stuart Howitt report on aid to dispaced persons in developing countries.</p>
<p>- Christiane Taubira-Delannon report on actions in developing countries for environment in context of sustainable development.</p>
<p>- Anne Andre-Leonard report on action against AIDS in developing countries.</p>
<p>- Undine Uta Bloch von Blottinitz report on the promotion of energy efficiency in the EU (SAVE II).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - EP committee of inquiry into BSE meets (1700/1600 GMT) (To Thursday).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>- (1900/1800 GMT) Foreign Affairs and External Economic Relations - European Commissioner van den Broek attends;</p>
<p>Budget;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Civil Liberties;</p>
<p>Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>Fisheries;</p>
<p>Rules of Procedure;</p>
<p>Women's Rights.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Health Council (1000/0900 GMT).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for EP and Council decision creating a network for the epidemiological surveillance and control of communicable diseases in the European Community.</p>
<p>- Setting-up of an EU-U.S. task force to develop and implement a global early warning system and response network for communicable diseases.</p>
<p>- Adoption of draft resolution on a strategy on safety and self sufficiency in blood.</p>
<p>- Draft resolution on the proposal for a Council directive on the approximation of the laws, regulations and administrative provisions of the member states relating to the advertising of tobacco products.</p>
<p>- Approval of draft Council conclusions on Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies (TSE).</p>
<p>- Draft resolution on integration of Community policy requirements in the health protection.</p>
<p>- European health card.</p>
<p>CAIRO (NEW ITEM) - The Troika of EU foreign ministers (Italy, Ireland and The Netherlands) meets Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy on the margins of the Middle east conference.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Brittan holds news conference on access strategy to markets (1215/1115 GMT).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Flynn holds news conference on the Court of Justice judgment on the work time directive (1230/1130 GMT). Venue: Council building, press room.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Liikanen holds news conference on the Court of Auditors' annual report (1300/1200 GMT).</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Marin meets EP President Klaus Haensch.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Parliament plenary session (second of five days).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Presentation of Court of Auditors annual report and insurance declaration - general budget 1995.</p>
<p>- Gerardo Gaelote Quecedo and Karsten Hoppenstedt joint report on television without frontiers directive.</p>
<p>- Jose Antonio Escudero-Lopez report on the return of cultural goods illegally taken out of a member state.</p>
<p>- Votes on:</p>
<p>- Helena Torres Marques report on equal treatment of men and women.</p>
<p>- Report without debate: ADAM.</p>
<p>- Joint discussion on:</p>
<p>- Ludivina Garcia Arias XXV report on 1995 competition policy.</p>
<p>- Carlo Secchi report on the single market in 1995.</p>
<p>- Bernhard Rapkay report on concentration controls between companies.</p>
<p>- Heidi Hautala report on industrial restructuring and delocalisations.</p>
<p>- Wilfried Kuckelkorn report on the grant of guarantee loans for SMEs investments for job creation.</p>
<p>- (1730/1630 GMT) Commission question time.</p>
<p>- (2100/2000 GMT) Christian Cabrol report on surveillance networks in transmisible diseases in the EU.</p>
<p>- Lone Dybkjaer report on a political and Community action programme &quot;Towards sustainable development&quot;.</p>
<p>- Ruebig report promoting NGOs mainly in defence and environment.</p>
<p>- Paul Lannoye report evaluating the effect of certain public and private projects on environment.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(1700/1600 GMT) Economic;</p>
<p>Energy;</p>
<p>Social Affairs;</p>
<p>Budget and Environment - European Commissioner Brittan attends.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Economic and Social Committee holds audition on &quot;Cooperation with third countries in research&quot; (1030/0930 GMT). Venue: ECOSOC. Contact: ECOSOC (322) 546 9764.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 13</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (0830/0730 GMT).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Orientation debate on whether the EU should continue to subsidise tobacco farmers.</p>
<p>- Environment impact assessment evaluation.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Brittan communication on common policy in standards and conformity evaluation.</p>
<p>- European Commissioners Gradin and Papoutsis communication on sex tourism - followed by a news conference.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commissioner de Silguy communication on European Investment Bank loans.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Parliament plenary session (third of five days).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Joint discussion on WTO:</p>
<p>- Peter Kittelmann report on the global international trade challenge - access strategy to EU markets.</p>
<p>- Peter Kittelmann report on strengthening of cooperation and regulations at an international level.</p>
<p>- Oral question on food biosafety.</p>
<p>- Wolfgang Kreissl-Doerfler report on trade and environment.</p>
<p>- Moniz report on international development in textiles and clothing.</p>
<p>- Luigi Alberto Colajanni report on the peace process in the middle east.</p>
<p>- Karl von Wogau report on community customs programme - customs 2000.</p>
<p>- Oral question on WTO accords on restrictions on the exports of farm products.</p>
<p>- Philippe Herzog report on the participation of citizens to the EU and inter-governmental conference (IGC) institutional system.</p>
<p>- Hedy d'Ancona repot on minimum procedure guarantees in asylum.</p>
<p>- Formal session for UNICEF 50th anniversary.</p>
<p>- (1730/1630 GMT) Council question time.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committee meets:</p>
<p>(1600/1500 GMT) Inquiry into Fraud in Transit.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (and Thursday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Commission communication on Community structural assistance and employment COM(96)109.</p>
<p>- European voluntary service for young people.</p>
<p>- The CAP and eastward enlargement.</p>
<p>- Parking cards for disabled persons COM(95)696.</p>
<p>- European year of local and regional democracy.</p>
<p>- The information society: from Corfu to Dublin - The new emerging priorities. The implication of the information society for the EU policies COM(96)395.</p>
<p>- The current and future policy of the EU in the Baltic Sea Region from local and regional perspective.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council decision on a multi-annual programme to assist tourism - PHILOXENIA (1997-1999) COM(96)168.</p>
<p>- Opinion on local employment pact.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Committee of the Regions holds forum on &quot;Local and regional employment pacts&quot; (and Thursday). Venue: European Parliament. Contact: Committee the Regions (322) 282 2155.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - ACP ministers hold council (and Thursday). Venue: ACP house, 451 avenue Georges Henri. Contact: ACP House (322) 743 0600.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce launches the business of adding value, an analysis of European retail and distribution based on a study by London economics, and the EuroCommerce recommendations for future policy in recognition of the vital importance of this sector to the European economy (1030/0930 GMT) (and Thursday). Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5 874.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Agra Europe holds third annual European grain conference (and Thursday). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>TILBURG, Netherlands - Former German President Richard von Weizsaecker gives address on Culture of European Union (2000/1900 GMT). Venue: Brabant Catholic University.</p>
<p>ROME - U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation holds world food summit (to Sunday). European Commissioner Fischler meets U.S. Department of Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman.</p>
<p>GENEVA - WTO holds conference with 48 poorest countries (to Friday).</p>
<p>PARIS - European Radiocommunications Office holds conference on &quot;Regulation and legislation in a liberalised market&quot; (1000/0900 GMT) (To Sunday). Venue: Hilton Hotel. Contact: European Radiocommunications Office (45) 35 25 0300.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 14</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Industry Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes</p>
<p>- Steel:</p>
<p>a) State aids code;</p>
<p>b) Sixth monitoring report on state aids in steel sector;</p>
<p>c) (possibly) Future of ECSC Treaty.</p>
<p>- Competition:</p>
<p>a) State aids;</p>
<p>b) Merger regulation;</p>
<p>c) Agreement with Canada.</p>
<p>- Shipbuilding:</p>
<p>- (possibly) State of ratification procedure - OECD agreement.</p>
<p>- SMEs:</p>
<p>a) Proposal for a Council decision on a third multiannual programme for small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) in the European Union (1997-2000);</p>
<p>b) Report on integrated programme.</p>
<p>- Competitiveness policy:</p>
<p>a) Commission's first report on the competitiveness of European industry;</p>
<p>b) A European policy for quality promotion;</p>
<p>c) Benchmarking;</p>
<p>d) Standards.</p>
<p>- Merger regulation:</p>
<p>- Review of regulation 4064/89 on the control of concentrations between undertakings.</p>
<p>- Automobile industry.</p>
<p>- Chemicals industry.</p>
<p>- Textiles:</p>
<p>- Communication from the Commission on the competitiveness of subcontracting in the textile and clothing industry in the European Union.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Recycling industry and environmental technology.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Space industry.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Cooperation with third countries.</p>
<p>BALLYCONNELL, Ireland (NEW ITEM) - Irish Finance Minister hosts seminar on &quot;Regional development&quot; (1600/1500 GMT) (and Friday). Main issues discussed are employment and structural funds and economic and social cohesion. Venue: Slieve Russel Hotel. Contact: Permanent Representation of Ireland (322) 230 8580.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Commission and EP host &quot;European film forum&quot; (To November 20). Venue: EP. Contact: Daniele Blin, DCB Productions (33) 1 42 768 82 14.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President Santer meets Uzbekistan President Islam Karimov.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President Santer and Commissioner Pinheiro meet South African Vice President Thabo M'Beki.</p>
<p>BEIJING (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Brittan attends EU-China ministerial meeting (to Sunday);</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Parliament plenary session (fourth of five days).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1000/0900 GMT) Joint debate on:</p>
<p>- Wim van Velzen report on EU energy policy to 2020.</p>
<p>- Umberto Scapagnini report on Euro-Mediterranean partnership in energy.</p>
<p>- Eryl Margaret McNally report on technical introduction of rationnal planning in the distribution of gas and electricity.</p>
<p>- Giles Bryan Chichester report on gas supply and its perspectives.</p>
<p>- Joan Colom I Naval report on ECSC integration to EU's budget.</p>
<p>- Carmen Fraga Estevez report on fisheries conservation measures in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>- Heinz Kindermann report on fisheries agreements with Latvia, Estonia and Lithuania.</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Debates on topical and urgent subjects of major importance, followed by votes (1730/1530 GMT).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (second of two days); European Commissioner Wulf-Mathies gives address on the cohesion report.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Europe's 500 - The Association for Dynamic Entrepreneurs hold international think-tank (To November 16). Venue: Conrad Hotel. Contact: Europe's 500 (322) 716 4838.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce holds conference on &quot;The business of adding value - European retailing and distribution&quot;. Main discussions focus on commerce in the cashless society and the challenges of multimedia (second of two days). European Commission President Jacques Santer attends. Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5874.</p>
<p>PARIS - Foreign ministers of countries involved in Bosnia discuss plans for two-year civilian peace consolidation programme in Bosnia; countries meeting include members of the contact group on former Yugoslavia of Western allies and Russia, and the Arab contact group.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - The Edmond Israel Foundation and the Cedel Group hold &quot;Vision for Europe&quot; award ceremony (1800/1700 GMT). Participants include: Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene and European Commission President Santer. Venue: European Centre, rue du Fort Thungen. Contact: Cedel Group Corporate Communications (352) 44 99 26 108.</p>
<p>NEHGELO, The Netherlands - European Ostrich Association (EOA) holds world congress (and Friday). Venue: Expo Centre. Contact: EOA (31) 546 81 3677.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 15</p>
<p>CORK, Ireland (NEW ITEM) - EU youth ministers hold informal meeting.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Parliament plenary session (last of five days).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Votes on reports without debates:</p>
<p>- Wolfgang Ullman reports on undesirable substances in animal feed; conservation of fisheries measures.</p>
<p>- Joan Colom I Naval report on healthy and efficient financial management for the year 2000.</p>
<p>- Livio Filippi report on specific measures in the plant sector.</p>
<p>- David John Alfred Hallam report on support measures for certain arable crops producers.</p>
<p>- Jessica Larive report on the implementation of equal chances between men and women.</p>
<p>- Angela Kokkola report on the rational use of and conservation in the wet zones.</p>
<p>PRAGUE - Elections to Czech senate (newly-created senate to be mostly an advisory body with limited legislative power) (and Saturday).</p>
<p>SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 16</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 17</p>
<p>QATAR - European Commission DG XVII and the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) hold joint conference on &quot;EU-GCC: extending partnership to natural gas&quot; (To Monday).</p>
<p>MOLDOVA - Presidential election; if no candidate wins a majority in a first round, a second round will be held on the first Sunday of December and the winner will be inaugurated on January 15.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
