<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178263" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mel Gibson's &quot;Ransom&quot; steals U.S. box office honors.</title>
<headline>Mel Gibson's &quot;Ransom&quot; steals U.S. box office honors.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mel Gibson thriller &quot;Ransom&quot; left no hostages at the U.S. box office as it grabbed $35 million in its opening weekend, according to studio estimates released Sunday.</p>
<p>The movie made more in the Friday to Sunday period than the rest of the entries in the top 10 combined. &quot;William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet&quot; was a distant second with $8.8 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Ransom&quot; stars Gibson as a self-made airline mogul who turns the tables on his son's kidnappers. It also features Rene Russo and Gary Sinise. Playing on 2,676 screens, the movie averaged $13,079 per screen, by far the highest in the top 10.</p>
<p>Walt Disney Co., which distributes the movie, said the three-day tally was the second-highest in the company's history, behind &quot;The Lion King&quot; with $40.9 million in 1994.</p>
<p>It also sets new milestones for Gibson and director Ron Howard. Gibson's previous best three-day opener was &quot;Lethal Weapon 3&quot; in 1992, with $33.2 million, while Howard's was &quot;Apollo 13,&quot; which opened with $25.4 million last year.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a picture that's got some unbelievable legs,&quot; said Chuck Viane, a senior vice-president at Disney's Buena Vista distribution arm.</p>
<p>He said in an interview that &quot;Ransom&quot; played strongly across all demographics, and he was &quot;shocked&quot; at the number of teenagers who were spending their Saturday nights at the movie.</p>
<p>He noted the movie helps fill a void in the marketplace for action dramas with plenty of suspense and strong characters. &quot;I think everybody likes to be involved in a movie. Once in a while you like to be gripped and this is one of those.&quot;</p>
<p>Last week's number one, &quot;William Shakespeare's Romeo and Juliet&quot; slipped to second with $8.8 million, a reasonable 21 percent fall from its opening weekend. It averaged $4,511 this weekend after boosting its screen total by 674 to 1,951. The movie's 10-day gross is $23.4 million.</p>
<p>News Corp.'s 20th Century Fox distributes the movie, which stars Leonardo DiCaprio and Claire Danes as the ill-fated lovers. Australian Baz Luhrman directs.</p>
<p>Opening in third with $8.5 million was the urban heist drama &quot;Set It Off,&quot; starring Jada Pinkett and Queen Latifah. Time Warner Inc.'s New Line Cinema released the movie on Wednesday to avoid the violence that often afflicts urban movies when they open on Fridays.</p>
<p>The movie averaged $8,342 from 1,019 screens, and its cumulative gross is $11.5 million.</p>
<p>The rest of the top 10 was left in the dust. &quot;Sleepers&quot; released by Time Warner's Warner Bros. fell two notches to fourth with $3.7 million, taking its 24-day total to $43.4 million.</p>
<p>The Jon Lovitz comedy &quot;High School High&quot; followed in fifth, also down two places, with $3.1 million. Its 17-day total is $16.8 million. Sony Corp.'s TriStar Pictures releases the movie.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
