<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178857" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan's Bhutto expects to be back in power soon.</title>
<headline>Pakistan's Bhutto expects to be back in power soon.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's ousted prime minister Benazir Bhutto said on Monday she was confident the Supreme Court would thrust her back into power within a month.</p>
<p>Brimming with self-assurance, a combative Bhutto told Reuters Television in an interview that she will lodge an appeal with the Supreme Court in the next two days asking that she be restored to power.</p>
<p>Bhutto said the court's decision in 1993 to overrule an order sacking former prime minister Nawaz Sharif gave her confidence she would be re-instated.</p>
<p>&quot;If the assembly dissolution with regard to Nawaz Sharif was wrong, the charges against me are even flimsier and the Supreme Court should restore the assembly within a month,&quot; she said, speaking from her stately official residence.</p>
<p>President Farooq Leghari dismissed Bhutto's government last Tuesday, citing corruption, mismanagement and extra-judicial killings among other accusations which he said had virtually paralysed the government.</p>
<p>Bhutto, wearing a beige scarf on her head and a purple silk &quot;shalwar kameez&quot;, said she considered her sacking to be &quot;a constitutional coup, a presidential coup and an act against democracy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider it to be illegal,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Bhutto said she planned to hold a meeting with lawyers on Monday. &quot;I hope we can wrap (the appeal) up. If we do, it will be filed tomorrow. Otherwise, the latest by the day after.&quot;</p>
<p>She said the legal petition would state that the allegations which Leghari levelled against her government were false, and that the ostensible aim of the presidential order -- to hold free, fair and impartial elections on February 3 -- was also false.</p>
<p>Bhutto, 43, said in bitter tones that she felt betrayed by Leghari, who once served in her cabinet and was handpicked by her to become president in 1993. She said he should step down.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel not only personally betrayed,&quot; Bhutto said. &quot;I believe he betrayed the blood of my father.&quot;</p>
<p>Benazir's father, Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, was Pakistan's first popularly elected prime minister, ruling from 1971 to 1977 when he was toppled by army chief General Mohammad Zia-ul-Haq.</p>
<p>Zulfikar was hanged in April 1979 on a disputed conviction for conspiring to commit a political murder.</p>
<p>Bhutto's legal challenge would be one of several which are expected to shift Pakistan's political crisis to the courts.</p>
<p>Interim Prime Minister Meraj Khalid told reporters on Sunday that his government was drawing up charges against Bhutto and her husband, Asif Ali Zardari. Asked if they would include criminal charges, he said: &quot;All kinds of charges.&quot;</p>
<p>Khalid, who is a member of Bhutto's Pakistan People's Party (PPP) but distanced himself from her some time ago, did not spell out the charges but said they were expected this week.</p>
<p>He acknowledged they could include the alleged breach of human rights in Karachi, where some 375 people have been killed this year in ethnic and political strife.</p>
<p>Bhutto is no stranger to courtroom battles. She was sacked in 1990 after 20 months in power and indicted on eight counts of abuse of power.</p>
<p>But courts cleared her of the charges, one by one, and she staged a comeback, winning re-election in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
