<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178859" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks rally to 55th record close of 1996.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks rally to 55th record close of 1996.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks soared to their 55th record close of 1996 on Monday, propelled by strong bullion prices and expectations of lower interest rates.</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index jumped 43.67 points to end the day at a lofty 5802.42.</p>
<p>Trading was brisk for a Remembrance Day holiday which closed banks and government offices and left Canadian markets lightly staffed.</p>
<p>Nearly 72 million shares changed hands for a total value of C$1.07 billion ($800 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The strength was pretty much right across the board for the Canadian market,&quot; said John Ing, president of Maison Placements Canada Inc in Toronto.</p>
<p>The heavily-weighted gold sector led 10 of Toronto's 14 sub-groups higher. COMEX December gold closed up US$2.30 at US$382.80 an ounce as bullion continued to recover from its October lows.</p>
<p>Other buoyant sectors included oil and gas, pipelines, base metals and forestry products. The weak side was led by communications and financial services.</p>
<p>Analysts said the TSE was also helped by expectations for another interest rate cut by the Bank of Canada. The central bank last lowered rates on Friday, for the 11th time in 1996.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Among gold issues, Barrick Gold Corp. gained 0.70 to 36.10 on 663,000 shares. Placer Dome Inc. jumped 0.90 to 33.70 on 577,000 shares.</p>
<p>* Tarxien Corp. closed up 0.20 to 14.50 after earlier hitting a 52-week high of 14.75.  The auto parts maker said on Monday it approved a directors' circular in response to a C$14.10 ($10.57) a share takeover offer from Gecamex Technologies Inc.</p>
<p>* Energy stocks were among the heaviest traders. NOVA Corp added 0.25 to 12.20 on 2.2 million shares, while Gulf Canada Resources Ltd. rose 0.20 to 9.15 on 1.9 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
