<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178858" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bergen, IVAX to merge in US stock deal.</title>
<headline>Bergen, IVAX to merge in US stock deal.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Drug wholesaler Bergen Brunswig Corp.  Monday agreed to buy generic drug maker IVAX Corp.  in a $1.6 billion deal that would form the United States' first integrated  manufacturer and distributor of pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>But news of the merger sent stocks of both companies down sharply. Wall Street appeared to overlook Bergen's forecast of higher margins and increased shareholder value, and focused instead on the problems it would encounter acquiring a money-losing company in the midst of a restructuring.</p>
<p>The deal was announced as Miami-based IVAX, which has been hurt by fierce competition in the generic drug industry, reported a third-quarter loss of $178.7 million, or $1.47 a share, and a 28 percent drop in revenues. IVAX also omitted payment of its semi-annual dividend for the second half of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (Bergen) may have done better to wait a year,&quot; said Robert Wasserman, an analyst with Southeast Research Partners.</p>
<p>Wasserman questioned whether Bergen's background in distribution had given it the expertise to oversee the sort of sweeping cost cuts that were more common in manufacturing operations and would be needed to put IVAX back on track.</p>
<p>Bergen's stock tumbled $5.125 to $27.625 on the New York Stock Exchange after the deal was announced, and IVAX lost $3.375 to close at $12.375 on the American Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The two companies said they plan to form a new company, BBI Healthcare Corp., which will acquire Orange, Calif.-based Bergen Brunswig and IVAX through an exchange of stock.</p>
<p>The value of the deal slid to about $1.6 billion with the drop in the company's stock prices on Monday, from about $1.65 billion based on Friday prices.</p>
<p>&quot;This combination will enhance revenues, take advantage of synergies by streamlining the supply chain, improve margins, and create shareholder value that exceeds the value of Bergen and IVAX as stand-alone businesses,&quot; Bergen Chairman Robert Martini said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bergen also said the merger will expand its business outside the United States for the first time. IVAX's Norton Healthcare subsidiary is the largest generic pharmaceutical company in Britain and serves as the hub of operations in Ireland, Poland, Germany, the Czech and Slovak republics, and China.</p>
<p>But other analysts questioned whether Bergen's acqusition of a major generic drug maker might damage its relations with others that were integral to its business.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is a lot of concern that Bergen's other suppliers might be scratching their heads and saying, 'Do we really want to do as much business with them now that they have acquired a big drug company?'&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be good if IVAX could literally supply them with all their drugs; but Bergen buys $2 billion worth of drugs a year, and even if IVAX gave them (Bergen) everything, it would only be 25 percent of their needs.&quot;</p>
<p>In another industry merger announced Monday, two California managed care companies, FPA Medical Management Inc. of San Diego and AHI Healthcare Systems Inc. of Downey, agreed to merge. They said the combination would form one of the nation's largest physician practice management companies with revenues of about $1 billion and more than 800,000 enrollees in 25 states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
