<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18106" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British trade deficit stable in June.</title>
<headline>British trade deficit stable in June.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's global trade deficit was unchanged at 1.12 billion pounds ($1.75 billion) in June, helping to ease fears that economic recovery may have damaged the trade balance, according to figures released Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics said total exports fell slightly to 13.63 billion pounds ($21.25 billion) and imports were also down at 14.75 billion ($22.99 billion).</p>
<p>The figures were better than financial markets had expected, although some economists predicted that the healthier tone could prove short-lived, with rising consumer demand likely to boost imports in the coming months.</p>
<p>The Treasury said the figures demonstrated the strength of export growth but some economists found them puzzling.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK's trade performance continues to mystify us,&quot; said Alex Garrard, an economist at stockbrokers UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;Import growth has slowed despite abundant evidence of an upswing in domestic demand. Even more surprising is the buoyancy of export growth, despite reduced competitiveness against major European currencies since the turn of the year and only tentative signs of a pick-up in overseas activity.&quot;</p>
<p>Garrard said the trade data were notoriously erratic and the deficit could be revised higher in the coming months.</p>
<p>There was better news on more up-to-date figures covering trade with countries outside the European Union in July. This showed a July deficit of 506 million pounds ($788.8 million), half of the June shortfall of 1.09 billion ($1.67 billion).</p>
<p>Economists said the figures probably made it slightly less likely that Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke, the nation's finance minister, would cut official interest rates again next month.</p>
<p>Clarke has cut rates four times since December to their present 5.75 percent level.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
