<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18102" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rugby union-England given until end of next week to change mind.</title>
<headline>Rugby union-England given until end of next week to change mind.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>England have been given until the end of next week to change their mind about an exclusive television deal with Rupert Murdoch's Sky Television and stay in the Five Nations' championship.</p>
<p>Scotland Rugby Football Union president Fred McLeod said on Wednesday if there was no change in the Rugby Football Union's (RFU) approach England would be excluded from the championship.</p>
<p>The championship, featuring England, Scotland, Wales, Ireland and France, is one of the most popular sporting contests in the British Isles.</p>
<p>But last April England infuriated their championship colleagues when they decided to sign a 87.5 million pounds sterling ($135.8 million) deal giving Sky television exclusive rights to rugby union matches in England.</p>
<p>&quot;We have given the RFU every opportunity to modify its approach to the sale of broadcasting rights, prior to and following England's exclusion from the Five Nations' championship,&quot; McLeod said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is no change in the RFU's approach by the end of next week, when representatives from the other four unions are due to meet, England's exclusion from the championship will be finally confirmed, and we will proceed with the new Four Nations' championship.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement earlier on Wednesday, the Four Nations TV Committee said dates had been set for a competition involving Scotland, Wales, Ireland and France next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Between now and then, discussions will take place in one final attempt to persuade the Rugby Football Union to save the Five Nations' championship in its current form,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The present contract with the British Broadcasting Corporation was shared between the four home nations while France have their own television deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
