<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18117" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Tankan boosts Japan government bonds but pitfalls ahead.</title>
<headline>Tankan boosts Japan government bonds but pitfalls ahead.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>International investors will likely be lured back into Japanese government bonds after a weak corporate sentiment survey sharply curtailed the chances of an interest rate rise this year, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the survey may prove to be a double-edged sword -- enticing politicians to unleash new stimulus measures as the economy falters -- and investors should be wary about going too overweight at the expense of other bond markets, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly it's dramatically changed the outlook of the market,&quot; said Kirit Shah, chief market strategist at Sanwa.</p>
<p>&quot;People were looking for JGB yields to head back up to 3.5 percent and mabe even four percent in a year's time but the tankan has radically shifted the trading range,&quot; said Shah, based in London.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan's quarterly corporate survey or &quot;tankan&quot; released earlier in Tokyo caught financial markets on the hop.</p>
<p>The key diffusion index for major manufacturers -- which gauges business sentiment -- fell to minus seven in August from minus three in May. Analysts had been expecting a slight rise.</p>
<p>Paul Meader, who manages 200 million pounds ($311.5 million) in fixed-income investments at Matheson Investment Management in London, added, &quot;The curve is very steep and that makes me feel perhaps international managers may start to look at extending up the curve a little bit.&quot;</p>
<p>Bond markets surged in Japan and held onto gains in London. The yield on the key 182nd 10-year bond fell below three percent in Tokyo for the first time since February.</p>
<p>It was quoted at 3.03 percent in London at 1150 GMT.</p>
<p>The survey revealed an economy still in dire straights and put a rise in the 0.5 percent official discount rate off until next year, analysts said.</p>
<p>In such a weak economic environment, the bond market would continue to make gains, said Stuart Thomson, chief international economist at Nikko (Europe).</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect it to maintain this bullish stance in the near term,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He forecast the yield on the 10-year bond dipping to 2.80 percent in the next few weeks. Matheson's Meader put 2.75 percent as his target.</p>
<p>But troubles loom beyond the short term, analysts said.</p>
<p>While Japan's Finance Minister Wataru Kubo said the tankan would not lead to any immediate decision on the need for an extra budget, analysts said the urge may prove irresistable, particularly with an election due by mid-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This weak economic scenario increases scope for another fiscal stimulus package and the budget deficit will become even more horrendous and supply will hit the market some time down the road,&quot; Shah said.</p>
<p>Meader added that with one of largest budget deficits of developed countries, interest rates at rock bottom and the yen continuing weak, the economy already had plenty of stimulus.</p>
<p>&quot;From a bond market perspective that fiscal stimulus, interest rate stimulus and currency stimulus is a very dangerous cocktail and it justifies real yields much higher and nominal yields much higher,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Meader said Matheson may increase its weighting slightly in JGBs from its slim eight percent weighting. The JP Morgan global bond index has a benchmark of 15 percent, he said.</p>
<p>But Shah would opt for U.S. Treasuries instead. &quot;The budget deficit in the U.S. is in much better shape. The roles have reversed from the 1980s to the 1990s,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nikko's Thomson preferred core Europe and particularly the short-end of Germany.</p>
<p>($1=.6421 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
