<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18115" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyds Abbey Life ignited by bid rumours. [CORRECTED 17:05 GMT]</title>
<headline>Lloyds Abbey Life ignited by bid rumours. [CORRECTED 17:05 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Jill Treanor</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Speculation about the ownership of life insurer Lloyds Abbey Life Plc ignited its share price on Wednesday as dealers reckoned it might be takeover fodder for cash-rich insurance giant Prudential Corp Plc.</p>
<p>Analysts said a more likely scenario was that British banking group Lloyds TSB Group Plc wanted to increase its 62 percent stake in the life insurer.</p>
<p>All three companies said they did not comment on market rumours, while Lloyds Abbey Life's share price traded 31 pence higher (Corrects from &quot;traded 30.5 percent higher&quot;) at 591.5 pence, just off the 607p day's high.</p>
<p>Since Lloyds' merger with TSB last December the future of Lloyds Abbey Life has hung in the balance as Lloyds acquired TSB's life assurance operation as a result of the merger.</p>
<p>Analysts said this raised the possibility of merging the two operations.</p>
<p>&quot;We're waiting for an announcement,&quot; one analyst said, referring to continuing internal discussions about Lloyds Abbey Life's strategic options under a steering group run by chief executive Stephen Maran.</p>
<p>Analysts said the options being considered were varied, and ranged from doing nothing to closing down altogether.</p>
<p>Maran declined to take calls from Reuters on Wednesday and a company official would only say that the company did not comment on market rumours. But at the time of its interim results in July finance director Laurel Powers-Freeling told Reuters the talks had not been concluded.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a range of options, there a number of permutations,&quot; Powers-Freeling said then.</p>
<p>ABN Amro Hoare Govett analyst John Russell said Lloyds Abbey Life was unlikely bid target for Prudential, on the look-out for a life insurer or building society and swilling with cash after selling its reinsurance arm Mercantile and General back to Swiss Re on Tuesday for 1.75 billion pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Prudential is more likely to demutualise a mutual and get access to IFAs,&quot; said Russell.</p>
<p>Analysts said a more likely fate for Lloyds Abbey Life was that Lloyds TSB will pick up the remaining stake or do a deal with the minority holders to give back Abbey Life and personal loans finance arm Bowmaker.</p>
<p>&quot;They may unravel it...and give Abbey Life back to minority shareholders,&quot; said Russell.</p>
<p>Among the minority shareholders is PDFM, the fund management arm of UBS, analysts said.</p>
<p>But analysts also noted comments by Lloyds TSB chief executive Sir Brian Pitman in June when he said the bank had no plans to increase its take in the insurer.</p>
<p>They also said Lloyds Abbey Life's shares could be adjusting to more realistic levels after the insurers' first-half profits showed a 28 percent rise to 259.2 million pounds last month.</p>
<p>Both the unnamed analyst and ABN Amro Hoare Govett's Russell said they had increased their valuation of the shares to 600 pence after its interim results, a level to which they rose on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
