<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18118" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - British trade deficit stable in June.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - British trade deficit stable in June.</headline>
<byline>Richard Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's global trade deficit was unchanged at 1.12 billion pounds ($1.75 billion) in June, helping to ease fears that economic recovery may have damaged the trade balance, according to figures released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics (ONS) said total exports fell slightly to 13.63 billion pounds and imports were also down at 14.75 billion.</p>
<p>The figures were better than financial markets had expected but some City economists predicted that the healthier tone could prove short-lived, with rising consumer demand likely to boost imports in the coming months.</p>
<p>The Treasury said the figures demonstrated the strength of export growth but some economists found them puzzling. &quot;The UK's trade performance continues to mystify us,&quot; said Alex Garrard, an economist at stockbrokers UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;Import growth has slowed despite abundant evidence of an upswing in domestic demand. Even more surprising is the buoyancy of export growth, despite reduced competitiveness against major European currencies since the turn of the year and only tentative signs of a pick-up in overseas activity.&quot;</p>
<p>Garrard said the trade data were notoriously erratic and the deficit could be revised higher in the coming months.</p>
<p>There was better news on more up-to-date figures covering trade with countries outside the European Union in July. This showed a July deficit of 506 million pounds, half of the June shortfall of 1.09 billion.</p>
<p>Economists said the figures probably made it slightly less likely that Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Kenneth Clarke would cut official interest rates again next month.</p>
<p>Clarke has cut rates four times since December to their present 5.75 percent level. With a general election due by May 1997, he has a strong political incentive to lower them further.</p>
<p>Jeremy Hawkins of Bank of America said the figures should remove worries that the recent rise in the value of sterling against major European currencies could undermine exports.</p>
<p>&quot;The smaller than expected July deficit is also positive for a pick-up in GDP growth this quarter, so another dent to rate cut hopes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other economists said the deficit could come under pressure from a pickup in investment once industry has disposed of stocks of unsold goods.</p>
<p>Britain's industrial base was eroded during the 1980s and a pick up in investment would lead to an influx of capital goods from abroad.</p>
<p>The consumer recovery, on the other hand, may be less threatening as Britain now plays host to a large number of foreign consumer goods manufacturers and is expected to be a net exporter of televisions and passenger cars by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;I still think the deficit will deteriorate as consumer spending picks up,&quot; said Ciaran Barr, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>($1=.6415 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
