<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18111" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Approval for Lloyd's settlement offer edges closer.</title>
<headline>Approval for Lloyd's settlement offer edges closer.</headline>
<byline>Alexander Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Final approval for Lloyd's of London's recovery plan edged closer on Wednesday as it declared that over 90 percent of members had accepted a settlement offer aimed at securing the 300-year-old insurance market's future.</p>
<p>Lloyd's said it had been swamped by U.S. investors signing up for its recovery plan after a U.S. appeals court overturned a ruling that had threatened the insurance market's survival. By Wednesday afternoon 66.7 percent of U.S. members had accepted.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of acceptances speaks for itself. Members have made their views toward the reconstruction of Lloyd's abundantly clear,&quot; Lloyd's chairman David Rowland said in a statement.</p>
<p>Earlier a Lloyd's spokesman said acceptances from U.S. Names, investors in the market, had flooded in overnight.</p>
<p>Almost half of the 2,700 U.S. Names had until last night held off. Only 53 percent had accepted by Tuesday.</p>
<p>This followed a Baltimore appeal court's decision late on Tuesday to overturn U.S. judge Robert Payne's ruling last Friday to allow U.S. Names more time to consider the plan.</p>
<p>Payne granted an injunction giving U.S. Names more time to consider the plan and ordered Lloyd's to provide further information by September 23. On Tuesday a panel of judges in Baltimore sent the case back to the Virginia district court with orders to dismiss it.</p>
<p>Rowland said he acknowledged many overseas members had deferred their acceptance in the light of the Virginia court judgement and the subsequent Baltimore ruling.</p>
<p>Over the last few days, evidence of support for the Lloyd's proposals among its 34,000 investors worldwide has grown. On Tuesday evening acceptances totalled 82 percent, compared to only 75 percent on Saturday.</p>
<p>Wednesday's noon deadline for accepting the recovery plan, under which Lloyd's proposes Names pay to help reinsure billions of pounds in liabilities into a new company called Equitas, was extended to give all a chance to respond.</p>
<p>Rowland said on Wednesday afternoon that in the circumstances it was &quot;fair and proper&quot; to exercise flexibility in pushing back the deadline for acceptances.</p>
<p>Lloyd's said that any formal, longer-term extension would be subject to a decision by its council at a Thursday meeting at which it would consider &quot;the prospect of declaring the settlement offer acceptances unconditional.&quot;</p>
<p>This extension will crucially allow the market enough time to collect the convincing majority of acceptances, especially from U.S. Names, which it needs to prove its own solvency.</p>
<p>Lloyd's problems began in the 1980s when a destructive combination of negligent underwriting, poor investment advice and a sequence of natural disasters conspired to bring about losses of several billion pounds.</p>
<p>Long-standing Names were for the first time in their lives suddenly faced with the prospect of unlimited losses.</p>
<p>The market is due to submit figures to Britain's Department of Trade and Industry next week in an annual solvency test, and file with the U.S. Treasury and New York Insurance Department later next month.</p>
<p>Equitas may lift off in two weeks if all goes as planned. The recovery plan's success increasingly looks likely, but another challenge by U.S. Names has not been ruled out.</p>
<p>However, U.S. legal sources said overnight that, while U.S. investors could in theory attempt to challenge Tuesday's order it would be difficult to do so successfully.</p>
<p>Despite that, one U.S. Name and chief negotiator for an action group known as the American Names Association, Kenneth Chiate, said he expected U.S. Names to appeal the Baltimore ruling.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
