<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18120" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyd's may seek closer ties with London market.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's may seek closer ties with London market.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London may seek closer ties with the rest of the London insurance market once its recovery plan is completed, chairman David Rowland said.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Rowland described how Lloyd's and the London companies market could co-operate in areas like marketing, international development and technology.</p>
<p>He also said that the regulation of Lloyd's in the future may be divided -- with the insurance market itself governing the supervision of professionals, and investor protection falling to an outside body like the Securities and Investments Board (SIB).</p>
<p>With Lloyd's confident it will have overwhelming support from members for its recovery plan by today's voting deadline, Rowland has been looking ahead to the insurance market's future.</p>
<p>The chairman set out how Lloyd's may evolve once the recovery plan goes ahead and the billions of pounds in &quot;long tail&quot; liabilities, which have threatened to bring it down, become the responsibility of a new reinsurance vehicle Equitas.</p>
<p>Rowland hopes a review of the market's activities, which is already underway, will identify how marketing, international development and support services could be more profit orientated and possibly lead to cooperation with others outside Lloyd's.</p>
<p>&quot;All of those can both be domestic or liberalised so they could become London market-wide,&quot; said Rowland. &quot;If you have the resource it could actually sell its services elsewhere.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not saying the conclusion will remotely be that, but I think we need to question a great deal about the way in which we provide service in that sort of fashion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lloyd's and the London companies market comprise insurers, reinsurers and brokers, all of whom are feeling the heat of intensified competition from other global insurance centres like Bermuda, which now provides more reinsurance to U.S. firms.</p>
<p>Future cooperation between Lloyd's and the rest of the London market is likely also to see greater integration of new technology such as recently-introduced electronic placing support, leading eventually to a common system serving clients as well.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to see the London market united under one system of access for brokers and clients,&quot; Rowland said.</p>
<p>Regulation at Lloyd's is also under scrutiny. Rowland is determined the terrible losses of the past caused by negligent underwriting and poor advice to investors will not be repeated.</p>
<p>He suggested that the supervision of the market, which includes corporate activity and the discipline of professionals, stay largely within Lloyd's itself, while investor protection could be handled by an outside body like the SIB for example.</p>
<p>At the moment all regulatory issues are handled ultimately by Lloyd's ruling council, because this is the statutory body.</p>
<p>&quot;It's likely that part of our responsibilities may still stay within us but answer separately, and that it is more likely to be the investor protection role which may answer outside.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;With the market supervision side, it's quite difficult to see it taking place without a great deal of market involvement.&quot;</p>
<p>After the completion of the recovery plan, Rowland is likely to step back from day-to-day management of the insurance market, leaving the bulk of this to Lloyd's chief executive Ron Sandler.</p>
<p>He said he would spend more time on governance, policy, the promotion of Lloyd's and the question of his succession.</p>
<p>The latter will assume greater significance next year. He does not plan to continue as chairman after 1997 and will seek to change the law governing Lloyd's to remove the restriction limiting the appointment to a working member only.</p>
<p>However, he noted it may be possible to widen the choice somewhat without changing the law, as a result of opening the doors to a different type of investor -- the corporate backer.</p>
<p>&quot;We have other people with wider business that are involved with this market and therefore I think the choice is potentially wider,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
