<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18132" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Wall St bounce lifts Australia stocks at open.</title>
<headline>Wall St bounce lifts Australia stocks at open.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian sharemarket firmed at the opening on Wednesday as a rebound on Wall Street saw a positive tone return to local markets.</p>
<p>At the opening, the All Ordinaries index was up 5.70 points at 2,268.0.</p>
<p>The September share index futures firmed eight points to 2,274 and was at a 6.0 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said the return of the long term bond rate to below seven percent had seen investors reassured after a hesitant two days' trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. has helped to steady things up with bonds pushed back below seven percent reassuring some nervous people,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>While the broker saw a positive outlook, he was not expecting major moves during the day with a firmer finish rather than a strong march ahead expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Locally we are still pretty sound, but I'm not expecting big things today,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Results season continues with the early major results from base metals miner, Pasminco, whose shares were two cents firmer after a big jump in full year net profit to A$40.8 million.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about nine to five, while about 48 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
