<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18138" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: FOCUS-Seoul shares at 34-month low on economy fear.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Seoul shares at 34-month low on economy fear.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Bruce</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean shares tumbled to a 34-month low on Wednesday, hammered by fears the economy was on a road to a deepening slowdown, market watchers said.</p>
<p>The sentencing of major business leaders to jail and the prospect of a flood of new stock offerings added to the gloom.</p>
<p>Shares fell 8.40 points to end at 753.35 on Wednesday. This was the lowest close since October 30, 1993, when the index ended at 750.72.</p>
<p>&quot;This was expected,&quot; said a Citizens Investment Trust Co fund manager. &quot;Recently, the market had been supported by small-cap shares. It was clear that they wouldn't be able to keep the market up.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors have been sour on stocks for the past several months, as a series of negative figures painted a picture of a slowing national economy.</p>
<p>The trade deficit was $10.35 billion in the first seven months of the year, against $7.85 billion in the year-ago period.  </p>
<p>Concern deepened on Tuesday's release of second quarter GDP figures that showed the economy had grown at a slower rate this year than last. The GDP grew by a real 6.7 percent in the second quarter against 9.7 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>Investors are worried despite analysts' assurances that there was nothing to be concerned about, as last year's growth had been exceptionally strong.</p>
<p>The index has fallen 23 percent since the end of April, when it traded at 981.</p>
<p>Although some bears said the market could fall as far as 700 level, other brokers said they expected the bourse to find its feet soon.</p>
<p>The market plunged on Monday, when the heads of several of the nation's largest conglomerates were sentenced to jail for bribing former president Roh Tae-woo.</p>
<p>The chairmen of the Daewoo  DWGR.CN, Hanbo, and Jinro groups were each sentenced to two years in prison. The chairman of the Dong Ah group companies was handed a 2-1/2 year term.</p>
<p>On Wednesday afternoon, news that Hyundai Electronics planned to go public in November further hit sentiment.  </p>
<p>&quot;Hyundai Electronics' listing of shares really impacted the sentiment this afternoon,&quot; said Richard Kim of KLB Securities.</p>
<p>Investors believe the market is already suffering from an oversupply of shares.</p>
<p>Five firms have been approved to hold initial public offerings in September, putting 17.55 million more shares on the bourse. A further 12 companies hope to list later this year, potentially adding another 23.8 million shares.</p>
<p>Customer deposits at brokerage houses were at around 2.3 trillion won, while margin loans reached 2.6 trillion. This was adding to the selling pressure, brokers said.</p>
<p>Wednesday's decline was led by small-caps and recent risers.</p>
<p>Young Poong Mining fell 2,800 won ($3.42) to 44,700.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical shares, which had led buying in recent weeks, plunged. The sector fell 86.24 points, or 5.15 percent, to 1,587.62. Dong Shin Pharmaceutical lost 2,700 won to 43,300 and Il Dong Pharmaceutical shed 3,00 won to 47,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
