<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18134" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Hyundai Electronics plans IPO to beat bad news.</title>
<headline>Hyundai Electronics plans IPO to beat bad news.</headline>
<byline>Yeom Yoon-jeong</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hyundai Electronics Industrial Co Ltd, one of the world's top five memory chip makers, announced plans on Wednesday for an initial public offering despite a poor earnings outlook.</p>
<p>Analysts said the issue by the electronics arm of South Korea's Hyundai group, was being rushed to the market because Hyundai, battered by slumping memory chip prices, has no other way to raise funds.</p>
<p>They said if the company waits until next year tougher listing requirements would preclude it from going to market.</p>
<p>Hyundai Electronics needs the cash to expand its dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chip-making facilities in the face of plummeting revenues. Semiconductor sales account for about 80 to 90 percent of the company's profits.</p>
<p>It will be the first company to seek a listing after the government abolishes its quarterly quota on new issues on September 1.</p>
<p>&quot;If it misses the chance this year, an initial public offering would seem impossible,&quot; said Jon Chong-hwa, an electronics analyst at Hanuri-Salomon Securities. He added that Hyundai was likely to post a loss for calendar 1996.</p>
<p>A company spokesman said: &quot;We expect a fall in profits but do not expect a loss this year.&quot;</p>
<p>The issue would expand Hyundai Electronic's paid-in capital to 280 billion won from 230 billion won. Subscription will be in November for listing in December.</p>
<p>&quot;External financing looks inevitable for the company from next year to help finance its huge investment for facilites and research and development,&quot; Jon said.</p>
<p>Hyundai recorded 834.6 billion won in profits on sales of 3.92 trillion won last year. But the global price of 16-megabit DRAM chips plunged by 70 percent in June from a year earlier when it was $45-50.</p>
<p>Semiconductors account for almost 80 to 90 percent of company profits. The rest comes from personal computers and other office equipment.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Hyundai listing added to worries of oversupply in a market that has tumbled to a 34-month low on pessimism over the country's economic outlook. (Conversion $1 = 818 won)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
