<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18133" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Tokyo shares end sharply lower on BOJ survey.</title>
<headline>Tokyo shares end sharply lower on BOJ survey.</headline>
<byline>Brian Rhoads</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks fell sharply on Wednesday after the release of a quarterly business survey revealed an economy that was weaker than expected.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) &quot;tankan&quot; survey of corporations virtually eliminated expectation of an interest rate hike and pushed down Japanese bond yields. But the news boosted the U.S. dollar and buoyed Australian shares.</p>
<p>Most other Asian markets advanced except for Singapore, down half a percent, and Seoul, which fell to a 34-month low.</p>
<p>Bourses in Bangkok, Sydney and Wellington gained one percent. Hong Kong posted modest gains.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, the key Nikkei 225 average ended down 200.46 points or 0.96 percent at 20,709.81. Its September futures lost 230 points to finish at 20,720.</p>
<p>But brokers said a further fall would be limited. &quot;We don't have fears stocks will keep falling, as we have become certain the BOJ will keep its interest rates at low levels and the yen weakened sharply against the dollar,&quot; said Hisao Suzuki, deputy general manager at Yamaichi Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>The BOJ announced after the morning trading session that the tankan's diffusion index for major manufacturers fell to minus seven in August from minus three in the previous survey in May.</p>
<p>The outcome boosted the dollar by more than half a yen past the 108-yen mark.</p>
<p>Buying on the Australian market picked up pace in the afternoon as the Japanese economic data eased concerns about a possible tightening of credit in Japan.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index was up 21.9 points, or 0.97 percent, at 2,284.2. September share index futures were 18 points up at 2,284.</p>
<p>Seoul shares continued their decline, falling 1.10 percent to provisionally close at a new 34-month low of 753.34. Brokers said fears over an economic slowdown and stock oversupply sidelined investors.</p>
<p>The finish was the lowest since October 30, 1993 when the composite stock index fell to 750.72.</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, stocks rebounded from earlier weakness in afternoon trade, with investors picking up market laggards in quiet trade, traders said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 24 points, or 0.36 percent, to 11,363.</p>
<p>In New Zealand, heavy buying in leading stock Telecom thrust the share market to new 30 month highs.</p>
<p>The top 40 index ended 21.43 points or 0.97 percent up at 2,240.49.</p>
<p>Brokers said Thai shares ended up 1.03 percent after buyers sought blue-chips on expectations of signs of an improved economy. The SET index was 11.25 points higher at 1,105.84.</p>
<p>&quot;The index rose after investors bought stocks on hopes that some of the key economic indicators to be released on Thursday would show the economy is improving,&quot; said Somchai Trairattanapirom of Sitca Investment and Securities.</p>
<p>Singapore's Straits Times Industrials Index dropped 11.57 points or 0.53 percent to 2,159.88.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is so quiet that brokers are playing on situational stocks -- particularly the shipyard stocks,&quot; said a dealer with a local brokerage.</p>
<p>In late Tokyo trade the dollar was at 108.35/45 yen and 1.4803/08 marks against its New York close of 107.65/75 and 1.4781/89.</p>
<p>Brent October futures prices on the Singapore International Monetary Exchange edged lower, undermined by a fall on NYMEX and a large crude build in the U.S.</p>
<p>October Brent on SIMEX last traded in late afternoon dealings at $19.99 per barrel, down four cents from London's settlement on Tuesday of $20.03.</p>
<p>Hong Kong gold bullion ended at US$388.50/389.00 an ounce Wednesday against New York's US$388.80/389.20 close on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
