<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18135" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Many Hong Kong IPOs disappointing - analysts.</title>
<headline>Many Hong Kong IPOs disappointing - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong IPOs have burst on to the market with great fanfare this year but a pop on the first trading day is about all some issues can muster because earnings risks worry the long-term investor, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ten of this year's 22 initial public offerings -- excluding market introductions -- were languishing below their offer price at Tuesday's market close.</p>
<p>Fourteen have traded below their IPO price at some stage.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently a number of IPOs have not been able to meet their first year forecast,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities. &quot;This has made investors a bit nervous.&quot;</p>
<p>Guangshen Railway is the latest company to disappoint investors with its first interim result announcement. The H-share, which listed in March at HK$2.91 per share, reported first half earnings of 510.15 million yuan on Tuesday. It has a full year target of not less than 1.08 billion yuan.</p>
<p>H-shares are Chinese companies listed in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Guangshen Railway shares slipped below their IPO price during Wednesday's session, shedding HK$0.175 to HK$2.875.</p>
<p>Analysts said poor performing IPOs were either suffering from a lack of visibility or stringent domestic competition.</p>
<p>Smaller companies tend to be the ones that disappoint the most, and earnings have peaked in some cases, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the second liners' results are very disappointing. Usually this type of company's earnings have peaked and then they issue new shares,&quot; said Patrick Chia, director of research at China Everbright Research.</p>
<p>David Semple, equity strategist at Peregrine Research Institute said research on smaller companies tended to be less diligent. &quot;In general terms the smaller the company the more likely you are to end up on the wrong side,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Infrastructure asset spinoffs are among the poor performers. Wai Kee Holdings Ltd's Road King Infrastructure listed in July at HK$8.40.</p>
<p>It is trading near HK$7.00. &quot;It's very hard to know how these things are going to do. These are not exactly operating businesses in the traditional sense,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are buying a road or a potential road or a licence to build a bridge or the potential development of some land -- what are you buying?&quot;</p>
<p>With the possibility of poor results looming, analysts said investors were only willing to take a short-term view on some IPOs, cashing in on quick gains before earnings came in.</p>
<p>&quot;The quality has not been that good so this triggers investors to sell the stock after the IPO. People take a trading view,&quot; said Kelvin Tang, analyst at ImPac Asset Management.</p>
<p>Analysts said the rush of infrastructure spinoffs this year, following the stock exchange's clarification of infrastructure company listing rules in January, gave investors more of a choice in the sector. IPOs were also being met by thin market liquidity as fears of higher interest rates dampened sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that after March, turnover came down quite substantially. Sentiment somewhat changed because of fears of rising interest rates in the U.S. and investors have become quite selective when they look at new issues,&quot; said Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International.  </p>
<p>Smaller companies tend to be the ones that disappoint the most, and earnings have peaked in some cases, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the second liners' results are very disappointing. Usually this type of company's earnings have peaked and then they issue new shares,&quot; said Patrick Chia, director of research at China Everbright Research.</p>
<p>David Semple, equity strategist at Peregrine Research Institute said research on smaller companies tended to be less diligent. &quot;In general terms the smaller the company the more likely you are to end up on the wrong side,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Infrastructure asset spinoffs are among the poor performers. Wai Kee Holdings Ltd's Road King Infrastructure listed in July at HK$8.40.</p>
<p>It is trading near HK$7.00. &quot;It's very hard to know how these things are going to do. These are not exactly operating businesses in the traditional sense,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;If you are buying a road or a potential road or a licence to build a bridge or the potential development of some land -- what are you buying?&quot;</p>
<p>With the possibility of poor results looming, analysts said investors were only willing to take a short-term view on some IPOs, cashing in on quick gains before earnings came in.  </p>
<p>The following is a table of 1996 initial public offerings in Hong Kong and their performance since their listing date - (1) - market introduction *  - trading below offer price as of 27/8 close  Company Name	     Offer   First  First    Stock price</p>
<p>			     Price   Trade  Close    as of 27/8 close</p>
<p>BUILDING SUPPLIES  Companion Marble	    n/a    0.99    -	 1.23</p>
<p>(Holdings) Ltd  (1) - listing date 25/4 (building suplier) --------------------------------------------------------------- CONSUMER GOODS  Guangdong Kelon 3.67    3.625  3.125    3.375 (*)</p>
<p>Electrical Holdings - listing date 23/7 TEXTILE: Elegance Int'l  Holdings Ltd		 1.08    1.18   1.20     1.48</p>
<p>- listing date 11/4  Nanjing Panda  2.13    2.15   2.00     1.20 (*)</p>
<p>Electronics Co Ltd - listing date 2/5</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
