<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18139" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASEAN fundamentals still strong - Singapore minister.</title>
<headline>ASEAN fundamentals still strong - Singapore minister.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian economic fundamentals remain strong despite recent setbacks to exports in the region, Singapore Trade Minister Yeo Cheow Tong said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;With our strong fundamentals, ASEAN (Association of Southeast Asian Nations) will remain one of the fastest growing regions in the world,&quot; Yeo said in a speech to the Thailand-Singapore Business Council.</p>
<p>He noted media reports suggesting a &quot;slightly less than positive outlook&quot; for ASEAN economies. &quot;In particular, export growth in several ASEAN countries has slowed considerably compared to the year before.&quot;</p>
<p>Thailand's export growth was only six percent in first-half 1996 and Singapore recorded a six percent export decline in June, Yeo said.</p>
<p>But while such slowdowns are likely to have some impact on economic growth, he said fundamentally growth momentum remained strong and sustainable.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of the current problem in export growth is cyclical,&quot; Yeo said. The global slowdown in electronics, which is dragging down exports, comes after several years of hectic growth, and a breather could be expected,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yeo said a second reason for optimism was the wave of liberalisation and deregulation sweeping Asia with spectacular economic results, Yeo said,</p>
<p>&quot;The transformation of China in particular has been astonishing. As it opens up, China will suck in imports from all over the world, including ASEAN.&quot;</p>
<p>ASEAN groups Thailand, Malaysia, Singapore, Brunei, Indonesia, the Philippines, and Vietnam.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
