<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18142" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Good exports seen boosting Malaysia palm oil prices.</title>
<headline>Good exports seen boosting Malaysia palm oil prices.</headline>
<byline>Syed Azman</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian palm oil prices, now trading at three-month highs, are expected to climb further in the near term on the back of strong export demand, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said a recent pick-up in the export business had also helped dispel earlier concerns that domestic palm oil stocks would reach one million tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Also, the seasonal increase in output has been at a slower pace than expected due largely to sharply lower production in the states of Sabah and Sarawak on Borneo island.</p>
<p>&quot;Stocks are not building up as fast as the market had expected. And with exports likely to remain healthy in the next few months, the market has greater upside than downside potential,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Malaysia's benchmark third position crude palm oil futures closed on Tuesday at 1,232 ringgit ($494) a tonne, up from 1,142 ringgit two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Traders said exports to India, a major export market in recent months, are expected to remain good in coming months.</p>
<p>Industry officials in India have said the country might import up to 250,000 tonnes of palm olein during the Hindu festival months of September and October to offset thin domestic supplies.</p>
<p>Most of the oil is likely to come from Malaysia as Indonesia, another leading exporter, is facing tight domestic supply, Malaysian traders said. In fact, Indonesia was said to have bought Malaysian palm olein in recent days.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, India's State Trading Corporation bought 12,000 tonnes of Malaysian palm olein for September/October shipment. Pakistan bought 6,000 tonnes RBD palm oil and 3,000 tonnes of palm olein for October 10 delivery.</p>
<p>Traders said India would continue to buy even at current prices as domestic oils are not available in bulk quantities ahead of the festival season.</p>
<p>India imported nearly 220,000 tonnes of palm olein between April and July, the industry officials said.</p>
<p>Traders said China may also make a return to the market after the government recently approved imports of 1.3 million tonnes of palm oil between August 1996 and March 1997.</p>
<p>While the news may have been factored into the market, they said China's incremental purchase of palm oil under the quota will help support prices.</p>
<p>Traders added that though rising prices could lead to some washout of existing contracts, the impact on prices would be minimal. Indian and Chinese buyers were said to have washed out some 35,000 tonnes of palm oil on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Washing out of contracts is possible as buyers take advantage of higher prices but I don't think it will have any significant impact,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Private crop forecaster Ivan Wong said in a recent report that Malaysian palm oil stocks would not reach worrisome levels as long as palm oil prices remain competitive in relation to other major oils and fats. He also expects the healthy exports to be sustainable up to October.</p>
<p>Stocks at the end of July stood at 754,634 tonnes, according to official Palm Oil Registration and Licensing Authority estimates. Exports in July were 646,017 tonnes, the second highest monthly figure ever recorded.</p>
<p>Cargo surveyor Societe Generale de Surveillance on Monday estimated Malaysia's palm oil exports for August 1-25 at 537,175 tonnes against 521,904 tonnes for July 1-25. ($1=2.4930 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
