<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18140" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China yuan interbank rates fall on interest cut.</title>
<headline>China yuan interbank rates fall on interest cut.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rates on China's renminbi interbank market have fallen sharply since the central bank cut loan and deposit rates last week and the downtrend is likely to continue, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>With inflation falling and Beijing expected to cut bank reserve ratios in the near future, the market's interest rates might fall to about an annual 10 percent by the end of this year from about 11.6 percent currently, they said.</p>
<p>The People's Bank of China cut bank deposit and loan rates by an average of 1.5 and 1.2 percentage points respectively on Friday. Rumours of the cut began circulating on the Shanghai-based interbank market as early as Monday last week.</p>
<p>On Wednesday last week, the China Interbank Offered Rates, the market's weighted averages, fell sharply across the board for the first time since the market opened early this year.</p>
<p>Since then, most of the rates have continued to drop, with all the rates for the seven contracts on the markets now below 12 percent for the first time.</p>
<p>Market traders said many members, including state banks and provincial short-term financing centres, money brokerages run by the central bank, had increased loan volume in the past week on expectations of further falls in the rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates on the markets became much higher than those for bank loans and deposits after the cut,&quot; said one trader with a major Chinese bank. &quot;The cut has reduced cost of money movements of the banks, making it possible for them to lend out more.&quot;</p>
<p>The annual rate for the shortest six-month bank loans has fallen to 9.18 percent since the cut, compared with 11.619 percent for the longest four-month contract on the interbank market as of Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;After a week of falling, the news of the cut has largely been digested and rates are likely to consolidate in a narrow range for a short period,&quot; said a second trader. &quot;But there are still many mid-term factors driving the rates down.&quot;</p>
<p>The most important of these was the central bank's promise to cut bank reserve ratios for banks and financial institutions within this year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Beijing currently requires banks and financial institutions to deposit 13 percent of their total deposits as reserves in the central bank and set aside another five to seven percent, also in the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;A bank reserve ratio cut will release huge amounts of money on to the market,&quot; said a Chinese banker. &quot;With supply increasing considerably, renminbi interbank rates will go down.&quot;</p>
<p>Banking analysts said another factor was that the market was expecting further but slight bank interest rate cuts by the central bank.</p>
<p>This year, the central bank has twice cut bank interest rates, with the first cut on May 1, which was the first cut since 1993. Up to now, the bank has adjusted the rates rarely but by large margins, the analysts said.</p>
<p>The central bank has said that it will adjust rates more often but in narrower ranges in future.</p>
<p>&quot;In the coming months, whenever there is news of falling inflation, the interbank rates are likely to move down slightly, with the market speculating about possible slight adjustments of bank interest rates,&quot; said a second banker.</p>
<p>Inflation was a year-on-year 7.1 percent in the first half of 1996, down from a year-on-year 14.8 percent in all 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
