<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18141" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: On death row, Chun keeps South Korea guessing.</title>
<headline>On death row, Chun keeps South Korea guessing.</headline>
<byline>Jean Yoon</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Condemned South Korean former president Chun Doo Hwan on Wednesday kept the nation guessing on whether he would appeal his death sentence, with media reports saying he may be courting martyrdom.</p>
<p>The tough ex-general has seven days to appeal his conviction against mutiny, treason and corruption handed down by a Seoul court on Monday.</p>
<p>By letting the deadline slip away, Chun would be casting his life into the hands of current President Kim Young-sam, who has power to offer a pardon.</p>
<p>Political analysts said this would put Kim in the politically uncomfortable position of having to choose between satisfying a thirst for vengeance by some Koreans and holding on to Chun's political supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;This will become a major headache for Kim and his party before presidential elections next year,&quot; said Cho Chang-hyun, political science professor at Hanyang University.</p>
<p>The Hankook Ilbo newspaper quoted Chun as telling one of his lawyers, &quot;I'd prefer to end the whole thing by sacrificing myself rather than appealing. I don't want the trial to be extended&quot;.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Chun were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>There was also no word on whether Chun's successor, Roh Tae-woo, would appeal his 22-1/2 year jail sentence on similar charges.</p>
<p>Analysts said President Kim almost certainly was hoping for a lengthy appeal process that would give him more time to gauge the public mood before making a decision.</p>
<p>&quot;If Chun chooses not to appeal, the sentence would be carried out sooner than Kim's administration had estimated,&quot; said Cho.</p>
<p>&quot;President Kim would have to make up his mind sooner than expected and that won't be easy.&quot;</p>
<p>Chun has done nothing to court public sympathy or curry favour with the judges.</p>
<p>He scoffed at legal proceedings, which he called a political circus orchestrated by Kim to settle a personal grudge and boost his popularity ratings. For that reason, some analysts believe he may feel there is little point trying to escape death row.</p>
<p>A hunger strike while in detention left Chun hanging on to life by a thread.</p>
<p>His uncompromising stand has won him the grudging respect of some Koreans.</p>
<p>State prosecutors on Tuesday said they would decide by the end of this week whether to appeal against Roh's sentence. They had demanded life in jail.</p>
<p>Business tycoons who received jail terms on Monday on charges of bribing Roh during his presidency began appealing against their sentences on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jinro group chairman Chang Jin-ho and Hanbo group's honorary chairman Chung Tae-soo both filed appeals. Daewoo head Kim Woo-choong and Dong-Ah chairman Choi Won-suk have said they will challenge the verdict.</p>
<p>Samsung chairman Lee Kun-hee was handed a two year jail sentence suspended for three years. Some media reports have speculated that Lee and four other tycoons handed suspended terms will not bother to return to court.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
