<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18144" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China tells Taiwan direct trade can't be stopped.</title>
<headline>China tells Taiwan direct trade can't be stopped.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Vice Premier Li Lanqing said on Wednesday that no one can stand in the way of direct trade betwen China and Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic development between the two sides is the general trend and no single person can obstruct this,&quot; he told a seminar on economic links with Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;Any person who tries to place artificial barriers to restrict economic cooperation is going against the will of the people of the two sides,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Taiwan currently bans direct trade with China but it has allowed trade to be conducted through other territories such as Hong Kong.</p>
<p>China has been pressing Taiwan to open up direct links. Last week, it issued a set of regulations it hopes will govern trade once there is agreement on the issue by the two sides.</p>
<p>The vice-premier also told the seminar, attended by a major delegation of Taiwanese businessmen, that he hoped Taiwan authorities would allow direct links as soon as possible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
