<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18145" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks slip in cautious morning trade.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks slip in cautious morning trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks turned weak in Wednesday morning trade, after moving slightly higher earlier, as investors cautiously awaited more corporate earnings and the expiry of August Hang Seng futures, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index was down 22.82 points at 11,316.11. Turnover was HK$889 million after the first hour of trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Dull trading will continue for a while,&quot; said Sunny Chan, senior research manager at Seapower Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow is settlement day for futures and after CITIC Pacific's results, no major blue chips are scheduled to release yet so I don't see much excitement before the major property counters release their interims at the end of September,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said a rebound in U.S. stocks overnight had helped the market edge higher in early trade. The Dow industrials rose 17.38 points on Tuesday to 5,711.27 and the U.S. long bond added 10/32 to yield 6.97 percent.</p>
<p>But they expected stocks to remain in a range ahead of Thursday's expiry of August Hang Seng futures. August Hang Seng futures were up eight points at 11,293.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment the range is 11,000 to 11,400. 11,500 will be major resistance,&quot; said Chan.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific rose HK$0.20 to HK$34.60 following its strong interim results. The company reported a 255 percent increase in profit attributable to shareholders to HK$4.99 billion. It also proposed a special dividend of HK$0.30.</p>
<p>Weak earnings continued to plague the H-share index which was down 10 points at 816. Harbin Power fell HK$0.11 to HK$1.19. It reported first-half net profit of 32.61 million yuan, down from 55.18 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
