<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181598" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-KLINSMANN SCORES TWICE IN BAYERN CUP WIN. [CORRECTED 4:29 GMT 14/11]</title>
<headline>SOCCER-KLINSMANN SCORES TWICE IN BAYERN CUP WIN. [CORRECTED 4:29 GMT 14/11]</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Juergen Klinsmann scored twice as Bayern Munich came back from a goal down to beat Werder Bremen 3-1 win on Tuesday and clinch a place in the German Cup quarter-finals for the first time since 1988.</p>
<p>(Corrects from &quot;German Cup semifinals&quot;)</p>
<p>The victory avenged a 3-0 league defeat by Bremen in September.</p>
<p>Bremen made the more positive start and went ahead in the 12th minute with a goal by Marco Bodo. Bodo had two further good scoring chances in the first half and his failure to convert them cost his side dearly.</p>
<p>Seconds  before the halftime whistle Klinsmann headed Bayern level from Christian Ziege's cross into the box.</p>
<p>Bayern were clearly the stronger team in the second half and took the lead in the 65th minute when Ruggiero Rizzitelli lured Bremen goalkeeper Oliver Reck out of his goal before laying on a fine pass for Ziege to score.</p>
<p>Klinsmann put the icing on the cake with his second goal in the final minute.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the team played their best home match of the season so far,&quot; said Bayern midfielder Lothar Matthaeus.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's other tie, regional league side Energie Cottbus secured a place in the quarter-finals for the first time in their history with a shock win over first division St Pauli in a penalty shoot-out.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
