<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18150" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turk MPs vote to abolish savings scheme.</title>
<headline>Turk MPs vote to abolish savings scheme.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's parliament voted to abolish a widely criticised state savings scheme in an emergency session that stretched out into the early hours of Wednesday, the state-run Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>The motion to abolish the scheme was passed with the votes of the Islamist-led government despite bloc opposition from the other parties. The government has 280 seats in the 550-seat parliament.</p>
<p>The scheme was instituted in 1988 to boost investment, but union leaders and other critics say it has been widely abused and offered little in the way of returns.</p>
<p>Analysts have said the fund abolition is likely to be welcomed by workers who will see an immediate benefit to their wage packets and employers, whose wage costs will fall.</p>
<p>But they say it will not be of any positive benefit to the economy as the government still has to make payments to workers and will have to consider alternative savings measures.</p>
<p>Since the scheme was set up, workers have paid two percent of their salaries and employers contributed a further three percent. The government has not provided figures on the size of the fund.</p>
<p>The abolition of the savings scheme, the latest in a series of populist moves by the Islamist-led coalition, will take effect in the month after it is published in the Official Gazette, Anatolian said.</p>
<p>In earlier populist moves, civil servants have been given a larger-than-expected wage rise and the minimum wage was doubled, raising concerns about the government's commitment to rein in Turkey's gaping deficits.</p>
<p>Annual inflation in Turkey is running at over 80 percent and the 1996 budget deficit is expected to total 1,300 trillion lira ($15 billion).</p>
<p>($1 = 86,000 lira)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
