<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18156" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Grain, cotton prices fall as speculators sell.</title>
<headline>Grain, cotton prices fall as speculators sell.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and cotton prices fell sharply Wednesday as professional speculators took profits and exited the market before the Labour Day holiday.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, soybeans keyed a general selloff in grain markets after the key November delivery could not sustain a gain over the $8 per bushel level. That level had not been reached since July 17.</p>
<p>November soybeans closed at $7.88-3/4, down 7 cents a bushel, after hitting a high during the day at $8.02.</p>
<p>Buying this week in soybeans has been underpinned by worries about the late-planted Midwestern crop and possible frost damage before harvesting this fall.</p>
<p>But soybeans are a speculative favourite, and analysts said that commodity funds, which are large speculative investors, wanted to lock in profits and take new positions next week in anticipation of warmer weather for the Midwest.</p>
<p>&quot;End-of-the-month fund profit-taking,&quot; said analyst Steve Bruce of E.D. and F. Man International, describing the slide in corn and wheat as well as soybeans. &quot;They've been buying it all month and don't want to hold it.&quot;</p>
<p>December corn closed 6 cents lower at $3.42-3/4 a bushel and December wheat ended 9 cents lower at $4.55.</p>
<p>At the New York Cotton Exchange, cotton prices also fell back after rising earlier this week on worries that Hurricane Edouard could damage the maturing Southeast cotton crop.</p>
<p>But the storm Wednesday was predicted to turn northwest in the Atlantic and largely miss the United States.</p>
<p>December cotton closed 0.65 cent a pound lower at $76.11.</p>
<p>The storm news overshadowed a revised forecast from the International Cotton Advisory Committee for China cotton output this season at 3.7 million metric tons, down from 4.1 million previously. China is a leading importer of cotton.</p>
<p>Reduced concern over possible damage from Hurricane Edouard also prompted a fall in lumber futures at the Chicago Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>September lumber, which hit a 2-1/2-year high Tuesday, closed 70 cents lower at $413.20 per thousand board feet.</p>
<p>But strong cash market demand for quick-shipment wood in many markets should support prices, traders said.</p>
<p>CME pork belly futures also ended lower as the red-hot bacon demand of the summer continued to cool off and physical supplies improved. February pork bellies closed down the 2.00 cent per pound daily limit at 82.050 cents.</p>
<p>August pork belly futures set an all-time high of 105.25 cents on Aug. 8 before plummeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Kills are increasing seasonally and this will give us more supply,&quot; said Julia Bussie, analyst for AG Edwards.</p>
<p>Oil prices at the New York Mercantile Exchange rose with the help of a drawdown in weekly U.S. oil product stocks and concern that tropical storm Fran may affect an Amerada Hess refinery in St. Croix in the Caribbean.</p>
<p>October crude oil rose 15 cents a barrel at $21.71. September unleaded gasoline rose 1.12 cents a gallon at 62.33 cents and September heating oil 0.91 cent a gallon at 62.04.</p>
<p>American Petroleum Institute statistics for the week to Aug. 23 showed gasoline stocks fell 2.238 million barrels and distillates or heating oil feedstock fell 463,000 barrels.</p>
<p>U.S. distillates stocks are now more than 19 million barrels, or 15 percent, below levels at the same time last year, raising concern among refiners in the runup to the Northern Hemisphere winter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
