<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18162" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: attorneys.</title>
<headline>attorneys.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The admission that three lysine producers conspired to fix prices means Archer Daniels Midland Co. is likely to face criminal charges in the government's probe of the food additives market, legal experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It puts them on notice that their alleged co-conspirators are cooperating with the government, providing both documents and oral testimony,&quot; said Robert Stephenson, a lawyer with Cotsirilos, Stephenson, Tighe &amp; Streicker in Chicago.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said on Tuesday that Ajinomoto Co. Inc. and Kyowa Hakko Kogyo Co. Ltd., both based in Tokyo, and the U.S. unit of South Korea's Sewon Company Ltd. admitted they conspired to fix prices for lysine, an animal feed supplement. It also said the three companies have agreed to provide documents and witnesses to investigators.</p>
<p>The agreement, under which three executives also pleaded guilty or no contest to the charges, significantly turns up the heat on Archer Daniels Midland (ADM), the lawyers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The table stakes have significantly increased that ADM will be charged,&quot; said Stephenson, who is not involved in the ADM case but is an experienced antitrust attorney.</p>
<p>ADM declined to comment. Since the government's probe of the food additives market came to light more than a year ago, the Decatur, Ill.-based agribusiness giant has denied any wrongdoing and said it was cooperating fully with investigators.</p>
<p>Justice Department spokeswoman Gina Talamona said Wednesday that all of the defendants except Ajinomoto agreed to plead guilty. Ajinomoto agreed to plead no contest, meaning it does not want to fight the charges, which in practice is little different from a guilty plea, lawyers said.</p>
<p>&quot;If they (the government) have signed some of the potential defendants to plea agreements that include a commitment to cooperate, that puts tremendous pressure on the remaining potential defendant, of which ADM is obviously one,&quot; said Joe Sims, an attorney with Jones, Day, Reavis &amp; Pogue.</p>
<p>That prospect was making some investors nervous, and ADM stock fell 62.5 cents to $17.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is definitely (saying), 'This can't be good news for ADM,'&quot; Dain Bosworth analyst Bonnie Wittenburg said. &quot;The fact that the foreign companies have agreed to cooperate in the government case (makes investors) nervous.&quot;</p>
<p>The pleas by the three companies and their executives came about 14 months after ADM acknowleged the government had asked for documents and testimony in its investigation of the markets for high-fructose corn syrup and citric acid, two common food additives, as well as lysine. Lysine sales alone exceed $600 million a year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Stephenson said the plea deals by Ajinomoto, Kyowa Hakko and Sewon diminish the government's need to rely on Mark Whitacre, a former ADM official turned government informant, as a witness against ADM. ADM fired Whitacre last year over allegations he embezzled millions of dollars from the company.</p>
<p>At this point, ADM may decide to enter a plea or it could face a criminal indictment, attorney Sims said.</p>
<p>&quot;Either one of those things can come reasonably promptly,&quot; said Sims, an antitrust expert who is not directly involved in the ADM case. &quot;I would not be surprised to see something in the next 30 days.&quot;</p>
<p>If ADM decided to enter a plea, analysts said it could easily afford the $10 million fines that were levied against Ajinomoto and Kyowa.</p>
<p>&quot;Those are not the kinds of fines that are going to break the company,&quot; Piper Jaffray analyst George Dahlman said. ADM had about $3 billion in working capital as of March, he said.</p>
<p>In a separate proceeding, ADM has agreed to pay $25 million to settle a civil lysine price-fixing lawsuit brought by its customers as part of an overall $45 million settlement that also involved Ajinomoto and Kyowa Hakko.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
