<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18165" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks gain in quiet market.</title>
<headline>Stocks gain in quiet market.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street stocks were slightly higher Wednesday in a sluggish session that saw much of the activity limited to a few individual issues.</p>
<p>At 1:00 p.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was up 1.48 points at 5,712.75. In the broader market, advancing issues led declines by a 11-9 on moderate volume of 177 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index was up 2.93 to 1,151.95 and the American Stock Exchange index rose 0.78 to 562.83.</p>
<p>Except for a few standout performers, blue chips were generally steady, paced by a subdued bond market ahead of Wednesdasy afternoon's Treasury auction of $12.5 billion in five-year notes.</p>
<p>&quot;The market continues to wallow and is basically directionless,&quot; said Dick Stein, vice president at U.S. Clearing Corp. &quot;I think everyone is looking forward to the long weekend.&quot;</p>
<p>Treasuries were generally steady, defying predictions that a sell-off would push yields up ahead of Wednesday's Treasury sale.</p>
<p>Analysts had expressed concern about demand for the notes after participation levels for Tuesday's two-year note auction proved disappointing.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury slipped 1/32, or 31 cents on a $1,000 bond, raising its yield to 6.98 percent from 6.97 percent at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>Among individual issues, CompuServe Corp. rose 1-1/16 to 13-3/8 after H&amp;R Block Inc., which holds a major shareholder, called off a proposal to spin off its 80 percent stake in the online service provider.</p>
<p>H&amp;R Block, which cited projected losses at CompuServe and online industry market uncertainties as reasons for the decision, fell 1-5/8 to 26-1/4. H&amp;R Block said it will continue to consider a future spin-off of CompuServe.</p>
<p>Reebok International Ltd. rose 15/16 to 35-1/2 after saying that it would buy back 17 million shares at $36 a share under a previously announced repurchase.</p>
<p>Garden Botanika Inc. slid 3-7/16 to 9-13/16 after it reported a loss for the latest quarter. The company also said its August sales were disappointing and could bode ill for its third-quarter results.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
