<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18166" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MFS-WorldCom deal opens gate for resellers.</title>
<headline>MFS-WorldCom deal opens gate for resellers.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hordes of smaller, aggressive telephone companies banging at the gates of AT&amp;T Corp., Sprint Corp., and MCI Communications Corp. have already grabbed $12 billion of the $80 billion long-distance market.</p>
<p>The merger pact between MFS Communications Co. Inc. and WorldCom Inc. announced on Monday will allow tiny resellers of phone capacity to make even bigger inroads into the lucrative businesses that the industry's giants have called their own.</p>
<p>MFS WorldCom will be a ferocious competitor, able to offer end-to-end business services. It is also likely to encourage new entrants in new markets by offering &quot;private label&quot; telecommunications services and capacity off the shelf.</p>
<p>&quot;It's international services, data, Internet and intranet as well as local service resale,&quot; said industry analyst Daryl Edmonds at brokerage Bear Stearns Cos. Inc.</p>
<p>Omaha, Neb.-based MFS provides local calling networks to businesses, while WorldCom, based in Jackson, Miss., is a long-distance and international carrier.</p>
<p>&quot;The move between WorldCom and MFS is a brilliant deal strategically,&quot; said Jack McLaine, chief financial officer of Excel Communications Inc., a small long-distance company that does not own phone lines but buys capacity to offer its services.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a good relationship with WorldCom and we look forward to talking with them about what these new products are,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Fast-growing companies such as Dallas-based Excel, one of about 400 such firms in the industry, have gobbled up chunks of the long-distance market and set the standard for cheap service, analysts said.</p>
<p>McLaine said Excel was interested in offering Internet, local telephone and home security monitoring services, and that the national reach of MFS WorldCom would make it easier for it to enter those markets.</p>
<p>For long-distance companies, and regional Bells trying to defend their home turfs, the advent of MFS Worldcom will mean more competition, more pressure on margins and harder work to keep customers, analysts and industry officials said.</p>
<p>The big three long-distance companies make fat profit margins on high-speed data, Internet access, international calls and similar services. MFS Worldcom threatens this not only as a competitor itself, but as a conduit for other smaller phone companies that lack their own capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;You now have one company, MFS WorldCom, which crystalizes the brave new world (of competition),&quot; said Simon Flannery at J. P. Morgan. Resellers could always have pieced together such services, but the MFS WorldCom merger will make it easier, he noted.</p>
<p>The advantage to MFS WorldCom is that as long as its customers market to consumers, they will not be competing with MFS WorldCom's own branded product, which is aimed at small businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;We think it is a very positive move for the reseller marketplace,&quot; MFS WorldCom Chief Executive-designate Bernard Ebbers said during a news conference on Monday, mentioning Excel and GTE Corp. as possible buyers of services.</p>
<p>GTE and some regional Bells already buy long-distance services from WorldCom as they seek to enter that market. Using MFS networks, they could extend local services into cities in other parts of the country.</p>
<p>UUNET, the Internet service provider that MFS bought for $2 billion earlier this month, will also benefit. As part of MFS WorldCom, it will be able to use 2,900 salespeople across the country instead of 63.</p>
<p>The new competition is one of the goals of the 1996 Telecommunications Act, but the irony is that the merger of MFS and Worldcom could have occurred without deregulation.</p>
<p>&quot;Both companies were unencumbered by national regulation,&quot; said Bear Stearns' Edmonds, though they still needed access to parts of regional Bells' local networks, a process that was eased by the new law.</p>
<p>&quot;MCI or Sprint will say 'We can do this too,'&quot; said J. P. Morgan's Flannery, referring to the integrated services MFS Worldcom is offering. But most long-distance companies lag some way behind.</p>
<p>MCI on Tuesday detailed its local phone service plans, but its MCI Metro network will reach only 25 cities by March 1997, while MFS already has 45 cities up and running.</p>
<p>Still, analysts reckon it will be some time before MFS WorldCom becomes a threat to what is the most profitable area for many phone companies -- the national or global communication accounts at large companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
