<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18172" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: H&amp;R Block decides not to spin off Compuserve.</title>
<headline>H&amp;R Block decides not to spin off Compuserve.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>H&amp;R Block Inc. said Wednesday it has decided not to pursue the proposed spin-off of the rest of its Compuserve Corp. online service.</p>
<p>The Kansas City, Mo.-based company, which owns 80 percent of Compuserve after spinning off part of the online provider earlier this year, cited Compuserve's recent and projected losses and market uncertainties regarding the online industry.  </p>
<p>H&amp;R Block said in a statement that it has decided not to present the proposed spin-off of the rest of Compuserve to shareholders at its annual meeting scheduled for Sept. 11.</p>
<p>&quot;The board continues to believe that a separation of Compuserve is in the best interests of H&amp;R Block shareholders and will continue to consider the matter,&quot; H&amp;R Block interim president Frank Salizzoni said.</p>
<p>The company said its annual meeting will take place in Kansas City as scheduled.</p>
<p>H&amp;R Block spun off 20 percent of Compuserve in April and had planned to distribute the rest to its shareholders later this year.</p>
<p>Last week Compuserve reported a loss for its fiscal first quarter and said it expected a loss for the second quarter as well. It said a decline in subscriber growth, investments in its WOW! service for novice users and other costs hurt its first-quarter performance.</p>
<p>Last month a group of investors filed a class-action lawsuit against Compuserve, alleging that the company and H&amp;R Block violated federal securities laws by failing to disclose that Compuserve's subscriber base growth and profitability were in jeopardy.</p>
<p>Compuserve shares rose $1.1875 to $13.50 after the announcement, but remained well below the $30 a share price of the stock offering in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
