<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18184" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU stays out of intense Swedish EMU debate.</title>
<headline>EU stays out of intense Swedish EMU debate.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission reacted cautiously to news on Wednesday that Sweden may decide not to join monetary union from its planned start in 1999, saying it did not want to interfere in an important internal debate.</p>
<p>However, a Commission spokesman noted that the European Union treaty listed only two countries -- Denmark and Britain -- as having the possibility to opt out from economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;These countries do not include Sweden. That is where we are right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether a country like Sweden could decide by itself to delay entry into monetary union, the spokesman said: &quot;I don't think we are yet in a position to discuss that.&quot;</p>
<p>He stressed, however, that the ultimate decision on which countries join the single currency would be taken by the member states, whose leaders are due to meet on the issue in 1998.</p>
<p>Denmark decided in a referendum in 1993 not to join the single currency. A new plebiscite would be needed to enable Copenhagen to overturn that decision.</p>
<p>Britain has an opt-out from EMU and has not yet made a final position on whether to join.</p>
<p>Despite not negotiating its own opt-out clause when it joined the EU on January 1, 1995, Sweden's Social Democratic government insists that it is the national parliament which will decide next year on Swedish EMU membership.</p>
<p>Fuelling speculation that the decision will be to wait for membership beyond 1999, Finance Minister Erik Asbrink said on Wednesday that Swedish entry to EMU could be delayed.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a question of yes or no to currency union. It is rather about 'yes now' or 'no now',&quot; he said in a signed article in the Dagens Nyheter newspaper.</p>
<p>Asbrink later said it was an open question whether Sweden would join EMU in the first stage or not.</p>
<p>The Social Democratic party is split on the EMU issue and a recent opinion poll showed that a majority of its supporters are opposed to membership.</p>
<p>The Commission spokesman declined to comment on Asbrink's article, saying he had only seen news reports about it.</p>
<p>But, he added, &quot;what we basically say is that we understand that there is an important debate going on in Sweden about this which we think is a very good thing because this is a major development and there should be a good internal poltical discussion within Sweden about it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;So we don't want to interfere into that debate,&quot; the spokesman added.</p>
<p>An EU monetary official said he did not believe that there would be a clash between Brussels and Stockholm on the issue of membership, acknowledging there was not much anyone could do if Sweden decided to stay out.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
