<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18188" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Safe-haven Swiss franc turns into money magnet.</title>
<headline>Safe-haven Swiss franc turns into money magnet.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nervous investors are still piling into the Swiss franc because of uncertainty about the future of Europe's single currency and to flee European Union tax havens that are coming under increasing scrutiny, Swiss bankers say.</p>
<p>A steady inflow of funds has helped underpin the franc near April highs against the mark, keeping the German currency near the Swiss pain threshhold of 80 centimes to the mark at a time the export-dependent Swiss economy is suffering.</p>
<p>The wave of funds reaching Switzerland makes little economic sense given the interest-rate differentials with Germany, but there is no stopping people running scared before the proposed 1999 start of Europe's Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;What we are seeing has nothing to do with rationality. This has more to do with fear,&quot; said Rainer Marian, a senior economist at Credit Suisse who tracks foreign exchange flows.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still people who for fear of EMU are investing in Swiss francs, but this is not rational.&quot;</p>
<p>Many people putting their nesteggs in Switzerland are keeping it in foreign currencies, he stressed, and Credit Suisse is advising its customers against switching into Swiss francs in a currency play based on fears of an unstable 'Euro'.</p>
<p>&quot;With 10-year German bonds yielding 6.35 percent and Swiss bonds at 4.25 percent, the 2.1-point difference compounded over 10 years means the mark/franc rate would have to drop from 80.70 to 66.10 for break-even. We do not think this is realistic.&quot;</p>
<p>Hans Kaufmann at Bank Julius Baer said EU efforts to make tax treatment the same across the board was pushing money out of places like Luxembourg -- where many German and French investors have traditionally parked funds -- into Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;And don't forget about Austria, where banking secrecy is not as safe as was thought,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Talk about postponing EMU or softening financial criteria for the single currency has also created some uncertainty among investors who often see the franc as a rock-hard store of value compared with the nascent Euro currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Money is coming in steadily. We can see it from our private clients,&quot; Kaufmann said, although he and other bankers said it was impossible to estimate how much money was involved.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people are coming into the Swiss franc to wait out the uncertainty,&quot; he observed.</p>
<p>What is more, big Swiss portfolio managers could also start switching into francs if they thought the Swiss National Bank (SNB) was not easing monetary policy enough in light of stagnant growth and rate cuts by other central banks, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would dwarf the proverbial German with a suitcase stuffed with cash,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kaufmann said the SNB was coming under increasing political pressure to ease up, adding: &quot;This is the first time I have seen some officials close to panicking.&quot;</p>
<p>The SNB has watched currency developments closely after EMU jitters pushed up the franc in 1995. It has added money market liquidity lately in what some economists see as a sign exchange rates are gaining importance versus money supply targets.</p>
<p>Union Bank of Switzerland analyst Walter Metzler said some foreign customers were apparently prepared to accept lower yields by switching into francs. &quot;This is the price of having lower risk,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he stressed that other factors as well were burnishing the franc's image as a safe bet, including uncertainty about political developments in Russia. &quot;This is not something with just one cause,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the franc's recent strength could tempt investors eager for a speculative play.</p>
<p>&quot;One factor is expectations that with the rate near 80 (centimes) the mark could shoot through levels that would push it to 70 and make lots of money for people with little downside risk,&quot; Metzler said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
