<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18183" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac wants France to snap out of doldrums.</title>
<headline>Chirac wants France to snap out of doldrums.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Jacques Chirac, chairing his first post-summer holiday cabinet meeting, urged his ministers on Wednesday to &quot;get yourselves together&quot; and not give in to the widening pessimism that has gripped France.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the behaviour that I expect from the government and all of its ministers,&quot; Chirac, back from a Riviera holiday, lectured the cabinet, warning against conduct that would contribute to &quot;the general gloom&quot;.</p>
<p>The government returned from its traditional summer break facing a daunting agenda including growing joblessness, labour unrest and anger over its botched handling of 300 African immigrants who occupied a Paris church in protest at hardline 1993 immigration law reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;To listen to the...commentators, the government's return to work has been marked by gloom. And this is true -- how could it be otherwise,&quot; Chirac said, according to government spokesman Alain Lamassoure.</p>
<p>&quot;The social and economic situation, in spite of encouraging signs, remains difficult despite the government's determined efforts to improve the situation in a France that has been weakened by a long period of carelessness,&quot; Chirac said.</p>
<p>According to a CSA poll published on Wednesday in the daily La Tribune, 54 percent of voters are pessimistic as they go back to work, with strikes, poverty and job losses topping worries.</p>
<p>The poll found that 77 percent expected strikes and trouble for the centre-right government in the autumn.</p>
<p>Record unemployment, planned public spending cuts and layoffs have infuriated unions, who are threatening a fresh wave of unrest in a possible revival of the lengthy public-sector strikes which virtually crippled France late last year.</p>
<p>Nicole Notat, head of the country's biggest union, the CFDT, and Louis Viannet, the head of the Communist-led CGT union, have warned of labour unrest after the holidays.</p>
<p>Teachers' unions have announced demonstrations and a likely strike over job cuts expected in the 1997 austerity budget. Farmers have also threatened protests.</p>
<p>Public support also has been growing for the Africans who were evicted from the Saint-Bernard church after a two-month occupation begun in hopes of winning residence in France.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe initially ignored the protest, but when it began to dominate the headlines he ordered hundreds of police to smash their way into the church. To let the Africans remain would be illegal, he announced.</p>
<p>But five days later, the government had expelled just four of the Africans and acknowledged that as many as two-thirds of the others might ultimately be allowed to stay.</p>
<p>The raid thus enraged both the left-wing opposition, which denounced the police action as a crude violation of human rights, and the far right, which said the government had opened the door to illegal immigration.</p>
<p>It also provided the unions with a potent new issue in a series of protests already planned for the next two months.</p>
<p>On another sticky issue confronting the cabinet, Chirac aides said he would meet on Friday a delegation of cattle breeders upset by plummeting beef prices due to fears over mad cow disease.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
