<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184765" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texaco seen unhurt by race issue in long haul.</title>
<headline>Texaco seen unhurt by race issue in long haul.</headline>
<byline>Ian Simpson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Texaco Inc's image may be tarnished but its profit outlook remains untainted by the turmoil of a race discrimination suit and the resulting boycott of the oil company's products.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said a boycott and picketing of Texaco service stations urged by black leaders in protest of alleged discrimination would be more likely to hurt thousands of independent Texaco franchisees than the company itself.</p>
<p>&quot;Is this (protest) going to bring the company down? Come on,&quot; said Peter Gilman, senior oil analyst at UBS Securities. &quot;It's going to blow over.&quot;</p>
<p>Texaco stock rose 2-1/2 to close 98 on Wednesday, its highest level since Nov 5, when the storm over racial discrimination broke.</p>
<p>A company spokesman said since only 1,000 of the 14,000 Texaco stations nationwide were owned directly by the company they did not have any information on the furor's impact on sales.</p>
<p>However, the Texaco Food Mart, a station a few miles away from Texaco's headquarters in White Plains, N.Y., has seen daytime sales drop five to 10 percent over the last two weeks, a spokesman said. Two other stations reported no drop.</p>
<p>Charles Fombrun, an economics professor at New York University and an expert on how businesses acquire reputations, said most boycotts had only temporary effects in changing the way companies do business.</p>
<p>Texaco &quot;certainly was aggressive in their strategies in the way they do business,&quot; Fombrun said. &quot;They are not one of the softer, gentler companies out there.&quot;</p>
<p>A 1994 federal suit by six black Texaco employees claimed the company had discriminated against them and fostered a hostile enviroment. The suit seeks $71 million in damages.</p>
<p>Texaco has suspended two executives and the benefits of two retirees allegedly involved in a plan to destroy documents in the suit.</p>
<p>According to a transcript of a tape recording, the executives allegedly also used racial epithets to describe black Texaco employees in a 1994 meeting. The company said an enhanced examination of the tape showed they did not use the most offensive term.</p>
<p>After a meeting with chairman and chief executive Peter Bijur on Tuesday, civil rights leaders the Rev. Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton called for picketing starting Saturday.</p>
<p>They also urged an immediate boycott and divestiture of shares by stockholders. The call was echoed by National Conference of Black Mayors.</p>
<p>Steven Pfeifer, an oil analyst at PaineWebber, said a boycott would probaby cut Texaco's earnings per share $0.01 to $0.02. Fourth-quarter earnings are predicted to be between $1.50 and $1.60 a share.</p>
<p>Bijur has vowed to eradicate racial discrimination in the company and settle the suit as quickly as possible. Pfeifer said full payment of the $71 million sought would cost Texaco $0.70 a share.</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk, (212) 859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
