<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184766" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texaco seen unhurt over long term by race issue. [CORRECTED 00:46 GMT 15/11]</title>
<headline>Texaco seen unhurt over long term by race issue. [CORRECTED 00:46 GMT 15/11]</headline>
<byline>Ian Simpson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Texaco Inc.'s image may be tarnished but its profit outlook remains untainted by the turmoil of a racial discrimination suit and the resulting boycott of the oil company's products, industry analysts said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The analysts said the boycott and picketing of Texaco service stations urged by black leaders to protest alleged discrimination was more likely to hurt thousands of independent Texaco franchise holders than the parent company.</p>
<p>&quot;Is this (protest) going to bring the company down? Come on,&quot; said Peter Gilman, senior oil analyst at UBS Securities. &quot;It's going to blow over.&quot;</p>
<p>A 1994 lawsuit by six black Texaco employees alleges the company discriminated against them and fostered a hostile enviroment. The lawsuit seeks $71 million in damages.</p>
<p>Texaco has suspended two executives and the benefits of two retirees allegedly involved in a plan to destroy documents in the suit.</p>
<p>A federal prosecutor in New York recently issued a subpoena to Texaco, seeking documents related to the employees' allegations, the company said Wednesday in a quarterly filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
<p>According to a transcript of a tape recording, the executives allegedly also used racial slurs to describe black Texaco employees in a 1994 meeting. The company said an enhanced examination of the tape showed they did not use the most offensive term.</p>
<p>After a meeting with Chairman Peter Bijur on Tuesday, civil rights leaders the Rev. Jesse Jackson and Al Sharpton called for protests at Texaco stations starting on Saturday and urged stockholders to sell their shares. The call was echoed by the National Conference of Black Mayors.</p>
<p>Steven Pfeifer, analyst at PaineWebber, said a boycott could cut Texaco's earnings by 1 to 2 cents a share. Analysts estimate the company will earn $1.50 to $1.60 a share in the current quarter.</p>
<p>Bijur has vowed to eradicate racial discrimination in the company and settle the suit as quickly as possible. Pfeifer said full payment of the $71 million sought would cost Texaco 25 cents a share. (Corrects from 70 cnets a share).</p>
<p>Charles Fombrun, an economics professor at New York University and an expert on business reputations, said most boycotts had only temporary effects in changing the way companies do business.</p>
<p>&quot;It's such a deep-rooted problem they (Texaco) are facing, it's not something you can deal with with a wave of the hand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A company spokesman said since only 1,000 of the 14,000 Texaco stations nationwide were owned directly by the company they would have incomplete information on the boycott's impact on sales.</p>
<p>However, the Texaco Food Mart, a station a few miles away from Texaco's headquarters in White Plains, N.Y., has seen daytime sales drop 5 percent to 10 percent over the last two weeks, a spokesman said. Two other stations reported no drop.</p>
<p>Separately, a federal judge dismissed a class-action suit brought against the company for alleged environmental damage in Ecuador. The suit was filed in White Plains and the judge said the United States was not the proper forum for the suit.</p>
<p>Texaco stock rose $2.625 to $98 after falling $1.875 on Tuesday, when the boycott was announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
