<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187969" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM says work stoppages to cost $700 mln.</title>
<headline>GM says work stoppages to cost $700 mln.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp said on Thursday that work stoppages at 17 of its North American plants will have an unfavorable impact of $700 million on its fourth-quarter 1996 net income, after recovery plans are implemented.</p>
<p>In a quarterly financial report filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission, General Motors said this will result in a reduction in earnings per share of $0.91 a share for its $1-2/3 par value stock and of $0.11 a share for its class H stock. </p>
<p>GM said that of the estimate, $655 million will impact its North American automotive operations while $45 million will affect the Delco Electronics section of its Hughes Electronics Corp unit.</p>
<p>The automotive giant also said it will take an after-tax charge in its fourth quarter 1996 income of $170 million due to lump sum retiree benefits under its recently announced labor agreement with the United Auto Workers labor union.</p>
<p>This will have an impact on the fourth quarter 1996 earnings per share of $0.22 a share for its $1-2/3 par value stock and $0.02 a share for its class H stock, it said. </p>
<p>Elsewhere in the report, GM said it anticipates that competition through its North American global purchasing process will negatively impact Hughes sales to GM's North American operations.</p>
<p>It added that the increasingly competitive environment in the automotive electronics industry will make it increasingly difficult for its Hughes unit to maintain the current level of operating profit margins.</p>
<p>It said that beyond 1996, operating margins of the section are expected to decrease as price and volume declines associated with GM's global sourcing initiatives more than offest Hughes' ability to achieve cost reductions.</p>
<p>As a result, operating margins of the automotive electronics section are expected to decline to &quot;low double digits&quot; as compared to full operating margins of 15.9 percent, 15.4 percent and 14.0 percent in 1995, 1994 and 1993, GM said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
