<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191069" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FOCUS-Indonesian partner threatens Bre-X with lawsuit.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Indonesian partner threatens Bre-X with lawsuit.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's Bre-X Minerals Ltd could face a multi-billion-dollar lawsuit over the ownership of its spectacular Busang gold deposit in Indonesia.</p>
<p>The young Calgary-based company said Friday that one of its Indonesian partners, PT Krueng Gasui, threatened it and 19 others with legal action in Canadian courts, claiming damages of US$1.9 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;I find it curious that PT Krueng Gasui has chosen to threaten a lawsuit in Canada relating to matters that allegedly occurred in Indonesia,&quot; Bre-X chief executive David Walsh said in a statement. &quot;However, we will sit down with them and listen to what they have to say.&quot;</p>
<p>Krueng Gasui owns an undisputed 10 percent of one section of the Busang discovery. It claims it owns up to 40 percent of the entire deposit, but Bre-X says the Indonesian company does not have the documentation to back up its claims.</p>
<p>Bre-X, which closed down C$1 at 20.90 in heavy trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange, said Friday it had received a letter from its Indonesian partner demanding a meeting before November 22 to resolve the dispute. If Bre-X refuses or does not make an attempt to settle the argument, Krueng Gasui will sue, the letter said.</p>
<p>Bre-X said it has asked its lawyers to arrange a meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion, this (threat of a lawsuit) appears to be a last minute act of desperation,&quot; said gold analyst Chad Williams of Research Capital Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;My question is, why have they waited so long? And why did they choose to do this in Canada?&quot;</p>
<p>The dispute between Bre-X and Krueng Gasui, who is backed by Australia's Golden Valley Mines NL, became public at the beginning of October.</p>
<p>The argument prompted the Indonesian government to delay issuing vital contracts of work until the two parties worked out their difficulties. Without the contracts, Bre-X cannot proceed with work on Busang and has had to stall its search for a major gold producer to operate or buy the discovery, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;The key is how the Indonesian government will react&quot; to the lawsuit, said Williams.</p>
<p>The threat of a lawsuit gives Bre-X a strong incentive to settle with Krueng Gasui and Indonesian businessman Jusuf Merukh, who controls Krueng Gasui, said gold analyst Catherine Gignac of Deacon Capital.</p>
<p>While most analysts said it was too early to tell whether the Indonesian case would stand up in Canadian court, they said the threat of a lawsuit will definitely force Bre-X to treat the claims more seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;It reinforces the uncertainty with respect to Bre-X,&quot; said gold analyst John Ing of Maison Placements. &quot;My sense is this thing is not going away. This is more of a manoeuvring than an actual threat, but it does not look like this will end any time soon.&quot;</p>
<p>Krueng Gasui said in its letter that it will also sue the other Indonesian partners of Bre-X, some Bre-X officers and Canada's Minorca Resources Inc., which has a small stake in the discovery.</p>
<p>Minorca president Roland Horst said his company has no reason to be involved.</p>
<p>Exploration at Busang has outlined 47 million ounces of gold so far, and some analysts predict there could be up to 100 million ounces.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
