<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194520" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-ATLETICO WIN, DEPORTIVO WASTE CHANCE TO GO TOP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ATLETICO WIN, DEPORTIVO WASTE CHANCE TO GO TOP.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deportivo Coruna wasted a golden opportunity to go top of the Spanish first division on Saturday in a tedious 0-0 draw at neighbours Compostela.</p>
<p>It was Deportivo's second consecutive goalless draw, and leaves John Toshack's side with 27 points from 13 games, one point behind Barcelona, who play Valladolid on Monday.</p>
<p>Deportivo missed suspended striker Mickael Madar and injured creative chief Fran Gonzalez in a Galician derby which looked more like a practice match. There were less than half a dozen shots on goal in the entire 90 minutes.</p>
<p>Champions Atletico Madrid, in sixth, closed the gap on Barcelona to seven points with a 2-1 win over Espanyol.</p>
<p>Atletico struggled to break down Espanyol in the first half, but Jose Luis Caminero capitalised on a mistake just after the break, and defender Santi Denia made it 2-0 on the hour with his first-ever goal for the club.</p>
<p>But Radomir Antic's side had to fight hard to hang on after Javi Garcia pulled one back for the visitors ten minutes from the end. Shortly afterwards Atletico were reduced to ten men when forward Kiko Narvaez picked up his second yellow card.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
