<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194519" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-DEPORTIVO SLIP UP AS PRESSURE GROWS ON VALENCIA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DEPORTIVO SLIP UP AS PRESSURE GROWS ON VALENCIA.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deportivo Coruna wasted a golden opportunity to overtake Barcelona at the top of the Spanish first division on Saturday in a tedious 0-0 draw at neighbours Compostela.</p>
<p>Champions Atletico Madrid hung on to beat Espanyol 2-1, but Tenerife and Valencia, both in European action this week, endured contrasting fortunes.</p>
<p>Tenerife beat Hercules 3-1 but Valencia could only manage a goalless draw at home to struggling Extremadura. Their unhappy fans booed beleaguered coach Luis Aragones at the end of the game and called for the return of Brazilian striker Romario, who left the club last month.</p>
<p>Deportivo's second consecutive goalless draw left John Toshack's side with 27 points from 13 games, one point behind Barcelona, who play Valladolid on Monday.</p>
<p>Deportivo missed suspended striker Mickael Madar and injured creative chief Fran Gonzalez in a Galician derby which looked like a practice match. There were less than half a dozen shots on goal in the entire game.</p>
<p>Atletico Madrid, in sixth place, closed the gap on Barcelona to seven points thanks to a strike by international playmaker Jose Luis Caminero and defender Santi Denia's first goal for the club.</p>
<p>But Radomir Antic's side had to fight hard to hang on after Javi Garcia pulled one back for the visitors 10 minutes from the end. Shortly afterwards Atletico were reduced to ten men when forward Kiko Narvaez picked up his seoncd yellow card.</p>
<p>Tenerife looked to have victory tied up thanks to a 55th minute goal by Antonio Robaina, only to see Hercules hit back with just five minutes to go. The Canary Islanders promptly struck again twice before the final whistle through Juanele Castanos and Meho Kodro.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
