<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194518" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PAPIN HITS TWO AS BORDEAUX BEAT LEADERS PSG 5-3.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PAPIN HITS TWO AS BORDEAUX BEAT LEADERS PSG 5-3.</headline>
<byline>Rex Gowar</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jean-Pierre Papin scored twice and Argentine substitute Claudio Baggio hit a crucial fourth goal as Bordeaux beat Paris St-Germain 5-3 to cut their lead at the top of the French league on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Parisians are now just three points above Monaco, who enjoyed a 1-0 win at lowly Caen thanks to a goal from teenager Thierry Henry two minutes from time.</p>
<p>Champions Auxerre dropped to fifth after a 1-0 loss at Rennes but Bordeaux's win takes them into third place, ahead of Bastia -- 2-1 winners at home to Metz -- on goal difference. Both are five points behind Monaco.</p>
<p>Papin opened the scoring in the fourth minute of an excellent match in front of 30,000 at Bordeaux before midfielder Johan Micoud put the home side two up in the 31st.</p>
<p>Patrice Loko, who now fills the striker role in the French national team that Papin once graced, struck twice late in the second half to put PSG 2-2 at the interval, only for Papin to put Bordeaux ahead again with a 52nd-minute penalty, taking his tally for the season to eight.</p>
<p>Panama's Julio Cesar Dely Valdes scored his sixth goal in five games as PSG equalised again in the 62nd minute.</p>
<p>But former San Lorenzo striker Biaggio put Bordeaux ahead again with a fine goal in the 74th minute after coming on for Papin, and laid on a fifth six minutes from time for Kaba Diawara.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a beautiful match,&quot; said PSG's Brazilian manager Rocardo.</p>
<p>&quot;We came from behind twice but tonight Bordeaux were too strong.&quot;</p>
<p>Bordeaux coach Rolland Courbis, whose side have scored nine goals in four days after a 4-3 win at Lens on Wednesday, compared the match with Bordeaux's UEFA Cup victory over AC Milan last season.</p>
<p>&quot;After we were leading 2-0, we thought we'd done the essential by getting on top of this team and their famous attacking foursome (Loko, Dely Valdes and Brazilians Leonardo and Rai),&quot; Courbis said.</p>
<p>&quot;All it took was for us to relax a little and they came back.</p>
<p>&quot;To play such a match on a night when the stadium is full is fabulous. It's a match that will remain in the memory.&quot;</p>
<p>PSG are at home next weekend against resurgent arch-rivals Marseille, who beat Lens 2-1 at home.</p>
<p>Coach Gerard Gili's preference for home grown midfielder Ludovic Asuar over Bulgaria's Yordan Lechkov was vindicated with the youngster's 18th-minute opening goal.</p>
<p>Auxerre, with two strikers on the injury list, fell victim to a third, Stephane Guivarc'h, who has been in brilliant form since the champions loaned him to Rennes for the season.</p>
<p>Guivarc'h struck his 13th goal of the championship to send Auxerre crashing to a defeat which augurs badly for Wednesday's European champions' league visit to Ajax Amsterdam.</p>
<p>Coach Guy Roux said: &quot;Last year when we had our dream team, we also got beaten by Rennes.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
