<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194977" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: Suicide, protest march and race row hit Miss World.</title>
<headline>Suicide, protest march and race row hit Miss World.</headline>
<byline>Simon Cameron-Moore</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suicide threats by traditionalist women's groups, race rows with the media and a protest march by 800 communists turned the Miss World beauty pageant into a farce on Sunday.</p>
<p>A women's activist group is threatening to upstage the crowning moment in Bangalore on November 23 by infiltrating the crowd, taking cyanide and setting their silk saris alight in front of an expected television audience of two billion.</p>
<p>The Mahila Jagran Samiti (Forum to Awaken Women) is holding its threat of suicides in abeyance while a court rules on a move to ban the show, which is being staged in India for the first time although Indian women have won the title twice.</p>
<p>A decision is expected on Monday. Previous attempts to block Miss World through the courts have failed.</p>
<p>&quot;We will decide on a course of action after the judgment,&quot; Kinay Narayan Shishikala, firebrand leader of the Mahila Jagran Samiti, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Miss Venezuela Anna Cepinska, the bookmakers' favourite to take the title, said on Sunday: &quot;I just hope everything will turn out alright. This threat of burning themselves makes me mad and sad.&quot;</p>
<p>One man died by self-immolation on Thursday in a protest against India hosting the beauty contest. The suicide sent shudders through the Miss World camp at the luxury Windsor Manor hotel in Bangalore.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the land of Gandhi, the land of peace. How can they take such an extreme step. Everybody has a right to protest but not in this form. I am very concerned,&quot; said Miss Costa Rica, Natalia Caravjal Lorenzo, an aspiring journalist.</p>
<p>While the 88 competitors were attending a function on the outskirts of Bangalore on Sunday, police stopped a march on their hotel by some 800 members of the Communist Party of India (Marxist).</p>
<p>Police have deployed around 12,000 officers for the beauty pageant and organisers hope a further 2,000 paramilitary will be cleared to join the security operation to ensure the show goes off smoothly.</p>
<p>To add to the controversy dogging this year's Miss World, the African contingent among the competitors say the media is shunning them because they are black.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't expect this kind of discrimination in India. I am really disappointed,&quot; Shose Akaro of Tanzania told Reuters at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian press has totally ignored us (black Africans) from the day we landed in your country. Just about everyone in the press is paying attention only to the whites,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Miss Zambia, law student Alice Banda who is hoping to make a career in politics after graduating, felt similarly ignored.</p>
<p>&quot;Just look at them. The press are going after the whites,&quot; she said as a battery of television crews and photographers -- both Indian and foreign -- closed in on white models.</p>
<p>Eric Morely, the man who started the competition 45 years ago in Britain said this year's event had attracted more publicity than ever before, but not the sort that anybody would want.</p>
<p>The opponents of Miss World say the beauty contest offends Indian culture and demeans women.</p>
<p>His wife Julia, who is president of the Miss World Organisation, appealed to the women's groups for talks to defuse the situation but was turned down flat.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really sad if they have to burn themselves as a mark of protest. I now learn that they only represent small groups and have just been making threats. Julia Morley has offered to discuss it with them but they have not accepted the offer,&quot; said Miss USA Kelly Webber.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
