<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195626" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY NOV 18-SUNDAY NOV 24, 1996.</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY NOV 18-SUNDAY NOV 24, 1996.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU agricultural ministers meet (Monday-Tuesday); discussions focus on the state of beef sector and support system for arable crops.</p>
<p>OSTEND, Belgium - The Belgian Presidency of the WEU holds council of ministers (Monday-Tuesday); discussions focus on the creation of the organisation of the WEU armament.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission President Santer and Commissioners van den Broek, Pinheiro and de Silguy meet World Bank Chairman James Wolfensohn (Monday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU budget ministers meet (Tuesday); discussions focus on 1997 Community budget.</p>
<p>PALESTINIAN AUTHORITY - EP President Klaus Haensch on official visit (Tuesday-Friday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (Wednesday); European Commissioner Brittan on Trans-Atlantic Business Dialogue - follow-up of Chicago meeting; relations with Cuba and Japan.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU education ministers meet (Thursday); public debate on Council conclusions on school effectiveness and meeting with central and eastern European counterparts.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU development ministers meet (Friday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU fisheries ministers meet (Friday).</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 18</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Farm Council (and Tuesday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Beef meat:</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulation on the identificaiton and registration of beef;</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulation on beef meat labelling and commodities.</p>
<p>- Support system for arable crops (durum wheat) - modifying regulation 1765/92 COM(96)361.</p>
<p>- Proposal for regulation on a common organisation of the potatoes market.</p>
<p>- European veterinary and plant-health agency.</p>
<p>- Nomination of the Community Office for Vegetable Varieties Appeal Court President, Vice-President and Deputy.</p>
<p>- State of work on BSE.</p>
<p>- Continuation of works on rural development - Cork conference.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Inter-governmental conference (IGC) representatives meet (and Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President Santer and Commissioners van den Broek, Pinheiro and de Silguy meet World Bank Chairman James Wolfensohn.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioners Marin and van den Broek meet Norwegian Foreign Minister Bjorn Tore Godal.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Energy;</p>
<p>Social Affairs;</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Foreign Affairs;</p>
<p>External Economic Relations;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Fisheries;</p>
<p>Inquiry into Fraud in Transit.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Maryland University International Policy attitudes Program Director Steven Kull holds news conference on &quot;Americans on expanding NATO: a study of U.S. public attitudes&quot; (1100/1000 GMT). Venue: NATO, Martino room.</p>
<p>OSTEND, Belgium (EXPANDED ITEM) - The Belgian Presidency of the WEU holds council of ministers (1100/1000 GMT) (first of two days). WEU defence ministers meet; discussions focus on the creation of the organisation of the WEU armament. Venue: Media Centre Ostend.</p>
<p>LONDON (NEW ITEM) - IIR Ltd holds conference on &quot;Assessing practical implications and impact of EMU on financial markets&quot; (and Tuesday). Agenda includes: current developments and key dates in the run up to the single currency; assessing the role of the European System of Central Banks; focusing on the benefits of trans-European automated real time gross settlement express transfer system; grasping the practicalities and consequences of conversion exchange rates into the Euro; the impact of the Euro on European capital markets; weighing up the consequences of EMU on exchange traded derivatives when formally converted into Euro; assessing the new post-EMU framework of the fixed income markets; assessing the impact of EU and EMU on the world's capital markets; the effects of EMU upon London as a financial centre; Ins and Outs and stability pacts; minimising the potential impact of the single currency on continuity of contracts; the Bank of England's involvement with EMU. Venue: The Marble Arch Marriott. Contact: (44) 171 9155055.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 19</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Budget Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Draft Community budget for 1997 (second reading).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Pinheiro meets Guinea-Bissau President Joao Bernardo Vieira</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Foreign Affairs;</p>
<p>External Economic Relations;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs - European Commissioner Gradin attends;</p>
<p>Social Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport - European Commissioner Bangemann attends;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Fisheries;</p>
<p>Inquiry into Fraud in Transit.</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Farm;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>Petitions;</p>
<p>PALESTINIAN AUTHORITY (NEW ITEM) - EP President Klaus Haensch on official visit (to Friday); meets Palestinian President Yasser Arafat; Legislative Council Speaker Ahmed Qurei; Health Minister Riad El Zaanuun and Bethlehem Mayor Elias Freij.</p>
<p>OSTEND, Belgium (EXPANDED ITEM) - The Belgian Presidency of the WEU holds council of ministers (0930/0730 GMT) (second of two days). Participants include European Commissioner van den Broek. WEU foreign ministers meet; discussions focus on the creation of a European Defence Identity in NATO.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Amnesty International holds news conference on human rights in Algeria (1130/1030 GMT). Venue: 4 Blvd Charlemagne. Contact: Marie Noel (322) 538 8177.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Forum Europe holds conference on &quot;Europe's competitive edge&quot; (0845/0745 GMT). Agenda includes: assessing the state of EU competitiveness; an agenda for future action. Speakers include: European Commissioner Bangemann, ERT Working Group on Competitiveness Chairman Baron Daniel Janssen; Irish Enterprise and Employment Minister Richard Bruton, Irish Congress of Trade Unions General Secretary Peter Cassells, DG V Director General Allan Larsson, DG III Director General Stefano Micossi, Amcham Chairman William Seddon-Brown, UNICE Chairman Francois Perigot, MEP Irene Slotwedel-Schefer, DG XIII Director General Robert Verrue. Venue: Concert Noble. Contact: Forum Europe: (322) 736 1430.</p>
<p>LONDON - Agra Europe holds ninth annual European and international dairy conference &quot;Dairy '96&quot; (and Wednesday). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 20</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission holds regular weekly meeting (0930/0830 GMT).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Papoutsis green paper on trade and distribution between SMEs.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Fischler communication on balancing of 1992 accounts.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Monti communication on excluded public markets such as water and energy; green paper on the follow-up to the copyright in the information society.</p>
<p>- European Commissioners Wulf-Mathies and Oreja communication on cohesion policy and culture: contribution to employment.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Pinheiro green paper on future relations with ACP countries.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Papoutsis green paper on energy for the future of renewable sources.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Gradin communication on trafficking in women.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner van den Broek action plan on Ukraine.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Cresson orientation debate towards the fifth framework programme.</p>
<p>- European Commissioners Cresson and Bangemann communication on the first action plan for innovation in Europe.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Bangemann communication on European telecoms numbering system.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Brittan on trans-Atlantic business dialogue - follow-up Chicago meeting; relations with Cuba and Japan.</p>
<p>- Second reading of 1997 budget.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - EU-Hungary joint EP committee.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - EU-Turkey joint EP committee.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Agriculture;</p>
<p>Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>Transport;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Youth;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>Petitions;</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Budget;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Civil Liberties;</p>
<p>Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Transparency Inrernational Brussels and Bank Brussels Lambert (BBL) hold joint conference on &quot;Corrupt practices and market discipline&quot; (1730/1630 GMT). Speakers include: European Commissioner Van Miert. Venue: BBL, 24 avenue Marnix. Contact: Julie Duhamel, BBL (322) 547 3759.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Centre for European Policy Studies (CEPS) holds seminar on &quot;The EU's waste policy&quot; (1315/1215 GMT). Speaker is European Commission Waste Management Head of Unit Ludwig Kraemer. Venue: CEPS. Contact: CEPS (322) 229 3911.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - The Karolinska Institute, WHO and Volvo hold joint conference on &quot;Traffic safety, communication and health&quot; (and Thursday). Sessions include: traffic safety and health; traffic safety in developing countries; traffic safety, mobility and health; transportation networks; traffic safety and environmental impact; human factors and human machine interaction in traffic safety. Contact: Volvo (46) 31 54 57 23.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 21</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - Education/Youth Council (1000/0900 GMT).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Public debate on Council conclusions on school effectiveness.</p>
<p>- Council conclusions on European year of lifelong learning.</p>
<p>- Council declaration on educatinal measures to protect children and the fight against paedophilia.</p>
<p>- Commission report on:</p>
<p>- Four conferences on &quot;Teaching and learning: towards a cognitive socirty&quot;;</p>
<p>- Green paper on trans-national mobility obstacles;</p>
<p>- Learning in the information society.</p>
<p>- Commission report on:</p>
<p>- SOCRATES (budgetary needs);</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council recommendation on grant transfers;</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council recommendation on the quality of higher education;</p>
<p>- Evaluation of the quality of elementary and secondary education.</p>
<p>- (1200/1100 GMT) Meeting with central and eastern European countries counterparts.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>- (0900/0800 GMT) Budget;</p>
<p>Environment;</p>
<p>Development;</p>
<p>Civil Liberties;</p>
<p>Institutional Affairs;</p>
<p>Social Affairs; - European Commissioner Monti attends;</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Confederation of European Paper Industries (CEPI) holds general assembly (0900/0800 GMT). Main discussion will focus on towards sustainable paper cycle. Venue: Hilton Botel. Contact: CEPI (32)627 4911.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Club de Bruxelles holds conference on the future of the West African Economic and Monetary Union (WAEMU) - The role of business and the European institutions in the context of regional integration and economic development of the countries of the WAEMU (0900/0800 GMT) (and Friday). Speakers include: European Commission President Santer (on video); Commissioners Pinheiro and de Silguy (on video); MEP Wilfried Martens; Burkina Faso President Blaise Compaore. Venue: Palais des Congres. Contact: Club de Bruxelles (322) 743 1520.</p>
<p>LEUVEN, Belgium (NEW ITEM) - European Centre for Public Affairs holds conference on &quot;Consumer protection and regulation: the role of the EU&quot; (and Friday). Venue: The Faculty Club. Contact: Amanda Breweton, European Centre for Public Affairs (44) 1865 735422.</p>
<p>THE HAGUE (NEW ITEM) - SDU holds conference on &quot;The information society and governmental information in Europe - How can EU and national government information be made accessible?&quot; (and Friday). Venue: Bilderberg Europa Hotel. Contact: SDU Communications (31) 70 3789528.</p>
<p>PARIS (NEW ITEM) - EU Economic and Social Committees hold second Euro-Mediterranean summit (and Friday). Main discussions focus on southern countries public debt; creation of a free exchange zone and migration; energy in Euro-Mediterranean zones. News conference at 1800/1700 GMT. Participants include: European Commissioner Marin. Contact: ECOSOC (322) 546 9213.</p>
<p>VIENNA (NEW ITEM) - ECOSOC holds conference on &quot;Economy and societies in an enlarged Europe&quot; (and Friday). Participants include: Austrian Economy Minister Hannes Farnleitner. Contact: ECOSOC (322) 546 9207.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 22</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Development Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- First ministerial exchange of views on ACP/EU relations post-Lome IV (Commission green paper).</p>
<p>- Further exchange of views on relief, rehabilitation and development.</p>
<p>- Resolution on the forestry sector.</p>
<p>- Adoption of a common position on the regulation on north/south cooperation in the fight against drugs.</p>
<p>- Adoption of a common position on the regulation on aid for population policies and programmes.</p>
<p>- Approval after EP second reading of the regulations on rehabilitation and construction in developing countries, refugees in Asia and Latin America, environmental measures in developing countries and HIV/AIDS related operations in developing countries.</p>
<p>- Horizon 2000 - coherence, complementarity and coordination.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Fisheries Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council regulations (EC) fixing:</p>
<p>- The guide prices for the fishery products listed in Annex I (A), (D) and (E) of Regulation (EEC) No. 3759/92 for the 1997 fishing year;</p>
<p>- The guide prices for the fishery products listed in Annex H to Regulation (EEC) No. 3759/92 for the 1997 fishing year;</p>
<p>- The Community producer price for tuna intended for the industrial manufacture of products falling within CN code 1604 for the 1997 fishing year.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation (EC) temporarily suspending totally or partially the autonomous duties of the Common Customs Tariff for certain fishery products (1997).</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council Regulation laying down (new) technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Proposal for a Council decision on MAGP IV.</p>
<p>- Commission report on third countries' activities in Community waters.</p>
<p>- Proposals for a Council regulation on the conclusion of the protocol establishing the fisheries rights and financial compensation provided in the agreement between the European Economic Community and the government of Senegal.</p>
<p>- (Possibly) Conclusion of new fisheries agreements with:</p>
<p>a) Certain countries of South America;</p>
<p>b) South Africa;</p>
<p>c) Namibia;</p>
<p>d) Mozambique.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Papoutsis meets German Economy Minister Gunther Rexrodt.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - Chancellor Helmut Kohl and various representatives from politics and the banking community attend the Frankfurt European Banking Congress 1996, opens 0630 GMT.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 23</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, NOVEMBER 24</p>
<p>No events scheduled.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
