<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201833" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovak journalists protest government ban.  [CORRECTED]</title>
<headline>Slovak journalists protest government ban.  [CORRECTED]</headline>
<dateline>BRATISLAVA 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The biggest Slovak union for journalists on Wednesday protested over the barring of four reporters from government briefings and appealed to the International Federation of Journalists for support.</p>
<p>The four were among a group of journalists who publicly denied allegations made by Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar that President Michal Kovac had told them at a news briefing in May that Meciar was suffering from a brain tumour.</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear the four were not banned merely for attending a meeting with Kovac.)</p>
<p>The Slovak government on Tuesday said it had barred the four from regular government news conferences for &quot;personal reasons&quot;.</p>
<p>The Slovak Syndicate of Journalists, in a statement on Wednesday, said: &quot;We appeal to all (Slovak) media not to bow to the pressure of the government. Freedom of information is guaranteed by the constitution and journalists are its medium.&quot;</p>
<p>Kovac and Meciar, once allies, have been locked in a bitter political battle since Kovac called on parliament to hold a vote of confidence on Meciar in 1994.</p>
<p>The government has come under scrutiny in the past two years for foot-dragging over promoting democratic reforms in Slovakia.</p>
<p>The European Union and the United States have expressed concerns over the development of democracy in Slovakia and its treatment of minorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRATISLAVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
