<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205451" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP FISHERIES COMMITTEE AGENDA - NOV 25-26.</title>
<headline>EP FISHERIES COMMITTEE AGENDA - NOV 25-26.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Fisheries [[ Monday 25 November 1996 ]] PUBLIC MEETING 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.823 ) 2. Chairman's announcements 3. Approval of minutes of meeting of: - 8/9 October 1996 (PE219.821 ) ===] In the presence of the Commission 4. Statement by the Commission on the outcome of the Fisheries Council of 22 No vember 1996 5. Objectives and procedures for restructuring the Community fishing industry ( 1 January 1997 - 31 December 2002) (T04907) CNS96142 COM(96)0237 C4-0438/96 + PECH Fond R KOFOED Niels A. (ELD) (PE219.275/REV) - Adoption of draft report 6. Fisheries agreement between the EC and Mauritania (T04905) AVC96210 COM(96)0417 C4-0599/96 + PECH Fond R GIR tO PEREIRA J. (UPE) (PE219.274 ) - Exchange of views ===] 25 November at 5.30 p.m. 7. Exchange of views with representatives of the Northern Ireland fisheries sector 8. Technical measures for the conservation of fishery resources (proposal for a Council regulation) (T04911) CNS96160 COM(96)0296 C4-0388/96 + PECH Fond R IZQUIERDO ROJO M. (PSE) - Consideration of draft report 9. Programme of work of the Committee on Fisheries for 1997 - Exchange of views 10. Community system for fisheries and aquaculture - amendment of Regulation (E EC) No 3760/92 (T04991) CNS96183 COM(96)0350 C4-0538/96 + PECH Fond - Initial exchange of views 11. Reference laboratories for the monitoring of marine biotoxins (amendment of Decision 93/383/EEC) (T04999) CNS96234 COM(96)0464 C4-0547/96 + PECH Fond - Initial exchange of views 12. EC ratification of the Agreement for implementing the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea (fish stock conservation) (T05019) CNS96238 COM(96)0472 C4-0551/96 + PECH Fond - Initial exchange of views 13. Arrangements for the management of fishing effort in the Baltic Sea (CNS96244 ) - Initial exchange of views 14. Decision on procedure 14.1 Moratorium on fisheries (B4-0708/96) 15. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure (possibly) 16. Any other business 17. Date of next meeting in Brussels (PE/XVII/OJ/96-21 ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
