<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205450" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP WOMEN'S RIGHTS COMMITTEE AGENDA - NOV 25-26.</title>
<headline>EP WOMEN'S RIGHTS COMMITTEE AGENDA - NOV 25-26.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Women's Rights [[ Monday 25 November 1996 ]] ** MINI PUBLIC HEARING ON AIDS PREVENTION IN PROSTITUTION ***************** PUBLIC MEETING *********************** 0.1 ===] Monday, 25 November 1996, 3.00 to 5.00 p.m. (5.30 p.m.) 0.3 ****** MINI HEARING ON AIDS PREVENTION IN PROSTITUTION ****** - Mrs Pia COVRE, Committee on Civil Rights for Prostitutes, Rome. - Mr Ruud MAK, EUROPAP, University Hospital Gent. - Mrs Lise THERY, Institut Pasteur, Brussels. 0.4 - o-o-o-===] 5.00 p.m. (5.30 p.m.) 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE219.538 ) 2. Chairperson's announcements 3. Reports by Committee Members on the activities of other Committees of which they are Members 4. Work Programme of the Committee on Women's Rights for 1997 - Exchange of views ===] 6.00 p.m. 4.2 Coordinators' meeting 4.3 - o-o-o-===] Tuesday, 26 November 1996 5. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure ===] In the presence of the Commission 6. The burden of proof in cases of discrimination based on sex (T04705) **I (T04705) SYN96196 COM(96)0340 C4-0539/96 + FEMM Fond - Appointment of rapporteur 7. European Union and the External Dimension of Human Rights Policy: from Rome to Maastricht and beyond (T04255) (T04255) COS0339 COM(95)0567 C4-0568/95 + FEMM Avis A JOUPPILA Riitta. (PPE) (PE217.389/REV) F POLI Fond R ROUBATIS Ioannis. (PSE) - Adoption of draft opinion 8. Situation of the wives of self-employed workers (T03547) (T03547) INI0300 INI0300 + FEMM Fond R LULLING Astrid. (PPE) (PE219.531/REV) - Consideration of revised draft report 9. Equal treatment for men and women for access to employment and vocational tr aining (amendment of Directive 76/207) (T04841) (T04841) CNS96095 COM(96)0093 C4-0317/96 + FEMM Fond LULLING Astrid. (PPE) - Exchange of views on Legal Affairs Committee's opinion on the legal basis 10. The need to establish a European-Union-wide campaign for zero tolerance of violence against women (T03638) (T03638) INI0519 INI0519 + FEMM Fond R ERIKSSON Marianne. (GUE) (PE219.539 ) - Consideration of working document 11. The burden of proof in cases of discrimination based on sex (T04705) **I (T04705) SYN96196 COM(96)0340 C4-0539/96 + FEMM Fond - Presentation by the Commission - Initial exchange of views 12. Petition No 176/95 by Mrs Erika STOSH on back-dated pensions claims for par t-time employees - Consideration of draft opinion in the form of a letter for the Committee on Pe titions 13. Reports on Conferences: - by Mrs TORRES MARQUES to Cork &quot;Rural Development&quot; - by Mrs GRONER to Vienna &quot;Women and Information Policies&quot; - by Mrs van DIJK to Brighton &quot;Violence against Women&quot; - by Mrs AHLQVIST to Warsaw &quot;Equal Treatment of women and men in Central and Eas tern Europe&quot; 14. Any other business 15. Date of next meeting in Brussels (PE/XIX/OJ/96-16 ) END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
