<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20767" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MORNING SPORT - GOLFER WOODS TURNS PRO - AUG 29.</title>
<headline>MORNING SPORT - GOLFER WOODS TURNS PRO - AUG 29.</headline>
<dateline>MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saying there were no more challenges left as an amateur, three-time U.S. Amateur Golf champion Tiger Woods turned professional on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Woods, 20, who won his record third consecutive amateur title on Sunday, will begin his professional career on Thursday at the PGA Greater Milwaukee Open tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew that after I won there was not much to achieve in amateur golf,&quot; Woods said at a news conference.</p>
<p>Never in the history of the game has a young golfer been saddled with such huge expectations as Woods.</p>
<p>Not only is he expected to win tournaments and sign up for lucrative endorsement contracts, he is touted as a huge draw for minorities to golf, which has had few prominent black golfers.</p>
<p>But, showing some of the poise that he exhibits on the golf course, Woods said of all the pressure: &quot;I'm going to play one shot at a time and have one hell of a good time.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods, from Cypress, California, is not a stranger to professional golf. The amateur sensation has teed it up 17 times with professionals-- 13 of them when he was still a teenager-- and six times in major championships.</p>
<p>&quot;Tiger is ready for this,&quot; said his father, Earl. &quot;I saw talent in him when he was three days old. I've been preparing him for this for 20 years. I've been preparing him to be his own boss.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods' best finish in a professional event was a tie for 22nd at the British Open in July.</p>
<p>&quot;In my life, I've never gone to a tournament thinking I couldn't win,&quot; Woods said. &quot;That's just my mindset. It's something I've always believed in. It's something I always will.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods has participated in 17 professional events since 1992, making seven cuts. His best finish was a tie for 22nd at the British Open in July.</p>
<p>&quot;I do have goals. Obviously one is to try to make the Tour,&quot; Woods said. &quot;Anything more specific I can't share with you because they're personal.&quot;</p>
<p>In turning pro, Woods turns his back on a collegiate career and the opportunity for a degree at Stanford, where he won the NCAA title last year. He said leaving school was his only regret.</p>
<p>&quot;(I'm) leaving some of my best friends,&quot; he said.  &quot;I can't hop over to their place at 11 at night and hang out with them. That I will miss.&quot;</p>
<p>Woods, who said he will play in five more PGA tournaments this year with sponsor exemptions, also said he still has not signed any endorsement contracts, although reports have indicated he will receive $40 million from Nike over five years and another $3-$5 million from Titleist.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't signed for a penny yet,&quot; he said. &quot;What's been printed is nice. I hope I get that. But I haven't seen any check in the mail yet, so I'm still broke.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he had to pay for dinner Tuesday night with a gift certificate he had received.</p>
<p>Butch Harmon, Woods' Houston-based swing instructor, said he had to loan his pupil $100 so he could pay the entry fee for the Milwaukee tournament.</p>
<p>Turning professional &quot;wasn't about money,&quot; Woods said. &quot;It was about happiness. The time was right. I knew my golf game was good enough. It boiled down to, how happy am I? And I'm happy.&quot;</p>
<p>Wednesday seemed to begin with some of the ingredients for happiness, or at least a stark contrast to his penny-pinching days as an amateur.</p>
<p>When he opened his locker Wednesday morning, he found it stocked with three boxes of new golf balls and four golf gloves. He had arrived at the course in his own courtesy car.</p>
<p>&quot;He was like a 10-year-old dropped into the middle of (a toy store),&quot; Harmon said.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as pure, raw athletic ability, he's got more of that than any golfer who has ever been great,&quot; Harmon said.</p>
<p>PGA Tour veteran Duffy Waldorf was paired with Woods in a pro-am tournament on Wednesday and quickly concluded that Woods has &quot;it&quot; -- that undefinable aura that surrounds superstars.</p>
<p>&quot;I got to see the future of golf, I think,&quot; Waldorf said of Woods. &quot;He's got all the potential to be the best, no doubt about it. He's young, he's smart and he's got all the shots.&quot; 290131 GMT aug 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
