<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20771" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: EAST EUROPE'S NEWS AGENCIES DEBATE FUTURE ROLE.</title>
<headline>EAST EUROPE'S NEWS AGENCIES DEBATE FUTURE ROLE.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The news agencies in Europe's formerly communist-ruled countries must quickly establish their independence or lose credibility, International Press Institute (IPI) Director Johann Fritz told a conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>Opening an IPI conference in Warsaw on News Agencies in Transition, Fritz said the discussion was needed now as parliaments in several Central and Eastern European states were about to decide on the future of such organisations.</p>
<p>&quot;News agencies in Eastern Europe must become more independent,&quot; Fritz said.</p>
<p>This could best be guaranteed by privatisation, but whether agencies were private, had mixed ownership or had special status as public companies, &quot;it is crucial that the impact of political influence is drastically diminished.&quot;</p>
<p>Otherwise their credibility would fall, they would lose clients and new competitors would take advantage of free-market conditions to take their place, Fritz said.</p>
<p>&quot;Changes must come fast. Time is running out,&quot; he told the meeting of several dozen delegates from news organisations in about 30 countries, including some where agencies have been emerging from under state control and striving to modernise.</p>
<p>The conference, also hosted by Poland's PAP agency, is due to end on Saturday by adopting a Warsaw Declaration on principles of agencies' relations with governments, political parties, society and the other media they supply with news.</p>
<p>The Vienna-based IPI groups journalists and media executives in 85 countries and seeks to defend press freedom. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
