<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20773" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: DROSED SETS MINIMUM ISSUE PRICE AT PLN 40.</title>
<headline>DROSED SETS MINIMUM ISSUE PRICE AT PLN 40.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish poultry firm Siedleckie Zaklady Drobiarskie SA (Drosed) set the issue price of its 160,000 to 300,000 new shares at at least 40 zlotys per share, an official from the BIG brokerage, offering the shares, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue price will be not lower than 40 zlotys and we have decided not to set any upper limits,&quot; Piotr Kowalczewski told a news conference, adding that the final issue price would be set three days before the opening of the subscription.</p>
<p>He said that the shares, which were cleared for public trading on Thursday, will be offered in two tranches - 110,000 to 250,000 for large investors and up to 50,000 for smaller investors, in a public offering from October 21 to 25.</p>
<p>The president of the company Ryszard Pietkiewicz, also present, said the funds from the issue would be used to purchase new machinery and equipment.</p>
<p>He also said that after the issue the company might apply for a transfer from the parallel to the main market of the Warsaw Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Drosed currently has 1.54 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
