<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20777" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: M&amp;R sees real growth in earnings by 2000.</title>
<headline>M&amp;R sees real growth in earnings by 2000.</headline>
<byline>Charles Phahlane</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Murray and Roberts Holdings Ltd said on Thursday it was confident it would grow earnings and double 1993's 5.7 billion rand turnover by the end of the century, despite its poor 1995/6 financial year results.</p>
<p>Chief executive Graham Hardy said that to achieve what he called their &quot;strategic intent&quot; would require earnings growth of 20 percent per annum until the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Our ability to reach our strategic intent is very good,&quot; Hardy said.</p>
<p>He said M&amp;R had been restructured to focus on four core groups - contractors, materials, transport and engineering.</p>
<p>The materials division was awaiting the competition board's ruling on the proposed merger between their unit Blue Circle Cement and Alpha Cement, he said.</p>
<p>The engineering division had been converted to an automative business to compete worldwide and the contractors division was looking at developing its worldwide capability, Hardy said.</p>
<p>The focused strategy in each operating group, continued realignment and disposal of non-core business, appropriate acquisitions and increasing internationalisation would help them achieve the strategic intent, Hardy said.</p>
<p>He said the slowdown in the building and construction sector and the provision for the dispute between its Union Carriage &amp; Wagon unit and Siemens had hit earnings.</p>
<p>He was confident that the dispute would be settled favourably as, he believed, they had a good case.</p>
<p>Earnings per share for the year ended June 30 fell to 109 cents from 126 cents a year ago and attributable income slipped to 375 million rand from 408 million rand the previous year.</p>
<p>Hardy said 58 percent of earnings were aligned to the building and construction components of the Gross Domestic Fixed Expenditure (GDFI) index and the 160 million provision made for the UCW and Siemens dispute had slashed earnings.</p>
<p>A study by the Union Bank of Switzerland forecast eight percent growth in the building and construction component of GDFI in 1996 to 13 percent growth in 1998.</p>
<p>The GDFI as a percentage of Gross Domestic product was also seen growing from 1997 to 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The environment has not been terribly friendly to us... We think (our goals) are within reach. We need luck and the experts are predicting that we will get there,&quot; Hardy said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
