<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20782" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks finish lower, hit by U.S. nosedive.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks finish lower, hit by U.S. nosedive.</headline>
<byline>Sarah Edmonds</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks lost more ground in afternoon dealings on Thursday, but emerged from a rough session less wounded than their U.S. counterparts which were badly beaten by strong U.S. economic data.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we held in exceptionally well in terms of the bond market. (Equities) were not that bad either,&quot; said independent strategist Bill Ram.</p>
<p>&quot;We held in well considering the long weekend is coming up, considering the stronger-than-expected (U.S.) figures and considering that some economists are saying that there is an increased possibility that the Fed will raise interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The TSE 300 Composite Index dropped 21.26 points to 5162.83 in turnover of 85.9 million shares worth C$970.96 million. Declining shares outweighed advances 461 to 419, with 286 issues holding their ground.</p>
<p>U.S. bonds suffered when the second quarter gross domestic product increase was revised up to 4.8 percent from 4.2 percent. This exceeded expectations and marked the largest rise since a 4.9 percent climb in the second quarter of 1994.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Index finished 64.73 points lower at 5647.65.</p>
<p>Sources within Richardson Greenshields of Canada Ltd. said that it will be bought by Royal Bank of Canada brokerage arm RBC Dominion Securities for roughly C$480 million ($351 million).</p>
<p>Rumors of a deal prompted activity in the shares of the large independent brokerages, First Marathon and Midland Walwyn Inc.</p>
<p>Circuit board manufacturer Circo Craft Co. received an C$11 ($8.05) per share offer from a U.S. investment firm.</p>
<p>The company is the subject of a hostile C$9.50 ($6.95) a share bid from C-MAC Industries. Circo Craft rose 0.65 to 10.90 in relatively active trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
