<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20789" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks end sharply lower on Dow, rebels.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks end sharply lower on Dow, rebels.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's stock market closed sharply down on Thursday, buffeted by rebel attacks in two southern Mexican states and a weakening Dow Jones average.</p>
<p>The market's main index fell 2.226 percent, or 75.94 points, to 3,334.90 points.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a combination of factors, and even without the guerrillas there were external factors that would have affected the stock market, as much in Mexico as in the United States,&quot; said Claudio Brocado, director of analysis with Valores Finamex in New York.</p>
<p>At least 13 people were killed overnight when scores of masked rebels struck at police and military posts in Oaxaca and Guerrero states in the biggest assaults in more than two years. The attacks, which appeared to be closely coordinated, were in six towns in Guerrero and Oaxaca states.</p>
<p>The Mexican market was also hit by economic factors.</p>
<p>The rise in the yield on the 30-year U.S. Treasury bond, which increased through 7.0 percent after a hefty upward revision in U.S. second-quarter gross domestic product, hit at the Mexican market.</p>
<p>&quot;Local investors were the most nervous due to the political signifigance. People started to say the (rebel) attack was tied to the upcoming state of the union address more than to social concerns,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Zedillo will give his annual state of the union address Sunday.</p>
<p>Among the biggest losers in Mexico was Tribasa *, down 1.50 pesos (20 cents) to 18.30 pesos ($2.44).</p>
<p>One of the few gainers was Grupo Financiero Banorte A, up 20 centavos (three cents) to 7.20 pesos (96 cents).</p>
<p>Volume was 110,214,185. There were 76 stocks that lost ground, nine that gained and 15 unchanged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
