<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20793" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CNBC finds no sign of improper conduct by Dorfman.</title>
<headline>CNBC finds no sign of improper conduct by Dorfman.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>CNBC said Thursday that Dan Dorfman, the influential commentator whose journalistic practices came under fire, did not violate any laws or internal policy of the financial news cable channel.</p>
<p>CNBC, owned by General Electric Co., had retained the law firm of Shearman and Sterling to review allegations that Dorfman had benefited from stock tips and received favours from companies for mentioning stocks in his broadcasts.</p>
<p>Dorfman, who suffered a mild stroke May 7, is expected to return to the network after he completes therapy,  CNBC said.</p>
<p>CNBC said in January, after Money magazine fired Dorfman as a columnist for the magazine, that it had no reason to believe he broke any law.</p>
<p>Money, published by Time Warner Inc., fired Dorfman after its managing editor said he needed to know the journalist's sources, which Dorfman had refused to reveal.</p>
<p>The law firm found no patterns of suspicious trading prior to any of Dorfman's reports, CNBC said. Dorfman supplied copies of records for securities accounts, bank accounts and tax returns, CNBC said.</p>
<p>CNBC said the law firm does not have investigative powers of the federal government, such as subpoenas and the ability to identify who conducted stock trades, and that the company would take any other information into consideration.</p>
<p>Dorfman continued working for CNBC until his stroke.</p>
<p>Business Week magazine reported last October that the U.S. attorney's office was investigating Dorfman and his relationship with Donald Kessler, a stock promoter and a regularly quoted source in Dorfman's reports. The report also said the officials were investigating insider trading charges.</p>
<p>Dorfman denied any wrongdoing when the report was issued, but Money magazine gave him a leave of absence in October, before his dismissal, to address the allegations in the Business Week article.</p>
<p>After Money fired Dorfman, he called the magazine's demands unacceptable.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
