<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20799" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. ag exports seen down $2 billion in 1997.</title>
<headline>U.S. ag exports seen down $2 billion in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department Thursday forecast that U.S. farm exports, hobbled by tight supplies and stiff competition, would fall by $2 billion in fiscal 1997 from this year's record $60 billion.</p>
<p>The department predicted that despite strong prices, wheat, feedgrain and cotton export volume would drop and shave sales of those commodities by $4 billion.</p>
<p>But it estimated oilseed exports would increase by $800 million in 1997 and that shipments abroad of livestock, poultry and fruits and vegetables would gain more than $1 billion.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected 1997 agricultural exports to remain strong and had cautioned that this year's booming total would be hard to match.</p>
<p>U.S. wheat exports were pegged at 25.0 million metric tons in 1997, down from 32.0 million tons in the prior year.</p>
<p>U.S. wheat faces tough competition from producers like Argentina, Australia and Canada, which are expected to enter the market with increased supplies this year at lower prices than U.S. grain.</p>
<p>The Agriculture Department forecast corn exports at 51.5 million tons, versus 55.0 million tons seen for this year.</p>
<p>It estimated fiscal 1997 U.S. soybean exports at 22.3 million tons, down slightly from 22.4 million tons for 1996 and pegged cotton exports at 1.5 million tons versus 1.7 million tons forecast for fiscal 1996.</p>
<p>The fiscal year runs from Oct. 1 through Sept 30.</p>
<p>Overall, USDA estimated U.S. exports of bulk commodities would total 109.1 million tons in fiscal 1997, down sharply from this year's forecast 120.2 million tons because of tight U.S. supplies and abundant crops worldwide.</p>
<p>Foul weather sapped U.S. wheat production this year and the small crop resulted in higher prices and constrained exports. This year's corn crop, while forecast as the fourth-largest on record, would barely be large enough to meet demand and do little to rebuild stocks.</p>
<p>U.S. agricultural imports were forecast at a record $32 billion in fiscal 1997, up $500 million from this year. USDA also raised its fiscal 1996 import estimate by $1 billion to $31.5 billion.</p>
<p>Agricultural trade is a consistent bright spot in the U.S. balance of trade picture. USDA projected a trade surplus of $28.5 billion for this year and $26 billion in fiscal 1997.</p>
<p>Exports account for about 25 cents of each dollar in cash receipts by U.S. farmers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
