<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20795" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco executive ordered extradited to Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Tobacco executive ordered extradited to Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former tobacco company executive accused of accepting $4.5 million in bribes was ordered extradited Thursday to Hong Kong to face charges there.</p>
<p>A U.S. magistrate ordered Lui Kin-Hong, former director of exports at the Hong Kong subsidiary of B.A.T Industries Plc, to return to Hong Kong to face nine charges he took payments from a cigarette distributor, the U.S. attorney's office in Boston said.</p>
<p>Judge Zachary Karol said in a 57-page opinion that he found sufficient evidence to support Hong Kong charges that Lui accepted about $3 million in outright payments and an additional $1.5 million in unsecured loans from the principals of Giant Island Ltd.</p>
<p>Lui allegedly took the payments from the distributor of British-American Tobacco Co. (HK) Ltd. cigarettes to ensure that Giant Island was supplied with the most popular brands.</p>
<p>Lui, who became a Canadian citizen in 1994, was arrested while on personal business in Boston last December and has been held in custody here since.</p>
<p>Lui argued that the extradition treaty between the United States and Britain would no longer include Hong Kong since the British protectorate will revert to China next year.</p>
<p>Judge Karol concluded that the U.S. secretary of state and not the judiciary should determine whether Hong Kong's status would affect Liu's case, according to the U.S. attorney's office in Boston.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
