<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20802" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends mixed, hit by stocks and bonds.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends mixed, hit by stocks and bonds.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed mixed Thursday after an early rally against the German mark faltered amid steep losses in the stock and bond markets.</p>
<p>The currency rebounded from overnight selling against the Japanese yen to end the session with a modest loss against the Japanese currency and a slight gain against the mark.</p>
<p>Fresh signs of U.S. economic strength helped lift the dollar early by raising expectations of higher domestic interest rates in coming months, dealers said.</p>
<p>Higher rates would strengthen the dollar by enhancing the relative value of assets denominated in U.S. currency.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department revised its estimate of second-quarter real gross domestic product growth to 4.8 percent from an initial reading of 4.2 percent.</p>
<p>Later, Commerce reported single-family home sales rose 7.9 percent in July, beating analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>But after modest initial gains on the data, the dollar succumbed to weakness in the stock and bond markets, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market took it right on the chin and bonds were down sharply. On the back of that, we saw a little see-sawing by the dollar,&quot; said Diego Giurleo, vice president at Royal Bank of Canada in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar edged lower late in the trading session as the benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bond fell 23/32 and the Dow Jones industrial average slid over 70 points.</p>
<p>The dollar closed at 1.4772 marks, up from 1.4767 late Wednesday. It slipped to 108.40 yen from 108.45.</p>
<p>The Bank of France was reported to have bought French francs against the mark, successfully halting the franc's recent slide. The dollar rose against the mark in sympathy, dealers said.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac also boosted the franc and the dollar with a statement to French ambassadors asserting that France would meet the January 1999 deadline for complying with the terms to enter the proposed European monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, the French actions probably set the tone. It was an action to limit the mark's gains,&quot; said Mike Malpede, senior foreign exchange analyst at Refco Group Ltd.</p>
<p>The dollar endured modest selling in Tokyo after a Japanese official played down Wednesday's tankan business confidence survey, which suggested Japan's economy had not yet emerged from recession.</p>
<p>Shinpei Nukaya, Vice Minister of Japan's Economic Planning Agency, called the drop in the tankan index a &quot;blip,&quot; insisting the economy was not in danger of stalling.</p>
<p>&quot;We had seen a pretty good selloff of the yen against the dollar the night before and this was a bit of a correction. The dollar is not quite sure what it wants to do,&quot; Giurleo said.</p>
<p>Given the strong U.S. data, an aggressive interest rate cut in Germany a week ago and a stumbling Japanese economy, dealers called the dollar's failure to sustain recent rallies a disappointment.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very hard to find an article that doesn't say the dollar is fundamentally strong, but the dollar hasn't been showing us any good signs,&quot; said Mark Gargano, managing director of foreign exchange at First Union National Bank.</p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar rose to 1.1948 Swiss francs from 1.1926. The British pound fell to $1.5577 from $1.5594.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to Canadian $1.3667 from C$1.3662.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
