<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20813" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP SUBCOMMITTEE ON MONETARY AFFAIRS AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</title>
<headline>EP SUBCOMMITTEE ON MONETARY AFFAIRS AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Economic and Monetary Affairs and Industrial Policy [[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]] SUBCOMMITTEE ON MONETARY AFFAIRS 0.1 ===] Monday 2 September 1996, pm 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.617 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 24-25 June 1996 (PE218.615 ) - 1 July 1996 (PE218.616 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Current monetary situation: Bullletin 22, September 96 5. Effects of the EMU on certain fiscal aspects (T03944) INI0348 INI0348 + ECON Fond R CHRISTODOULOU Efthym (PPE) (PE217.518/DT ) - First consideration of draft report 6. Monetary policies and their effects on the real economy in the context of pr eparation for the third stage of EMU (T03572) INI0316 + ECON Fond R HARRISON Lyndon. (PSE) (PE217.495/AM ) - Further consideration of draft report 7. Convergence criteria, the third stage of EMU and the various social security systems (T04222) INI0514 INI0514 B4-0589/95 B4-0589/95 + ECON Fond R WILLOCKX Frederik A. (PE217.722/AM ) (PSE) - Further consideration of draft report 8. Hearing of experts on new technologies and money - Hearing of experts - Rapporteur: John STEVENS - (Monday 2 September from 4.30 pm) ===] Tuesday 3 September 1996, am 9. Hearing of experts from the European chemical and pharmaceutical industry (f rom 9 am) - Hearing of experts - (Tuesday 3 September from 9 am) 10. Report on convergence (T04762) ATT1183 + ECON Fond R METTEN Alman. (PSE) (PE217.509/DT ) - Further consideration of working document 11. The changeover to the single currency (report by the European Monetary Inst itute) (T04566) COS0336 C4-596/95 C4-0559/95 + ECON Fond R HOPPENSTEDT Karsten (PPE) - First consideration of draft report 12. Consideration of written questions for Mr DUISENBERG, successor to Mr Lamfa lussy, President of the EMI 13. Any other business 14. Date of next meeting (PE/IV/OJ/96-10/S-C ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
