<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20812" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP ENERGY COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</title>
<headline>EP ENERGY COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Research, Technological Development and Energy</p>
<p>[[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]]</p>
<p>===] Monday, 2 September 1996 at 3 pm.</p>
<p>1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.596 )</p>
<p>===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 2/3/4 June 1996 - Delegation Sicily (PE218.172 ) - 10/11 June 1996 in Brussels (PE218.165 ) - 18 June 1996 in Strasbourg (to be controled) (PE218.173 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Any other business 5. Improving energy efficiency: continuation of the SAVE programme after 1995 ( CO2 strategy) (T03884) **II (T03884) SYN95131 COM(96)0195 C4-0375/96 + ENER Fond R BLOCH von B. (V ) - Consideration of Common Position of Council 6. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (T04556) BUD0074 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + ENER Avis A McNALLY Eryl M. (PSE) (PE218.171/DEF) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE218.307 ) - First consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 7. Rational planning techniques in the electricity and gas distribution sectors (T03727) **I (T03727) SYN95208 COM(95)0369 C4-0030/96 + ENER Fond R McNALLY Eryl M. (PSE) (PE216.801/REV) - Further consideration of draft report - Consideration of amendments 8. Towards sustainability: Community programme of policy and action in relation to the environment (T03713) (T03713) COD96027 COM(95)0647 C4-0147/96 + ENER Avis A AHERN Nuala. (V )</p>
<p>(PE217.782 ) F ENVI Fond R DYBKJ R Lone. (ELD) (PE217.883 ) - Further consideration of draft opinion - Consideration of amendments 9. Community policy in the field of telecommunications and postal services (T04 820) (T04820) CNS96042 COM(96)0045 C4-0284/96 + ENER Avis A McNALLY Eryl M. (PSE) (PE218.586 ) F ECON Fond R van VELZEN W. (PPE) - First consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 10. White Paper on an energy policy for the European Union (T03923) (T03923) COS0361 SEC(95)2283 C4-0018/96 + ENER Fond R van VELZEN W. (PPE) (PE217.771 ) - First consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments ===] Possibly, followed by coordinators' meeting ===] Tuesday, 3 September 1996 at 9 am. 11. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 12. Rational planning techniques in the electricity and gas distribution sector s (T03727) **I (T03727) SYN95208 COM(95)0369 C4-0030/96 + ENER Fond R McNALLY Eryl M. (PSE) (PE216.801/REV) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 13. Towards a European Union strategy for relations with the Transcaucasian Rep ublics (T04279) (T04279) COS0410 COM(95)0205 C4-0242/96 + ENER Avis L (PE218.591 ) F POLI Fond R CARRERE D'ENCAUSSE H (UPE) (PE217.251/REV) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 14. Towards sustainability: Community programme of policy and action in relatio n to the environment (T03713) (T03713) COD96027 COM(95)0647 C4-0147/96 + ENER Avis A AHERN Nuala. (V )</p>
<p>(PE217.782 ) F ENVI Fond R DYBKJ R Lone. (ELD) (PE217.883 ) - Vote on and adoption of draft opinion 15. Petition no 751/94 and 1030/94 - construction of an electricity interconnec tor between Scotland and N-Ireland (PET0045 ) - Further consideration of draft opinion - Vote on and adoption of draft opinion 16. Euro-Mediterranean partnership in the energy sector (T04819) (T04819) COS0406 COM(96)0149 C4-0238/96 + ENER Fond R SCAPAGNINI Umberto. (UPE) (PE218.594 ) - First consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments ===] From 11 am - 12.30 pm: Colloque 17. Community policy on research and sustainable development (T04003) (T04003) INI0404 INI0404 + ENER Fond R MARSET CAMPOS P. (GUE) - Exchange of views with experts 18. Date of next meeting (PE/V/OJ/96-18 ) - FIN - 6 END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
