<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20815" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</title>
<headline>EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Agriculture and Rural Development</p>
<p>[[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]]</p>
<p>PUBLIC MEETING</p>
<p>1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.438 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 10/11 June 1996 (PE217.844 ) - 17 June 1996 (PE218.430 ) - 25/26 June 1996 (PE218.432 ) - 8/9 July 1996 (PE218.434 ) - 15 July 1996 (PE218.437 ) ===] In the presence of the Commission 3. General Community strategy for the forestry sector (T03499) INI0287 INI0287 B4-0186/94 B4-0186/94 B4-0462/94 B4-0462/94 B4-0051/94 B4-0051/94 + AGRI Fond R THOMAS David E. (PSE) (PE213.578/A ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 4. Minimum standards for the protection of calves (amendment of Directive 91/62 9/EEC) (T04750) CNS96029 COM(96)0021 C4-0133/96 + AGRI Fond R ROSADO FERNANDES R. (UPE) (PE217.832 ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 5. Trade arrangements for goods derived from the processing of agricultural pro ducts (amendment of Regulation 3448/93) (T04755) CNS96039 COM(96)0049 C4-0156/96 + AGRI Fond R GILLIS Alan L. (PPE) (PE217.834 ) - Consideration and adoption of a draft report 6. Community water policy (T04766) COS0387 COM(96)0059 C4-0144/96 + AGRI Avis A des PLACES E. (EDN) (PE214.530 ) F ENVI Fond R FLORENZ Karl-Heinz. (PPE) (PE218.545 ) - Consideration of draft opinion ===] Tuesday, 3 September at 9 a.m. 7. Exchange of views with Mr Ivan YATES, Ireland's Minister for Agriculture, Fo od and Forestry, President-in-Office of the Council, on current problems 8. Creation of a European Rural Charter (T03605) INI0418 INI0418 B4-0019/94 B4-0019/94 B4-0055/95 B4-0055/95 + AGRI Fond C HYLAND Liam. (UPE) (PE216.622 ) + AGRI Fond R HYLAND Liam. (UPE) (PE216.622 ) - Vote on and adoption of draft report 9. White Paper on an energy policy for the European Union (T03923) COS0361 SEC(95)2283 C4-0018/96 + AGRI Avis A SCHIERHUBER Agnes. (PPE) (PE218.439 ) F ENER Fond R van VELZEN W. (PPE) (PE217.771 ) - Consideration of draft opinion 10. Integrated administrative and control system for certain Community aid sche mes (amendment of Regulation 3508/92) (T04839) CNS96122 COM(96)0174 C4-0313/96 + AGRI Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.440 ) F CONT Fond R GARRIGA POLLEDO S. (PPE) (PE218.055 ) - Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter 11. Sugar, honey, fruit juice, milk and jams for human consumption - proposal f or a Council directive (T04896) + T04893 and T04894 CNS96113 COM(95)0722 C4-0402/96 CNS96114 COM(95)0722 C4-0403/96 CNS96115 COM(95)0722 C4-0404/96 CNS96116 COM(95)0722 C4-0405/96 CNS96118 COM(95)0722 C4-0406/96 + AGRI Avis A HAPPART Jose H. (PSE) + AGRI Avis HAPPART Jose H. (PSE) F ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) F ENVI Fond LANNOYE Paul. (V ) - Exchange of views 12. Application of the procedure without report (Rule 143(1) of the Rules of Pr ocedure) 12.1 Marketing of lemon products. Derogation from Reg.(EC) 1035/77 for 96/97 an d amendment of Reg. 1543/95 (T04895) CNS96144 COM(96)0240 C4-0392/96 CNS96145 COM(96)0240 C4-0393/96 + AGRI Fond 13. Decision on procedure (Rules 52, 99, 59 or 143) (possibly) 14. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure (possibly) 15. Any other business 16. Date of next meeting in BRUSSELS (PE/II/OJ/96-19 ) 16.1 16.2 N.B. The coordinators will meet during this meeting. A D D E N D U M 0.1 0.2 ===] Insert two new items after Item 5 0.4 5.1 Beef, arable crops and agricultural structures: amendment of Rgulations (EEC) 805/68, 1765/92 and 2328/91 (T04950) CNS96211 COM(96)0422 C4-0447/96 CNS96213 COM(96)0422 C4-0449/96 CNS96212 COM(96)0422 C4-0448/96 + AGRI Fond - The Council has asked for the urgent procedure (Rule 97) for the part-session of 4-5 September - Decision on procedure 5.2 1997 budget - Section III - Draftsman: Anthony Joseph WILSON - Deadline for tabling amendments Deadline for tabling amendments to the draft Council budget - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
