<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20811" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP EXTERNAL ECONOMIC RELATIONS COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</title>
<headline>EP EXTERNAL ECONOMIC RELATIONS COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on External Economic Relations</p>
<p>[[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]]</p>
<p>P U B L I C M E E T I N G</p>
<p>===] Monday 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.809 ) 2. Chairman's announcements ===] In the presence of the Council and Commission 3.1 Information from the Commission on work in progress 3.2 Helms-Burton Act - Decision on procedure 4. Agreements between the EC and Israel on procurement by government and telcommunications operators (T04821) CNS96104 COM(96)0148 C4-0323/96 + RELA Fond R DE CLERCQ W. (ELD) (PE218.552 ) - Consideration of draft report 5. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (T04556) BUD0074 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + RELA Avis A MONIZ Fernando. (PSE) (PE218.566 ) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE218.328 ) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 6. White Paper on an air traffic management (Freeing Europe's airspace) (T03915) (T03915) COS0394 COM(96)0057 C4-0191/96 + RELA Avis A BERES Pervenche. (PSE) (PE217.851 ) F TRAN Fond R CORNELISSEN Petrus A (PPE) (PE218.713 ) - Consideration of draft opinion 7. Trans-European cooperation scheme for higher education (TEMPUS II) (1 July 1994 - 30 June 2000) (T04858) (T04858) CNS96133 COM(96)0198 C4-0361/96 + RELA Avis A PORTO Manuel. (ELD) (PE217.870 ) F JEUN Fond R EVANS Robert J. (PSE) - Consideration of draft opinion - Deadline for tabling amendments 8. The changeover to the single currency (report by the European Monetary Institute) (T04566) COS0336 C4-596/95 C4-0559/95 + RELA Avis A DE CLERCQ W. (ELD) F ECON Fond R HOPPENSTEDT Karsten (PPE) - Exchange of views 9. Delegation visit to Oporto from 30 September to 2 October 1996 - Presentation of the draft programme by Mr MONIZ ===] Coordinators' meeting at 6.15 p.m. 9.2 - oOo-===] Tuesday 10. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure (see addendum) 11. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 8-9 July 1996 (PE218.559 ) 12. Slovenia: negotiation of a Europe association agreement - economic/trade aspects (T04059) INI0417 INI0417 + RELA Fond R POSSELT Bernd. (PPE) (PE218.553/A ) - Adoption of draft report 13. Aid to shipbuilding - proposal for a Council regulation (T04859) CNS96165 COM(96)0309 C4-0387/96 + RELA Avis A SAINJON (ELD) (PE218.625 ) - Consideration and adoption of draft opinion 14. Application of the PHARE and TACIS programmes - Preparation for a joint meeting (30 October 1996, 3 - 5.30 p.m.) with the committees and delegations concerned 15.1 World Trade Organization (T03463) (T03463) INI0268 INI0268 + RELA Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE218.565/A ) + RELA Fond S KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE218.565/A ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 15.2 Strengthening international cooperation and rules (T04150) COS0290 COM(95)0359 C4-0352/95 + RELA Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE217.869/A ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 15.3 Trade and environment - Commission communication (T04781) (T04781) COS0391 COM(96)0054 C4-0158/96 + RELA Fond R KREISSL-DORFLER Wolf (V ) (PE218.562 ) - Consideration of draft report - Deadline for tabling amendments 16. Any other business 17. Date of next meeting (in Strasbourg): (PE/VI/OJ/96-19 ) A D D E N D U M ===] Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure ===] - Opinion ===] CONSULTATIONS 1. Algeria: Euro-Mediterranean association agreement (T04799) ATT1198 + RELA Avis F POLI Fond - Appointment of draftsman 2. Implementation of the action plan annexed to the Barcelona Declaration (T04510) COS0436 7987/96 C4-0414/96 + RELA Avis F POLI Fond SAKELLARIOU Jannis. (PSE) (PE218.799/B ) - Appointment of draftsman 3. Amendment of Regulation 40/94 on the Community trade mark (Protocol on the International Registration of Trade Marks) (T03826) CNS96198 COM(96)0372 + RELA Avis F JURI Fond - Appointment of draftsman 4. EC accession to the Madrid Protocol on the International Recognition of Marks (proposal for a decision) (T04948) CNS96190 COM(96)0367 + RELA Avis F JURI Fond - Appointment of draftsman ===] Any other business 5. Petition 1181/95 by Mr Spencer on the destruction of the Amazon rain forests - Decision on procedure 9 END OF DOCUMENT</p>
<p>Committee on Legal Affairs and Citizens' Rights</p>
<p>[[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]]</p>
<p>1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.249 )</p>
<p>1.1 In the presence of the Council and Commission</p>
<p>2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 12.02.1996 (PE216.133 ) - 03.-04.06.1996 (PE217.576 ) - 21.-22.06.1995 (PE213.157 )</p>
<p>===] Monday, 2 September 1996</p>
<p>===] afternoon</p>
<p>3. Free movement of doctors and recognition of their diplomas, certificates and other qualifications (T03603) (95/014) COD94305 COM(95)0437 C4-0381/96 + JURI Fond R FONTAINE Nicole. (PPE) (PE218.248/RC )</p>
<p>- Consideration of a draft recommendation - Decision on procedure</p>
<p>4. Merger control (amendment of Council Regulation (EEC No 4064/89) - Green Pap er (T04371) (96/030) (T04371) COS0373 COM(96)0019 C4-0106/96 + JURI Avis A JANSSEN van R. (PPE) (PE217.897 ) F ECON Fond R RAPKAY Bernhard. (PSE) (PE218.622 )</p>
<p>- Adoption of draft opinion</p>
<p>5.1 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (96/007/A) (T04556) BUD0074 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + JURI Avis A ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE216.131/AM1) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE218.265 )</p>
<p>- Adoption of amendments</p>
<p>5.2 1997 budget - other sections (T04557) (96/007/B) (T0457) BUD0075 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + JURI Avis A ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE216.131/AM1) F BUDG Fond R FABRA VALLES J. (PPE)</p>
<p>(PE218.286 )</p>
<p>- Adoption of amendments</p>
<p>6. Interparliamentary conference on combating fraud against the Community budge t (T04884) (96/084) (T04884) INI0504 INI0504 + JURI Avis L ODDY Christine M. (PSE) (PE218.246 ) F CONT Fond R THEATO Diemut. (PPE) (PE218.049 )</p>
<p>- Adoption of a draft opinion in the form of a letter</p>
<p>7. Priorities for consumer policy 1996-1998 (T03746) (95/134) (T03746) COS0324 COM(95)0519 C4-0501/95 + JURI Avis A ANOVEROS TRIAS d. (PPE) (PE216.128 ) F ENVI Fond R WHITEHEAD Phillip. (PSE) (PE218.208/A )</p>
<p>- Consideration of draft opinion - Decision on procedure</p>
<p>8. Convention on the European Information System (T04120) (95/091) (T04120) COS0275 12029/94 C4-0249/95 + JURI Avis A SCHAFFNER Anne-Marie (UPE) (PE214.185 ) F LIBE Fond R TERRON I C. (PSE) (PE215.800 )</p>
<p>===] Tuesday, 3 September 1996</p>
<p>===] morning</p>
<p>9. (96/001) Decisions on the opportunity to introduce proceedings before the Eu ropean Court of Justice</p>
<p>9.1 This item will be held IN CAMERA on Tuesday 3 September 1996 at 9 am with th e participation of Mr GARZON CLARIANA, Jurisconsult</p>
<p>10. Agreements between the EC and Israel on procurement by government and telco mmunications operators (T04821) (96/090) CNS96104 COM(96)0148 C4-0323/96 + JURI Avis S SIERRA GONZ uLEZ A. (GUE) F RELA Fond R DE CLERCQ W. (ELD) (PE218.552 )</p>
<p>11. Common Catalogue of Varieties (70/457/EEC amended 17 times) - codification (T02734) (96/009C) CNS95322 COM(95)0628 C4-0080/96 + JURI Fond ULLMANN Wolfgang. (V ) (PE218.245/CM )</p>
<p>- Exchange of views</p>
<p>12. Injunctions for the protection of consumers' interests (Member States' legi slation) (T03102) (96/035) COD96025 COM(95)0712 C4-0127/96 + JURI Fond R VERDE I A. (PSE) (PE216.820/DT )</p>
<p>- Exchange of views on the basis of a working document</p>
<p>===] afternoon</p>
<p>13. 25th annual report on competition policy (T04761) (96/44) (T04761) COS0408 COM(96)0126 C4-0240/96 + JURI Avis A FLORIO Luigi A. (UPE) (PE217.327 ) F ECON Fond R GARCIA ARIAS L. (PSE) (PE218.621 )</p>
<p>- Adoption of draft opinion</p>
<p>14. Social security for migrant workers: amendment of Regulations 1408/71 and 5 74/72 (persons seeking employment) (T03825) (96/019) (T03825) CNS96004 COM(95)0734 C4-0116/96 + JURI Avis A HLAVAC Elisabeth. (PSE) (PE217.325/DT ) F ASOC Fond R OOMEN-RUIJTEN M.G.H. (PE217.872 ) (PPE)</p>
<p>- Exchange of views on the basis of a working document</p>
<p>15. Recognition of qualifications: craft trades and other business activities ( T03668) (96/036) COD96031 COM(96)0022 C4-0123/96 + JURI Fond R GEBHARDT Evelyne. (PSE) (PE216.818 )</p>
<p>- Exchange of views</p>
<p>16. Convention on computerization in the field of customs (T04119) (95/090) (T04119) COS0274 LET 8406/95 C4-0248/95 + JURI Avis A ULLMANN Wolfgang. (V ) (PE214.186 ) F LIBE Fond R SCHULZ Martin. (PSE) (PE215.793 )</p>
<p>- Consideration of draft opinion - Decision on procedure</p>
<p>17. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure - (PE218.249/AN1) - (PE218.249/AN2)</p>
<p>18. Any other business</p>
<p>19. Date of next meeting (PE/VII/OJ/16-96 )</p>
<p>19.1 Deadline for texts for translation before the next meeting (reminder): - Wednesday, 14 August 1996</p>
<p>A N N E X I</p>
<p>===] APPOINTMENT OF RAPPORTEUR</p>
<p>1. Settlement finality and collateral security (proposal for directive) (T04890 ) (96/077) (T04890) COD96126 COM(96)0193 C4-0306/96 + JURI Fond - item held over from the meeting of 22-24 July 1996 - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - 2. Progamme of incentives and exchanges for practitioners in the justice area ( proposal for a Council decision) (T04902) (96/085) (T04902) CNS96146 COM(96)0253 + JURI Fond - item held over from the meeting of 22-24 July 1996 - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - 3. Amendment of Regulation 40/94 on the Community trade mark (Protocol on the I nternational Registration of Trade Marks) (T03826) (96/086) (T03826) CNS96198 COM(96)0372 + JURI Fond - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - 4. EC accession to the Madrid Protocol on the International Recognition of Mark s (proposal for a decision) (T04948) (96/094) (T04948) CNS96190 COM(96)0367 + JURI Fond - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - 4.1 * * * ===] Petition forwarded by the Committee on Petitions to the Legal Affairs Commi ttee for information: 5. Petition 1107/95 by Mr Leo De Nul on exclusion from amnesty of those guilty of the unlawful practice of the profession of oral surgeon - On 22 July 1996 Mr Newman, the chairman of the Committee on Petitions, wrote t o Mr Casini forwarding this petition - to the Legal Affairs Committee for information. - The Committee on Petitions has closed examination of the petition but asks the Legal Affairs Committee to inform it - of any action taken. A N N E X II ===] Rule 45 motion referred to the committee as committee responsible at the pa rt-session from 15 to 19 July 1996 - Decision on procedure (Rule 45(2)) - include the motion with other motions or reports - deliver an opinion, possibly in letter form - draw up a report, for which authorization has to be obtained from the Conferen ce of Presidents 19. Promoting the sponsorship of children in care who have reached the age of l egal majority (B4-0699/96) ( (96/089) ) - Rapporteur - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - Group - - - - - - Points - - - - - - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
