<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20810" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP ENVIRONMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</title>
<headline>EP ENVIRONMENT COMMITTEE AGENDA - SEPT 2-3.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on the Environment, Public Health and Consumer Protection [[ Monday 02 September 1996 ]] 0.1 ===] Monday, 2 September 1996, 3.00pm 1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE218.662 ) 2. Approval of minutes of meetings of: - 8-9 July 1996 (PE218.661 ) - 22-23 July 1996 (PE218.663 ) 3. Chairman's announcements 4. Comparative advertising (Dir. 84/450/EEC) (T01054) (T01054) COD0343 COM(94)0151 C4-0325/96 + ENVI Fond R OOMEN-RUIJTEN M.G.H. (PPE) - Consideration of common position 5. Community Action Programme on health data and indicators, to provide informa tion back-up (cancer, AIDS, etc.) (T03748) (T03748) COD95238 COM(96)0222 C4-0354/96 + ENVI Fond R POGGIOLINI Danilo. (PPE) (PE218.544 ) - Consideration of draft recommendation for 2nd reading 6. Cocoa and chocolate products for human consumption - Proposal for EP and Cou ncil Directive (T04894) (T04894) COD96112 COM(95)0722 C4-0303/96 + ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) - Discussion on procedure 7. Consumer access to justice and the settlement of consumer disputes in the in ternal market (T04803) (T04803) COS0398 COM(96)0013 C4-0195/96 + ENVI Avis A KUHN Annemarie. (PSE) (PE218.663 ) F JURI Fond R FLORIO Luigi A. (UPE) (PE218.241 ) - Consideration of draft opinion 8. Network for surveillance of communicable diseases in the European Community (T04784) (T04784) COD96052 COM(96)0078 C4-0189/96 + ENVI Fond R CABROL Christian E. (UPE) (PE218.210 ) - Consideration of draft report ===] Tuesday, 3 September 1996, 9.00am 9. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure 10. CITES: Convention on endangered species of wild flora and fauna (T01053) **II (T01053) SYN0370 COM(93)0599 C4-0285/96 + ENVI Fond R PUTTEN Maartje J. (PSE) (PE218.009 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation for 2nd reading 11. Supervision and control of shipments of waste within, into and out of the E uropean Community (T04044) **II (T04044) SYN95107 COM(96)0062 C4-0331/96 + ENVI Fond R VIRGIN Ivar. (PPE)</p>
<p>(PE218.547 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation for 2nd reading 12. Air quality: improvement of comparability and transparency at European leve l (reduction of emissions) (T02662) **II (T02662) SYN94194 COM(95)0468 C4-0330/96 + ENVI Fond R POLLACK Anita. (PSE) (PE218.542 ) - Adoption of draft recommendation for 2nd reading 13. 1997 budget - Section III (T04556) (T04556) BUD0074 COM(96)0300 C4-0350/96 + ENVI Avis A FLORENZ Karl-Heinz. (PPE) (PE218.209/DEF) F BUDG Fond R BRINKHORST Laurens J (ELD) (PE218.327 ) - Consideration of draft opinion 14. Maritime strategy 14.1 Towards a new maritime strategy (T04818) (T04818) COS0405 COM(96)0081 C4-0237/96 + ENVI Avis L (PE218.664 ) F TRAN Fond R DANESIN Alessandro. (UPE) (PE218.415 ) - Consideration and adoption of draft opinion 14.2 Competitiveness of the shipping industry (T04389) (T04389) COS0402 COM(96)0084 C4-0211/96 + ENVI Avis L</p>
<p>(PE218.665 ) F ECON Fond R KATIFORIS Georgios. (PSE) - Consideration and adoption of draft opinion 15. Trade and environment - Commission communication (T04781) (T04781) COS0391 COM(96)0054 C4-0158/96 + ENVI Avis A PIMENTA Carlos. (ELD) F RELA Fond R KREISSL-DORFLER Wolf (V ) (PE218.562/A ) - Consideration of draft opinion 16. The legal protection of biotechnological inventions (T04629) (T04629) COD95350 COM(95)0661 C4-0063/96 + ENVI Avis A SANDB K Ulla. (EDN) (PE218.217/DT ) F JURI Fond R ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE218.021 ) - Consideration of working document 17. Reciprocal recognition of approval for motor vehicle equipment and parts - EC accession to 1958 Agreement (T04728) (T04728) AVC96006 COM(95)0723 C4-0186/96 + ENVI Avis L F RELA Fond R KITTELMANN Peter. (PPE) (PE217.860 ) - Consideration and possible adoption of draft opinion 18. Any other business 19. Date of next meeting in Brussels (PE/XI/OJ/96-15 )</p>
<p>[FOOTNOTES]1. ) Coordinators meeting to be held on Monday, 2 September 1996, at 6.00pm A N N E X ===] Item 9 of the agenda ===] Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure ===] CONSULTATIONS ===] - Responsible 1. Recasting of Directive 88/379/EEC on the classification, packaging and labelling of dangerous preparations (T04363) COD96200 COM(96)0347 C4-0426/96 + ENVI Fond 2. Extraction solvents used in the production of foodstuffs (amendment of Directive 88/344/EEC) (T04944) COD96195 COM(96)0375 C4-0428/96 + ENVI Fond 3. BSE - protection of human and animal health (T04923) COS0437 C4-417/96 C4-0417/96 + ENVI Fond R PAPAYANNAKIS Mihail. (GUE) ===] - Opinion 4. Defining a Community aviation safety improvement strategy (T04934) COS0438 SEC(96)1083 C4-0423/96 + ENVI Avis F TRAN Fond R (PPE) A D D E N D U M 0.1 ===] After item 13, add the following item 13.1 Complementary (or non-conventional) medicine (T03525) INI0330 INI0330 B4-0024/94 B4-0024/94 + ENVI Fond R LANNOYE Paul. (V ) (PE216.066 ) - Further consideration of draft report g END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
