<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20827" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French farmers erect blockades in mad cow protest.</title>
<headline>French farmers erect blockades in mad cow protest.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of farmers threw up surprise blockades on roads across France overnight, stopping and checking lorries suspected of importing non-European Union beef in protest at falling prices following the mad cow crisis.</p>
<p>Farmers had threatened an &quot;incendiary&quot; end to the summer holidays and this show of force was the first in a wave of social unrest expected to target the austerity-minded government in coming weeks.</p>
<p>The FNSEA farmers' union, which mobilised demonstrators with mobile phones and faxes in complete secrecy, said about 15,000 farmers set up blockades on main roads and at motorway toll gates in many areas to carry out spot checks on cargoes.</p>
<p>The main quarry were trucks carrying imports from Britain, outside the European Union and especially cheap imports from eastern Europe, which breeders say have helped force beef prices down by a third in recent months.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very happy with today's mobilisation. The aim of the checks is to ensure that both producers and consumers benefit from complete openness on the origin of meat,&quot; FNSEA head Luc Guyau told Europe-1 radio.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be inflexible,&quot; he said, adding that checks were still continuing although the great majority of trucks checked had been cleared. More than 2,000 lorries were searched.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to take things into our own hands and clean things up. We'll find what we're looking for, that's for certain,&quot; echoed an FNSEA official in western Mayenne.</p>
<p>A dozen trucks had suspect cargoes. On the Franco-Belgian border, one Dutch driver who resisted orders to have his load searched had the tyres of his lorry punctured. His cargo was handed over to local customs officials.</p>
<p>In the Losere region, farmers who stopped a truck found frozen meat among more than 500 kg (1,100 lb) of frozen fish.</p>
<p>The blockades coincided with surprise protests called in a host of towns, on the eve of a European Union meeting on how to counter the mad cow crisis. In Laval, farmers unloaded veal in the streets. Protesters occupied the offices of the prefecture (local government authority) in the Creuse region.</p>
<p>Near Grenoble, 100 farmers occupied a slaughterhouse at Hieres sur Amby to check the origin of meat, police reported.</p>
<p>Asked whether he wanted a ban on imports from outside the EU, Guyau said: &quot;When we talk about stopping the fall in prices, it's crucial we start by dealing with imports. We don't want to close borders but we want agreements to be totally respected.&quot;</p>
<p>In a separate protest, a group of breeders who have marched their cows from the provinces to Paris will walk into the courtyard of President Jacques Chirac's Elysee palace on Friday and put their grievances to him.</p>
<p>European beef sales plunged after Britain announced the discovery of a likely link between bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), or mad cow disease, and its fatal human equivalent Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease (CJD).</p>
<p>Marc Blondel, leader of the Force Ouvriere union, warned that social conflicts in the autumn could be worse than last year's crippling public sector strikes over welfare reform.</p>
<p>&quot;It's my problem as a unionist that this risks happening outside the control of the unions. More a sort of 'Poujadism',&quot; Blondel said, referring to a popular political uprising led by grocer Jean-Pierre Poujade in the 1950s.</p>
<p>Chirac, chairing his first post-holiday cabinet meeting on Wednesday, urged his ministers to &quot;get yourselves together&quot; and exude optimism to help snap France out of doldrums fuelled by record unemployment, planned spending cuts and layoffs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
