<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20821" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Daimler takes first step out of record loss.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Daimler takes first step out of record loss.</headline>
<byline>Kirsten Ridley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's largest industrial conglomerate, Daimler-Benz AG, took its first step towards financial recovery on Thursday, reporting a rebound in first half earnings after record losses last year.</p>
<p>Daimler, much criticised for last year's 5.7 billion mark ($3.86 billion) loss, said net profits in the first six months of the 1996 climbed to 782 million marks from a 1.6 billion mark loss for first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Juergen Schrempp told a London news conference that first-half sales climbed 1.3 percent to 49.07 billion marks as operating profit swung to a 827 million mark profit from a 613 million mark loss.</p>
<p>For the second half of 1996 Daimler said it expects a further positive developments although Schrempp said more work was needed to increase profits.</p>
<p>&quot;So let there be no mistake. We have only just begun,&quot; Schrempp said. &quot;Our goal remains that each business unit will achieve a return that is among the top of the world class companies in each sector where we compete.&quot;</p>
<p>Schrempp hinted the results, which were released in London according to U.S. GAAP accounting principles in order to increase transparency of its accounts and to stimulate global awareness, may enable the company the pay a dividend this year after making no payout to shareholders in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We will go back to discuss dividends,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The net profit result was near the high end of analysts' expectations.</p>
<p>The profit rise was led by the group's flagship unit, car and truck maker Mercedes-Benz AG. Mercedes, benefitting from a stronger dollar and booming sales of its E-Class model, posted an 2.8 percent rise in operating profit to 1.4 billion marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Mercedes is now the most profitable automobile manufacturer in the world on a per unit basis and we intend to keep it that way,&quot; Schrempp said.</p>
<p>Daimler-Benz Aerospace (DASA), in the midst of a massive cost cutting campaign, showed an operating loss of 677 million marks.</p>
<p>This loss was smaller than the first-half 1995 operating loss of 1.62 billion marks however.</p>
<p>Schrempp restated his belief that DASA would reach breakeven by 1998, saying he was encouraged by overall growth in the global aircraft industry and a record inflow of Airbus orders. DASA is a major partner in the Airbus Industrie consortium.</p>
<p>Daimler-Benz InterServices (Debis), the financial and services division, saw operating profits climb to 212 million marks from 156 million marks in the year earlier period.</p>
<p>Daimler shares, which had been climbing over the last few days in anticipation of strong numbers, slipped seven pfennigs to 81.25 marks on profit-taking, traders said.</p>
<p>Germany's largest conglomerate was pushed deep into the red last year as it undertook a massive reorganisation aimed at returning it to its transportation roots, abandoning dreams to become an integrated technology company.</p>
<p>In 1995, it took one-off charges of 3.9 billion marks, including a 2.3 billion mark writedown of Dutch aircraft maker Fokker NV and 1.6 billion marks for streamlining of its AEG unit.</p>
<p>Schrempp said Daimler had cut the number of business units in the group's portfolio to 25 from 35 since last May.</p>
<p>&quot;The earnings potential for the steamlined portfolio has increased substantially,&quot; he said. ($1=1.4770 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
