<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20825" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia amends laws to boost offshore centre.</title>
<headline>Malaysia amends laws to boost offshore centre.</headline>
<byline>Madhav Reddy</byline>
<dateline>LABUAN, Malaysia 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia will amend laws governing its Labuan island financial centre to make the offshore banking zone more attractive to foreign fund managers, Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He also said new laws being drafted would allow Malaysians to own offshore companies as well as help Labuan's International Offshore Financial Centre (IOFC) offer a wider range of financial services.</p>
<p>Mahathir was speaking at the inauguration of the Labuan Financial Park, a 360 million ringgit ($145 million) commercial complex that houses 50 banks, several insurance and other financial services companies.</p>
<p>He said further measures were being adopted to establish Labuan as a premier IOFC.</p>
<p>&quot;For instance, the Offshore Companies Act 1990 will be amended to allow Malaysians to own offshore companies as well as permitting offshore companies to invest in Malaysia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Laws would also be introduced soon to recognise offshore businesses such as limited partnerships, securities industries and Islamic financial services.</p>
<p>Malaysia is promoting Labuan as an international offshore financial hub. The duty-free island in the South China Sea, off Borneo, has been modelled after tax havens such as Bermuda, the British Virgin Islands and the Channel Islands.</p>
<p>At present, Malaysians are not allowed to own non-financial offshore companies in Labuan. There are already some 800 offshore trading companies operating on the island.</p>
<p>The Labuan IOFC is a key part of Malaysia's goal of becoming a regional financial centre and bankers on the island said Mahathir's strong support would make the centre more attractive to investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The things he mentioned in his speech today are definitely going to give a boost to the development of Labuan,&quot; said Nathaniel Savarimuthu, executive director of the Public Bank (L) Ltd.</p>
<p>Bankers have said they hope to attract some of the $120 billion in Islamic funds parked in interest-free accounts around the world. Under Islam's Shariah principles, paying interest on money held in bank accounts is considered usury.</p>
<p>The bankers have also been predicting large movement of funds from Hong Kong to Labuan as the colony reverts to Chinese control in 1997. ($1 = 2.49 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LABUAN, Malaysia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
