<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20838" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold prices turn easier in very quiet trade.</title>
<headline>London gold prices turn easier in very quiet trade.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Precious metals were stuck in a narrow and lower range on Thursday compared with prices earlier this week in a market which dealers described as gloomy.</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $388.05 per ounce after $388.50 on Wednesday and a close of $388.55.</p>
<p>&quot;Physical business is beginning to kick in but it is doing no more than mopping up any surplus,&quot; a dealer said, adding that he did not get bullish for gold until late September.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect to see much before that and meanwhile the physical offtake is taking up any profit-taking from the longs (holders of gold) who bought in the rally from $381 to $389,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Both New York and the Far East were quiet and featureless overnight with gold marginally easier in New York and regaining European closing levels in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Dealers said the precious metals would probably remain quiet this week ahead of the three-day U.S. Labor Day weekend.</p>
<p>Silver was no more exiting but dealers' and analysts' views varied on the medium-term price trend.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver has been mixed and very difficult to figure out. Until gold starts to move I can see it sitting in a $5.15-$5.25 range,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Others were less optimistic, seeing silver losing ground after its continual failure to get over $5.25 per ounce earlier this week.</p>
<p>Platinum and palladium were also lukewarm with platinum indicated down $0.25 at $399.75 and palladium 80 cents easier at $126.20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
