<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20839" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: B.A.T seeks to reassure on U.S. litigation.</title>
<headline>B.A.T seeks to reassure on U.S. litigation.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's B.A.T Industries Plc on Thursday said it and the tobacco industry as a whole were confident that U.S. tobacco litigants would ultimately make no significant progress.</p>
<p>In a letter to be posted to shareholders, B.A.T said it was also confident that the recent award of damages against it to a plaintiff who suffered from lung cancer would be overturned.</p>
<p>&quot;Notwithstanding this, the litigious framework in the U.S. means that we will see continuing activity in the courtrooms of America,&quot; B.A.T said in the letter.</p>
<p>The letter follows a slump in B.A.T's share price after news last week of a lung cancer award by a Florida court and on moves by President Clinton to support the Food and Drug Administration's proposal limiting youth access to tobacco products.</p>
<p>Shares in the group, which plunged to a year-low of around 420 pence on the two developments, have since moved up to 445 pence.</p>
<p>Referring to Clinton's approval for the new FDA regulations on youth access, B.A.T said it strongly opposed government regulations &quot;whose true purpose is to restrict the rights of adults to smoke...&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very unfortunate that the discussions between the U.S. administration and members of the U.S. tobacco businesses...have been sacrificed to political grandstanding ahead of the US presidential elections in November,&quot; it added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
