<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20844" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares fall, seen locked in tight range.</title>
<headline>Polish shares fall, seen locked in tight range.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares fell on Thursday after Wednesday's rise but analysts said the stronger buying after price fixing signalled a rise on Friday with the market continuing this week's see-saw performance.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems to be a balance between buyers and sellers...we're currently near 13,700 points so it seems the market should stay within 13,500 and 14,000 over the next few sessions,&quot; said Dariusz Szepieniec of Bank Slaski brokerage.</p>
<p>But some analysts saw possible growth, with the market getting a boost next week from funds returned after the recent oversubscription of the Kompap paper firm's public offering.</p>
<p>The main market's all-share WIG index fell 0.6 percent to 13,691.0 points and turnover fell 6.3 percent to 79.3 million zlotys ($29 million) on both markets. Losers led gainers by 48 to 20 with nine stocks flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said another good sign were rises by some large- capitalised stocks such as Bank Gdanski and bank WBK, which set 52-week highs, rising 2.2 percent and 1.8 percent respectively.</p>
<p>Analysts said biggest mover construction firm Exbud, down 5.6 percent, fell in profit-taking after its surprising 10-percent jump on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 87,900 zlotys ($32,000), with biggest mover tyremaker Debica up 1.7 percent. No stocks had traded live on Wednesday.</p>
<p>NFI units were flat at 87 zlotys ($31.8) in 7.6-million- zloty ($2.8 million) trade while in the continuous session they rose 2.9 percent to 89.5 zlotys ($32.7), signalling possible growth in Friday's regular session after recent falls, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
