<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20845" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks meander to weaker close.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks meander to weaker close.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market meandered to a weaker close on Thursday, having spent the day trapped in a 10 point range with little incentive to attempt escape.</p>
<p>July balance of payments figures, one possible market motivator, came in on expectations and was promptly ignored.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index lost 4.9 points to close at 2279.3 while September share index futures dipped five points to close at 2279, a 0.3 point discount to the index.</p>
<p>Turnover ended at impressive levels as August series options reached expiry.</p>
<p>While the market came off its lows in the afternoon, players said they had little to work with, resulting in the day's basically flat performance.</p>
<p>&quot;It improved in the afternoon. Commonwealth Bank led the way back even though BHP went into reverse,&quot; said broker Kevin Lourey of brokerage Peake Lands Kirwan.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no real reason for it to be as flat as it is. Volumes are quite good.&quot;</p>
<p>Others traders agreed, saying the market had been essentially rudderless with the options expiry probably as strong a force as any on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;There was not much to work with and that is exactly what it did - not much,&quot; said a Sydney-based dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Options-related trade accounted for a lot of the business and the balance of payments surprised no-one.&quot;</p>
<p>Strongest performance of the day came from gas utility, AGL, whose shares streaked to record highs, fuelled by a record full year net profit of A$124.3 million (US$98.6 million).</p>
<p>Other companies to report included minerals sands and base metals miner, RGC, which posted a 46.6 percent rise in full year net profit to A$142.81 million. Its shares closed fractionally firmer.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about 11 to 10, while about 31 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.7930)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
