<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20850" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: By James Hatton.</title>
<headline>By James Hatton.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices slid on Thursday in Tokyo and Hong Kong, but the declines failed to drag down the smaller markets in the region, all driven by local issues.</p>
<p>The Seoul and Bombay bourses both added more than one percent. Most other area markets posted smaller gains, while those in Bangkok, Kuala Lumpur and Sydney saw slight declines.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks closed lower as concern about Japan's economic recovery lingered following Wednesday's weak &quot;tankan&quot; data. Most buyers sat on the sidelines, and brokers said the sluggish trade was expected to continue until September.</p>
<p>The 225-share Nikkei average shed 156.65 points, or 0.76 percent, to end at 20,553.16 after drifting between 20,503.62 and 20,706.99. September futures lost 130 points to 20,590.</p>
<p>&quot;People are gauging where the bottom of the market is,&quot; said Kenzo Doi, senior analyst at Kokusai Securities Co Ltd.</p>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended weaker with a share placement from New World Development dulling the market's tone, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index fell 51.28 points to 11,328.21. Turnover was HK$4.07 billion compared to HK$3.65 billion on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand the market lacks direction in the short term and also New World is down quite a lot because of a placement,&quot; said Ben Kwong of Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>Profit-taking cut into a strong rally in Bombay. Share prices fell near the bell, but the 30-share BSE index still finished up 54.44 points, or 1.58 percent, at a provisional 3,493.24 after rising to 3,529.19.</p>
<p>Brokers said the surge had been sparked by reports that the government would ease a controversial minimum tax proposal for some sections of industry.</p>
<p>Seoul stocks rose on the hope of an announcement soon on the raising of the foreign shareholding limit, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing on the market changed, but there was talk that the finance ministry would announce a higher ceiling after a meeting between the new finance minister and the president,&quot; said Ha Yong-hyun of Hyundai Securities.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed up 12.83 points, or 1.70 percent, to 766.16.</p>
<p>Taiwan share prices were higher on active late buying of blue chips favoured by foreign funds, brokers said. The index ended up 55.67 points, or 0.89 percent, at an intraday high of 6,312.43. Turnover was a modest T$38 billion.</p>
<p>Dealers saw active late buying of blue chips. Financials led the gains, with Cathay Life up T$3 to T$169.</p>
<p>Singapore shares were slightly up in mixed trading, dealers said. Blue chips edged lower at the close, but the Straits Times Industrials Index finished up 2.77 points at 2,162.65. Market volume was a thin 81.41 million, with declines ahead of advances by 183 to 111.</p>
<p>Kuala Lumpur Second Board stocks ended lower as buyers paused after three days of record-setting gains. Blue chips also were down slightly.</p>
<p>The Composite Index slid 0.84 points, or 0.08 percent, to 1,110.49. The Second Board dropped 10.69 points or 1.97 percent to 531.06 after hitting a session peak of 545.44.</p>
<p>Thai stocks were nearly unchanged in moderate trade on disappointment over key economic data wiped out earlier gains.</p>
<p>The SET index shed 0.25 points to 1,105.59 on 4.4 billion baht trade. Gainers led decliners 151 to 135 while 136 issues were unchanged. The SET-50 index slipped 0.21 point to 84.42.</p>
<p>&quot;The index fell after the central bank released key economic indicators in the afternoon. Investors weren't happy with some figures,&quot; said Lan Pajasalmi of First Asia Securities.</p>
<p>The Australian share market closed weaker after spending the day trapped in a 10 point range with little incentive to escape. The All Ordinaries index closed down 4.9 points, or 0.21 percent, at 2279.3. September share index futures closed five points lower at 2279, a 0.3 point discount to the index.</p>
<p>Manila shares finished higher after a tentative start as foreign investors started buying up the market, traders said. The main index climbed 14.81 points to 3,215.79.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
