<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20853" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end down, New World hurts prices.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end down, New World hurts prices.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended weaker on Thursday, with a share placement from New World Development dulling the market's tone, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index fell 51.28 points to 11,328.21. Turnover was HK$4.07 billion compared to HK$3.65 billion on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;On the one hand the market lacks direction in the short term and also New World is down quite a lot because of a placement,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>Trading in New World was suspended during the afternoon. The stock was down HK$0.90 at HK$38.00 before the suspension.</p>
<p>Sources said the company was placing 70 million shares. The price is expected to be HK$37.10 per share, one placing source said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors normally do not perceive it as good sign when blue chip companies place shares. They think the blue chip companies will make use of a short-term market peak for placements and also investors are worried about whether other companies will follow the same move,&quot; said Kwong.</p>
<p>August Hang Seng futures, which expired on Thursday, ended 46 points higher at 11,396. September futures fell 47 points to 11,335.</p>
<p>Kwong said stocks are likely to remain confined to ranges on Friday. &quot;I expect the market will consolidate and hopefully we will see a better performance in September,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Losses in the H-share index were limited by strong gains in Qingling Motors stock.</p>
<p>The H-share index closed 0.69 point lower at 814.92.</p>
<p>&quot;The H-shares are holding up reasonably well. Part of it is because one or two big stocks are doing quite well,&quot; said Alan Hutcheson, director of research at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Qingling hit a year high at HK$3.15 after reporting interim profit of 183.01 million yuan compared to 29.65 million. The stock ended the session up HK$0.15 at HK$3.05.</p>
<p>Yizheng Chemical rose HK$0.06 to HK$1.81.</p>
<p>Shares in First Pacific closed HK$0.05 higher at HK$12.85 and Henderson Investment fell HK$0.10 to HK$8.50. Both stocks will join the Hang Seng index on Friday replacing Hong Kong Aircraft Engineering Co, unchanged at HK$19.50, and Miramar Hotel, down HK$0.48 at HK$14.60.</p>
<p>Shares in Television Broadcasts Ltd fell HK$0.65 to HK$28.60. It posted a drop in interim net profit to HK$177.96 million compared to HK$189.01 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
