<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23458" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NationsBank acquiring Boatmen's for $9.5 billion.</title>
<headline>NationsBank acquiring Boatmen's for $9.5 billion.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>NationsBank Corp. said Friday it agreed to acquire Boatmen's Bancshares Inc. for about $9.5 billion, creating a financial giant stretching from North Carolina to New Mexico.</p>
<p>Investors greeted the news with mixed reactions, boosting Boatmen's shares by $10.6875 to $53.75 on the Nasdaq market and pushing NationsBank down $7.375 to $85 on the New York Stock Exchange .</p>
<p>The transaction, the third-biggest bank merger on record, will create a bank with some $230 billion in assets, $20 billion in shareholders' equity and a market capitalisation of $33 billion, a joint announcement said.</p>
<p>The statement said the new company, with more than 13 million customers in 16 states, will become the country's fourth-largest commercial bank and have the potential to produce $3 billion in profits next year.</p>
<p>NationsBank, with $192 billion in total assets, had been the fifth-largest U.S. commercial bank.</p>
<p>Under the deal, NationsBank, based in Charlotte, N.C., will exchange 0.6525 share of its common stock for each share of St.Louis-based Boatmen's, which has about $41 billion in assets.</p>
<p>Based on Thursday's $92.375 closing price for NationsBank shares, the transaction will be worth about $9.487 billion.</p>
<p>Some merger specialists expressed surprise at the amount NationsBank was offering, which represents a 40 percent premium over Boatmmen's closing price of $42.94 Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;What stunned me is the price,&quot; one said. &quot;That's 2.7 times book value, and a premium like that has never been paid for a commercial bank. It's coming down to paying hefty premiums to consolidate.&quot;</p>
<p>The announcement said the deal will be structured as a &quot;cash election&quot; merger for Boatmen's shareholders, meaning they will have the right to receive either stock or cash.</p>
<p>The transaction will be a tax-free exchange for Boatmen's shareholders to the extent they receive shares of NationsBank, the companies said.</p>
<p>They added that at least 60 percent of the purchase price paid to all holders will be in NationsBank common stock. The balance will be paid in either cash or NationsBank stock, or a mix of the two.</p>
<p>NationsBank said it expected to realise $335 million in annual cost savings from the merger by 1999. This represents a reduction in the combined expenses of 5 percent, it said.</p>
<p>The merger is subject to the approval of both companies' shareholders and the appropriate regulatory authorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
