<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23452" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, SEPT 2 - SUNDAY, SEPT 8.</title>
<headline>EC REPORT WEEKLY DIARY FOR MONDAY, SEPT 2 - SUNDAY, SEPT 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>****</p>
<p>HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>****</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament Inquiry Committee into mad cow disease holds first meeting (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commissioner Brittan meets U.S. Under Secretary for Trade and President Clinton's special envoy on the Helms-Burton Cuban trade restrictions, Stuart Eizenstat (Tuesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (Tuesday-Wednesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Commission holds first regular weekly meeting after its summer break (Wednesday); discusses dispute over Saxony regional government's decision to grant aid to Volkswagen plant despite a ban by the European Commission.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (Tuesday-Wednesday).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EU Scientific and Veterinary Committee meets; reviews recent findings that mad cow disease can be passed from cows to their calves and studies scientific reports saying Britain's mad cow epidemic should die out by 2001 (Friday).</p>
<p>TRALEE, Ireland - EU foreign ministers hold informal General Affairs Council (Friday-Sunday); main discussions focus on reviewing progress in the IGC.</p>
<p>MONDAY, SEPTEMBER 2</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) - Agriculture;</p>
<p>- Monetary Sub-Committee;</p>
<p>- Energy;</p>
<p>- External Economic Relations;</p>
<p>- Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>- Environment;</p>
<p>- Youth and Culture;</p>
<p>- Budgetary Control;</p>
<p>- Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>ST PETERSBURG - EUROSTAT holds seminar on &quot;The way ahead for statistics in new independent states&quot; (To September 6). Main topics discussed are the evaluation of the development of statistical systems targeting market-driven economies in the Tacis countries.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, SEPTEMBER 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Brittan meets U.S. Under Secretary for Trade and U.S. President Bill Clinton's Special Envoy on Helms-Burton Cuban trade restrictions, Stuart Eizenstat.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Bjerregaard attends EU-Poland joint committee.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commission President Santer meets Competitiveness Advisory group Chairman Paercy Barnevik.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - IGC Working Party of EU foreign ministers' representatives meets to continue review of EU treaties (and Wednesday). Topics include: citizenship, fundamental rights, subsidiarity, simplification and codification.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament Inquiry Committee into mad cow disease holds first meeting. Spanish Socialist leader in the European Parliament Manuel Medina presents report.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) - Agriculture;</p>
<p>- Economic and Monetary Affairs;</p>
<p>- Energy;</p>
<p>- External Economic Relations;</p>
<p>- Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>- Environment;</p>
<p>- Youth and Culture;</p>
<p>- Budgetary control;</p>
<p>- Institutional Affairs;</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) - Budget;</p>
<p>- Youth and Culture;</p>
<p>- Legal Affairs;</p>
<p>- Institutional Affairs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Agriculture Commissioner Franz Fischler and Irish Agriculture Minister Ivan Yates address EP temporary committee of inquiry into BSE from 1500/1300 GMT.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, SEPTEMBER 4</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (EXPANDED ITEM) - European Commission holds first regular weekly meeting after its summer break (0930/0730 GMT).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (NEW ITEM) - Chairmen from three EU scientific committees report on their findings on the safety of a strain of genetically modified maize.</p>
<p>- Discussion on dispute on Saxony regional government's decision to grant aid to Volkswagen plant despite a ban by the European Commission.</p>
<p>- European Commission President Santer, European Commissioners Bangemann, Flynn, de Silguy, Liikanen, Papoutsis present communication on questions related to the expiry of the ECSC Treaty - orientation debate.</p>
<p>- (possibly) European Commissioner Monti presents communication on draft directive on media concentrations - orientation debate COM(96)396.</p>
<p>- European Commissioner Bjerregaard presents communication on marketing quotas for HCFCs.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioners Bonino and Marin meet U.S. Under Secretary for Trade and U.S. President Bill Clinton's Special Envoy on Helms-Burton, Stuart Eizenstat.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (and Wednesday).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1500/1300 GMT) Statement by the Commission on urgent political matters of major importance, followed by questions.</p>
<p>- (1630/1430 GMT) Statements by the Council and the Commission an public services followed by a debate.</p>
<p>- Robin Teverson report on the sixth annual report for 1994 on the structural funds COM(95)583.</p>
<p>- Joint debate:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Konstantinos Klironomos report on development issues relating to Objective I structural measures in Greece.</p>
<p>- Giles Chichester report on development issues/Objective 1 - structural measures in Portugal.</p>
<p>- Angela Siepra Gonzalez report on development problems/structural measures under Objectives 1-2 and 5b in Spain (1994-1999).</p>
<p>- Bernd Lange report on the 1995 annual report on the research and technological development activities of the European Union COM(95)443.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Karl von Wogau report on the rates of duty laid down in Council directive 92/79/EEC of 19 October 1992 on the approximation of taxes on cigarettes, Council directive 92/80/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of taxes on manufactured tobacco other than cigarettes, Council directive 92/84/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of the rates of excise duty on alcohol and alcoholic beverages and 92/82/EEC of 19 October 1992, on the approximation of the rates of excise duties on mineral oils COM(95)285.</p>
<p>- Werner Langen report on the common system of Value Added Tax (level of the standard rate) COM(95)731.</p>
<p>- Gipo Farassino report on the proposal for a Council directive amending directive 91/439/EEC on driving licences COM(96)55.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Per Stenmarck report on the proposal for a Council directive on safety rules and standards for passenger ships COM(96)61.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - Following EP committees meet:</p>
<p>(0900/0700 GMT) - Budget;</p>
<p>(1500/1300 GMT) - Inquiry into Fraud in Transit.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, SEPTEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - European Commissioner Bjerregaard meets European Investment Bank (EIB) Vice President Rudolf De Corta.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament mini-session (second of two days).</p>
<p>Provisonal agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (until 0900/0700 GMT) Political group meetings.</p>
<p>- (0900/0700 GMT) Edgar Schiedermeier report on a European strategy for encouraging local development and employment initiatives COM(95)273.</p>
<p>- Michel Rocard report on the reduction of working hours.</p>
<p>- (1100/0900 GMT) Votes on reports under the cooperation, codecision and assent procedures and motions for resolutions on which the debate has closed.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Executive committee of the Bosnian Peace Implementation Council, known as the Steering Board, meets ahead of September 14 Bosnian elections to discuss post-election framework peace plan.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, SEPTEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - EU Scientific and Veterinary Committee meets; reviews recent findings that mad cow disease can be passed from cows to their calves and studies scientific reports saying Britain's mad cow epidemic should die out by 2001.</p>
<p>TRALEE, Ireland - Informal General Affairs Council (to Sunday).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1730/1630 GMT) Irish Foreign Minister and European Council President Dick Spring addresses reception at Abbey Gate Hotel.</p>
<p>- (2000/1900 GMT) Presidency hosts dinner.</p>
<p>LINZ, Austria - GLOBE holds conference on &quot;Responding to climate change&quot;. Contact: GLOBE (322) 230 6589.</p>
<p>SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 7</p>
<p>TRALEE, Ireland - Informal General Affairs Council (second of three days).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (1500/1400 GMT) Informal working sessions begins; main discussions focus on the review of progress in the IGC.</p>
<p>SUNDAY, SEPTEMBER 8</p>
<p>TRALEE, Ireland - Informal General Affairs Council (last of three days).</p>
<p>Agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (0930/0830 GMT) Informal working session continues.</p>
<p>- (1215/1115 GMT) Irish Foreign Minister and Council President Dick Spring holds closing news conference.</p>
<p>If you have items for inclusion in the Reuter European</p>
<p>Community diary, please contact:</p>
<p>Telephone: Cynthia Simpson (322) 287 6851</p>
<p>Fax: (322) 230 5573</p>
<p>For technical queries regarding</p>
<p>the service, please call (322) 287 6666</p>
<p>Reuters 61, rue de Treves 1040 BRUSSELS</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>EC Report (C)opyright Reuters Limited</p>
<p>Unauthorised copying prohibited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
