<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23463" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hughes said to top list to buy PanAmSat.</title>
<headline>Hughes said to top list to buy PanAmSat.</headline>
<byline>Nick Louth</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aerospace company Hughes Electronics Corp. heads the list of bidders to buy satellite services provider PanAmSat Corp., a source close to the talks said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are just looking at the best offers on the table now,&quot; the source told Reuters, adding that Hughes' offer was currently about the best on the table.</p>
<p>Both PanAmSat, based in Greenwich, Conn., and Hughes declined to comment on what they called speculative reports. Los Angeles-based Hughes is part of General Motors Corp.</p>
<p>Hughes Chief Executive Mike Armstrong told Reuters Wednesday that the company was considering a multibillion-dollar acquisition in aerospace and defence.</p>
<p>&quot;We are always looking at ventures that will make our business grow&quot; said Hughes spokeswoman Marcy Garber.</p>
<p>PanAmSat has a unique franchise as the only global competitor to Intelsat, which is owned by numerous governments and was set up under a treaty.</p>
<p>Panamsat's customers include a vast array of international broadcasters, from Time Warner Inc. to News Corp, the British Broadcasting Corp. and China Central TV.</p>
<p>Analysts say PanAmSat could be worth $3.5 billion or more, a substantial premium over the $2.75 billion market capitalisation of the company. The stock was trading at $27.75, up 75 cents, on the New York Stock Exchange late Friday.</p>
<p>The source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said that talks are continuing, but no deal is imminent. He would not say how much Hughes was offering.</p>
<p>PanAmSat's majority owners are Grupo Televisa SA of Mexico and the family of founder Rene Anselmo, which each own 40.5 percent of the company's 100 million shares. The rest are publicly traded.</p>
<p>&quot;Rene Anselmo did a great job and took a lot of risks, and now his benefactors are going to reap the rewards,&quot; said analyst Jimmy Schaeffler of the Carmel Group.</p>
<p>In April, Televisa and the Anselmo family asked investment bankers Morgan Stanley to find a takeover or joint venture partner for the company, or to plan a secondary stock issue.</p>
<p>The source said that Televisa preferred a sale option, though the Anselmo family had no preference.</p>
<p>Other rumoured bidders include Lockheed Martin Corp., General Electric Co., Loral Space &amp; Communications Ltd., and Deutsche Telekom of Germany.</p>
<p>Schaeffler said Panamsat's expansion plans put it in a powerful position for new services and covering new areas like Africa and the Central Asian republics, which so far have no western satellite coverage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
