<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23468" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends firmer on strong data, German comments.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends firmer on strong data, German comments.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar rose Friday, bolstered by supportive comments from a key German official and signs of surprising strength in the American economy, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>A sharp selloff on Wall Street stock and bond markets tempered the dollar's gains, but a growing perception that official German interest rates will keep falling while American rates rise offset the temporary weakness.</p>
<p>The dollar ended at 1.4820 German marks, up from 1.4770 Thursday, and rose to 108.90 Japanese yen from 108.42.</p>
<p>U.S. trading ended early and will not resume until after the Labour Day holiday on Monday.</p>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer fanned expectations for a cut in German interest rates when he told a German news agency that the American economy's recent performance argued for a stronger dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Tietmeyer had something to say and that influenced the market obviously,&quot; said Jeffrey Yu, vice president at Sanwa Bank in New York.</p>
<p>The dollar climbed as high as 1.4844 marks in early trading before paring its gains.</p>
<p>Currency markets seemed to shrug off a surprisingly large cut in German interest rates last Thursday, but Tietmeyer's comments spurred speculation that more rate cuts would follow.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think the Bundesbank has perhaps made its last move and he's sort of telling us that,&quot; said David Durrant, senior currency strategist at consulting group IDEA.</p>
<p>Dealers in Europe also speculated that the Bundesbank might enter the currency markets on Monday to buy dollars against the mark in an effort to bolster the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>Three U.S. economic reports showed surprising growth, which sank Treasury bond and stock prices and hit the dollar as well.</p>
<p>July factory orders rose 1.8 percent, the August Chicagoland Business Barometer rose to 60.0, its highest in 18 months, and the University of Michigan August consumer sentiment index rose to 95.3 from 94.7.</p>
<p>The reports support similarly strong data in recent weeks and suggest the Federal Reserve may soon raise official short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>While that prospect should bolster the dollar, the immediate reaction in the market was to sell dollars along with other U.S. assets.</p>
<p>&quot;Weak U.S. assets mean the dollar comes off, but there's always a point where you start looking at higher rates as a sign it's time to get long on the dollar,&quot; Durrant said. &quot;It increases the perception the Fed will do something.&quot;</p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar rose to 1.2010 Swiss francs from 1.1947 Thursday. The British pound rose to $1.5605 from $1.5575. The dollar edged higher to Canadian $1.3682 from C$1.3670.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
