<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25729" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-ALLENBY SCRAMBLES MASTERS WIN IN PLAY-OFF WITH MARTIN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ALLENBY SCRAMBLES MASTERS WIN IN PLAY-OFF WITH MARTIN.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHAMPTON, England 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Robert Allenby almost threw away the British Masters on Saturday when he dropped four shots in six holes before clinching the title in a play-off against Spaniard Miguel Angel Martin.</p>
<p>Allenby was four shots clear with eight holes to play but then had four bogeys in his next six holes for a closing 73 which allowed the Spaniard to catch him with a 68 that included a 25-yard holed bunker shot for an eagle at the ninth.</p>
<p>They tied on a four-under-par total of 284 and then, in a somewhat fitting finale to a tournament in which everyone complained about the condition of the greens, Martin ran up a double-bogey seven to lose at the first sudden-death hole.</p>
<p>Just off the green at the 508-yard 18th in three, he chipped 30 feet past, putted three feet past and, after missing his next shot, conceded defeat with Allenby two feet away in four.</p>
<p>It allowed the 25-year-old from Melbourne to grab his third victory of the season which took him into third place in the European Order of Merit behind Ian Woosnam and Colin Montgomerie, who finished fifth and ninth respectively.</p>
<p>&quot;I just hung in there at the end and got pretty lucky,&quot; said Allenby, winner in June of the English and French Opens. &quot;After nine holes, things were looking good. But anything can happen on this course, as we all saw.&quot;</p>
<p>Woosnam needed an eagle at the par-five last to be in the play-off, was on the green in two but then putted right off it and took six to drop to fifth place.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to say anything because, if I do, I may say something bad. I've had enough,&quot; said the Welshman.</p>
<p>The tournament will be remembered, though, not so much for Allenby's victory as for the dire state of the greens at the European tour-owned Northampton course.</p>
<p>Ryder Cup captain Seve Ballesteros adding his influential voice to the massive criticism of the course for the event, the first qualifying tournament for next year's Ryder Cup.</p>
<p>The Spaniard, who finished in 57th place, said: &quot;If we play in these conditions I don't really think I will have the right team for the Ryder Cup.</p>
<p>&quot;I am willing to call for a meeting but need everyone's support. We can't continue like this -- if we do, we will lose players and sponsors.&quot;</p>
<p>Ballesteros added: &quot;Players are getting fed up with the situation and are going where there are better facilities and courses.</p>
<p>&quot;We will end up with 54 tournaments every year, but very cheap ones. It's not right. As I have said in the past many times, I want quality not quantity.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHAMPTON, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
