<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25739" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-BALLESTEROS JOINS IN COURSE CRITICISM.</title>
<headline>GOLF-BALLESTEROS JOINS IN COURSE CRITICISM.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHAMPTON, England 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seve Ballesteros added his considerable voice on Saturday to the criticism of the European Tour's decision to stage the British Masters at Collingtree Park.</p>
<p>Europe's Ryder Cup captain also widened the argument to the whole future of the Tour.</p>
<p>&quot;If we play in these conditions I don't really think I will have the right team for the Ryder Cup,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am willing to call for a meeting but need everyone's support. We can't continue like this -- if we do, we will lose players and sponsors.&quot;</p>
<p>Nick Faldo headed for the United States two years ago citing tournament conditions as one of the reasons.</p>
<p>Ballesteros commented: &quot;Players are getting fed up with the situation and are going where there are better facilities and courses.</p>
<p>&quot;We will end up with 54 tournaments every year, but very cheap ones. It's not right. As I have said in the past many times, I want quality not quantity.&quot;</p>
<p>The greens at the Northampton course have been in atrocious condition this week.</p>
<p>Ian Woosnam called them &quot;the worst I've ever played on&quot; and Colin Montgomerie said the entire field had come close to walking out.</p>
<p>Thirteen players made early exits for one reason or another, but Ballesteros described their action as &quot;a bit anti-professional&quot;.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I want to see courses set up tougher and in better condition, but this is what we have and we must play with what we have. Walking out is a pity as it gives a poor impression to the new sponsors.</p>
<p>&quot;But to be honest, the problem is ours (the players). We must sit down, select the committee and say how we want the Tour to be run.</p>
<p>&quot;When we complain in little groups in bars, cafeterias and locker rooms, nothing happens. I have fought by myself many times already, but maybe we will all meet soon.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just this week. Last week was also embarrassing.&quot; Ballesteros had criticised the German Open course at Stuttgart for being too easy as the halfway cut came at five-under-par.</p>
<p>The European Tour are joint owners of Collingtree Park with Mark McCormack's International Management Group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHAMPTON, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
