<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25730" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-PAKISTAN SUFFER ONE-DAY THRASHING.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-PAKISTAN SUFFER ONE-DAY THRASHING.</headline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, England 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fine century from opener Nick Knight and an impressive bowling debut from Adam Hollioake helped England thrash Pakistan by 107 runs on Saturday to take an unbeatable 2-0 lead in the one-day series between the sides.</p>
<p>Knight, on his home ground at Edgbaston, hit 113 as England built on a fast start to pile up a formidable total of 292 for eight.</p>
<p>Pakistan lost two wickets early in their reply and were bowled out for 185 in the 38th over, Surrey all-rounder Hollioake taking four for 23 on his first international appearance.</p>
<p>The final match of the series takes place at Trent Bridge on Sunday, but England have already gained some consolation for their emphatic 2-0 test series defeat against Wasim Akram's side.  </p>
<p>England's much-changed side, picked specifically with one-day cricket in mind, played with a confidence which contrasted totally with their demeanour after their third test collapse at the Oval last Monday.</p>
<p>Knight and Alec Stewart set the tone with a superb century opening stand inside 13 overs despite the tourists' formidable new-ball attack comprising Wasim and Waqar Younis.</p>
<p>A straight driven six from Stewart against off-spinner Saqlain Mushtaq ensured the second 50 took only 25 deliveries and, although Stewart and Michael Atherton then fell to Mushtaq Ahmed in the space of three balls, Knight kept the momentum going.</p>
<p>By the time he was cleverly stumped by Moin Khan off Saqlain, his 113 had occupied only 132 balls and included 11 boundaries, but three run-outs meant England were grateful to all-rounder Ronnie Irani who hit 45 not out.</p>
<p>Pakistan's reply was in trouble the moment Aamir Sohail miscued an attempted pull in the first over and Alan Mullally trapped Moin lbw in the next with the total on six.</p>
<p>Saeed Anwar hit a sparkling 33 off 25 balls in a 48-run partnership with Ijaz Ahmed in seven overs as Pakistan took advantage of the fielding restrictions.</p>
<p>But Anwar attempted one shot too many and became Darren Gough's second victim, caught behind by Stewart's diving catch, before Hollioake brushed aside the lower order.</p>
<p>Fittingly, man-of-the-match Knight claimed the final catch as England wrapped up victory with 12.1 overs remaining, giving their captain Atherton something to smile about for a change.</p>
<p>&quot;We deserved our victory...we thoroughly outplayed them today,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
