<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25736" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-KNIGHT SLAMS FIRST ONE-DAY INTERNATIONAL CENTURY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KNIGHT SLAMS FIRST ONE-DAY INTERNATIONAL CENTURY.</headline>
<dateline>BIRMINGHAM, England 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opener Nick Knight struck his first one-day international century to power England to 292 for eight in the second 50 overs match against Pakistan at Edgbaston on Saturday.</p>
<p>Knight stroked 113 off 132 balls and Alec Stewart smashed a rapid 46 to give England a whirlwind start in which they put on 103 for the first wicket in 14 overs after being put in to bat by Wasim Akram.</p>
<p>Pakistan recovered from the early mauling, with leg-spinner Mushtaq Ahmed taking two for 33 in his 10 overs, but they still faced a demanding target to level the three-match series after losing the opening game by five wickets at Old Trafford on Thursday.</p>
<p>Knight and Stewart, who plundered his 46 off 32 deliveries, shared a century partnership of such mounting authority that the second 50 took a mere 25 balls.</p>
<p>Stewart's last two scoring shots were sixes, the first over the extra cover boundary off paceman Ata-ur Rehman and the next was a sweetly-timed straight hit from the off-spin of Saqlain Mushtaq.</p>
<p>However, Mushtaq Ahmed's introduction for the 14th over checked England's exhilarating progress.</p>
<p>Stewart, trying to force square a ball too far up to him, was bowled, then captain Mike Atherton departed four balls later, lbw for one trying to turn to leg.</p>
<p>Knight, who completed his half-century in 47 balls with nine fours, then effectively assumed the anchor role until his fine innings, in only his second one-day international, ended in the 38th over when he was stumped off Saqlain. The Warwickshire opener hit 11 fours.</p>
<p>Ronnie Irani, with an unbeaten 45, did his best to sustain the momentum as three run outs to remove Matthew Maynard (1), debutant Adam Hollioake (15) and Darren Gough (0) put the brake on England's advance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BIRMINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
