<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25734" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN STAYS FASTEST AHEAD OF SAN MARINO GP.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN STAYS FASTEST AHEAD OF SAN MARINO GP.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>IMOLA, Italy 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>World champion Michael Doohan, hoping to win the 500th 500cc motorcycling grand prix on Sunday, remained the fastest rider at Imola on Saturday as steady rain dampened final qualifying.</p>
<p>The Australian, who could clinch his third consecutive world crown if he wins and closest rival Alex Criville of Spain finishes out of the points, clocked the best lap of one minute 50.250 seconds on a dry track on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's only a Friday time, it really doesn't mean a great deal,&quot; said Doohan. He will take Honda's winning streak to nine in a row if he triumphs.</p>
<p>&quot;I really enjoy the layout, it's really very different to what I suppose you would call a modern-day circuit. It's classical and a little dangerous, especially in the wet.&quot;</p>
<p>The circuit near Bologna has not hosted a race since 1988 and was redesigned after Formula One world champion Ayrton Senna and Austrian Roland Ratzenberger died during the San Marino Grand Prix meeting in 1994.</p>
<p>Doohan said the track would be perfect if it were resurfaced, eradicating the bumps that made qualifying a tricky business on both Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>No other rider managed to improve on Friday's times as local hero Luca Cadalara entertained the bedraggled fans with the day's best of 2:08.643.</p>
<p>The bad weather meant France's Jean-Michel Bayle stayed second ahead of Japan's Norifumi Abe and Cadalora.</p>
<p>Criville, who crashed heavily on Friday morning and rode with an inflamed wrist in official qualifying later in the day, was on the second row of the grid in fifth place.</p>
<p>He said he had injections to control the swelling and applied an ice pack to his wrist every two hours overnight. The Spaniard missed Saturday's morning free practice but went out in the afternoon to make sure he could handle the bike.</p>
<p>&quot;We lost time working on the suspension fittings and I was also hoping to try another tyre,&quot; he said. &quot;I am looking for a good race but will not be 100 percent fit.&quot;</p>
<p>Bayle's position continued the former motocross world champion's remarkable improvement -- at least in qualifying -- this season after a tough baptism to the sport.</p>
<p>The Frenchman, who was quickest in qualifying two weeks ago in the Czech Republic, moved up to 500cc this season with Kenny Roberts' Yamaha team after a poor spell in 250cc.</p>
<p>&quot;We felt that Jean-Michel was wasting his time in 250 racing,&quot; said Roberts. &quot;We don't know where he's going and we don't know that he'll be world champion but he's certainly capable of riding a motorcycle.</p>
<p>&quot;People say that he's good at qualifying. Well, this is his first year on a 500 and he's out-qualified a lot of people that are veterans,&quot; added the former 500cc champion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SMARNO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IMOLA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
