<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25741" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CYCLING-WOMEN'S PURSUIT WORLD RECORD SMASHED THREE TIMES.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-WOMEN'S PURSUIT WORLD RECORD SMASHED THREE TIMES.</headline>
<dateline>MANCHESTER, England 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The women's 3,000 metres world record was broken three times in pursuit qualifying at the world track cycling championships on Saturday.</p>
<p>Olympic champion Antonella Bellutti of Italy finally reduced the mark to three minutes 31.526 seconds.</p>
<p>Earlier, Lucy Tyler-Sharman of Australia and Marion Clignet of France had also bettered the old record of 3:31.924 set by Bellutti in Cali, Colombia in April.</p>
<p>Tyler-Sharman clocked 3:31.830 and 10 minutes later Clignet improved the time to 3:31.674.</p>
<p>Clignet had an even briefer reign as world record-holder for Bellutti was next on the track. She had a slower start than Clignet, but finished strongly to reach the quarter-finals to be held later on Saturday as the fastest qualifier.</p>
<p>Bellutti, a former athlete who switched to cycling only two years ago, is bidding for her first world title after taking the silver medal at Bogota, Colombia, last year.</p>
<p>Five world records have now been set during the first four days of racing on the 250-metres indoor track.</p>
<p>Britain's Chris Boardman's had two record-breaking rides in the men's 4,000 metres individual pursuit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
