<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25748" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-REBROV GIVES UKRAINE WINNING WORLD CUP START.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-REBROV GIVES UKRAINE WINNING WORLD CUP START.</headline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Substitute Sergei Rebrov scored a late goal to give Ukraine the result they desperately needed as they opened their tough group nine World Cup qualfying account with a 1-0 win over Northern Ireland on Saturday.</p>
<p>Rebrov delivered the killer blow in the 79th minute when he rose above two defenders to head home a cross from Victor Skrypnyk. Goalkeeper Alan Fettis, who had produced a string of superb saves, got a hand to the ball but was unable to prevent it going into the net.</p>
<p>With only one team qualifying automatically from the group for the 1998 finals in France it was an important victory for Ukraine but a disastrous one for Northern Ireland. The other teams in the group are Germany, Portugal, Albania and Armenia.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland felt they should have been awarded a goal when goalkeeper Aleksandr Shovtovski spilled a shot from Michael Gray.</p>
<p>Although Shovtovski managed to retrieve the situation by scooping the ball away at the second attempt the ball looked to have gone over the line but French referee Alain Sars signalled for a corner, waving away furious Irish protests.</p>
<p>Keith Gillespie was also out of luck, beating the keeper with a superb chip only for Sergei Popov to scramble back and head the ball off the line.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
