<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25746" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-HUGHES AND SAUNDERS HELP WALES WIN 6-0.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HUGHES AND SAUNDERS HELP WALES WIN 6-0.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strikers Dean Saunders and Mark Hughes scored two goals each as Wales crushed San Marino 6-0 in a World Cup qualifier in Cardiff on Saturday.</p>
<p>Saunders, back in the English premier league with Nottingham Forest after a spell in Turkey, opened the scoring after 82 seconds when Manchester United winger Ryan Giggs put him through on goal.</p>
<p>Hughes, who plays for Chelsea, headed home Wales's second 24 minutes later and Andy Melville and John Robinson both scored before the interval to give Bobby Gould's side a 4-0 halftime cushion.</p>
<p>Hughes and Saunders scored a goal apiece after the break as the Welsh went one goal better than their 5-0 victory over San Marino's part-timers in their first group seven World Cup clash in June.</p>
<p>Both players were denied hat-tricks by the woodwork in the closing stages of the match, and Saunders missed a penalty.</p>
<p>The only frustration for Wales was the referee's decision to book Giggs, which means he will miss the next World Cup match against the Dutch.</p>
<p>Giggs sarcastically clapped San Marino's Bryan Gasperoni for over-reacting to a challenge. The referee appeared to believe he was the target of the sarcasm and reached for the yellow card.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very, very bad news,&quot; Welsh captain Barry Horn said. &quot;Our first three goals all came from Ryan's passes. (The booking) was a bad decision.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SMARNO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
