<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25750" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-HILL'S FUTURE AT WILLIAMS HANGS IN BALANCE.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-HILL'S FUTURE AT WILLIAMS HANGS IN BALANCE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Damon Hill's future in Formula One motor racing appeared in doubt on Saturday amid rumours he would be replaced in the championship-winning Williams team next year by Germany's Heinz-Harald Frentzen.</p>
<p>&quot;Damon Hill is in pretty desperate straits,&quot; a reliable source within the sport told Reuters. &quot;It seems his talks with Williams have broken down. He has started talking to several other teams about next season.&quot;</p>
<p>The source said Hill, currently leading the drivers' championship from team mate Jacques Villeneuve, had approached the Jordan and Stewart teams, and has also been linked with the McLaren stable.</p>
<p>A second source in Germany said Williams had already offered Frentzen -- currently with the low-profile Swiss team Sauber-Ford -- a driver's berth for the 1997 season.</p>
<p>Hill's manager, solicitor Michael Breen, declined to comment on the rumours but has organised a news conference in London on Sunday to clarify the situation.</p>
<p>Hill, who leads the championship by 13 points with three races of the season to go, remained at his Dublin home and declined to comment, as did the Williams team.</p>
<p>Williams have developed a reputation for ditching successful drivers.</p>
<p>Brazilian Nelson Piquet left them in 1987 after winning the drivers' crown, Briton Nigel Mansell fell out with the team in 1992 after taking the title, and Frenchman Alain Prost quit in 1993 after a row about the choice of his driving partner.</p>
<p>Piquet joined Lotus, Mansell went to American Indycar racing and Prost retired from the sport.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
