<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25783" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: SQUASH-HILL BRANDS WORLD CHAMPION JANSHER A CHEAT.</title>
<headline>SQUASH-HILL BRANDS WORLD CHAMPION JANSHER A CHEAT.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Controversial Australian Anthony Hill called Jansher Khan a cheat during his acrimonious defeat by the world number one in the Hong Kong Open semifinals on Saturday.</p>
<p>The match boiled over when Hill made to walk off court after what he claimed was a game-winning point in the third.</p>
<p>When the referee called Jansher's return good and the decision was accepted by the player, Hill shrieked at the Pakistani: &quot;You cheat.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He was standing right there and knew the shot was down so I called him a cheat,&quot; said Hill, whose squash career has been blighted by fines and suspensions for unacceptable behaviour.</p>
<p>&quot;He knew it was down and accepted what I called him because of that.&quot;</p>
<p>Hill won the game on the next point and said later that Jansher was generally honest on court but played by the referee's decision.</p>
<p>The Australian had upset Jansher's rhythm with his mixture of gamesmanship and fluent stroke-making but eventually succumbed 15-7 17-15 14-15 15-8.</p>
<p>&quot;I changed my strategy against him today and had him rattled,&quot; he added. He is not as fit as he used to be be but was too good for me in the end. I shook him a bit but he will come out next time and be a better player for it -- that's Jansher.&quot;</p>
<p>Jansher said that he was disturbed to be called a cheat. &quot;What he did was bad for squash, bad for the crowd and bad for the sponsors.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to build up squash like tennis and players should not say things like that.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Professional Squash Association should look into this matter and deal with it properly. I am not calling for him to be banned but they have to take some action.&quot;</p>
<p>Jansher, bidding for an eighth Hong Kong Open title, plays second-seeded Australian Rodney Eyles in the final.</p>
<p>Eyles played his best squash of the tournament to beat fourth-seeded Peter Nicol of Scotland 15-10 8-15 15-10 15-4.</p>
<p>Eyles, who defeated Jansher in the semifinals of the Portuguese Open in 1993, said that he would like to win for the good of the game.</p>
<p>&quot;I have nothing against Jansher but it will be great if I could beat him,&quot; said Eyles. &quot;My biggest problem against Jansher is concentration. I want to beat him so badly that I just cannot get it together.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
