<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25789" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SPAIN, U.S. TEAMS OPEN ON ROAD FOR 1997 FED CUP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SPAIN, U.S. TEAMS OPEN ON ROAD FOR 1997 FED CUP.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>This year's Fed Cup finalists -- defending champion Spain and the United States -- will hit the road to open the 1997 women's international team competition, based on the draw conducted Saturday at the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>Spain travels to Belgium, while the U.S. team heads to the Netherlands for first-round matches March 1-2. The other two first-round ties will pit hosts Germany against the Czech Republic and visiting France against Japan.</p>
<p>The semifinals are July 19-20, and the final September 27- 28.</p>
<p>Life on the road this year did not slow the Americans, who will try to avenge their 3-2 defeat in the final last year when they host Spain on September 28-29 in Atlantic City.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year we stood on the court after we had lost and we put out hands together and made it our committment to bring back the Cup,&quot; U.S. captain Billie Jean King said at the draw. &quot;That is our sole goal.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States edged Austria in Salzburg 3-2 in the opening round in April, and then blanked Japan 5-0 in Nagoya last month in the semifinals.</p>
<p>The victory against Japan marked the Fed Cup debut of Monica Seles, who became a naturalised U.S. citizen in 1994. Seles easily won both her singles matches and King is counting on the co-world number one to lead the team again.</p>
<p>&quot;I told Monica we need her if we want to win,&quot; King said.</p>
<p>Seles's sore left shoulder and a wrist injury to Fed Cup veteran Mary Joe Fernandez have forced King to take a wait and see attitude regarding her squad for the best-of-five match. Fernandez was forced to withdraw from the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>&quot;We will wait until the last minute so we check with everybody and their injuries,&quot;said King. &quot;What we like would be Seles, (Olympic champion Lindsay) Davenport and Mary Joe Fernandez.&quot;</p>
<p>If she can get that threesome together, King will feel good about her chances against the Spain's formidable duo of Arantxa Sanchez Vicario and Conchita Martinez.</p>
<p>&quot;To be a great coach you have to have the right horses and I got the right horses,&quot; said King.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
