<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25788" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-CHANG SURVIVES HIS CLIFFHANGER AT U.S. OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHANG SURVIVES HIS CLIFFHANGER AT U.S. OPEN.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Chang, following the precarious path of fellow-favourites Pete Sampras and Andre Agassi, survived his own cliffhanger episode at the U.S. Open on Saturday to win a five-set thriller on Stadium Court.</p>
<p>The second-seeded Chang was down two sets to one, with fellow-American Vince Spadea serving for the match at 5-4 when he shook himself free of self-doubts and won 11 points in a row as he pounded his way to a 6-4 5-7 2-6 7-5 6-3 victory.</p>
<p>Chang's close call mirrored the harrowing experiences of two of the field's other most prominent contenders.</p>
<p>Top-seeded defending champion Sampras had to go five draining sets to beat stubborn Czech Jiri Novak on Friday. The day before, Agassi plunged to a 3-6 0-4 deficit before climbing back to beat Indian Leander Paes.</p>
<p>&quot;I was definitely in a hole down there,&quot; Chang said about the onslaught he faced from Spadea, who challenged him from the net and cracked blistering winners from both flanks in a gutsy performance under a blazing sun at the National Tennis Centre.</p>
<p>&quot;I just tried to do my best. I was really tired in the fifth set. I just tried to hang tough.&quot;</p>
<p>Very few players can hang as tough as Chang, who took a 16-2 summer hardcourt record into the Open.</p>
<p>Both players were obviously exhausted by the end of the three hour 50 minute struggle but the indominatable Chang proved fitter as he improved his career record in five-set matches to 18-8.</p>
<p>&quot;He was moving well and I was a little tight,&quot; said the 22-year-old Spadea, ranked 69. &quot;I was obviously getting a little fatigued out there.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I was trying to serve the match out and that's difficult to do even if you're playing the match out in Central Park,&quot; he said. &quot;He makes you work for each ball.&quot;</p>
<p>Also joining Chang into the fourth round were 13th seed Thomas Enqvist of Sweden and France's Arnaud Boetsch.</p>
<p>Enqvist advanced with a 6-4 6-4 6-2 victory over Pablo Campana of Ecuador, while Boetsch reached the round of 16 by beating American Jeff Tarango 6-4 6-2 7-6 (8-6).</p>
<p>Steffi Graf led an orderly procession of women's seeds into the fourth round. The top-seeded defender rallied from a sluggish start to beat Natasha Zvereva 6-4 6-2 for her 16th victory without a loss to the Belarussian.</p>
<p>Seventh seed Jana Novotna of the Czech Republic beat American Tami Whitlinger-Jones 6-2 6-3, 16th-seeded teenager Martina Hingis of Switzerland defeated Japan's Naoko Kijimuta 6- 2 6-2 and number 17 Karina Habsudova of Slovakia prevailed 6-2 6-3 over Austrian Sandra Dopfer.</p>
<p>Other advancers included Austrian Judith Wiesner, the first-round conqueror of fifth seed Iva Majoli, and Italy's Rita Grande.  </p>
<p>Spadea, a winner of six national junior titles by the age of 14, looked invincible for a long stretch after dropping the first set to Chang, who helped his opponent look good with a pitifully poor 35 percent success rate on his first serves.</p>
<p>Despite his grace and grit on court in pulling off the courageous comeback, Chang was hurting after the match. He did not sit down during his post-match interview for fear of cramping.</p>
<p>&quot;To be honest, I don't really know how I was able to win today's match,&quot; he said. &quot;He was covering the net like he was Stefan Edberg. He was playing great all-court tennis.&quot;</p>
<p>Spadea reached the fourth round of the Open last year with a victory over this year's French Open champion, Russian Yevgeny Kafelnikov, and looked at first as if he would be making an unlikely return visit.</p>
<p>He broke Chang in the opening game of the fourth set and nursed the advantage until the second seed leveled it at 4-4. But Spadea broke right back as he pressured Chang's second serve and grabbed a 5-4 lead to serve for the match.</p>
<p>That is when Chang turned it up another notch.</p>
<p>Whipping deep groundstroke drives from both sides, he broke at love and then held at love to seize a 6-5 lead. Spadea netted an ill-advised drop shot try from the baseline to lose his serve and the set in the next game.</p>
<p>The final set was also a struggle. Chang broke in the second game but Spadea matched him in the next. The second seed finally took his winning edge with another service break in the sixth game.</p>
<p>&quot;I was in control of the match, it was my match to win,&quot; said a sombre Spadea. &quot;I was the better player in the third and the fourth sets.</p>
<p>&quot;But in a Grand Slam it's three out of five sets.&quot;  </p>
<p>:</p>
<p>Later, Agassi took a calmer route to the fourth round with a 6-4 6-2 7-6 (9-7) win over Dutchman Jan Siemerink.</p>
<p>David Wheaton, a one-time Wimbledon semifinalist, won a third-round match against fellow Stanford University standout Alex O'Brien.</p>
<p>O'Brien, a former collegiate champion who won his first pro title two weeks ago in New Haven, fell 1-6 7-5 6-1 6-2.</p>
<p>The day's most scintillating finish belonged to Spain's Javier Sanchez, who saved four consecutive match points from 2-6 in the fifth-set tiebreaker, winning the last six points in all to beat Australian Jason Stoltenberg 6-4 3-6 4-6 6-2 7-6.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
