<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25786" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-CHANG SHOWS THE HEART OF A LION YET AGAIN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-CHANG SHOWS THE HEART OF A LION YET AGAIN.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Chang put tennis's biggest heart on display yet again at the U.S. Open on Saturday by playing with a never-say-die desire that is his most potent weapon.</p>
<p>The second-seeded Chang turned back the spirited challenge of unseeded Vince Spadea, who served for the match at 5-4 in the fourth set only to be broken at love. Chang survived 6-4 5-7 2-6 7-5 6-3 to reach the fourth round.</p>
<p>&quot;A match as tough as today's is just not over until that last point is hit,&quot; Chang said of the three hour, 50 minute epic.</p>
<p>&quot;Vince knows that I'm not going to give it to him. If he's able to come out and hit great shots and beat me, then he's too good.&quot;</p>
<p>For nearly four sets, the 22-year-old Spadea was too good, but Chang never surrendered.</p>
<p>&quot;If I'm down in a match I don't count myself out. I think that's very important for me. If I count myself out mentally, I'm going to lose for sure,&quot; said Chang, who won 12 of the last 14 points in the fourth set to force a decisive fifth set.</p>
<p>&quot;For me it's just going out and not worrying about the situation, not being absorbed by it,&quot; Chang said of his mindset in the final games of the fourth set.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just going out and playing each point, because you know points turn into games, games turn into sets, sets turn into matches.&quot;</p>
<p>More often than not, that philosophy has turned Chang into a winner. In five-set matches Chang has a career record of 18-8.</p>
<p>&quot;He is going to make you work for every ball,&quot; said Spadea. &quot;He's going to make you hit the shots at 6-6 and 5-5 that you hit at 1-0, when you're feeling a little bit different emotionally.&quot;</p>
<p>The 24-year-old Chang says he gets his will to win from his mother.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I probably get it more from my mom that anybody else because my mom is an incredibly competitive person,&quot; Chang said of his mother Betty, who regularly sits at courtside for  his big matches.</p>
<p>&quot;She's just one never to give up. If you tell her she can't do it, she'll go and try, try till she proves you wrong. In many ways, that's the way I am.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to give yourself the hope of coming back.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
