<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25793" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SOCCER-MOORE SCORES TWICE AS U.S. BEAT EL SALVADOR 3-1.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MOORE SCORES TWICE AS U.S. BEAT EL SALVADOR 3-1.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forward Joe-Max Moore scored twice and Eric Wynalda, the U.S. national team's leading scorer, added another goal as the United States beat El Salvador 3-1 in an international soccer friendly on Friday.</p>
<p>Moore scored his 13th and 14th international scores and Wynalda his 25th.</p>
<p>Moore opened the scoring in the third minute after collecting a John Harkes through ball at the top of the penalty area.</p>
<p>He dribbled past one defender before slamming a 12-metres shot past goalkeeper Alvaro Sanchez into the low left corner. He closed the scoring in the 88th minute, converting a penalty kick after Frankie Hejduk was dragged down in the penalty box.</p>
<p>El Salvador tied the match at 1-1 in the 59th minute when Luis Lazo ran onto a bouncing ball in the left side of the penalty box and bent a hard shot around U.S. goalkeeper Brad Friedel into the upper right corner.</p>
<p>Wynalda tallied the game winner just two minutes later. Cobi Jones's cross from the right side was flicked on by Brian McBride and Wynalda's sliding volley put the Americans ahead to stay.</p>
<p>The United States will open the first round of World Cup qualifying on November 3 in Washington, D.C., against Guatemala. The Americans will play six games in seven weeks in the first raund, home and away against Guatemala, Trinidad &amp; Tobago and Costa Rica.</p>
<p>Lineups:</p>
<p>U.S. - Brad Friedel, Jeff Agoos, Alexi Lalas, Paul Caligiuri, John Harkes (Mike Sorber 64th), Joe-Max Moore, Tab Ramos, Jason Kreis (Roy Lassiter 46th), Cobi Jones (Miles Joseph 89th), David Wagner (Brian McBride 46th), Eric Wynalda (Frankioe Hejduk 64th)</p>
<p>El Salvador - Alvaro Sanchez, William Osorio, Leonel Batres, Jorge Rodriguez, Carlos Castro, Jorge Rivera (William Renderos 82nd), Raul Diaz Arce (Marlon Menjivar 70th), Ronald Cerritos, Mauricio Cienfuegos (Marlon Medrando 65th), Luis Lazo (Nelson Quintanilla 86th), Wilfredo Sanabria</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ELSAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
