<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25790" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-GRAF GETS ANGRY TO GET INTO GEAR FOR ZVEREVA.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-GRAF GETS ANGRY TO GET INTO GEAR FOR ZVEREVA.</headline>
<byline>Larry Fine</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steffi Graf used a disputed line call to help get herself in gear Saturday and then roared off to a 6-4 6-2 victory to reach the round of 16 at the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>The top-seeded defending champion carried a 15-0 career record into her third-round match against Natasha Zvereva but was broken by the Belarussian in the opening game and struggled to get untracked under the bright sun on Stadium Court.</p>
<p>Umpire Andreas Egli of Switzerland did the top-ranked German a favour by overruling a linesman and calling a Graf shot out that gave Zevereva, serving at 4-3, a 40-15 lead in the eighth game.</p>
<p>&quot;It probably helped get me more aggressive,&quot; said the usually impassive Graf, who was visibly angered by the ruling.</p>
<p>&quot;The umpire said he saw a clear space, yet it was on the opposite side of the court,&quot; said Graf. &quot;I was close to saying, 'You should be happy you have a clear space between me'.&quot;</p>
<p>Graf took her frustration out on Zvereva. She hit a backhand crosscourt winner to save one game point, got to deuce and then unleashed a forehand crosscourt winner to break serve.</p>
<p>After holding serve at 30, Graf won the first three points off Zvereva's serve in the 10th game for triple set point and claimed the set two points later on a double fault.</p>
<p>&quot;She can play great games and then have lapses in between,&quot; Graf said. &quot;So you know you're going to get your chances.&quot;</p>
<p>Now in full stride, Graf won the first four games of the second set on her way to a 58-minute victory and a berth in the fourth round, where she was joined by two other fast finishers.</p>
<p>Martina Hingis of Switzerland, the 16th seed, matched Graf minute-for-minute in beating Japan's Naoko Kijimuta 6-2 6-2, while Austrian Judith Wiesner needed only 49 minutes to beat Czech Petra Langrova.</p>
<p>Graf faces the winner of the night match between 14th seed Barbara Paulus and 15-year-old Russian Anna Kournikova, with Hingis likely to meet third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario, who plays Russian Elena Likhovtseva on the grandstand.</p>
<p>Wiesner, who upset fifth seed Iva Majoli in the opening round, has her fourth-round opponent -- Rita Grande of Italy, a 7-5 6-1 winner over Els Callens of Belgium.</p>
<p>On the men's side, 13th seed Thomas Enqvist of Sweden became the first player into the fourth round by storming past Pablo Campana of Ecuador 6-4 6-4 6-2.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
