<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25802" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-DUTCH SCRAMBLE DRAW WITH LAST MINUTE PENALTY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DUTCH SCRAMBLE DRAW WITH LAST MINUTE PENALTY.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Netherlands needed a last minute penalty, converted by substitute Jean Paul van Gastel, to salvage a 2-2 draw against World Cup holders Brazil in a soccer friendly on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Dutch, captained for the first time by Frank de Boer, had the best of the early play, but it was Brazil who broke the deadlock after 14 minutes through Giovanni.</p>
<p>Finding himself unmarked on the edge of the six-yard area, the Barcelona striker slotted the ball past Edwin van der Sar's outstretched right hand.</p>
<p>Both teams had further chances in the first half but failed to convert them.  </p>
<p>The game's tempo picked up in the second half with Bergkamp looking increasingly dangerous around the box.</p>
<p>In the 52nd minute the Arsenal striker broke down the right wing and pulled the ball back for Ronald de Boer, who fired a low hard shot into the left-hand corner of the goal.</p>
<p>But the Dutch supporters, who only half-filled Ajax Amsterdam's big new stadium, had just three minutes in which to celebrate before Marcello Goncalves put the Brazilians ahead again with another close range goal.</p>
<p>The Brazilians looked on course for victory until Bergkamp was pulled down just inside the penalty area with seconds remaining.</p>
<p>After the Brazilian players' protests died down, second-half substitute van Gastel of Feyenoord stepped up and gave 'keeper Carlos Germano no chance with the spot kick.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
