<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25800" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SELES WASTES LITTLE TIME IN BEATING RANDRIANTEFY.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SELES WASTES LITTLE TIME IN BEATING RANDRIANTEFY.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following her own advice, second-seeded Monica Seles didn't waste any time in beating Dally Randriantefy of Madagascar to march into the fourth round of the U.S. Open on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't want to play around with night matches. You just want to finish and go home,&quot; Seles said after winning the first 11 games on her way to a 6-0 6-2 win under the National Tennis Centre stadium lights.</p>
<p>In fact, Seles has spent very little time this week actually on the court after losing just one game in her opening-round match and then winning her second-round match on Wednesday without hitting a single ball -- Laurence Courtois couldn't play due to an knee injury.</p>
<p>Seles welcomed having the extra days off to rest her ailing left shoulder.</p>
<p>&quot;You never want to win a match like that, but I just think of it as a positive way. I'll save my shoulder, one less match to play,&quot; said Seles, who faces the prospect of surgery after playing for the United States in next month's Fed Cup final against Spain.</p>
<p>Seles looked fit and in good form through the 57-minute win that filled out the bottom half of the fourth round women's pairings.</p>
<p>Seles, who is just one of three remaining seeds in that half, will next play Sandrine Testud of France.</p>
<p>Also getting through were eighth-seeded American Lindsay Davenport, the Olympic gold medallist, and fourth-seeded Spaniard Conchita Martinez.</p>
<p>Davenport, winner of her last two tournaments, beat Anne-Gaelle Sidot of France 6-0 6-3 for her 14th consecutive match win. Martinez beat veteran Czech Helena Sukova 6-4 6-3.</p>
<p>But crowd favourite Gabriela Sabatini, the 15th seed from Argentina, did not make it to her appointed spot in the final 16. The 1990 Open champion, who missed both the French Open and Wimbledon this year with a stomach injury, fell to unheralded Swede Asa Carlsson 7-5 3-6 6-2.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess that I have to accept that I lost,&quot; said Sabatini. &quot;It's going to be a little hard. This tournament is a big tournament for me. This is where I really wanted to do well.&quot;</p>
<p>Seles is also anxious to do well at the Open after having suffered unexpected early-round setbacks at the French Open and Wimbledon.</p>
<p>&quot;I definitely want to do well in the Grand Slams,&quot; said Seles, who had opened the year by winning the Australian Open for the fourth time. &quot;I think that at the end of my career those are the ones that I like to win, do the best I could in all of them.&quot;</p>
<p>But in her first full year back playing since her emotional return to competition last summer when she reached the U.S. Open final, the 22-year-old Seles has found that the winning hasn't come as easy as when she took seven of eight majors beginning with the 1991 Australian Open.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean, it's hard, the expectations sometimes with me are so high. It's hard to live up to what I was before,&quot; Seles said of her 27-month layoff after being stabbed in the back during a match in Hamburg on April, 30, 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be a matter of putting in those hours, that I used to put in before,&quot; said Seles. &quot;I feel I'm slowly coming back to where I should be, and hopefully will be.&quot;</p>
<p>This time Seles played as expected, rattling off 23 winners with her double-fisted groundstrokes to only six for her overmatched foe from Madagascar.</p>
<p>But the 104th ranked Randriantefy compensated for her lack of firepower with her fighting spirit as she never surrendered and won the respect of Seles, who joined in the applause for the 19-year-old as she left the court.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of players at 6-0, 5-0, they just stop,&quot; Seles said. &quot;She was running, almost played better. She figured, I have nothing to lose, match is almost finished, let me give it everything I have'.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
