<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25801" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-HENKE HOLDS LEAD IN MILWAUKEE, TIGER WOODS MAKES CUT. [CORRECTED 07:15 GMT 31/8]</title>
<headline>GOLF-HENKE HOLDS LEAD IN MILWAUKEE, TIGER WOODS MAKES CUT. [CORRECTED 07:15 GMT 31/8]</headline>
<dateline>MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nolan Henke shot a five-under-par 66 Friday (corrects day from Thursday) to maintain a two-stroke lead after the second round of the $1.2 million Greater Milwaukee Open, and Tiger Woods made the cut in his first tournament as a pro.</p>
<p>Duffy Waldorf, who tied for second at last week's World Series of Golf, shot his second 65 to climb into sole possession of second place at 12-under 130.</p>
<p>Mike Heinen, Loren Roberts, Jesper Parnevik of Sweden and Bob Estes were tied in third place at 11-under 131, three shots behind Henke. Heinen fired a 63, Roberts shot 65, Parnevik had a 66 and Estes posted a 67.</p>
<p>Henke, who has three career PGA Tour victories but none since the 1993 BellSouth Classic, followed his opening-round 62 with an eagle, four birdies and a bogey. His 14-under 128 fell three strokes short of the 36-hole tournament record.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Woods shot a two-under 69 for a two-round total of six-under 136.</p>
<p>Woods, who turned professional Tuesday after winning an unprecedented third successive Amateur Championship, collected four birdies with two bogeys. He played the back nine first and closed with a birdie on the par-four ninth hole to move to six under.</p>
<p>Defending champion Scott Hoch shot a four-under 67, but dropped seven shots behind at seven-under 135.</p>
<p>The top four on the PGA Tour money list -- Phil Mickelson, Mark Brooks, Tom Lehman and Mark O'Meara -- all skipped this event after last week's World Series of Golf, won by Mickelson.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
