<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25829" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Monthly Review - Life on Mars? Peace in Chechnya.</title>
<headline>Monthly Review - Life on Mars? Peace in Chechnya.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said it had found evidence of life on Mars and the conflict in Chechnya flared again in August, triggering more peace moves between Russia and separatist guerrillas.</p>
<p>The discovery of possible signs of primitive life on the mysterious red planet held awesome implications, if confirmed, President Bill Clinton said.</p>
<p>Chechen rebels stormed the capital Grozny in a five-day offensive that humiliated Russian troops. But after heavy fighting, Kremlin security chief Alexander Lebed was dispatched to the area and agreed a ceasefire effective from Aug 23, with a political settlewent still under discussion.</p>
<p>Here is a chronology of the main events of the month.</p>
<p>Aug 1 - Italian court throws out war crimes charges against former SS Captain Erich Priebke, but he is re-arrested the next day. Germany seeks his extraditon on the 12th.</p>
<p>Aug 1 - British agriculture ministry confirms that mad cow disease can be passed from cow to calf.</p>
<p>Aug 1 - Bishop Pierre Claverie is assassinated in Algeria hours after meeting French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette in Algiers.</p>
<p>Aug 2 - An Arkansas court clears two of President Clinton's political allies of fraud charges in the Whitewater affair.</p>
<p>Aug 2 - Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's hardline government ends a four-year freeze on settlement building.</p>
<p>Aug 3 - Denmark's defence chief, Admiral Hans Joergen Garde, is killed when his plane crashes on the Faroe Islands.</p>
<p>Aug 4 - Israel's Supreme Court rejects an appeal by convicted Yitzhak Rabin assassin Yigal Amir.</p>
<p>Aug 5 - President Clinton signs the Iran and Libya Sanctions Act, which punishes foreign firms that invest in energy projects in the two countries.</p>
<p>Aug 6 - Bosnian Moslems and Croats agree to an EU-mediated deal to form a local government in Mostar, paving the way for countrywide elections in September.</p>
<p>Aug 6 - Syria rejects Israeli Prime Minister Netanyahu's offer to resume peace talks on a &quot;Lebanon first&quot; basis.</p>
<p>Aug 6 - Chechen rebels storm the capital Grozny in their biggest offensive for months. They hold the city until the 11th when Russian troops break through their blockade.</p>
<p>Aug 6 - A team of U.S. scientists say they have discovered evidence of ancient life on Mars in remains from a meteorite founbd in Antarctica. President Clinton the next day pledged a big effort by the American space programme to confirm the discovery.</p>
<p>Aug 8 - At least 86 people die when a torrent of mud and rock sweeps over a crowded family campsite in the Pyrenees mountains of northern Spain.</p>
<p>Aug 9 - Boris Yeltsin takes the presidential oath for his second term in office.</p>
<p>Aug 10 - Bob Dole announces that former housing secretary Jack Kemp is his Republican vice-presidential running mate. Dole is formally chosen as presidential nominee on the 14th.</p>
<p>Aug 11 - A Greek Cypriot man is killed in clashes with Turkish Cypriots across the ceasefire line dividing the island. A second man is killed on Aug 14 when soldiers from the Turkish side fire on Greek Cypriot protesters.</p>
<p>Aug 12 - Iran and Turkey agree a huge gas supply deal worth $23 billion a week after a new U.S. law penalising foreign investment in Iran's energy sector.</p>
<p>Aug 12 - Afghan government announces a ceasefire with the forces of northern warlord General Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>Aug 12 - Bosnian Serbs bow to NATO pressure and agree to permit inspection of a key Serb military site at Han Pijesak.</p>
<p>Aug 14 - The National Party, architects of South African apartheid, moves to the opposition benches for the first time in 48 years.</p>
<p>Aug 14 - Gambia lifts a two-year ban on political activity in preparation for presidential elections, but on Aug 16 bans the three main political parties from taking part.</p>
<p>Aug 14 - President Yeltsin issues a decree giving his security supremo Alexander Lebed sweeping powers to settle the conflict with separatist rebels in Chechnya.</p>
<p>Aug 14 - North Korea hands over a South Korean novelist to Chinese authorities after detaining him for over two weeks for violating its border with China.</p>
<p>Aug 15 - Senior Bosnian officials sign an agreement to fully form the country's Moslem-Croat Federation and dismantle the self-styled Bosnian Croat republic of Herceg-Bosna.</p>
<p>Aug 16 - Leonel Fernandez becomes the 100th president of the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Aug 16 - Seven Russian civil pilots held hostage for more than a year by Islamic opposition militia in Afghanistan escape to the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>Aug 17 - West African leaders agree on a new timetable for disarming Liberian militia and for holding elections. They also choose Ruth Perry to chair the ruling council of state.</p>
<p>Aug 17 - The bodies of two eight-year-old child sex victims are unearthed in Belgium, a day after two others were rescued from a house owned by the man arrested for the murders.</p>
<p>Aug 18 - Two days of riots fuelled by the doubling of bread prices subside in the Jordanian town of Karak.</p>
<p>Aug 19 - Six cosmonauts from Russia, France and the U.S. meet aboard Russia's orbiting Mir space station after a Soyuz rocket docked with it.</p>
<p>Aug 20 - South Korean police storm a Seoul campus to end an occupation by students demanding reunification with the North.</p>
<p>Aug 20 - Pastor Antoine Leroy, a Haitian opposition leader and another member of his party, are assassinated by gunmen.</p>
<p>Aug 21 - At South Africa's &quot;Truth Commission&quot;, former president F.W. de Klerk apologises for human rights violations under white rule.</p>
<p>Aug 22 - The 61-nation Conference on Disarmament ends in failure after India blocks agreement on a Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty.</p>
<p>Aug 23 - Police storm a Paris church and evict 300 African migrants, ending their protest against moves to expel them from France.</p>
<p>Aug 23 - Croatia and Yugoslavia sign a mutual recognition accord, ending five years of hostility.</p>
<p>Aug 24 - Jordan orders three Iraqi officials to leave the country, accusing them of involvement in riots a week earlier.</p>
<p>Aug 25 - Israeli President Ezer Weizman says he, Prime Minister Netanyahu and Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai will meet Palestinian President Yasser Arafat within two weeks.</p>
<p>Aug 26 - A South Korean court sentences former president Chun Doo Hwan to death and his successor, Roh Tae-woo, to 22-1/2 years in prison on charges of masterminding a 1979 coup and an army massacre of pro-democracy demonstrators the following year.</p>
<p>Aug 26 - Fugitive U.S. financier Robert Vesco is found guilty of economic crimes by a Cuban court and sentenced to 13 years in jail.</p>
<p>Aug 27 - Armed Iraqis hijack a Sudanese Airbus 310 to London's Stansted airport where they release 199 passengers and crew and are taken into police custody.</p>
<p>Aug 28 - Princess Diana and Prince Charles are officially divorced.</p>
<p>Aug 28 - U.S. Democrats nominate President Clinton for a second term. The next day he accepts the nomination and launches his bid for a second term.</p>
<p>Aug 29 - Palestinians hold a strike in the West Bank, the first in two years, the day after Yasser Arafat says Israel declared war on Palestinians with more settlements.</p>
<p>Aug 29 - An airliner carrying Russian coal miners to the remote Arctic island of Spitzbergen crashes killing all 141 passengers and crew.</p>
<p>Aug 30 - Israel thwarts Palestinian President Arafat's call for a mass prayer protest at Jerusalem's al-Aqsa mosque by ringing the city with police and roadblocks.</p>
<p>Aug 30 - The Netherlands ends conscription after 187 years.</p>
<p>Aug 31 - Alexander Lebed and rebel military leader Aslan Maskhadov sign a deal four days after a truce was finalised and agree to defer the decision on whether Chechnya should be independent until December 31, 2001.</p>
<p>Aug 31 - Iraqi troops supported by tanks and heavy artillery fight their way into the Kurdish city of Arbil inside a U.N.-declared safe haven and raise the Iraqi flag. President Clinton puts U.S. forces in the Gulf on high alert.</p>
<p>Notable deaths in August included: Tadeus Reichstein, Swiss chemist whose Nobel prize-winning work led to the widespread use of Cortisone (1); General Mohamed Farah Aideed, scourge of U.S. and U.N. peacekeepers (Announced 2 Aug); Former French prime minister Michel Debre (2); Kiyoshi Atsumi, Japanese actor in the &quot;Tora-san&quot; series of films (4);</p>
<p>Abdulrahman Mohamed Babu, Tanzanian politician in the 1950's and 60's (5); Hernan Siles Zuazo, former Bolivian president (6); Frank Whittle, British inventor of the jet engine (8); Granny Vanga, Bulgaria's  most revered psychic (11); Rafael Kubelik, Czech-born conductor and composer (11); Sergiu Celibidache, Romanian-born orchestral conductor (14); Masao Maruyama, Japan's leading post-war political scientist (15); Rabbi Hugo Gryn, Auschwitz survivor and BBC Radio broadcaster (18); Sylvia Fisher, Australian opera singer (25); Alejandro Lanusse, former dictator of Argentina (26).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
