<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25823" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EUROPEAN BIKERS RIDE AGAINST TIGHTER EU LAWS.</title>
<headline>EUROPEAN BIKERS RIDE AGAINST TIGHTER EU LAWS.</headline>
<byline>Geert De Clercq</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of bikers from all over Europe rode past European Union buildings in Brussels on Saturday to protest against plans for tighter motorcycle laws.</p>
<p>If passed, the new EU laws will limit engine noise and make it illegal to change manufacturers' specifications, outlawing the customisation favoured by bike enthusiasts.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to stop our machines from making sound,&quot; Belgian Patricia Godelieve, owner of a Honda Shadow, told Reuters, screaming above the thundering noise of fellow bikers' machines.</p>
<p>&quot;This is my bike, this is how I like it,&quot; said Belgian Alain Barbieux, a poodle peeking out of his leather jacket. His 1400 cc customised Suzuki has an extended front-fork and extra-wide handlebars, his helmet is a non-authorized model.</p>
<p>Simon Milward, general secretary of the Federation of European Motorcyclists (one of the organisers of the demonstration) said that 15,000 bikers had attended the rally. Police estimated their number at 10,000.</p>
<p>Traffic in central Brussels was disrupted all afternoon by the demonstration.</p>
<p>Most of the bikers rode standard bikes, some had custom-made tanks or elongated front-forks, while a few two- or three- wheelers looked like they came straight out of a Mad Max-movie.</p>
<p>&quot;We are fighting for the right to wear what we want,&quot; said German biker Oliver Walter, straddling a standard 900 cc BMW and wearing a colourful racing suit. Walter said he was against plans to oblige all bikers to wear fluorescent clothes.</p>
<p>Another biker from Austria atop a very un-standard-looking black machine with two wheels said he just wanted to get rid of &quot;the damm helmet&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want (the EU bureaucrats) to tell us how we move about,&quot; French Harley-Davidson rider Jean-Marie Mignolet said.</p>
<p>A final decision on the new rules is expected in October after a meeting between the European Parliament and the EU's decision-making Council of Ministers.</p>
<p>The European Commission argues that the measures are needed on environmental and health grounds. &quot;We are not against motorcycles in principle,&quot; a spokeswoman said earlier.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G156">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
