<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25825" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Opposition says Iraqis advance in Kurdish north.</title>
<headline>Opposition says Iraqis advance in Kurdish north.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi opposition group in exile said on Saturday it had received reports that Iraqi forces were shelling and advancing on the Kurdish town of Arbil in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>A London-based spokesman of the Iraqi National Congress (INC) said Iraqi artillery was shelling the city and Iraqi tanks had moved to within 10 km (six miles) of Arbil, administrative centre of the Kurdish rebel-controlled region of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;At 4.50 a.m. Iraq time (0050 GMT) Iraqi forces began an artillery attack on the outskirts of Arbil,&quot; the INC spokesman, who asked not to be named, told Reuters in a telephone call.</p>
<p>&quot;Tanks are advancing towards the city of Arbil and are about 10 km (six miles) from the centre. Kurdish forces are defending the city,&quot; the spokesman said, adding that damage and casualties in Arbil were heavy.</p>
<p>He also said four Iraqi helicopter gunships had attacked the village of Sar Bashak, 25 km (15 miles) southwest of Arbil.</p>
<p>The Iraqi Broadcasting Corporation, linked to the INC, said in a statement the attacks continued at 6 a.m. (0200 GMT) and the Iraqi forces also shelled a gas refinery at Arbil.</p>
<p>In Washington, U.S. officials said they could not confirm the reports.</p>
<p>But the Washington representative of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK), Barham Salih, said he had received word from sources in Arbil that shelling had reached the city centre and Iraqi tanks were within five km (three miles) of the city 300 km (190 miles) north of the Iraqi capital Baghdad.</p>
<p>He said in a statement that villagers were fleeing the advancing army and &quot;urgent and decisive international response to counter the Iraqi onslaught is required to mitigate a humanitarian disaster in Iraqi Kurdistan&quot;.</p>
<p>A United Nations representative in Arbil, Mohsin Habib, told CNN television:</p>
<p>&quot;People from the villages are fleeing away and their houses have been destroyed -- that's what the people are saying. But who is shelling we could not confirm.</p>
<p>&quot;But heavy weapons are being used and it is closing very fast towards the city,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked if U.N. staff had seen any Iraqi troops, he said: &quot;No, negative, we have not seen any Iraqi army.&quot;</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Friday ordered the U.S. military to prepare for any possible action as Washington turned up the heat in the deepening crisis over Iraqi troop movements in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>U.S.-led air power has been protecting the Kurds in northern Iraq since shortly after Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's defeat in the 1991 Gulf War over Kuwait.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Iraq accused Iran of aggression and said it reserved the right to retaliate for Tehran's alleged deployment of troops into northern Iraq, where fighting broke out between the two main Iraqi Kurdish rebel groups on August 17.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said on Friday that Washington was monitoring Iraqi troop movements very carefully and consulting other members of the international community.</p>
<p>A U.S. official said the concerns were focused on the area around Arbil.</p>
<p>The Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) of Massoud Barzani has said that Iran sent troops and military equipment into northern Iraq in support of the guerrillas of its rival, the PUK led by Jalal Talabani.</p>
<p>The PUK said on Wednesday that Baghdad was massing troops near the Kurdish region for an attack. It said the Iraqi army's action reflected Baghdad's cooperation with the KDP.</p>
<p>Northern Iraq has been split into rival zones since large-scale fighting broke out between the two groups in 1994.</p>
<p>A U.S.-brokered ceasefire to end the latest round of fighting between KDP and PUK took effect on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
