<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26152" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ATHLETICS-THIRD TIME LUCKY FOR KOMEN AS HE BREAKS WORLD RECORD.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-THIRD TIME LUCKY FOR KOMEN AS HE BREAKS WORLD RECORD.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hanna</byline>
<dateline>RIETI, Italy 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Daniel Komen of Kenya made it third time lucky on Sunday when he shattered Noureddine Morceli's 3,000 metres world record by nearly five seconds at an international  meeting.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Kenyan, who failed to qualify for the Atlanta Olympics, clocked seven minutes 20.67 seconds, breaking Morceli's time of 7:25.11 set two years ago in Monte Carlo.</p>
<p>The Kenyan failed to qualify for the Olympics but has been on blistering form on the grand prix circuit since and was only 0.05 of a second outside Morceli's mark in Monaco last month.</p>
<p>He then clocked 7:25.87 at the Brussels grand prix on August 23, the third fastest time in history, with Morceli finishing well back in sixth place.</p>
<p>Kenyan David Kisang led the field through 1,000 metres in 2:25.89 before Komen took the lead, clocking 4:53.18 at the 2,000 mark and carrying on to finish more than 20 seconds ahead of his nearest rival.</p>
<p>Kenyas's Shem Kororia, was second in 7:43.17 with Italian Gennaro di Napoli third in 7:46.39.</p>
<p>Morceli, the Olympic and world 1,500 metres champion, said he would be back.</p>
<p>&quot;Komen is young and very good and deserves today's result,&quot; Morceli told reporters. &quot;I'm sure he has the means to do other things, but I've still got something to say.&quot;</p>
<p>Morceli, who holds the world 1,500 metre and mile records, comfortably won the 1,500 in 3:29.99 ahead of Burundi's Olympic 5,000 metres champion Venuste Niyongabo.</p>
<p>Kenyan-born Wilson Kipketer, who runs for Denmark, set the third fastest time in history in the 800 metres clocking one minute 41.83 seconds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIETI, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
