<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26154" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CYCLING-ROUSSEAU COMPLETES UNIQUE DOUBLE.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-ROUSSEAU COMPLETES UNIQUE DOUBLE.</headline>
<byline>Martin Ayres</byline>
<dateline>MANCHESTER, England 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florian Rousseau of France completed a unique double when he won the world sprint cycling championship on Sunday only five weeks after taking the Olympic gold medal in the 1-km time trial at Atlanta. </p>
<p>On the final day of the five-day championships, Rousseau defeated 1994 sprint champion Marty Nothstein of the United States 2-0 in the best-of-three final.</p>
<p>The Frenchman said: &quot;I didn't expect to win. The last time I beat Nothstein was two years ago at the Bercy track in Paris.&quot;</p>
<p>The American appeared to be drained by a three-race battle to overcome the defending champion Darryn Hill of Australia in the semifinals. </p>
<p>Hll crossed the line first in two matches but was relegated to second place for rough riding in the last 200 metres.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I got robbed, I always seem to get bad decisions against Marty. I'll be out to beat him in next year's worlds on my home track in Perth,&quot; he said. </p>
<p>After losing the final Nothstein said: &quot;I felt good thanks to my win in the keirin earlier in the series, but today I could not find my power. The motor was not there I was riding on pure heart and determination.&quot; </p>
<p>Marion Clignet completed a double for France, beating Lucy Tyler-Sharman of Australia in the women's individual pursuit final.  </p>
<p>Clignet, Tyler-Sharman and third-placed Antonella Bellutti all broke the world 3,000 metres record during the event.</p>
<p>Clignet has adopted the streamlined &quot;Superman&quot; riding style, developed last year by Britain's ex-world champion Graeme Obree.</p>
<p>&quot;It made an amazing difference, as much as four or five seconds, I got more power and did not move about so much on my bike,&quot; Clignet said. </p>
<p>A countback was needed to decide the 40-kms points race title, won by Rossello Llaneras of Spain from Michael Sandstod of Denmark.</p>
<p>Llaneras and Sandstod lapped the field with an early attack, and spent the rest of the race battling for sprint points. Neither rider succeeded in gaining an advantage and they finished level on 29 points.</p>
<p>Llaneras was awarded the gold medal, becoming the first Spanish winner of the title, thanks to scoring more lap wins than Sandstod. </p>
<p>Defending champion Silvio Martinello of Italy missed the breakaway and had to settle for the bronze medal, one lap in arrears, despite having the highest points score. </p>
<p>France, winners of this year's grand prix-style World Cup competition, confirmed their status  as the world's most successful track nation, winning four of the 12 championships here.</p>
<p>Italy and Australia took two each, with the rest going to Britain, Russia, Spain and the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANCHESTER, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
