<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26153" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ECUADOR: SOCCER-ECUADOR TAKE ANOTHER STEP TOWARDS FIRST WORLD CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ECUADOR TAKE ANOTHER STEP TOWARDS FIRST WORLD CUP.</headline>
<text>
<p>QUITO, Sept 1 (Ecuador) - Ecuador took another step towards their first World Cup when they beat Venezuela 1-0 on Sunday to record their third win in four qualifying games.</p>
<p>Captain Alex Aguinaga scored the winner in a game featuring the only two South American nations who have never played in the World Cup tournament.</p>
<p>Despite three more precious points, Ecuador were jeered off the field by a 45,000 crowd who had expected a higher score against South American's weakest team who have taken only one point from their four games so far.</p>
<p>Aguinaga snapped up a rebound following a shot by Brazilian-born Gilson de Souza in the fourth minute but Ecuador were unable to add to their tally.</p>
<p>Ecuador, coached by Colombia's former national team boss Francisco Maturana, have already beaten Argentina at home in their impressive start and have a good chance of finishing in the top four of the nine-team group.</p>
<p>But they still have a long way to go and questions were asked when they lost 4-1 defeat by Chile in Santiago last month on their only venture outside Ecuador so far.</p>
<p>Ecuador - Carlos Morales; Wagner Rivera, Ivan Hurtado, Maximo Tenorio, Luis Capurro; Jorge Diaz (Alfonso Obregon, 79th minute), Hector Carabali, Alex Aguinaga, Jose Garcia (Angel Fernandez, 46th); Gilson de Souza, Eduardo Hurtado.</p>
<p>Venezuela - Rafael Dudamel; Luis Filosa, William Gonzalez, Edson Tortolero, David Macintosh; Sergio Hernandez, Jess Valiente (Gabriel Urdaneta, 40th), Luis Vera, Gabriel Miranda; Juan Socorro (Luis Hernndez, 79th), Juan Garcia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ECUADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
