<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26167" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-KNIGHT HITS SECOND HUNDRED AS ENGLAND REACH 246 ALL OUT.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KNIGHT HITS SECOND HUNDRED AS ENGLAND REACH 246 ALL OUT.</headline>
<dateline>NOTTINGHAM, England 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warwickshire opener Nick Knight hit his second hundred in two days as England reached 246 all out from their 50 overs in the third one-day international against Pakistan at Trent Bridge on Sunday.</p>
<p>Knight, who scored his maiden test century in the recent series against the Pakistanis, hit a fine 113 in the second one-day match on Saturday.</p>
<p>On Sunday, though, he capped that and completed a superb weekend when he carried his bat for 125 not out from 145 balls.</p>
<p>Opening the innings, Knight played with brisk assurance despite seeing wickets fall regularly at the other end. </p>
<p>In the 42nd over he pushed the occasional left-arm spinner Asif Mujtaba through midwicket for two and punched the air in celebration. His century came from 120 balls and included nine fours.</p>
<p>Captain Mike Atherton, batting at number three, had to retire hurt on 14 when he was struck a painful blow on his right hand by Shahid Nazir's second delivery.</p>
<p>He went to hospital for an x-ray and then returned to the crease at the fall of the fifth wicket when Adam Hollioake hit a ball from Saqlain down Ijaz Ahmed's throat at deep midwicket.</p>
<p>Atherton went on to make 30 from 48 balls before he holed out a delivery from Wasim to Nazir at mid-off.</p>
<p>Otherwise England's batsmen failed to capitalise on good starts. After the early dismissal of Alec Stewart, caught and bowled by Wasim Akram, Matthew Maynard (24), Graham Lloyd (15) and Hollioake (13) all got themselves in but were unable to go on.</p>
<p>Maynard was beautifully bowled by Nazir, who later removed Ronnie Irani for a duck in the same fashion, and Lloyd skied a leading edge to Shadab Kabir as he tried to clip Saqlain over midwicket.</p>
<p>Wasim put in two excellent spells to finish with three for 45 from his 10 overs and he also ran out Peter Martin off his own bowling.</p>
<p>England lead the three-match series 2-0.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOTTINGHAM, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
