<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26169" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS END NEGOTIATIONS TO RETAIN HILL.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS END NEGOTIATIONS TO RETAIN HILL.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Collings</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>World championship-leading Briton Damon Hill will leave the Williams motor racing team at the end of this season, it was confirmed on Sunday.</p>
<p>Team owner Frank Williams said in a brief statement: &quot;I can confirm that the Williams-Renault team will not be using Damon Hill's services in 1997. His replacement will be made known in due course.&quot;</p>
<p>Hill's manager and lawyer Michael Breen told a news conference in London that the Williams team had ended contract discussions with the 35-year-old Englishman abruptly last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Breen said both he and Hill were surprised and disappointed by the news.</p>
<p>Sources in Germany and Britain told Reuters on Saturday and again on Sunday that Hill's seat with the championship-winning team had already been filled for next season by rising German star Heinz-Harald Frentzen.</p>
<p>Frentzen, currently with Sauber, has not won a Grand Prix but is believed to be a driver of potential who is admired by many Germans. It is thought that Williams are keen to use German BMW engines in 1998 when their current deal with Renault ends.</p>
<p>The news that Hill was effectively being dumped by Williams in the season when he is expected to win his first drivers' championship stunned many observers but left hardened veterans in Formula One recalling the Williams teams' handling of many similar situations in the past.</p>
<p>In 1992, Briton Nigel Mansell secured the drivers' championship before being replaced in the team by Frenchman Alain Prost. Prost himself won the title in 1993 only to find he was being replaced the following season by Brazilian Ayrton Senna.</p>
<p>Breen pointed to Hill's excellent record with Williams which has included 20 Grand Prix victories, 19 fastest laps and 18 pole positions. &quot;Those facts speak for themselves and I am sure that many team owners will be interested in taking him on,&quot; said Breen.</p>
<p>It seemed certain that Frentzen was approached at the same time as Hill was told his agreement with Williams was little more than a formality.</p>
<p>Breen said he had received many calls from interested parties and stressed that Hill still had &quot;a lot to offer in Formula One racing,&quot; because he was both an outstanding racing driver and a first-class test and development driver.</p>
<p>Hill now looks likely to move to the Peugeot-powered Jordan team on a two-year contract but may also interest newcomers Stewart Grand Prix, owned by his father's old friend Jackie Stewart.</p>
<p>Breen said Hill was as disappointed for the team as he was for himself as they had been together for six years and he wanted to defend his title in a Williams with a number one on the nose of his car.</p>
<p>Breen said: &quot;To set the record straight, we only began negotiations with Frank Williams in mid-August. Obviously, there were several points put on the table.</p>
<p>&quot;On Wednesday, Frank called to withdraw from discussing Damon's contract any further, giving no reason for his decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Breen gave the clear impression that he believed there were no financial or other problems in his dealings with Williams and that the only obstacle had been that the team owner had already committed himself to another driver.</p>
<p>&quot;Personally, I think we could have done a deal if there was a deal to be done,&quot; said Breen.</p>
<p>Hill, 13 points ahead of Williams team mate Jacques Villeneuve at the top of the championship standings, was not at the news briefing.</p>
<p>He remained at home in Dublin but is expected to give his thoughts on his future when he arrives at Monza for the Italian Grand Prix on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
