<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26696" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Britain commits to Eurofighter at air show.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Britain commits to Eurofighter at air show.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain on Monday launched its largest ever air show by giving the go-ahead for production of the much-delayed Eurofighter fighter aircraft.</p>
<p>Britain's vote of confidence in the four-nation consortium building the 21st century plane gave a boost to the European industry battling U.S. aviation giants in a cut-throat market.</p>
<p>The 40 billion pound ($60 billion) fighter, delayed several years by technical problems and political wrangling, is to be the star of the Farnborough air show where it will be put through its paces before the world's leading buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;Our assessment is that Eurofighter is the best available combat aircraft to meet the needs of the post-Cold War strategic environment,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine said at this southern English airfield.</p>
<p>As Heseltine inaugurated the show, Defence Minister Michael Portillo announced that Britain is to go ahead with the purchase of 232 of the jets, opening the way for the production programme to start.</p>
<p>The fighter, a joint venture by Britain, Germany, Italy and Spain, is costing around 12 billion pounds to develop.</p>
<p>But now the four industrial partners need their governments to invest another 30 billion pounds on the production programme.</p>
<p>Due to the delays, Portillo had contemplated leasing or buying some U.S. F-16 fighters either as a stop gap or even as an alternative to Eurofighter. That is now firmly ruled out.</p>
<p>The Eurofighter consortium is led by British Aerospace, Daimler Aerospace, Italy's Alenia and Casa of Spain, who plan a initial production line of 620 planes.</p>
<p>Shares in British Aerospace rose 9p to 1005p on the news.</p>
<p>Following the resolution earlier this year of a bitter Anglo -German row over worksharing, British industry is to get 37 percent of the production programme followed by Germany with 30 percent and the rest shared out between Italy and Spain.</p>
<p>The first civil aviation orders at the biennial air show were announced by the American giant McDonnell Douglas which is selling six aircraft to four airline customers in a deal worth $365 million.</p>
<p>Farnborough, which has attracted more than 1,000 exhibitors from 60 nations, is the perfect showcase for European hi-tech companies. This is the first time that the Eurofighter, France's Rafale jet and Sweden's Gripen have all been on display at the same show.</p>
<p>Defence companies face a dogfight battling for orders but civil aviation is booming.</p>
<p>Heseltine was upbeat, saying: &quot;Civil aircraft traffic is set to grow by five percent per year in the medium term. That means a doubling of demand in the course of 15 years.&quot;</p>
<p>In the Transatlantic battle, the American giant Boeing Co is pitched against Europe's Airbus Industrie group.</p>
<p>In the vital new &quot;superjumbo jet&quot; market, Boeing is eager to trump Airbus by announcing plans for a new version of its B-747 jet. Airbus is developing its own 500 plus seater A3XX.</p>
<p>The British engineering group Rolls Royce said development of its Trent 900 aero-engine gave it a head start over its U.S rivals in supplying Boeing.</p>
<p>Rolls Royce chairman Sir Ralph Robins said the Trent was cost effective and lighter. &quot;Our weight advantage is going to be very, very tough to erode,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
