<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26697" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan prosecutors launching task force on Sumitomo.</title>
<headline>Japan prosecutors launching task force on Sumitomo.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese prosecutors are to launch a special task force this month to probe huge losses on unauthorised copper trading by a Sumitomo Corp trader and question company officials, sources close to the case said.</p>
<p>The Tokyo District Public Prosecutor's Office plans to probe the case with a view to charging Yasuo Hamanaka, 48, the trader blamed by Sumitomo for the $1.8 billion dollar loss, with breach of trust, sources close to the case said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Tokyo prosecutor's office is going to set up a special task force within this month with up to five or six specialists,&quot; a source close to the prosecutor's office said.</p>
<p>&quot;As a first step, they will start questioning Sumitomo Corp officials who had connections with Hamanaka,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Sumitomo officials to be questioned soon by the Tokyo prosecutor's office include Masahiro Mogari, who worked as a senior copper trader until July, and Akio Imamura, general manager of its non-ferrous metals division, they said.</p>
<p>A copper trader who is currently assigned to its New York branch is also on the prosecutors' list, they said.</p>
<p>Sumitomo, one of Japan's giant trading houses, said on June 13 that Hamanaka lost the money in unauthorised copper trading, mainly on the London Metal Exchange, over a 10-year period.</p>
<p>It fired Hamanaka in June 14 and he has been in seclusion at his home without commenting on the matter.</p>
<p>U.S. and British law enforcement authorities have already opened investigations into the case to determine if any illegal trading practices were involved in their countries.</p>
<p>In early August, Britain's Serious Fraud Office searched the homes of two British businessmen as part of its probe.</p>
<p>When the Tokyo prosecutors will interview Hamanaka, the man at the heart of the scandal, is unclear, the sources said.</p>
<p>Hamanaka emerged from hiding on Sunday to reveal that for the past two months he has evaded the media and overseas authorities who wanted to question him simply by staying secluded at his own home.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been living in my home since leaving Sumitomo,&quot; Hamanaka told a Reuters reporter on Sunday afternoon as he walked along the aisles of a small supermarket near his home with his wife. He first came out of hiding three weeks ago when he met a Reuters reporter.</p>
<p>Asked when he would give his side of the story of the world's biggest financial trading loss, Hamanaka replied: &quot;I have nothing to say on that.&quot;</p>
<p>He also declined comment on whether he expected to face legal action, either by Sumitomo or authorities, over trading losses.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Sumitomo reiterated that it will continue to cooperate with investigative authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been cooperating and will fully cooperate with official probes,&quot; a Sumitomo spokesman said. But he refused to comment on Tokyo prosecutors' launch of the task force.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
