<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26692" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Jet fuel soars to 5-year high, airlines' gamble fails.</title>
<headline>Jet fuel soars to 5-year high, airlines' gamble fails.</headline>
<byline>Sam Arnold-Forster</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>The price of jet fuel soared nearly $9 a ton to $239 a ton on Monday, its highest level in five years.</p>
<p>A delay in Iraq's oil-for-food deal pushed the market sharply higher, but dealers said underlying demand from airlines caught short of fuel had already driven prices near record levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the airlines simply got it wrong,&quot; said a trader at a Wall Street bank who sells to airlines.</p>
<p>Airlines and package tour companies have been scrambling to buy fuel in recent weeks for next year's vacaton season after missing the boat earlier in the year, he said. &quot;They didn't want to buy in the spring because of high prices and then they thought Iraq would come back sooner than it did,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Last spring Brent crude hit its highest level since the Gulf War due to low oil stocks and tightness in the United States. During the summer many airlines delayed buying in the hope that oil prices would fall when began Iraq exporting again.</p>
<p>Iraq's invasion of Kuwait in 1990 sent jet fuel prices to record levels when military demand by the U.S.-led coalition sent prices soaring.</p>
<p>The delay in the oil-for-food deal, announced by U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Sunday, pushed the premium for jet fuel higher on Monday morning. The deal had been expected to come into force this month.</p>
<p>Dealers said jet fuel for deliver in the fourth quarter was bid at $40 a ton above IPE gas oil futures. This is some $7 below the big premiums seen during the spring, but the absolute level of $239 a ton is higher due to strong gas oil.</p>
<p>The underlying gas oil market also hit five-year highs on Monday and is the driving force behind strong European oil prices.</p>
<p>Stocks of heating oil are low in the German and U.S. markets, new green rules for diesel fuel have pushed prices higher and low refinery runs are keeping supplies tight, traders say.</p>
<p>Sources at one of the largest airlines in the world said physical supplies of jet fuel were also tight.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't seen nearly as much from the Mediterranean as last year. It is mostly going to Asia or down to West Africa at the moment,&quot; one source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
