<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26695" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Oil prices jump higher, dollar gains support.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Oil prices jump higher, dollar gains support.</headline>
<byline>Roger Jeal</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices advanced strongly on Monday as dealers rushed to buy after the United Nations delayed oil sales by Iraq following a move by its troops into Kurdish areas at the weekend.</p>
<p>The renewed tension in northern Iraq gave limited support to the dollar, often a safe haven currency, but dealers said a more vital factor was growing market speculation about higher U.S. interest rates by the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iraqi stuff is a small support. The main factor is the possibility of higher U.S. rates,&quot; said one British bank dealer.</p>
<p>Buoyant oil shares following the rise in crude prices led the London stock market, Europe's biggest, to recoup some of its recent losses.</p>
<p>But interest rate concerns brought the London market back from its highs by the end of the morning and other key European bourse showed a mixed pattern.</p>
<p>&quot;The market rose on the strength of oils this morning,&quot; said one senior London share trader. &quot;If we took the oils out, it (the London stock market) would be barely changed.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers on various European markets said the Labor Day holiday in the United States was expected to dampen the enthusiasm to trade on this side of the Atlantic.</p>
<p>October futures for benchmark Brent crude opened 70 cents a barrel higher at $21.48 on London's International Petroleum Exchange after the United Nations delayed implementation of an oil-for-food deal that would allow Baghdad to re-enter oil markets for the first time in six years.</p>
<p>Oil prices extended their gains to $1 at one point and were up 82 cents around midday.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't expect Iraqi oil in the near future and distillate demand is still there for the winter,&quot; said Alastair Harris at brokers MeesPierson Derivatives in London.</p>
<p>U.N. relief officials and guards said Iraqi troops had now evacuated Arbil, Iraqi Kurdistan's capital which they captured on Saturday.</p>
<p>London shares slipped from their highs after strong British economic data dimmed hopes of an interest rate cut after the next regular monetary meeting between the Chancellor of the Exchequer and the Bank of England governor on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The August PMI purchasing managers index rose to 51.8, its highest level in a year.</p>
<p>&quot;This really underpins what the Bank of England has been saying, that the whole economy is starting to turn round. The chances of another rate cut are falling by the wayside,&quot; said Ciaran Barr, economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>But some economists said political considerations could still overrule economic arguments and prompt a rate cut.</p>
<p>The Frankfurt bourse was lower, in line with debt and futures markets and with the U.S. holiday removing much of the impetus to trade. The inclination to do business was similarly lacking in Paris, where the market was slightly higher.</p>
<p>Traders said the French bourse, which has fallen for the past five sessions, could trade in a narrow range ahead of U.S. August jobs data on Friday and the French 1997 budget on September 10.</p>
<p>But Euro Disney shares rallied around five percent after Chairman Philippe Bourguignon said it was on track to show a second annual profit.</p>
<p>The dollar held its higher levels above 1.48 marks and 109 yen at the European midsession ahead of the next major statistics which may hold clues on where U.S. interest rates might be going and when.</p>
<p>Tuesday will bring news on the U.S. NAPM purchasing managers' index for August and Friday the key U.S. August non-farm payrolls data.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 109.13 yen and 1.4828 marks, compared with 108.70 and 1.4800 in late European business on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1130 GMT</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 index was up 8.1 at 3,875.7.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index was down 11.81 at 2,532.02.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 index was up 3.88 at 1,974.49.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed at $386.90 an ounce in the morning, compared with Friday's close of $386.35. It was helped higher by strength in silver, which gained three cents to $5.19.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
