<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26701" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Aerospace plans to disappear.</title>
<headline>British Aerospace plans to disappear.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Aerospace hopes consolidation in the European defence and aerospace industries will see its own identity dissolved in a series of cross-border mergers by 2002, senior industry officials said Monday.</p>
<p>Industry insiders said at the start of the Farnborough airshow that the company is planning to reduce itself to little more than a holding company if it can persuade other European firms to do likewise and create a single giant &quot;European Aerospace&quot; company in the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are still around in five years' time then we have failed to do our job,&quot; a senior company official said.</p>
<p>Moves are already afoot to merge the continent's civil aerospace businesses by incorporating the four-nation Airbus Industrie consortium into a single company.</p>
<p>But Airbus partners led by BAe and Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace also want to see a rapid consolidation of Europe's military businesses.</p>
<p>Industry leaders have already said Europe needs to consolidate in order to survive against the transatlantic threat of giant combines like Lockheed Martin and Boeing Co., which have emerged from a rapid series of U.S. mergers and are now scouring the world for exports to offset defence spending cuts in their home market.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are going to survive in the defence market then Europe has got to come together ... so that the U.S. doesn't dominate,&quot; said one industry source.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't remain as separate companies in Europe against the United States,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly Airbus is going to move to a separate entity to embrace all the civil aircraft activities in Europe,&quot; said another source. &quot;But I think in the long term if we want to compete with the American giants we need to have a company that spans military and civil aircraft,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>It remains to be seen whether the incorporation of Airbus will lead to wider consolidation. But the path could become a lot easier once the Airbus partners have overcome the task of transforming their interests into corporate shareholdings.</p>
<p>An outline plan is due to be agreed between the partners by the end of this year, with a view to completing incorporation before the end of the decade.</p>
<p>The consortium is currently trying to determine what assets each partner should inject into the new company, and what value should be put on them.</p>
<p>However, the sources said it is likely that current shareholdings will remain the same, with BAe holding 20 percent, for instance. They said any excess value to be found in assets transferred could be offset with some kind of compensation, such as a one-off payment, or even shares should Airbus be floated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
