<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26708" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: No change seen after Russia shares/loans deadline.</title>
<headline>No change seen after Russia shares/loans deadline.</headline>
<byline>Nigel Stephenson</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A key deadline in Russia's controversial shares-for-loans privatisation programme has passed but the government shows no signs of repaying the loans or winning firms of selling the shares.</p>
<p>The winners of last year's auctions, in which banks and other companies bid for the right to manage state stakes in blue-chip firms in exchange for loans to the government, had to hold the shares until Sept. 1 and could then sell them.</p>
<p>&quot;There is that right but nobody is in a hurry to use it,&quot; State Property Committee spokesman Igor Plotnikov told Reuters.</p>
<p>The arrangement, masterminded by former economic reform chief Anatoly Chubais, proved highly controversial.</p>
<p>Critics accused the government of selling stakes in &quot;crown jewel&quot; firms for knockdown prices to raise cash for the budget. The programme brought in some 4.7 trillion rubles last year ($878 million at current rates).</p>
<p>Tenders were often won by companies close to the auction organisers and at close to the starting prices.</p>
<p>The parliamentary audit chamber said in April that some of the deals broke the law. The chamber called Friday for Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin to extend the moratorium on selling the stakes, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that in some companies, with some stakes, a supplementary decision will be taken soon,&quot; Plotnikov said but declined to give details.</p>
<p>If winners decide to sell the shares, they keep 30 percent of the capital gains, after the loan is repaid with the proceeds, and 70 percent goes to the budget.</p>
<p>However, analysts said there was no sign of this happening.</p>
<p>&quot;The government and banks have found a way of working together,&quot; said Par Mellstroem, head of research at Brunswick Brokerage.</p>
<p>The Uneximbank banking group won the right to manage a 38 percent stake in the Norilsk Nickel metals combine and 51 percent in the Sidanko oil company. It has made widespread management changes at both.</p>
<p>A bank spokeswoman said Uneximbank had no plans to sell the shares. &quot;It would be senseless to put the shares up for sale. The real, interesting work is just beginning,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The Federal Property Fund is holding an investment tender for a further 34 percent of Sidanko and analysts say Uneximbank is expected to win it, consolidating its hold over the firm and making a reversal of the shares-for-loans deal even less likely.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said the bank had proposed that shares tendered under the programme should be held permanently in trust by winners but had not had a response from the government.</p>
<p>Privatisation has underpinned economic reform in Russia but officials have said the era of mass sell-offs is over.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
