<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26704" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain backs Eurofighter, urges integration.</title>
<headline>Britain backs Eurofighter, urges integration.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain gave the green light Monday to the long-delayed Eurofighter advanced combat jet and called for more European aerospace mergers to combat the industry's U.S. giants.</p>
<p>The Eurofighter announcement kick-started Britain's biggest-ever air show, at which Boeing Co. and McDonnell Douglas Corp. fired the first salvoes in a fierce transatlantic fight for civil aviation orders.</p>
<p>The 40 billion pound ($60 billion) Eurofighter, delayed several years by technical hitches and political dispute, was given a major boost by Britain's carefully timed announcement to the world's leading plane buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;Our assessment is that Eurofighter is the best available combat aircraft to meet the needs of the post-Cold War strategic environment,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine said at this southern English airfield.</p>
<p>Britain is to purchase 232 of the jets, opening the way for the production programme to start.</p>
<p>Heseltine urged Britain's joint venture partners in Germany, Italy and Spain to follow suit, saying: &quot;We want a decision as quickly as we can get it.&quot;</p>
<p>With the U.S. aviation industry launched on a string of mergers to sharpen its challenge in an increasingly crowded market, Heseltine urged Europe to follow suit.</p>
<p>&quot;This process is unstoppable and very, very desirable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Heseltine said integration was vital as research and development costs soared. &quot;The projects of tomorrow are going to be very, very expensive,&quot; he said at the show, attended by more than 1,000 exhibitors from 60 countries.</p>
<p>His message was echoed by John Weston, chairman of British Aerospace Defence, lead partner in the Eurofighter consortium.</p>
<p>&quot;We have developed the right aircraft at the right time and at the right price. When compared with existing combat aircraft such as the (U.S.) F-18, Eurofighter offers 2.5 times the combat capability for the same price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Eurofighter had been dogged by political wrangling with Germany and Britain arguing over work-sharing and British Defence Minister Michael Portillo contemplating the leasing of U.S. F-16 fighters instead.</p>
<p>European industry leaders are increasingly vociferous in their call for governments to allow more cross-border mergers.</p>
<p>Insiders at British Aerospace went so far as to suggest that the company could disappear altogether within the next five years and be replaced by a single European leviathan.</p>
<p>The first civil aviation orders at the biennial air show were announced by U.S. giants Boeing and McDonnell Douglas.</p>
<p>Boeing launched a new 300-seat version of its 757 jet and announced orders totalling $6.36 billion from seven airlines.</p>
<p>McDonnell Douglas is selling six aircraft to four airline customers in a deal worth $365 million.</p>
<p>Defence companies face a dogfight in landing orders in a much reduced market. But civil aviation has shaken off recession.</p>
<p>&quot;Civil aircraft traffic is set to grow by 5 percent per year in the medium term,&quot; Heseltine said. &quot;That means a doubling of demand in the course of 15 years.&quot;</p>
<p>The big growth market will be the new generation of &quot;superjumbo&quot; jets each carrying up to almost 600 passengers.</p>
<p>Boeing, with its new version of its B-747 jet, is pitched against Europe's Air Industrie Group, which is developing its own 500-seater plus 3AXX. The race is on to see who will be first in the market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
