<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26703" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Trader takes huge tonnage of cocoa after failed gamble.</title>
<headline>Trader takes huge tonnage of cocoa after failed gamble.</headline>
<byline>Jalil Hamid</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A major commodity trader had to take virtually all the 215,200 metric tons of cocoa delivered on a London futures market Monday after an attempt to squeeze the market failed.</p>
<p>The London Commodity Exchange said 21,250 original tenders representing 212,500 tons were registered on Monday, the largest ever delivery in one day.</p>
<p>The LCE gave no further details, but market sources said a single large trader was believed to have received virtually all the cocoa and has additional long positions of 8,000 to 9,000 10-ton lots.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an attempt to squeeze which didn't work because they underestimated the size of the crop and they underestimated the strength of other commodity traders,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;They never thought there would be enough cocoa that could be put on the market and they've been proved wrong,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>The trader's position of around 300,000 tons of cocoa is equivalent to a third of top grower Ivory Coast's crop.</p>
<p>Monday's delivery marked the climax of a five-month long war of nerves over the London September cocoa futures contract.</p>
<p>Although the tonnage came as no surprise, traders said the market is now watching the major trader's next move.</p>
<p>Traders estimated that it would cost the trader at least 42,000 British pounds ($65,000) a day or 1.25 million ($1.9 million) a year to finance storage of the cocoa.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't suppose there's much else they can do in this moment in time,&quot; said a trader. &quot;The market has given them cocoa that they thought they would get and they have just to carry (it) for the time being. There's nothing else they can do,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Any move to sell the cocoa would put further pressure on a sliding market amid ample crops from producers and slack demand from the chocolate industry.</p>
<p>Cocoa delivered on the LCE has to have a grading certificate proving it is of acceptable quality. The certificate is valid for six months.</p>
<p>Almost all of the current certificates expire by November and to regrade them would cost another 1.5 million pounds ($2.3 million).</p>
<p>The LCE said there were about 35,400 lots of cocoa graded since April 1, indicating that there is sufficient cocoa to satisfy the trader's position.</p>
<p>Market analysts said the trader was banking on lower Ivorian and Ghanaian crops this season after last year's record harvest.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess they felt the market was heading for a small and late Ivory Coast crop. Neither of those things are going to be likely at the moment,&quot; said one.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
