<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26702" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Carnaby Street, lucrative but no longer trendy.</title>
<headline>Carnaby Street, lucrative but no longer trendy.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carnaby Street was the heart of swinging London, where the hip and trendy of the 1960s went for their Mary Quant mini skirts and psychedelic shirts.</p>
<p>Now part of the Street is up for sale to anyone who wants to buy a piece of the British capital's modern history.</p>
<p>Dutch property group Wereldhave said Monday it was selling the three-acre (1.214 hectares) site of shops and offices it acquired in 1988.</p>
<p>The company expects to raise around 70 million pounds ($110 million) from the sale of part of the street where designers Mary Quant and John Stephens -- creator of hipster trousers -- set up shop in the early 1960s.</p>
<p>Pop stars like Cliff Richards once shopped here and London's trendies cruised by in their brightly coloured Mini cars, while the music of The Beatles and The Kinks filled the air.</p>
<p>In the 1970s it became a favourite haunt of punks with their parrot-coloured mohican hair styles and vamp make-up.</p>
<p>By the 1980s the punks of Carnaby Street began appearing on gift-shop postcards. It was a sure sign the street had passed its trend-setting heyday and had become just a spot on the tourist map.</p>
<p>The Carnaby Street of the 1990s is little more than a tawdry extension of Oxford Street, selling a plethora of souvenirs and cheap t-shirts.</p>
<p>More than half of the 28 million tourists who visit London each year come to Carnaby Street, only to find their search for a still-swinging city was in vain.</p>
<p>&quot;Its a great disappointment,&quot; said Eric Simpson from Durban, South Africa, as he strolled down the street.</p>
<p>&quot;I grew up in the era, the 60s and 70s, with the Beatles and all that. Now the most outrageous fashions here are the boots,&quot; said Simpson.</p>
<p>Far from trying to cut its losses in an area that has fallen on hard times, Wereldhave is selling a valuable piece of property in the centre of London. &quot;We're looking to see what it's worth,&quot; Wereldhave spokesman Peter Neervoort said. &quot;If we get a very good offer we will consider selling.&quot;</p>
<p>Film, television and media companies have set up offices in the area and annual rental income for Carnaby Street is estimated at around 5.8 million pounds ($9 million).</p>
<p>Newspaper reports said Wereldhave is hoping to raise around 70 million pounds ($109 million) from the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;Rental from retailing has increased six-fold since 1988 and for office space even more,&quot; said a spokeswoman for the company.</p>
<p>Such wealth is barely apparent at street level, however.</p>
<p>Carnaby Street was almost empty Monday morning and shop owners stood in doorways vying for customers for their souvenir mugs and baseball caps.</p>
<p>The fashions on sale appeared frozen in time. A large poster of Jim Morrison of The Doors fills the window of one shop selling flowing tie-dye clothing and 1960s-style beads.</p>
<p>Many more sell racks and racks of combat gear and the brightly-coloured &quot;Dr. Martin&quot; boots once loved by punk rockers.</p>
<p>Incongruously, the only music in the street is a strain of 1990s dance music, from an open-front t-shirt shop.</p>
<p>&quot;It's boring. Its just a tourist attraction now,&quot; said a German tourist.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
