<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26709" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine's new hryvnya currency makes shy debut.</title>
<headline>Ukraine's new hryvnya currency makes shy debut.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV, Ukraine</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine, fulfilling a long-held dream, launched its hryvnya currency on Monday but the new banknotes were hard to come by in many parts of the country.</p>
<p>The majority of exchange points failed to open and only a handful of large banks took in the old karbovanets currency and exchanged it for the new.</p>
<p>&quot;I just wanted to see what one of these new little papers looked like,&quot; said a beaming man, who stood in line for 20 minutes for a small pile of one-hryvna notes and gold-coloured kopeck coins.</p>
<p>The hryvnya -- whose name is taken from money used during the Kievan Rus empire about 1,000 years ago -- was fixed at 1.76 to the dollar at its debut on the Ukraine Interbank Currency Exchange, and the central bank said it did not intervene to support the new currency.</p>
<p>The hryvnya, launched five years after Ukraine became independent, was selling at 1.70 to the dollar at the few street exchange points that were open.</p>
<p>The government has set Sept. 16 as the deadline to take the karbovanets out of circulation, but said it may extend it if necessary. One hryvnya is worth 100,000 karbovanets, the interim currency that replaced the ruble at the end of 1991.</p>
<p>Many stores avoided the early confusion of having two currencies in circulation at once by staying closed, posting signs that said &quot;Sanitary clean-up day&quot; or &quot;Closed for technical reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>Many cash registers will have to be reprogrammed, by removing five zeros, to make way for the new currency.</p>
<p>Some stores had already posted prices in the new hryvnya, sitting alongside karbovanets prices, but most transactions were still being conducted in the old currency.</p>
<p>The government also announced a month-long price freeze to start the same day as the hryvnya's introduction, but many stores raised their prices immediately after the government announced the date for the hryvnya's introduction a week ago.</p>
<p>The situation outside the capital was much the same, with only a few banks in the western city of Lviv and in the Crimean peninsula distributing the hryvnya.</p>
<p>The government has promised to bring money into villages which have no exchange points.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Viktor Pynzenyk said the hryvnya would remain stable at least until the end of the month.</p>
<p>Ukraine had promised many times to introduce the new currency but had to delay due to economic problems.</p>
<p>With record-low inflation of 0.1 percent in June and July and the old karbovanets stable at about 176,000 to the dollar for a few months the government felt confident enough to undertake currency reform.</p>
<p>The karbovanets, the unwieldy currency better known as the coupon, devalued so quickly in 1994 that one state company recycled worthless small denominations into toilet paper.</p>
<p>Ukraine is negotiating with the International Monetary Fund on a $1.5 billion stabilisation fund to back the hryvnya.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV, Ukraine"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
