<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26717" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-SHEFFIELD WEDNESDAY WIN AGAIN TO GO FIVE POINTS CLEAR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SHEFFIELD WEDNESDAY WIN AGAIN TO GO FIVE POINTS CLEAR.</headline>
<dateline>SHEFFIELD, England 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sheffield Wednesday maintained their 100 percent record and went five points clear at the top of the English premier league on Monday by beating newly-promoted Leicester City 2-1.</p>
<p>Wednesday, who escaped relegation on the final day of last season, have now made their best start in 65 years, winning their first four matches and scoring twice in every game.</p>
<p>Ritchie Humphreys set the Yorkshire side on their way in the 25th minute with his third goal of the season.</p>
<p>Collecting a loose ball on the halfway line, the 18-year-old apprentice striker cut through the heart of the Leicester defence, pulled the ball on to his left foot, and coolly lobbed goalkeeper Kasey Keller from the edge of the area.</p>
<p>Three minutes later an equally spectacular goal brought Leicester level.</p>
<p>Steve Claridge, who sealed his side's promotion to the premier league with a last-minute extra-time goal in a play-off at Wembley in May, surged past former England defender Des Walker and blasted the ball into the top left-hand corner of Kevin Pressman's goal from 25 metres.</p>
<p>Andy Booth, who joined Wednesday for 2.65 million pounds ($4.1 million) from first division Huddersfield in the close season, scored their winner six minutes into the second half, latching on to a long pass from defence and slotting the ball under Keller.</p>
<p>Wednesday, whose previous victims were Leeds, League Cup holders Aston Villa, and last season's championship runners-up Newcastle, lead the table by five points from Chelsea on seven points, with Arsenal and Villa a further point back.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHEFFIELD, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
