<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26710" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bell to take over Romania helicopter plant.</title>
<headline>Bell to take over Romania helicopter plant.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST, Romania</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bell Helicopter Monday signed an accord to take over a Romanian helicopter maker and start production of Cobra attack helicopters in the Balkan country, a senior executive said.</p>
<p>Under a deal with Romania's State Ownership Fund, Bell will buy 51 percent of Intreprinderea Aeronautica Romana SA, IAR general manager Nicolae Banea told Reuters from the Farnborough air show in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement is a major step. We will finalise the business plan by end-September. If everything goes fine, Bell might get its 51 percent in IAR by October,&quot; Banea said.</p>
<p>The memorandum signed in Farnborough caps more than a year of talks between Bell, a unit of Textron Inc., and the state-run IAR on a $1 billion project to co-produce 96 twin-engined AH-1W Super Cobra attack helicopters at IAR.</p>
<p>Discussions were slowed by Romania's desire to acquire the more modern AH-1W aircraft rathern than the AH-1F originally offered, as well as by the legal steps involving approval of transfer of sensitive U.S technology to Romania.</p>
<p>Banea said a team of Bell experts was expected to arrive next week to outline the business plan and investments needed at the plant in the Transylvanian city of Brasov, 250 km (156 miles) north of Bucharest.</p>
<p>The memorandum was signed in the presence of Bell President Lloyd Shoppa and Romanian Defence Minister Gheorghe Tinca, Banea said.</p>
<p>Banea cited among the terms of the memorandum a &quot;fair and attractive&quot; price of shares in IAR, keeping IAR's main production profile as aircraft producer and retaining its present staff.</p>
<p>Under the deal, IAR would produce the Cobra aircraft under licence, with Bell supplying technology transfer, production tooling and training.</p>
<p>IAR would be responsible for the airframe and the Bucharest-based Turbomecanica SA aircraft engine maker would produce the dynamics system.</p>
<p>The takeover deal would also establish Textron's first manufacturing presence in East Europe.</p>
<p>IAR has already signed a deal with Eurocopter, a joint venture of France's Aerospatiale and Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace, to build 80 small Ecureuil helicopters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
