<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26726" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-KENT BEAT NOTTINGHAMSHIRE TO EDGE AHEAD.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-KENT BEAT NOTTINGHAMSHIRE TO EDGE AHEAD.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kent moved to the top of the English county championship on Monday after cruising to a seven-wicket victory over Nottinghamshire at Tunbridge Wells.</p>
<p>They edged one point ahead of previous leaders Derbyshire, who beat Worcestershire on Saturday, nine points ahead of Leicestershire, and 10 ahead of Surrey.</p>
<p>Kent's eighth championship win of the season came courtesy of a century stand between Trevor Ward (54 not out) and Carl Hooper, whose 86 included 13 fours and a six.</p>
<p>Nigel Llong joined in with 34 not out, including a six which shattered a nearby window.</p>
<p>Nottinghamshire had set the home side a target of 213 by advancing from an overnight 167 for six to 242 all out, thanks mainly to lower order resistance from Chris Tolley (67) and Kevin Evans (54).</p>
<p>Kent's Martin McCague finished with four for 80 and a match analysis of eight for 135, while Mark Ealham, playing his first match since recovering from a rib injury, took five for 52.</p>
<p>Yorkshire needed just an hour to mop up Essex's last five wickets and clinch a 98-run win at Headingley which revived their slender title hopes.</p>
<p>Left-arm spinner Richard Stemp took four for 19 in 10 overs as Essex, who had won their previous five matches, slumped from 100 for five to 149 all out.</p>
<p>John Crawley, who hit a debut test century against Pakistan at The Oval eight days ago, compiled an unbeaten 112 as Lancashire beat Sussex by five wickets at Hove.</p>
<p>He shared a third-wicket stand of 150 in 29 overs with Neil Fairbrother as Lancashire claimed only their second championship win of the season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
