<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26722" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: MOTORCYCLING-500CC WORRY ABOUT GOING GREY.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-500CC WORRY ABOUT GOING GREY.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>IMOLA, Italy 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aggressive, highly-opinionated and blisteringly fast on a bike? Then 500cc Grand Prix motorcycling could use you.</p>
<p>As the world championship roared to another milestone on Sunday, clocking up the 500th race since Briton Harold Daniell won the first Grand Prix in June 1949, some feared that the sport was looking a little grey in middle age.</p>
<p>Former world champion Kenny Roberts, the 'King' who won three 500 titles from 1978 to 1980, was one of those convinced that it was time to apply a spot of colouring.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they need to kick it (the sport) in the butt a little bit right now,&quot; said the American, who manages a Yamaha team with son Kenny Jr. as one of his riders.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to get some people who are going to kick Mick's butt,&quot; he added, figuratively of course.</p>
<p>'Mick', world champion Michael Doohan of Australia, won the 500th race at Imola, his seventh victory in 12 races in a season that has long looked a procession towards the quiet-spoken, greying Australian's third consecutive title.</p>
<p>It is not the Australian's fault, but the lack of genuine rivals has made much of the season less than gripping.</p>
<p>There were only two riders really competing in Imola: Doohan and Spaniard Alex Criville -- whose two wins in the last three races have been real highpoints -- and the limited excitement fizzled out in a downpour long before the finish.</p>
<p>The 500th win put Doohan in good company with Briton Mike 'The Bike' Hailwood who won the 100th race, Italian Giacomo Agostini who won the 200th, Briton Barry Sheene the 300th winner and American 'Steady' Eddie Lawson the 400th victor.</p>
<p>Those names alone are enough to bring back memories of legendary track battles and high-octane excitement from times when the world championship was more basic, more dangerous and light years from the current professional operation.</p>
<p>Organisationally and financially, most agree that the championship is fit and well after going through the doldrums on more than one occasion in the last 47 years.</p>
<p>There is no more talk of rival circuits tearing the championship in two directions and the superbikes have not yet materialised as a serious challenge.</p>
<p>But excitement levels are not what they were.</p>
<p>&quot;When you make wine you have some years that are exceptional and some that are pretty lean,&quot; said Roberts, who identified 1991 as the last truly great year for the sport.</p>
<p>&quot;You'd have to say 91 was the real cream of vintages. Wayne (Rainey) and Kevin (Schwantz) and Doohan.</p>
<p>&quot;It's come down to one name at the moment. It's kind of a low point in 500 grand prix racing.&quot;</p>
<p>The problems, as identified by Roberts and one or two others, is that the hard-riding older stars have made way for new riders who have yet to find their feet.</p>
<p>The likes of American John Kocinski, well known for expressing his views in a forceful and not altogether pleasant fashion, or Australian world champion Wayne Gardner -- whose aggression on the track was legendary -- have gone.</p>
<p>Randy Mamola, famous for clowning and roaring down the pits on one wheel and a prayer, has long retired.</p>
<p>American former world champion Kevin Schwantz, a flamboyant and forceful spokesman for the riders, has called it a day, while Californian triple world champion Wayne Rainey is in a wheelchair, running his own Yamaha team.</p>
<p>Roberts, at least, wants more of a show.</p>
<p>&quot;At times I'd like to see it more entertaining and that comes down to the people on the racetrack,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the world champion actually guides a lot of that himself. I think when I was world champion I was a little more forceful and a little more controversial.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Mick's probably too nice, too quiet. I think if Kevin were racing with him it would be different.</p>
<p>&quot;Wayne Gardner was what we need.&quot;</p>
<p>Sito Pons of Spain, a former 250cc world champion, sympathised with Doohan, however.</p>
<p>&quot;The championship has certainly lost some of its spectacularity,&quot; he wrote in a team newsletter.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not that the old days were better but that the racing was different. Some of the powerful teams are in an investment phase with their riders mostly beginners in the category.&quot;</p>
<p>The Spaniard added that recent technical changes, such as increased weights and smoother engines, had also reduced the fierceness of the bikes, making them easier to ride.</p>
<p>That had made races less spectacular but should ensure closer racing longer term when the newcomers learnt the ropes and began to push their machines to the limits.</p>
<p>Rainey agreed. &quot;I think next year will be a lot better,&quot; he said. &quot;Everybody's still adjusting this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Roberts said the top class could be swiftly improved by encouraging talented riders to move up from the 250s and 125s.</p>
<p>&quot;The thing about this sport is that it can turn around so quickly,&quot; he said. &quot;It doesn't take much.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IMOLA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
