<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26723" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: SOCCER-ASPRILLA SCORES HAT-TRICK AS COLOMBIA WIN AGAIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ASPRILLA SCORES HAT-TRICK AS COLOMBIA WIN AGAIN.</headline>
<dateline>BARRANQUILLA, Colombia 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striker Faustino Asprilla scored a hat-trick, including a superb individual goal, as Colombia hammered Chile 4-1 in a World Cup qualifying match on Sunday.</p>
<p>Asprilla scored with two first-half headers but saved the best for the second half when he dribbled through a bemused Chilean defence and scored with a powerful left-foot shot.</p>
<p>The result kept Colombia, who finished with ten men after defender Alexis Mendoza was sent off, top of the South American World Cup qualifying competition with ten points out of a possible twelve.</p>
<p>They are one point ahead of Ecuador but five clear of third-placed Argentina in a contest which sees the top four of the nine teams going into the 1998 tournament in France.</p>
<p>Colombia coach Hernan Dario Gomez was forced to make rare changes to his side due to the suspension of midfielders Freddy Rincon and Leonal Alvarez.</p>
<p>But it was veteran Carlos Valderrama who put Colombia on the road to victory with a perfect cross onto the head of Asprilla in the third minute.</p>
<p>Asprilla, who plays for English club Newcastle, was on hand again to head in Jose Santa's cross in the 31st minute.</p>
<p>Two minutes from halftime Colombia scored with another header, this time through defender Jorge Bermudez, who rose to connect with a cross from Harold Lozano.</p>
<p>Asprilla completed his scoring in the 47th minute with his fifth goal of the qualifying competition.</p>
<p>Chile striker Ivan Zamorano, who had a chance to equalise in the 13th minute but headed wide, scored his country's consolation goal in the 55th minute from a penalty after suffering the foul which resulted in Mendoza's dismissal.</p>
<p>&quot;Colombia were very dynamic with plenty of variety in attack,&quot; said a satisfied Gomez.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Colombia: Farid Mondragon; Jose Fernando Santa, Hugo Galeano, Jorge Bermudez, Alexis Mendoza; Harold Lozano, Luis Quinones (Osman Lopez), Mauricio Serna, Carlos Valderrama; Faustino Asprilla (John Mario Ramirez), Victor Hugo Aristizbal (Anthony de Avila).</p>
<p>Chile: Nelson Tapia; Jose Luis Sierra (Francisco Rojas), Juan Carlos Gonzalez, Javier Margas, Christian Mora; Luis Musrri, Fabian Estay, Christian Romero, Marcelo Vega; Ivan Zamorano, Marcelo Salas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARRANQUILLA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
