<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26721" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: SOCCER-GOALKEEPER SCORES TO EARN PARAGUAY DRAW.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GOALKEEPER SCORES TO EARN PARAGUAY DRAW.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goalkeeper Jose Luis Chilavert scored from a free kick to give Paraguay a 1-1 draw away to Argentina in a World Cup qualifying match on Sunday.</p>
<p>The burly, outspoken goalkeeper also made a splendid save at the other end to deny Gabriel Batistuta a last-gasp winner for Argentina, who have won only one of their four qualifying matches.</p>
<p>Chilavert thumped his free kick past the Argentine wall and into the goal off goalkeeper German Burgos in the 42nd minute to give underdogs Paraguay a point that few had expected them to obtain.</p>
<p>Sixteen minutes earlier, Chilavert had watched helplessly as a perfectly executed free kick by striker Batistuta flew past him and into the top corner of the Paraguayan goal.</p>
<p>It was Batistuta's 35th international goal, making him the top scorer in the history of the Argentine national team. The record previously belonged to Diego Maradona.</p>
<p>Chilavert, who plays his club soccer with Argentine champions Velez Sarsfield, scored four goals in the Argentine championship which finished last month, two from penalties and two from free kicks.</p>
<p>One of the free kicks was scored against Burgos from 60 metres in a match against River Plate.</p>
<p>Chilavert, whose goalkeeping made him the hero when Paraguay beat Uruguay 2-0 away in their last game, had said before the match: &quot;Burgos is mediocre. If I can I will score a goal to help my country in this important meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If we get a free kick on the edge of the penalty area, I want to take it because I want to score against Argentina.&quot;</p>
<p>When Argentine full-back Jose Chamot gave away a free kick on the edge of the penalty area, Chilavert, with no hesitation, rushed straight out of his goal and stood over the ball.</p>
<p>The two-times world champions, whose previous results have included a 2-0 defeat by Ecuador, dominated the first half when defensive-minded Paraguay left Richard Baez as their lone striker.</p>
<p>But the Paraguayans grew in confidence after the equaliser and Baez twice scared the home side with long-range shots in the second half.</p>
<p>Argentina, who are third in the group from which four of the nine teams qualify, concentrated too many of their attacks through the middle of the solid Paraguayan defence.</p>
<p>Paraguay, who have a game in hand, are fifth but have a game in hand over the top three teams.</p>
<p>Argentina - German Burgos; Javier Zanetti (Jose Albornoz, 88th minute), Roberto Ayala, Fernando Caceres, Jose Chamot; Guillermo Barros Schelotto (Claudio Lopez, 53rd), Christian Bassedas (Sebastian Veron 53rd), Matias Almeyda, Hugo Morales; Ariel Ortega, Gabriel Batistuta.</p>
<p>Paraguay - Jose Luis Chilavert; Celso Ayala, Silvio Suarez, Carlos Gamarra, Julio Cesar Enciso; Catalino Rivarola, Aristides Rojas (Gabriel Gonzalez 60th), Roberto Acuna (Jorge Alcaraz 87th), Harles Bourdier; Vidal Sanabria (Francisco Esteche 80th), Richard Baez.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PARA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
