<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26729" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS PLEDGE TO SUPPORT HILL'S TITLE BID.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS PLEDGE TO SUPPORT HILL'S TITLE BID.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Damon Hill has been promised the full backing of Williams as he fights out the destination of the world drivers' championship with team mate Jacques Villeneuve.</p>
<p>Williams have vowed not to undermine Hill's hopes of winning the title, even though he has been dropped by team boss Frank Williams for next season.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as the team are concerned Damon will be given 100 percent support in the remaining races, as will Jacques,&quot; said a Williams spokeswoman on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;They will be given the same equipment and the same support as has been the case throughout the season. The team will make sure they both have an equal chance of winning the championship.&quot;</p>
<p>Hill's axing had prompted speculation that Williams might concentrate their efforts on Canadian Villeneuve, 13 points behind the Briton with three races left, so that they have a world champion in one of their cars next year.</p>
<p>Hill would clinch the title with victory in Sunday's Italian Grand Prix at Monza if Villeneuve fails to finish in the top three.</p>
<p>Jordan have emerged as candidates for Hill's services next season.</p>
<p>The team confirmed they had already held talks with the driver and would do so again in the near future.</p>
<p>Current drivers Martin Brundle and Rubens Barrichello are both on one-year contracts, although Jordan have also been linked with Michael Schumacher's younger brother, Ralf.</p>
<p>Jordan have secured a major sponsorship deal which should help them meet Hill's wage demands, which are likely to be less than the estimated six million pounds ($9.38 million) paid by Williams.</p>
<p>&quot;There are seats available for 1997,&quot; a Jordan spokeswoman said. &quot;We are and will continue to talk to every driver who is available and who we feel meets our criteria.&quot;</p>
<p>McLaren and Stewart Grand Prix, the new team headed by former world champion Jackie Stewart, are other possibilities.</p>
<p>Williams are expected to sign Heinz-Harald Frentzen, the German they have courted ever since Ayrton Senna's death at the San Marino Grand Prix in 1994. Frentzen's contract with Sauber ends this season.</p>
<p>Villeneuve plans to take advantage of Hill's uncertainty over his future.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that I am in the team next season,&quot; said Villeneuve. &quot;It is one less thing for me to think about than Damon.</p>
<p>&quot;The battle is on and all I can do is be aggressive. Either we get the points or we go off. I have to be in front of him, then we will see what happens.</p>
<p>&quot;I respect Damon, he's very quick, especially when he's in front, and this year he has been mostly at the front. But he seems to make more mistakes when he's not in the lead and it's my plan to keep him behind me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
