<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26735" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: ICE HOCKEY-CANADA PULLS OUT WIN OVER SLOVAKIA.</title>
<headline>ICE HOCKEY-CANADA PULLS OUT WIN OVER SLOVAKIA.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steve Yzerman's goal at 16:10 of the third period broke a 2-2 tie and lifted Canada to a a 3-2 win over underdog Slovakia in the World Cup of ice hockey on Sunday.</p>
<p>Just prior to the goal by the Detroit Red Wings star, Canadian goalkeeper Curtis Joseph of the Edmonton Oilers made three brillant saves, stopping Richard Zednik of the Washington Capitals from in close twice and Zigmund Palffy of the New York Islanders on another.</p>
<p>The win left Canada with a 2-1  record in the opening round and Slovakia facing elimination with a 0-2 record. The United States (1-0) plays Russia (1-1) Monday in New York.</p>
<p>Slovakia, whose lineup included only nine players with National Hockey League experience, had taken a 2-1 lead at 18:22 of the second period when Lubomir Kolnik took a pass out from Jan Varholik and beat Joseph from close in.</p>
<p>Slovakia tried to play defensively early in the third period to protect the lead, but it backfired when the Calgary Flames' Theoren Fleury put his own rebound behind Roman Mega, the Slovak goalkeeper, at 2:02 to tie the game at 2-2.</p>
<p>After a scoreless first period in which Canada outshot Slovakia 12-7, Vincent Damphousse of the Montreal Canadiens put Canada ahead at 5:49 of the second period. He tipped in a 50-foot point shot by Paul Coffey of the Red Wings on which Mega had no chance.</p>
<p>At 8:06 of the middle stanza Coffey was penalised for hooking, and during the ensuing power play Slovakia tied it at 1-1 when the Washington Capitals' Peter Bondra drilled a 30-footer past Joseph on his short side.</p>
<p>Canada outshot Slovakia 37-23.</p>
<p>&quot;Joseph saved us, and Steve Yzerman got the winner,&quot; said Canadian coach Glen Sather. &quot;Slovakia played a great game. They were very tough and we were in a real struggle.&quot;</p>
<p>Bondra, a 50-goal scorer with Washington, observed: &quot;Canada had everything they could handle. We lost to Russia 3-1 and to Canada 3-2. The European countries are getting better all the time and we are getting closer to winning against the big countries.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Sweden captured the European pool championship by scoring the final five goals and defeating Finland 5-2 at Stockholm.</p>
<p>The Swedes completed pool play at 3-0 and earned a bye in next weekend's single-elimination semifinals in North America.</p>
<p>Finland finished 2-1 in pool play and will face the third-place finisher from the North American pool Friday at Ottawa. Germany (1-2) will play the second-place team from the North American pool Thursday at Montreal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
