<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26733" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-GOALKEEPER SCORES IN VIVID WORLD CUP WEEKEND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GOALKEEPER SCORES IN VIVID WORLD CUP WEEKEND.</headline>
<byline>Graham Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paraguay goalkeeper Jose Luis Chilavert scored from a free kick, Faustino Asprilla inspired Colombia with a hat-trick and Alan Shearer, soccer's costliest player, made a winning start as England captain.</p>
<p>The exploits of this trio marked a weekend of vivid World Cup action as European teams began in earnest a journey already started by those in South America, with France in 1998 as the ultimate destination.</p>
<p>Qualifying for the finals of the game's most prestigious tournament was being contested by South American countries even before a ball had been kicked in Euro 96, and Colombia are setting a lively pace.</p>
<p>Colombia stayed top of the nine-team South American group, from which the top four qualify, after Asprilla's hat-trick enabled them to trounce Chile 4-1 in the steamy Caribbean port of Barranquilla.</p>
<p>Striker Asprilla, who plays for English premier league Newcastle, scored with two first-half headers but kept his best effort for early in the second half when he pierced a demoralised defence and scored with a powerful left-foot shot.</p>
<p>Equally stunning was Chilavert's free kick to earn unfancied Paraguay a 1-1 draw against Argentina in Buenos Aires where his 25-metre shot beat the defensive wall and went into the net off rival 'keeper German Burgos.</p>
<p>Chilavert also pulled off a splendid save to deny Gabriel Batistuta a last-gasp winner for Argentina, who have won only one of their four qualifying matches.</p>
<p>England, seeking to build on the improvement they showed as hosts of the European championship finals, launched their World Cup campaign with a 3-0 win over Moldova in Chisinau.</p>
<p>Shearer, bought by Newcastle from Blackburn for 15 million pounds sterling ($23.36 million) just before the recent start of the English season, sealed victory with the third goal after strikes from Nick Barmby and Paul Gascoigne.</p>
<p>New skipper Shearer made it a double celebration with new coach Glenn Hoddle, who started his reign as England coach in succession to Terry Venables on a winning note.</p>
<p>Hoddle was among a number of new men in charge of European teams, though not all enjoyed such an encouraging start as the England boss.</p>
<p>Switzerland, now guided by Rolf Fringer, lost 1-0 in Azerbaijan while Turkey, with Mustafa Denizli having taken over from Fatih Terim, went down 2-1 to Belgium in Brussels in a game marred by crowd trouble.</p>
<p>Turkish fans, upset by their team's 2-0 first-half deficit, tore up plastic seats and threw them over the fence. Riot police took around 10 minutes to restore order. There were 50 arrests, mostly outside the stadium early in the second half.</p>
<p>It was on the same site in the Heysel stadium riot that 39 people died before the 1985 European Cup final between Liverpool and Juventus. The stadium has since been razed, rebuilt and rebaptised the King Baudouin stadium after the country's fifth monarch.</p>
<p>Artur Jorge, who has returned to coach his native Portugal after an unhappy stint with Switzerland, saw his new charges draw 0-0 in Armenia.</p>
<p>The new team chief with former European champions Denmark, Swedish-born Bo Johannsen, got off to a victorious start when Allan Nielsen and Soeren Andersen scored in the last 12 minutes to overcome Slovenia 2-0 in Ljubljana.</p>
<p>Spain, beaten quarter-finalists in Euro 96, launch their bid for a berth in the France finals when they travel to play the Faroe Islands on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The next round of qualifying matches is at the beginning of October when European champions Germany make their entrance with a trip to Armenia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
