<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26732" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLISH AND SCOTTISH LEAGUE FIXTURES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLISH AND SCOTTISH LEAGUE FIXTURES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>English and Scottish league soccer fixtures for</p>
<p>period September 6-9:</p>
<p>Friday, Sept 6:</p>
<p>English division one - Wolverhampton v Charlton</p>
<p>Saturday, Sept 7:</p>
<p>English premier - Aston Villa v Arsenal, Leeds v Manchester United,</p>
<p>Liverpool v Southampton, Middlesbrough v Coventry, Nottingham Forest v</p>
<p>Leicester, Sheffield Wednesday v Chelsea, Tottenham v Newcastle, Wimbledon v</p>
<p>Everton.</p>
<p>Division one - Bradford v Norwich, Grimsby v Swindon, Ipswich v</p>
<p>Huddersfield, Manchester City v Barnsley, Oldham v Sheffield United, Portsmouth</p>
<p>v Port Vale, Queen's Park Rangers v West Bromwich, Southend v Bolton, Stoke v</p>
<p>Crystal Palace, Tranmere v Birmingham,.</p>
<p>Division two - Blackpool v Walsall, Bournemouth v Crewe, Bristol City v</p>
<p>Preston, Bury v Rotherham, Chesterfield v Brentford, Gillingham v Burnley,</p>
<p>Millwall v Bristol Rovers, Plymouth v Notts County, Watford v Stockport, Wrexham</p>
<p>v Peterborough, Wycombe v Luton, York v Shrewsbury.</p>
<p>Division three - Barnet v Northampton, Brighton v Scarborough, Cambridge v</p>
<p>Torquay, Cardiff v Exeter, Carlisle v Swansea, Chester v Lincoln, Doncaster v</p>
<p>Mansfield, Fulham v Colchester, Hereford v Hartlepool, Hull v Rochdale, Leyton</p>
<p>Orient v Darlington, Wigan v Scunthorpe.</p>
<p>Scottish premier - Celtic v Hibernian, Hearts v Dundee United, Kilmarnock v</p>
<p>Dunfermline, Motherwell v Rangers, Raith v Aberdeen.</p>
<p>Scottish division one - Clydebank v St Mirren, Dundee v Airdrieonians,</p>
<p>Morton v East Fife, St Johnstone v Partick, Stirling v Falkirk.</p>
<p>Scottish division two - Berwick v Queen of the South, Clyde v Dumbarton,</p>
<p>Livingston v brechin, Stenhousemuir v Ayr, Stranraer v Hamilton.</p>
<p>Scottish division three - Albion v Caledonian Thistle, Cowdenbeath v Queen's</p>
<p>Park, East Stirling v Forfar, Montrose v Arbroath, Ross County v Alloa.</p>
<p>Sunday, Sept 8:</p>
<p>English premier - Sunderland v West Ham.</p>
<p>Division one - Reading v Oxford.</p>
<p>Monday, Sept 9:</p>
<p>English premier - Blackburn v Derby.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
