<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26748" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-HEAVYWEIGHTS AGASSI AND MUSTER TO ROCK OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HEAVYWEIGHTS AGASSI AND MUSTER TO ROCK OPEN.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tennis heavyweights Andre Agassi and Thomas Muster are ready to rock the U.S. Open with a quarter-final clash between two titanic hitters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to be big tennis,&quot; the sixth-seeded Agassi said of his marquee showdown against the third-seeded Austrian.</p>
<p>&quot;Big tennis is when you get two guys trying to establish their will out there on the court,&quot; Agassi said.</p>
<p>&quot;We both are going to be beating the ball pretty good from the baseline. You'll hear explosions off the racket four, five, six times a point. That's big tennis.&quot;</p>
<p>Neither player needed to raise the decibel level of his game on Monday. Muster, in fact, prevailed over 13th-seeded Swede Thomas Enqvist 7-6 6-2 4-6 6-1 despite being weakened by the effects of an upset stomach.</p>
<p>&quot;The more pain I felt, the worse my opponent played,&quot; Muster told a reporter after receiving treatment.</p>
<p>There were no such concerns for Agassi after his 4-6 6-2 6-3 6-4 Stadium Court win over countryman David Wheaton.</p>
<p>Regardless of Muster's health, Agassi is expecting the gritty left-hander to give his usual all-out effort.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he punches the clock every time he steps on the court,&quot; Agassi said of the 1995 French Open champion. &quot;Every time he gets out there, he busts his ass to win. I don't expect him to do anything less.&quot;</p>
<p>Other story lines heightened the rivalry between the two players who split their eight previous encounters.</p>
<p>Muster was one of the most vocal critics of the Open's decision to elevate Agassi two spots in the seedings from his ATP ranking and drop the Austrian one spot.</p>
<p>Earlier in the year Agassi questioned Muster's legitimacy as the ranking number one since he had won only on clay.</p>
<p>But Agassi said he did not see the upcoming confrontation between the two former Grand Slam champions in personal terms.</p>
<p>&quot;I think if anyone makes this more than a tennis match, it's their own issue,&quot; said Agassi, winner of the 1994 Open as well as the 1995 Australian Open and 1992 Wimbledon.</p>
<p>&quot;Come on, we're in the quarter-finals of the U.S. Open. We both have won big events before. We both want to do it again.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what we're both going out there and trying to do. To make it anything more than that is a waste of time.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
