<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26743" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-GOALKEEPER CHILAVERT SCORES TO STUN ARGENTINA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GOALKEEPER CHILAVERT SCORES TO STUN ARGENTINA.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goalkeeper Jose Luis Chilavert stunned Argentina when he scored from a free kick to earn unfancied Paraguay a 1-1 draw in Buenos Aires in a World Cup qualifying match on Sunday.</p>
<p>Striker Faustino Asprilla scored a hat-trick, including a brilliant individual goal, as Colombia hammered Chile 4-1 to stay top of the single South American qualifying group while Ecuador are second after beating Venezuela.</p>
<p>Chilavert, who as far as most South Americans are concerned is the world's best goalkeeper, thumped a 25-metre shot past the Argentine wall and into the net off rival keeper German Burgos just before halftime.</p>
<p>Earlier, Chilavert had been helpless as Gabriel Batistuta's exquisite free kick flew past him and into the net to put the two-times world champions ahead.</p>
<p>It was Batistuta's 35th international goal, making him the top scorer in the history of the Argentine national team.</p>
<p>In the dying minutes, Chilavert, who plays his club soccer for Argentine champions Velez Sarsfield, made a fine save to deny Batistuta a last-gasp winner.</p>
<p>Chilavert scored four goals in the Argentine championship which finished last month, two from penalties and two from free kicks when Burgos was one of the victims.</p>
<p>&quot;Burgos is mediocre,&quot; Chilavert said before the match. &quot;If we get a free kick on the edge of the penalty area, I want to take it because I want to score against Argentina.&quot;</p>
<p>Asprilla, who plays for English premier league side Newcastle, scored with two first-half headers in the steamy Caribbean port of Barranquilla.</p>
<p>But he saved the best for early in the second half, when he ran through a demoralised defence and scored with a powerful left foot shot. Defender Jorge Bermudez scored Colombia's other goal, also from a first-half header, while Ivan Zamorano converted a penalty to give Chile a consolation.</p>
<p>Colombian defender Alexis Mendoza was sent off for the challenge on Zamorano which led to the penalty.</p>
<p>Colombia lead the group, from which the top four teams qualify for the 1998 tournament, with ten points out of a possible twelve. Each team plays 16 matches.</p>
<p>Francisco Maturana, the man who led Colombia to the last two World Cups, is now in charge of Ecuador, whose 1-0 home win over minnows Venezuela kept them one point.</p>
<p>Midfielder Alex Aguinaga scored the only goal for Ecuador in the fourth minute but the 45,000 crowd in Quito jeered them off the field, having expected a bigger tally against opponents who lost their last game 6-1 to Bolivia.</p>
<p>Ecuador, who have never taken part in the finals, and Colombia have both played three of their games so far at home.</p>
<p>Argentina are third with five points, followed by Paraguay, Bolivia and Chile with four each. However, Paraguay are in a healthier position, having played all three of their games so far away and with a game in hand over Argentina.</p>
<p>Bolivia missed a chance to improve their position when they were held to a 0-0 draw in La Paz, where they had won their previous seven World Cup qualifying matches, by Peru. Bolivia twice hit the woodwork.</p>
<p>Peru, who like Chile are hoping to qualify for the first time since 1982, have drawn their last three games but desperately need a win. For the second match in a row, their finishing let them down as they wasted several good chances on the break.</p>
<p>South America's other country, Brazil, are exempt from the marathon, qualifying automatically as holders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PARA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
