<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26751" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-HINGIS OUSTS SANCHEZ VICARIO TO REACH U.S. OPEN QUARTERS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGIS OUSTS SANCHEZ VICARIO TO REACH U.S. OPEN QUARTERS.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fifteen-year-old Martina Hingis struck a blow for the youth brigade and claimed the highest seeded scalp of the U.S. Open so far by upending third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario on Monday.</p>
<p>The 16th-seeded Swiss opened second-week play with a 6-1 3-6 6-4 upset of the 1994 Open champion to reach the second Grand Slam quarter-final of her fledgling career.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Hingis became the youngest-ever Australian Open quarter-finalist and she will next play either seventh seed Jana Novotna or Karina Habsudova (17) with a final-four berth on the line.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a Grand Slam and Arantxa Sanchez is not an easy player,&quot; said the beaming Hingis, who leaped for joy after stopping the Spaniard who had reached the final of her last five tournaments, including the Olympics.</p>
<p>&quot;I just had my best match today and I'm very happy about it,&quot; added Hingis, who handed Steffi Graf one of her two WTA Tour defeats this year at the Italian Open.</p>
<p>The match was not without its strange twists with a pair of bad overrules by the chair umpire causing frustration on both sides of the net and a match point that was interrupted by a rolling water bottle.</p>
<p>On the Grandstand, 24th-ranked Austrian veteran Judith Wiesner moved into the final eight, coasting to a 6-0 6-3 win over 21-year-old Italian Rita Grande. Wiesner became the third unseeded quarter-finalist on the women's side, joining Sunday winners Amanda Coetzer and Linda Wild.  </p>
<p>Hingis lived up to her famous namesake, Martina Navratilova, in zooming through the first set in just 19 minutes with a mere four unforced errors along the way.</p>
<p>A miserable Sanchez service game, punctuated by a double fault at break point, temporarily put Hingis in the driver's seat at 3-2.</p>
<p>But the never-say-die Spaniard broke right back to draw even in the second set.</p>
<p>At deuce for the fourth time in the following game, Hingis hit a forehand that the line judge called in. But as the two continued hitting, chair umpire Jane Harvey called the forehand long.</p>
<p>Hingis became unhinged by the call and television replays showed that the ball had in fact hit squarely on the baseline.</p>
<p>The Swiss teen quickly lost the next point, giving Sanchez the game and threw her racket at her chair as she stormed off court for the changeover.</p>
<p>&quot;Sometimes it makes you really angry,&quot; admitted Hingis. &quot;I'm very lucky I could come back. I just kept fighting in the third set.&quot;</p>
<p>Still rattled, Hingis promptly lost the next four games, giving Sanchez a 2-0 third-set lead.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very disappointed with myself because I let her get back,&quot; said Sanchez.</p>
<p>Hingis was assisted in her comeback by Sanchez, who smacked 22 of her 52 unforced errors in the third set.</p>
<p>After breaking Sanchez in the fourth game to put the set back on serve, it was Hingis who got the benefit of an overrule. This time, Sanchez put the ball on the baseline only to have the chair call it out, giving the teenager the game and a 4-3 lead.</p>
<p>Hingis then broke Sanchez for the sixth time and a 5-3 edge. But she appeared terribly nervous serving for the match and was broken at love by the Barcelona battler.</p>
<p>Sanchez, however, was unable to take advantage and Hingis put the Spaniard in a 15-40 hole to reach double match point.</p>
<p>The next point was halted midway as an empty water bottle got lose and rolled toward the court during the pivotal point.</p>
<p>When they played it over, Sanchez sailed a backhand slice well out and Hingis won her big victory.</p>
<p>&quot;It's nice to be able to see young players (come along),&quot; said the  Wimbledon and French Open runner-up, shaking off the defeat.</p>
<p>&quot;It's good for the game.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
