<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26758" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-LEMKE ERROR IN 12TH LETS CUBS BEAT BRAVES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-LEMKE ERROR IN 12TH LETS CUBS BEAT BRAVES.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A throwing error by second baseman Mark Lemke with two out in the bottom of the 12th allowed Luis Gonzalez to score the winning run from second as the Chicago Cubs edged the Atlanta Braves 3-2 Sunday.</p>
<p>With Joe Borowski (2-2) pitching, Gonzalez doubled to left over the head of Ryan Klesko and Dave Magadan was walked intentionally before Ryne Sandberg hit a slow roller towards Lemke, who rushed his throw.</p>
<p>First baseman Fred McGriff got a piece of the throw, but it rolled towards the Braves' dugout and Gonzalez scored without a throw.</p>
<p>&quot;I really didn't think I could reach the ball,&quot; said McGriff about the throw. &quot;It just went off my glove and was over, bang, bang.&quot;</p>
<p>Mike Campbell (3-0) pitched a scoreless 12th inning for the win, allowing one hit and one walk.</p>
<p>Atlanta starter John Smoltz, winless in his last three starts since recording his 20th win, allowed only Magadan's solo homer in the second and Mark Grace's infield single in the seventh. He walked three and struck out nine.</p>
<p>&quot;I never get down on this team,&quot; said Smoltz. &quot;They've won so many games for me. To be honest, I should have thrown a shutout. Magadan went down and got a good pitch and hit it out.&quot;</p>
<p>Chicago starter Dave Swartzbaugh, making his major-league debut, allowed one run and five hits with one walk and four strikeouts in four innings.</p>
<p>&quot;It was certainly a surprise when they told me I was starting,&quot; said Swartzbaugh. &quot;One day you're down in Triple-A, the next you're pitching against the best team in baseball.&quot;</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, pinch-hitter Ruben Amaro delivered a three-run double during a five-run eighth inning that vaulted the Phillies to a 6-3 victory over the Los Angeles Dodgers.</p>
<p>Wendell Magee, who hit his first major-league homer in the fifth, singled home Amaro to cap the rally.</p>
<p>The Dodgers, who had a three-game winning streak snapped, squandered a chance to tie the Padres for first place in the National League West. Instead, Los Angeles remained one-half game ahead of Montreal in the race for the wild-card berth.</p>
<p>In Montreal, Cliff Floyd homered and drove in three runs and F.P. Santangelo added two RBI as the Expos built a six-run lead then hung on for a 7-6 win over the San Diego Padres.</p>
<p>San Diego's Steve Finley cut the deficit to a run with his 22nd homer to lead off the ninth and Mel Rojas walked Rickey Henderson before getting Tony Gwynn to bounce into a double play and Ken Caminiti to ground out for his 27th save.</p>
<p>Jeff Fassero (14-8) won for the fifth time in his last six decisions.</p>
<p>Henderson finished 2-for-4, including a leadoff homer for the Padres. It was the 70th leadoff homer for Henderson and the third this season.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Jermaine Allensworth's two-run single snapped a tie and highlighted a six-run seventh inning as the Pirates defeated the Houston Astros 9-5.</p>
<p>Dave Wainhouse (1-0) picked up his first major-league win, allowing just one walk in 2 1/3 scoreless innings. Pittsburgh snapped a four-game losing streak and won for only the second time in its last eight games.</p>
<p>Jeff King, Carlos Garcia and Al Martin hit solo homers for Pittsburgh.</p>
<p>Danny Darwin (9-11) took the loss for Houston, which now leads St Louis by just 1 1/2 games in the N.L. Central.</p>
<p>In St Louis, pinch-hitter Gary Gaetti's bases-loaded single highlighted a six-run seventh inning and the Cardinals tied a season high with 18 hits as they completed a three-game sweep of the Colorado Rockies with a 15-6 rout.</p>
<p>John Mabry had four hits and two RBI and scored three runs for St Louis, which had lost eight of its first nine meetings with the Rockies this season. Ray Lankford, Willie McGee and starting pitcher Danny Jackson also drove in two runs apiece for the Cardinals.</p>
<p>Vinny Castilla homered and drove in three runs for the Rockies, who have lost four straight.</p>
<p>In Cincinnati, Mark Hutton allowed five hits over six innings and Gary Sheffield hit a two-run homer, his career-high 38th, as the Florida Marlins defeated the Reds 6-1 for their eighth victory in nine games.</p>
<p>Hutton (3-1) struck out six and walked one as he shut down the Reds, who exploded for 22 runs the day before. He allowed Willie Greene's 12th homer in the fourth but not much else.</p>
<p>Felix Heredia started the seventh and was relieved by Robb Nen with two out and two on in the eighth. Nen got the final four outs for Florida.</p>
<p>In New York, Andy Tomberlin doubled home the tying run in the bottom of the 10th and scored the winning run on a fielder's choice as the Mets rallied for a 6-5 victory over the San Francisco Giants.</p>
<p>John Franco (4-3) got the win, although he had yielded a 10th-inning go-ahead run and was ejected after the inning for arguing with home plate umpire Larry Poncino.</p>
<p>Rod Beck (0-7) took the loss.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
