<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26753" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: SOCCER-WIZ WIN, MOVE INTO MLS WESTERN CONFERENCE LEAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WIZ WIN, MOVE INTO MLS WESTERN CONFERENCE LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Kansas City Wiz rallied from a two-goal deficit in the final 20 minutes to record a 3-2 shootout victory over the New York/New Jersey MetroStars in Major League Soccer Sunday to take undisputed possession of first place in the Western Conference.</p>
<p>The one-point shootout win for Kansas City (17-13, 41 points) broke a tie with the idle Dallas Burn (16-11, 40), who clinched a playoff spot when the Colorado Rapids dropped a 2-1 decision to D.C. United Thursday. Dallas next plays at New England on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Ian Hennessy and A.J. Wood had given the MetroStars a 2-0 halftime lead, but the Wiz, the league's highest scoring team (60 goals), equalised on an own goal by midfielder Damian Silvera in the 70th minute and a score by Zimbabwean Digital Takawira six minutes later.</p>
<p>Kansas City outscored New York (12-14), which dropped a third consecutive match, in the shootout, 3-1, as goalkeeper Garth Lagerway made three saves. Former Scottish international Mo Johnston, Preki and Mike Sorber converted their shootout attempts.</p>
<p>The Los Angeles Galaxy (16-11, 40) had an opportunity to move into first place with a regulation victory, but had to settle for a 2-1 shootout win over the host San Jose Clash that snapped a four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Greg Vanney, John Garvey and Jorge Salcedo scored goals for the Galaxy in the 3-1 shootout triumph, which clinched a playoff berth and moved the Galaxy into a second-place tie with Dallas. U.S. international Cobi Jones scored for Los Angeles in regulation, Missael Espinoza for San Jose.</p>
<p>Roy Lassiter scored his league-high 21st goal for the Tampa Bay Mutiny (15-12) in a 3-1 win over the New England Revolution (13-14) Saturday. Steve Ralston and Goran Hunjak also tallied for Tampa Bay. Imad Baba spoiled goalkeeper Steve Budnick's bid for a shutout in the 73rd minute.</p>
<p>The Columbus Crew (12-16)), considered a longshot to reach the playoffs last month, moved into fourth place over the Revolution after stopping Los Angeles at home Wednesday, 2-0.</p>
<p>The Crew, who had goals from Brian McBride and U.S. international defender Paul Caligiuri, won for the sixth consecutive time without a loss under coach Tom Fitzgerald.</p>
<p>U.S. international goalkeeper Brad Friedel recorded his second shutout in five appearances since joining the Crew.</p>
<p>Steve Rammel scored his sixth game-winning goal of the season in United's 2-1 triumph over Colorado (10-19), whose playoff chances are virtually nil after four consecutive losses, in Denver. Shawn Medved had given United (14-14) a 1-0 lead before Jean Harbour equalised for the Rapids.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
