<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26750" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS - SANCHEZ VICARIO STILL POSITIVE DESPITE OPEN DEFEAT.</title>
<headline>TENNIS - SANCHEZ VICARIO STILL POSITIVE DESPITE OPEN DEFEAT.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>After suffering a surprise fourth-round defeat at the U.S. Open on Monday the always optimisitc Arantxa Sanchez Vicario managed to put a positive spin on a year of near misses.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very happy with the year that I've been having,&quot; the 24-year-old Spaniard said of a 1996 campaign that has seen her win two titles and reach six other finals. &quot;If I would not get to the final is when I have to worry more. I mean it's better to win when you get to the final, but I just think that I have had a great year.&quot;</p>
<p>Not that the bubbly Barcelonan wasn't disappointed with her failure to capitalise on a 2-0 third-set lead, instead allowing 16th-seeded Swiss teenager Martina Hingis to rally for a 6-1 3-6 6-4 win.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a little bit disappointed with myself because I let her get back,&quot; said the third seed, who won the Open in 1994 but now has consecutive fourth-round exits. &quot;I did have my chances to close it out and I didn't do it.&quot;</p>
<p>Sanchez's year has been a series of close calls. After losing a marathon Australian Open quarter-final to American Chanda Rubin 16-14 in the final set in January, Sanchez played runner-up to Steffi Graf titles at the French Open and Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Her 6-3 6-7 10-8 loss to world number one Graf at Roland Garros is recognised as a recent classic.</p>
<p>This summer, Sanchez extended her runner-up streak, losing to American Lindsay Davenport in the Olympics, then to Monica Seles at the Canadian Open and Kimiko Date of Japan in San Diego.</p>
<p>&quot;You just have to see that I didn't stop playing for three months, not injured , doing my best getting to the finals losing three sets all the time, &quot; said Sanchez. &quot;That means that I'm in very good shape, so I have to be happy.</p>
<p>&quot;Most other players would like to be where I am right now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
