<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26761" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-BALTIMORE WINS IN RETURN TO LEAGUE, AS DOES JIMMY JOHNSON.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-BALTIMORE WINS IN RETURN TO LEAGUE, AS DOES JIMMY JOHNSON.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The NFL is back in Baltimore, and Jimmy Johnson is back in the NFL.</p>
<p>Vinny Testaverde rushed for one touchdown and scrambed 12 yards to set up the go-ahead score by Earnest Byner in a 19-14 season-opening win for the Baltimore Ravens -- the former Cleveland Browns -- over the Oakland Raiders Sunday.</p>
<p>It was a special return for head coach Ted Marchibroda, who was head coach of the Baltimore Colts from 1975 to 1979.</p>
<p>&quot;To come from behind like that in front of a full house, it probably doesn't get too much better than this,&quot; said Marchibroda, who won his first game as head coach of the Ravens after taking the Indianapolis Colts to within one win of the Super Bowl last season.</p>
<p>Testaverde was 19-for-33 for 254 yards and was not intercepted. He also rushed eight times for 42 yards.</p>
<p>&quot;We played the no-huddle and they couldn't get any rest between plays,&quot; Testaverde said. &quot;The crowd pumped us up big time.&quot;</p>
<p>The game was played before 64,124 fans at Memorial Stadium, the largest crowd for a sporting event in Baltimore.</p>
<p>It was the first National Football League regular-season game in Baltimore since December 18, 1983, when the home team was the Colts, who left for Indianapolis after the season.</p>
<p>But Cleveland Browns owner Art Modell moved his team to Baltimore this season, breaking hearts in one city and thrilling them in another.</p>
<p>Also in a new city is Jimmy Johnson, the former Dallas coach who made a successful debut in Miami when rookie Karim Abdul-Jabbar rushed for 115 yards and a touchdown in a 24-10 Dolphins victory over the New England Patriots.</p>
<p>Johnson led Dallas to two Super Bowl titles in five years before taking over in Miami for the legendary Don Shula.</p>
<p>&quot;Going into the game, I was nervous,&quot; Johnson said. &quot;You never know how a young team will respond. Our owner Wayne Huizenga gave me a game ball and I told our players that this game ball meant more to me than any other game ball than I've ever received.&quot;</p>
<p>Dan Marino threw for 176 yards as the Dolphins relied on their running game.</p>
<p>In San Francisco, wide receiver Jerry Rice had a two-yard scoring run as the 49ers scored all three of their touchdowns on the ground in a 27-11 victory over the New Orleans Saints.</p>
<p>Rice, who had five receptions for 88 yards, posted his 10th career rushing score and extended his NFL record with his 157th touchdown.</p>
<p>Steve Young completed 18-of-29 passes for 199 yards and carried six times for 52 yards for the Niners.</p>
<p>In Jacksonville, Mark Brunell threw for 212 yards and a pair of first-half touchdowns and James Stewart added a late scoring run as the Jaguars surprised the defending AFC champion Pittsburgh Steelers 24-9.</p>
<p>Pittsburgh star linebacker Greg Lloyd suffered a season-ending torn left patella tendon in the third quarter when he collided with teammate Rod Woodson.</p>
<p>In Denver, John Elway completed 16-of-33 for 183 yards and led the Broncos to four first-half touchdowns en route to a 31-6 rout of tne New York Jets.</p>
<p>Neil O'Donnell, who quarterbacked the Steelers to the Super Bowl last season, in his first start for the Jets was sacked eight times and completed just 7-of-13 passes for 50 yards with an interception.</p>
<p>At Tampa Bay, Brett Favre threw four touchdown passes as the Green Bay Packers demolished the Buccaneers 34-3, spoiling the debut of coach Tony Dungy.</p>
<p>Favre, the 1995 Most Valuable Player who spent part of the off-season in a rehabilitation centre recovering from an addiction to painkillers, hooked up with Keith Jackson in the first half on scoring passes of one, four and 51 yards.</p>
<p>Favre tied Joe Namath as the third-fastest to reach 15,000 yards, doing so in 66 games. Only Dan Marino (56) and Jim Everett (64) reached the milestone faster.</p>
<p>In Minnesota, Brad Johnson replaced injured starter Warren Moon and hit Cris Carter with a 31-yard touchdown pass with 66 seconds left to lift the Vikings to a 17-13 victory over the Detroit Lions.</p>
<p>Minnesota linebacker Jeff Brady intercepted a pass by Detroit's Scott Mitchell at the Vikings' 10-yard line with 20 seconds left to preserve the win.</p>
<p>Moon suffered a right ankle injury late in the first half and did not return.</p>
<p>In Indianapolis, Jim Harbaugh shook off an arm bruise and threw two touchdown passes, one with 1:54 remaining, as the Colts beat the Arizona Cardinals 20-13, spoiling the coaching debut of former defensive coordinator Vince Tobin.</p>
<p>The Colts were victorious in their first game under new head coach Lindy Infante.</p>
<p>In Washington, Rodney Peete passed for 257 yards and two touchdowns in the first half and the Philadelphia Eagles held on for yet another close victory over the Redskins, 17-14.</p>
<p>The Eagles have won the last eight meetings by a total of 29 points, an average of less than four points a game.</p>
<p>In Houston, Steve Bono threw two touchdown passes as the Kansas City Chiefs erased an early 10-point deficit and pulled out a 20-19 victory over the Oilers.</p>
<p>Only 27,725 fans showed up in the Astrodome to see the Oilers, who are scheduled to move to Nashville, Tennessee after the 1997 season.</p>
<p>In San Diego, John Carney kicked five field goals and the Chargers rushed for 185 yards in a 29-7 victory over the Seahawks. The Chargers have won five straight and nine of the last 10 meetings from Seattle.</p>
<p>In St Louis, rookie Lawrence Phillips had two short touchdown runs and the Rams used turnovers to score 19 unanswered points in a 26-16 win over the Cincinnati Bengals.  </p>
<p>In East Rutherford, New Jersey, quarterback Dave Brown's fumble in his own territory set up Steve Christie's 34-yard field goal with 4:52 left in overtime as the Buffalo Bills erased a 17-point deficit and beat the New York Giants 23-20.</p>
<p>The Giants raced to a 17-0 lead 23 minutes into the game. But Thurman Thomas scored on a one-yard run with 3:14 left in the second quarter and turned the momentum in Buffalo's favour.</p>
<p>The Bills dominated the second half, getting a pair of field goals and a 60-yard touchdown pass from Jim Kelly to Andre Reed to force overtime.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
