<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26762" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-ROBERTS WINS GREATER MILWAUKEE OPEN ON FIRST PLAYOFF HOLE.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ROBERTS WINS GREATER MILWAUKEE OPEN ON FIRST PLAYOFF HOLE.</headline>
<dateline>MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Loren Roberts sank a six-foot birdie putt on the first playoff hole to defeat Jerry Kelly at the $1.2 million PGA Greater Milwaukee Open on Sunday and capture his second title of the year.</p>
<p>Roberts, who was three shots back entering the final round, birdied four of the last six holes to force a playoff with Kelly, a Wisconsin native who could not ride the home-state advantage to his first career PGA Tour victory.</p>
<p>Tiger Woods completed his first tournament as a professional in grand style by firing a final-round three-under-par 68, including a hole-in-one. He finished at seven-under 277 and received his first check of $2,544.</p>
<p>Roberts shot a three-under 68 to finish at 19-under 265. The 1994 runner-up birdied the fourth hole and bogeyed the ninth and 10th before his surge on the last six regulation holes.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I'd have to be 22 under par, but the course didn't play as easy for me with the wind,&quot; said Roberts. &quot;I was trying to be patient. After 10, I thought I'd have to pull something out. I didn't hit a whole lot of good shots, but the three-putt on 10 snapped me out of it.&quot;</p>
<p>Roberts, who earned $216,000 for the victory, became the sixth multiple winner on Tour this year, having also taken the MCI Classic in April. This was Roberts' fourth career title.</p>
<p>Kelly, who started the day seven shots off the pace, carded a seven-under 64 at the Brown Deer Park Golf Course.</p>
<p>Kelly stormed through the front nine, birdying five of the first six holes, including two from over 20 feet out and a 35-footer on the par-three 164-foot fifth hole. He bogeyed the eighth hole but continued his torrid play on the back nine, birdying three of the last four.</p>
<p>&quot;I really came on strong,&quot; said Kelly.</p>
<p>&quot;The playoff was nervous. After the tee shot, I was fine. I'm happy to gain the experience.&quot;</p>
<p>Jesper Parnevik of Sweden, who was the leader entering the final round, had a chance to join Roberts and Kelly in the playoff, but missed a six-foot par putt on the final hole to finish at one-over 72 for the day and in a four-way tie at 18-under 266.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought I had a good shot on 18, but it took a huge bounce,&quot; said Parnevik. &quot;I knew if I could get to 20-under, I would win.&quot;</p>
<p>Nolan Henke, who fired a course record-tying 62 in the opening round, shot a 71 to join Parnevik, Steve Stricker and Andrew Magee in third place.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old Woods, who turned professional Tuesday after winning an unprecedented third successive U.S. Amateur Championship, amazed the crowd by eagling the par-five 485-yard fourth hole before firing a hole-in-one on the par-three 188-yard 14th hole.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, it was a lot of fun,&quot; said Woods. &quot;Once you start playing for a living, everything changes. I thought the media would have died down, but it didn't. The fan support was outstanding.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILWAUKEE, Wisconsin"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
