<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26760" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-WILD BOUNCES DAVENPORT OUT OF OPEN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-WILD BOUNCES DAVENPORT OUT OF OPEN.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unseeded American Linda Wild smudged up the golden reputation of her country's Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport with a smashing 6-2 3-6 6-0 fourth-round upset at the U.S. Open Sunday.</p>
<p>Wild didn't hold back on any shots, blistering the National Tennis Centre stadium court with 24 winners in sending the eighth-seeded Davenport crashing to her first loss of the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew going into the match I had to go for the first strike, go after her,&quot; said Wild after reaching the quarterfinals of a Grand Slam for the first time in the 25-year-old's career.</p>
<p>&quot;If I got into a rally, and I didn't get her moving before she got me moving, then I was dead.</p>
<p>&quot;I thought the key was that I was playing more of a first-strike match than her,&quot; said Wild, ranked 32nd in the world.</p>
<p>After losing in the second round of Wimbledon to Larisa Neiland, the 20-year-old Davenport had put together a 16-match winning streak, punctuated by a win over Arantxa Sanchez Vicario in the Atlanta Games final and a victory the following week over Steffi Graf in the Los Angeles semifinals.</p>
<p>&quot;This is definitely a huge disappointment after I had a great two months,&quot; said Davenport, who had lost just 10 games in her first three Open wins. &quot;I was looking forward to doing well here. It's going to be hard because this was pretty much the biggest tournament of the year for myself.&quot;</p>
<p>Except for Davenport's nighttime exit, things went as expected for the seeded women in action as number two Monica Seles and number four Conchita Martinez cruised into the final eight.</p>
<p>Seles flirted briefly with trouble, trailing 3-5 in the first set, before winning the last nine games to beat Frenchwoman Sandrine Testud 7-5 6-0.</p>
<p>&quot;I just told myself, just go for your shots, even if you lose the set, no big deal, there's still another set to go,&quot; said Seles.</p>
<p>Martinez never was troubled by Swede Asa Carlsson in the Spaniard's 6-2 6-1 win.</p>
<p>Davenport was in trouble right away. The match was not even 10 minutes old when she was already down 3-0. It was 5-0 after just 16 minutes.</p>
<p>&quot;She started off playing unbelievable tennis, some of the best tennis I've played against in a very long time,&quot; said Davenport. &quot;She came in fighting hard and ready to take it, as she did.&quot;</p>
<p>Said Davenport: &quot;Once I got down in the beginning, I lost my confidence a lot.&quot;</p>
<p>Davenport regrouped in the second set to find her golden touch long enough to sweep three games in a row for a 5-2 lead and then held serve at love at 5-3 to even the match.</p>
<p>But the comeback stopped there. Davenport made 13 unforced errors and won just 10 points in the final set.</p>
<p>Davenport had been lighter and faster around the court this summer after sheding 20 pounds (nine kg) off her 6 foot, 2 inch (1.89 metres) frame. But she could only lumber around the court in futile pursuit of Wild's winners.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt a little out of it,&quot; said Davenport. &quot;I don't know what it was. I was just flat.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
