<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28465" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti's De Benedetti quits as profit eludes him.</title>
<headline>Olivetti's De Benedetti quits as profit eludes him.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carlo De Benedetti, chairman of troubled Italian information technology group Olivetti, said on Tuesday he was stepping down after nearly 20 years with the company after failing to pull it back into profit.</p>
<p>Olivetti, which has turned in a succession of losses since 1990, announced a further pre-tax loss for the first half of 1996 of 440.2 billion lire ($291 million) after making a full year consolidated loss of 1.598 trillion in 1995.</p>
<p>De Benedetti, in a statement from Olivetti, said he had decided to resign as chairman and board member in line with a declaration he made linked to the successful outcome of a 2.26 trillion lire capital increase concluded in early 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;On that occasion I declared that if the company had not reached positive economic results in the course of 1996, I would respond with what I considered to be the appropriate steps,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to thank all those who worked with me as I leave a company that for almost 20 years I have helped change profoundly, and to which I have given my utmost and, in the last few years, I have led successfully in the telecommunications sector,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The board named board member Antonio Tesone as the new chairman at a meeting held in Milan late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Francesco Caio remains managing director after his appointment in July and the board also proposed creating an executive committee of Tesone, Caio and two other board members.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares spun seven percent lower on the Italian stock market on Tuesday before closing five percent weaker at 726 lire. They had fallen three percent on Monday and were close to their all-time low of 681 lire per share hit in late July.</p>
<p>Rumours abounded all day of conflict among Olivetti top management and traders sold on concerns losses would be greater than forecast previously. The company had been due to announce first half results on September 26.</p>
<p>Olivetti said its operating loss was 80.8 billion lire in the 1996 first half while the net loss was 147.9 billion.</p>
<p>The board also approved a 200 billion lire provision against possible charges stemming from divestments and restructuring &quot;deriving from the decision of the company to accelerate the reduction of its presence in the hardware sector,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Net consolidated sales were 4.224 trillion lire against 4.738 trillion in 1995 although it said the figures were not comparable.</p>
<p>Net debt at the end of the first half of 1996 was 1.26 trillion lire, compared with 764.8 billion at December 31, 1995.</p>
<p>Olivetti gave no comparisons for first half of 1995 but the company made a net consolidated loss of 1.598 trillion lire in the whole of 1995, with a consolidated operating profit of 114 billion on turnover of 9.84 trillion.</p>
<p>$1=1,514 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
