<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28467" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: U.S. punishes Iraq, Saddam unbowed.</title>
<headline>U.S. punishes Iraq, Saddam unbowed.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States pounded Iraq with 27 cruise missiles on Tuesday in retaliation for its capture of a rebel Kurdish city but an unbowed Iraqi President Saddam Hussein vowed to fight back.</p>
<p>Washington, receiving a mixed international response, portrayed its reprisal for Saddam's weekend attack on the northern Iraq city of Arbil as a deterrent to Iraqi aggression against its neighbours.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton said a U.N. plan for Iraq to sell oil to buy food and medicine could not proceed at present and announced the expansion of a no-fly zone for Iraqi aircraft in southern Iraq to the outskirts of the Iraqi capital.</p>
<p>&quot;This will deny Saddam control of Iraqi air space from the Kuwaiti border to the southern suburbs of Baghdad,&quot; Clinton said in a statement from the White House. &quot;It significantly restricts Iraq's ability to conduct offensive operations.&quot;</p>
<p>Saddam, in a speech soon after the attacks that Iraq said killed five people and wounded 19, urged his air force to attack U.S. and allied planes policing the Western-imposed air exclusion zones in the south and north of his country.</p>
<p>&quot;You men of our air defence and falcons of the skies, consider from now their damned imaginary lines north of the 36th parallel and south of the 32nd parallel non-existent,&quot; said Saddam, appearing on television in his field marshall's uniform.</p>
<p>&quot;Hit back with capability and efficiency, relying on God, the Almighty, at any hostile plane the aggressors fly to violate the airspace of your great country throughout Iraq from now and in future.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. attack sent oil prices soaring to post-Gulf War highs but by late on Tuesday had settled back, nearly unchanged on the day as traders saw little effect for markets beyond the continued absence of Iraqi oil. Iraq has not been allowed to export since invading Kuwait six years ago.</p>
<p>But in Iraq, the attack and fading prospect of oil exports sent the dinar plummetting to 1,750 from 1,250 dinars to the dollar before recovering to 1,500. The state Iraqi News Agency said Iraqis took to the streets to denounce the U.S. strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;We must make it clear that reckless acts have consequences or those acts will increase,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;... Our objectives are limited but clear: to make Saddam pay a price for the latest act of brutality, reducing his ability to threaten his neighbours and America's interests.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said Iraq's action in driving one Kurdish faction from Arbil and installing its Kurdish allies posed a &quot;clear and present danger&quot; to neighbouring countries and the flow of oil. He said the United States reserved the right to take further action.</p>
<p>The United States said its attacks were &quot;effective&quot; but did not have a final assessment. Washington denied Iraqi claims it had destroyed many of the approaching cruise missiles.</p>
<p>In the north of Iraq, aid workers headed north from Arbil toward the Turkish border in the wake of the Iraqi attack and the U.S. reprisal.</p>
<p>The White House had said there was evidence that some Iraqi forces were &quot;penetrating deeper&quot; into northern Iraq and threatened Sulaimaniya, administrative capital of the Kurdish opposition.</p>
<p>But Iraq's Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said after Saddam spoke that Baghdad would complete a withdrawal from the Kurdish north on Tuesday and denied reports Iraq was massing forces close to Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>The White House believes Saddam sent three tank divisions composed of 30,000-40,000 elite Republican Guards into northern Iraq to help the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KPD), involved in a bloody power struggle with another Kurdish group with links to Iran, the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>The U.S. attack was one of the largest on Iraq since the end of the Gulf War, when a U.S.-led coalition drove Iraq from Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>B-52 bombers and American warships in the Gulf unleashed the 27 cruise missiles at about 15 targets identified as air defence radars, missile sites and command and communication centres near several areas in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Washington says U.N. Security Council resolutions approved after the Gulf War provide the legal basis for its attack but Aziz said the action violated international law.</p>
<p>The international reaction also showed uncertainty over the legality, a contrast to the near universal backing Washington gained when Saddam invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>While German and Britain endorsed the U.S. action, France was silent and Russia called it &quot;inappropriate and unacceptable.&quot; Countries of the region, even traditional enemies of Saddam, expressed deep unease.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
