<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28464" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oil price rally fades after surge on Iraq events.</title>
<headline>Oil price rally fades after surge on Iraq events.</headline>
<byline>Harry Milling</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices in New York surged 5 percent Tuesday after the latest confrontation between the United States and Iraq.</p>
<p>Crude oil for October delivery closed up $1.15 at $23.40 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange after rising as high as $24.25 in early trading.</p>
<p>The initial surge came as the market returned from a long holiday weekend amid news of the U.S. missile strike against Iraq in response to Baghdad's incursion into protected Kurdish zones in the north of Iraq.</p>
<p>The Iraqi move caused United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali to suspend a deal that would have allowed Iraq to sell up to $2 billion of oil over six months to pay for badly needed food and medicines.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market has now reacted proportionately. People were saying it had gotten overbought,&quot; said one New York oil trader.</p>
<p>Although there had been numerous delays since negotiations began last March, the Iraq-U.N. oil deal had been expected to be implemented over the next several weeks.</p>
<p>The State Department and a U.S. envoy to the U.N. indicated it would be some time, perhaps several months, before the oil deal could be put back on track.</p>
<p>ING Derivatives analyst Tom Bentz said suspension of the deal will probably add about $1.50 to the price of a barrel of crude oil.</p>
<p>&quot;I still think oil is going to $25 before the year is out. This just means it's going to get their sooner,&quot; said Bentz.</p>
<p>Benchmark West Texas oil prices hit a post-Gulf War high in April at $25.70 but slipped to below $20 during the summer.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy to the United Nations Edward Gnehm told Reuters that the length of any delay in implementing the oil-for-food deal depended on Saddam Hussein's next moves. He added that the terms of the deal would have to be re-examined in the wake of Baghdad's aggression, and said any resolution could take &quot;months and months.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal would have allowed Iraq to sell about 700,000 barrels a day at a time when crude supplies are relatively tight. Moreover, historically low U.S. heating oil inventories are expected to require particulary high refinery runs.</p>
<p>&quot;It changes the dynamic for the fourth quarter for oil,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst John Saucer. &quot;Low refined products stocks promised higher refinery runs and now there won't be the Iraqi oil,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Heating oil for October delivery closed up 1.95 cents a gallon at 65.07 cents while October gasoline rose 1.35 cents to 62.96 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>The fate of the oil-for-food deal was put into further uncertainty after the United States responded to Iraq's invasion in the Kurdish territory by firing 27 cruise missles against targets in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Although market watchers said the possible fallout of the U.S. military strikes was still unknown, any possible ripple effect on U.S.-Arab relations would add volatility to prices.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market is in a new range. There is going to be a lot of volatlity from here,&quot; said Saucer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
