<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28476" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Airbus and Boeing trade abuse.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Airbus and Boeing trade abuse.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's Airbus Industrie, on Tuesday announced $3 billion worth of new orders and traded insults with U.S giant Boeing Co over who sold the most planes.</p>
<p>The spat between the two arch rivals dominated Farnborough, one of the world's largest air shows where bulging order books showed the industry had bounced back from recession.</p>
<p>The European consortium accused Boeing of playing fast and loose with market share figures. Boeing insisted it was still overall leader.</p>
<p>The two also came to verbal blows over sales forecasts and cost estimates for a new generation of &quot;superjumbo&quot; jets planned by Airbus in its battle to break the Boeing monopoly.</p>
<p>Boeing enlivened the show on Monday by announcing a $6.36 billion package of plane sales. Airbus fired back on Tuesday with orders for 44 planes around the world from North America to South Korea.</p>
<p>Sales at Farnborough are already three times bigger than they were at the last show in 1994.</p>
<p>Airbus' top order was for 18 A321 short-haul aircraft from South Korea's Asiana, a new customer for Airbus that could produce other multi-billion dollar sales.</p>
<p>International transport company Federal Express Corp took 11 A300-600 freighter aircraft, Hong Kong's Cathay Pacific bought three more ultra long-range A340-300's and the German airline Condor agreed to buy 12 A320 type planes, although the latter awaits full Condor approval.</p>
<p>Boeing and Airbus fell out over how strong the market was for &quot;superjumbos&quot; that could take up to 700 passengers.</p>
<p>Airbus, eager to loosen Boeing's big plane monopoly, is bidding to deliver by the year 2003 its own plane, the A3XX, that would carry 560 passengers.</p>
<p>Its forecasts show that 25 percent of all airline revenues in the next 20 years will come from large-capacity planes as airports become more congested and runway space is at a premium.</p>
<p>Boeing, mulling plans to develop its range from the current 747-400 jumbo jet and move up to 500 and 600 stretch versions, says the market is not big enough for its rival to justify developing a new plane.</p>
<p>&quot;Boeing has said there is no room for another large capacity aircraft. I would suggest they opt out of the competition,&quot; one Airbus executive said.</p>
<p>Boeing forecast it would cost $5 billion to develop a stretch version of its current jumbo jet &quot;workhorse&quot; while Airbus has put an $8 billion price tag on its A3XX project.</p>
<p>Boeing's marketing vice-president Bruce Dennis said he could not understand how Airbus arrived at the figure of $8 billion &quot;unless they see something we cannot see.&quot;</p>
<p>Airbus is a consortium of France's Aerospatiale, British Aerospace Plc, Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace and Casa of Spain.</p>
<p>Lockheed Martin, world leaders in defence and aerospace, announced a new joint venture with Alenia to develop a military transport plane based on the Italian firm's G222.</p>
<p>Lockheed also announced a link-up with compatriot Northrop Grumman Corp to market airborne early warning aircraft.</p>
<p>Dismal morning weather conditions at Farnborough cleared in time for the world's top test pilots to put their jets through their paces for a spectacular afternoon air display.</p>
<p>But there was one notable exception -- the Russian Sukhoi Su-37 was not given safety clearance to perform its more daring acrobatics at high altitute. It was confined to a lower level.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
