<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28473" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares lower on Iraqi tension.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares lower on Iraqi tension.</headline>
<byline>Aydan Eksin</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares clawed back early losses caused by U.S. missile strikes on Iraq on Tuesday, but the market remained cautious, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is nervous because of the possibility that the crisis in Iraq may last longer,&quot; said Alp Tekince from Bumerang securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said the index traded in narrow ranges after regaining part of early losses with the help of support which surfaced at around 62,000.</p>
<p>&quot;It was normal for the shock fall to be followed by reaction buys because of cheap prices. But the duration of the Iraqi crisis will be important (for the market) from now on,&quot; said Bihlun Tamayligil from Deha securities.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 market index which sank 2.2 percent to a low of 61,922 at the opening on news of the air strikes, closed the day at 62,561.01, down 1.13 percent from Monday.</p>
<p>It had shed 1.95 percent on Monday in a negative mood sparked by weekend fighting in Kurdish-held northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Daily trade volume remained thin at 4.9 trillion lira ($56.3 million).</p>
<p>U.S. navy warships in the Gulf and B-52 bombers fired 27 cruise missiles on military facilities in southern Iraq in retaliation for Iraqi attacks on Kurds in the north.</p>
<p>He also said a U.N. plan to let Iraq sell $2 billion of oil to buy food and medicines could not proceed under current circumstances. Turkey said on Monday it would appeal to the U.N. and its Western allies against any delay in the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will remain tense because of the situation in Iraq, but the index is unlikely to fall below the 61,000-62,000 range,&quot; said Yalcin Arican from Hak securities.</p>
<p>Bankers said financial markets were quiet.</p>
<p>&quot;Some customers who were worried by the recent developments were buying hard currencies, but there was no negative reaction from banks,&quot; said a private bank dealer.</p>
<p>The Turkish lira closed at 86,980 per dollar, weaker than Monday's 86,760 in line with the dollar's gains against the mark in world markets.</p>
<p>Overnight money rates fell and Treasury-bill yields dropped by between one and two percentage points across the board as the market concentrated on the Treasury's bill auction rather than the situation in Iraq.</p>
<p>$1 = 86,980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
