<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28472" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Arab states question U.S. missile strike on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Arab states question U.S. missile strike on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Christine Hauser</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Arab world's reaction to U.S. cruise missile attacks on Iraq on Tuesday was mixed, with some countries saying the strikes violated Iraq's sovereignty and raised tension in the Middle East.</p>
<p>Kuwait approved the bombing but most Gulf Arab states, including Washington's biggest regional ally Saudi Arabia, did not react officially hours after U.S navy ships and B-52 bombers fired 27 missiles at targets in southern Iraq in response to Iraqi attacks on Kurds in the north.</p>
<p>Egypt and Jordan were concerned the action could spawn further violence, while Syria and Libya condemned the attacks, one of the biggest military strikes by the United States on Iraq since the 1991 Gulf war.</p>
<p>&quot;The bombing of targets in Iraq this morning constitutes a threat to the unity of Iraq and its regional safety and increases the suffering of the Iraqi people,&quot; a Syrian foreign ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It contradicts the United Nations charter and international laws which protect the unity and sovereignty of countries and reject the interference in internal affairs.&quot;</p>
<p>The official Libyan news agency JANA quoted (Pan-Arab) Unity Affairs Jomaa al-Fezzani as saying: &quot;The American aggression against Iraq constitutes an infringement to an Arab country's sovereignty and an interference in its internal affairs.&quot;</p>
<p>An Iraqi army spokesman said five people were killed and 19 wounded - including civilians - in the U.S. missile strike.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said Iraq's military actions posed a &quot;clear and present danger&quot; to the region.</p>
<p>Kuwait, Iraq's small southern neighbour occupied by Baghdad in 1990-91, expressed &quot;full understanding&quot; for the attack, the official news agency KUNA said.</p>
<p>&quot;Kuwait reaffirms the necessity  north Iraq, in southern Iraq for that matter, will further aggravate the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Jordanian Information Minister Marwan Muasher told reporters: &quot;Jordan is following with concern the latest escalation in the situation and the military operations which might return Iraq to the cycle of violence and counter-violence.&quot;</p>
<p>Jordan's Islamist-led opposition deputies, in a show of solidarity, met the Iraqi envoy to denounce the U.S. attack.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials condemned the attack as unjustified and said Iraq was entitled to protect its borders.</p>
<p>Two radical Palestinian groups accused Washington of playing the role of an international policeman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
