<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28479" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Airbus announces $3 billion package of sales.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Airbus announces $3 billion package of sales.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's Airbus Industrie, firing a shot in its sales war with U.S. rival Boeing Co, on Tuesday announced a $3 billion package of aircraft sales across the globe.</p>
<p>This followed a $6.3 billion package announced by Boeing on Monday as the two locked horns over the future of &quot;Superjumbo&quot; jets in the fast-expanding civilian aircraft market.</p>
<p>The two giant order packages lifted the sales total at Farnborough, one of the world's leading aviation showcases, to beyond the $3 billion achieved at the last show in 1994.</p>
<p>Airbus claimed it had now overtaken Boeing in the markets where the two compete head to head.</p>
<p>The European consortium's biggest order was for 18 A321 short-haul aircraft from South Korea's Asiana, a new customer for Airbus that could produce further big sales.</p>
<p>The international transport company Federal Express Corporation took 11 A300-600 freighter aircraft, Hong Kong's Cathay Pacific took three more ultra long-range A340-300's and the German airline Condor agreed to buy 12 A320 type planes.</p>
<p>Boeing and Airbus traded blows over just how strong the market was for developing &quot;superjumbos&quot; that could take up to 700 passengers.</p>
<p>The European consortium, eager to loosen Boeing's monopoly at the top end of the  market, is racing to deliver by the year 2003 its own plane, the A3XX, that would carry 550 passengers.</p>
<p>Its forecasts show that 25 percent of all airline revenues in the next 20 years will come from large-capacity planes as airports become more congested and runway space is put at a premium.</p>
<p>Boeing, which is mulling plans to develop its range from the current 747-400 jumbo jet and move up to 500 and 600 stretch versions, argues the market is not big enough for its rival to justify developing a completely new plane.</p>
<p>John Leahy, Airbus's senior vice-president of strategy, told reporters: &quot;Boeing has said there is no room for another large capacity aircraft. I would suggest they drop out of the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Boeing has forecast it would cost $5 billion to develop a stretch version of its current jumbo jet &quot;workhorse&quot; while Airbus has put an $8 billion price tag on its A3XX project.</p>
<p>Boeing's marketing vice-president Bruce Dennis said he could not understand how Airbus arrived at the figure of $8 billion for a new aircraft &quot;unless they see something we cannot see.&quot;</p>
<p>The sniping did not stop there.</p>
<p>Airbus' Leahy disputed Boeing's sales figures which he said flattered the American giant's share of the market as they did not take account of past order cancellations.</p>
<p>Airbus is a consortium of France's Aerospatiale, British Aerospace Plc, Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace and Casa of Spain.</p>
<p>Airbus' optimism was shared by GE Aircraft Engines, part of the giant U.S. industrial combine General Electric Corp.</p>
<p>Its chief executive Gene Murphy predicted a surge in profits for his company due to &quot;a long awaited recovery in the commercial sector and a return to profitability for airlines.&quot;</p>
<p>Lockheed Martin, the world leaders in defence and aerospace, announced a ground-breaking new joint venture agreement with Italy's Alenia to develop a military transport plane.</p>
<p>Lockheed predicted that the new aircraft model could have a market of up to 300 by the year 2015.</p>
<p>Lockheed also announced a link-up with compatriot Northrop Grumman Corp to market airborne early warning aircraft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
