<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28481" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: U.S. cruise missiles hit Iraq; Saddam defiant.</title>
<headline>U.S. cruise missiles hit Iraq; Saddam defiant.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Tuesday launched the biggest military strike against Iraq since the Gulf War, firing 27 cruise missiles at air defence targets in retaliation for Iraqi attacks on Kurds in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein responded in a defiant speech by urging his air force and anti-aircraft gunners to attack U.S. and allied planes policing Western-imposed air exclusion zones in the south and north of his country.</p>
<p>&quot;You men of our air defence, consider their damned imaginary lines north of the 36th parallel and south of the 32nd parallel non-existent and hit back with capability and efficiency, depending on the Almighty, (at) any hostile plane violating the airspace of your country now and in future,&quot; Saddam said on television and radio.</p>
<p>He told his forces to give &quot;a new lesson in the meanings which they (Americans) with their empty...souls do not carry&quot;.</p>
<p>Saddam said God &quot;humiliated the aggression and the aggressors&quot; and Iraqi losses were minimal. &quot;The sons of Iraq were on their guard for the aggressors, downing a great number of their missiles,&quot; he said, without specifying how many.</p>
<p>Shortly after Saddam spoke, Iraq's Deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz said Baghdad would complete a troop withdrawal from the Kurdish north on Tuesday and denied reports that Iraq was massing forces close to the town of Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>The Defence Department in Washington said the U.S. raids were launched on orders from President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>U.S. defence officials said the unmanned, highly accurate missiles were fired from B-52 bombers and American warships in the Gulf at air defence command and control military targets in and around Baghdad.</p>
<p>A Pentagon statement said: &quot;At the direction of the president, the Department of Defence has launched cruise missiles to attack selected air defence targets in Iraq. No further details are available at this time.</p>
<p>&quot;The president plans to make a formal statement on this operation at approximately 8 a.m. (1200 GMT),&quot; it added.</p>
<p>In London, British Defence Secretary Michael Portillo told BBC radio: &quot;The Americans have launched a number of military attacks against rural areas. They are purely military targets. They have been selected to minimise collateral damage, that is to say loss of civilian life.</p>
<p>&quot;The no-fly zone in southern Iraq will be extended to allow the allies operating there to have a greater opportunity to control more of Saddam's airspace and bring greater control over him.&quot; Raising the prospect of more strikes, Portillo told BBC television: &quot;Of course that possibility does have to remain open.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1993 Clinton launched a cruise missile attack on Iraq in response to its alleged plot to assassinate former president George Bush while Bush was visiting Kuwait that year.</p>
<p>The 23 missiles destroyed an Iraqi intelligence headquarters in central Baghdad where U.S. officials said the plot had been hatched. Six civilians were killed.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters earlier there was evidence that some of the Iraqi forces that overran the northern Iraqi city of Arbil during the weekend were &quot;penetrating deeper&quot; into northern Iraq and threatened Sulaimaniya, administrative capital of the Kurdish opposition.</p>
<p>McCurry said there was also reason to believe that some Iraqi troops were involved in executions of leaders of an anti-Baghdad Kurdish faction in Arbil.</p>
<p>The White House believes Saddam sent three tank divisions composed of 30,000-40,000 elite Republican Guard troops into northern Iraq to help the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KPD), involved in a bloody power struggle with another Kurdish group with links to Iran, the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>It says U.N. Security Council resolutions approved after the 1991 Gulf War provide the legal basis for responding.</p>
<p>Oil prices shot briefly to post-Gulf War highs of $23.50 a barrel early on Tuesday. Gold and the dollar rose and stocks and bonds fell, although price movements were not dramatic.</p>
<p>On the diplomatic front, initial reaction was mixed.</p>
<p>In Cairo, the Arab League condemned the attack as infringing the sovereignty of an Arab country.</p>
<p>Russia's Interfax news agency quoted a foreign ministry source as saying that Moscow viewed the situation in the Gulf as &quot;extremely dangerous&quot;.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said the attacks were an &quot;appropriate and justified&quot; response, but France withheld support for the U.S. move while urging Baghdad to withdraw from Kurdish areas.</p>
<p>Japan said it supported the air raid as a way to ensure Iraqi compliance with U.N. resolutions ending the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>China called for restraint, saying &quot;We hope all sides will not take action that could further aggravate the situation in that area.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton's political rival, Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole, said in a statement: &quot;I trust that this development marks the beginning of decisive action by the United States to curtail the power of Saddam Hussein, and the end of his defiance of the international community and of his atrocities against the Kurdish minority in Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>PUK Kurdish leader Jalal Talabani welcomed the strikes but said they had so far failed to deter tank and artillery movements toward his rebel positions.</p>
<p>An Iraqi opposition group also welcomed the U.S. action while expressing concern about possible civilian casualties.</p>
<p>&quot;We welcome any action to reverse Saddam Hussein's invasion of northern Iraq,&quot; a spokesman for the Iraqi National Congress told Reuters. &quot;But we are concerned about civilian casualties. Saddam often puts military facilities in residential areas.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraqis in Baghdad shrugged off news of the cruise missile attacks and life went on as normal.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever America does it will be nothing in comparison to what it did in the war over Kuwait. Their sabre-rattling finds more of a hearing at home,&quot; said a taxi driver on his way to the northern city of Kirkuk.</p>
<p>In Geneva, the United Nations refugee agency said it had set up an emergency task force to draw up contingency plans in case of a refugee exodus from Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
