<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28483" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. fires missiles at Iraq, Saddam defiant.</title>
<headline>U.S. fires missiles at Iraq, Saddam defiant.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. military on Tuesday fired 27 long-range cruise missiles against air defense and communications targets in southern Iraq in retaliation for Iraqi military attacks against Kurds.</p>
<p>The Defense Department said that the unmanned missiles were fired from bombers and warships against &quot;selected air defense targets in Iraq&quot; on orders from President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>The results of the attack were not immediately known, but U.S. defense officials said 13 Tomahawk cruise missiles were fired by the U.S. Navy cruiser Shiloh and destroyer Laboon in the Persian Gulf. Another 14 AGM-86 air-to-ground missiles were fired from B-52 bombers off Iraq.</p>
<p>In Baghdad, Iraqi television reported that Iraq's defiant President Saddam Hussein said damage from the strike was minimal and that many missiles were shot down. He urged Iraqi troops to resist and said his country would no longer recognize &quot;no fly zones&quot; policed by allied warplanes over northern and southern Iraq.</p>
<p>U.S. defense officials said that no U.S. missiles were fired at military targets in and around Baghdad, although reports from the Iraqi capital said air raid sirens had blared there.</p>
<p>Clinton administration officials warned on Monday that Saddam must be made to pay for ignoring U.S. warnings and launching weekend attacks against Kurds north of the 36th parallel in his country.</p>
<p>No details or results of the raids were given in the Pentagon's brief formal announcement issued at 2 a.m. EDT (0600 GMT), which was about 10 a.m. in Baghdad.</p>
<p>It said Clinton ordered the strikes and planned to make an announcement at the White House at about 8 a.m. EDT (1200 GMT). That was to be followed by a news conference by Defense Secretary William Perry.</p>
<p>In Baghdad, residents said air raid sirens had blared in parts of the Iraqi capital on Tuesday but were not heard all over the city. Witnesses said anti-aircraft fire was launched from positions in Baghdad, but it was not immediately clear what the fire was aimed at.</p>
<p>An Iraqi television channel run by Saddam's son, Uday, confirmed the U.S. strikes against Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;At the direction of the president, the Department of Defense has launched cruise missiles to attack selected air defense targets in Iraq. No further details are available at this time,&quot; Tuesday's brief Pentagon announcement said.</p>
<p>The $1.2 million ship-launched Tomahawk missiles can fly unmanned nearly 700 miles (1,120 km) and strike targets with high accuracy.</p>
<p>In London, British Defense Secretary Michael Portillo told BBC Radio in an interview on Tuesday that no British planes were involved but that Britain provided logistical support for the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;The Americans have launched a number of military attacks against rural areas. They are purely military targets. They have been selected to minimize collateral damage, that is to say loss of civilian life,&quot; Portillo said.</p>
<p>U.S. and allied fighter jets have been policing &quot;no fly&quot; zones north of the 36th parallel in northern Iraq and south of the 32nd parallel in southern Iraq to keep Saddam's forces from attacking Kurds in the North and Shiite Moslems in the south.</p>
<p>But Portillo said in a CNN interview the Western allies were extending the no-fly zone over southern Iraq northward to within some 30 miles (48 km) of Baghdad to give allied warplanes more control over Saddam's forces in the south.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency quoted a Russian Foreign Ministry source as saying on Tuesday that Moscow viewed the situation in the Gulf as &quot;extremely dangerous&quot; and warned it could move out of control after U.S. air strikes against Iraq.</p>
<p>In Beijing, a Chinese Foreign Ministry spokesman urged the United States and Iraq to use restraint and not take action that could further aggravate conflict in Iraq.</p>
<p>Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole said he hoped Clinton's missile strike against Iraq marked the start of decisive action to curtail Saddam's power.</p>
<p>&quot;I trust that this development marks the beginning of decisive action by the United States to curtail the power of Saddam Hussein, and the end of his defiance of the international community and of his atrocities against the Kurdish minority in Iraq,&quot; Dole said in a statement.</p>
<p>The White House believes Saddam sent three tank divisions composed of 30,000-40,000 elite Republican Guard troops into northern Iraq over the weekend to help a Kurdish faction involved in a bloody power struggle with another Kurdish group with links to Iran.</p>
<p>It says U.N. Security Council resolutions approved after a U.S.-led coalition defeated Iraq in the 1991 Gulf War provide the legal basis for responding to Saddam's actions.</p>
<p>The State Department on Monday night urged all American citizens to leave Iraq, citing &quot;soaring violence&quot; in the north and Baghdad's &quot;renewed campaign of repression.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
