<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28485" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Crude oil jumps in Asia on Iraq-U.S. tensions.</title>
<headline>Crude oil jumps in Asia on Iraq-U.S. tensions.</headline>
<byline>Junko Oshima</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia jumped to their highest levels in more than four months on Tuesday in response to rising tension between United States and Iraq and delays in Iraqi crude oil exports.</p>
<p>The benchmark U.S. light crude oil for October delivery rose to $23.48 per barrel by early afternoon after trading at above $23.50 earlier. During Asian trading hours, the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) crude oil contracts trade on the after-hours ACCESS system.</p>
<p>NYMEX October crude was at its highest level since April 22 and up more than $1.00 from Friday's close in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;If the current momentum keeps up, NYMEX October could rise above $24.00,&quot; one oil trader said.</p>
<p>The jump followed a rally in North Sea Brent crude prices in London on Monday. The U.S. financial markets were closed for the Labor Day holiday.</p>
<p>The oil market buying stemmed from tensions following Iraqi troop movements into Kurdish-held opposition territory and news that U.S. President Bill Clinton was preparing a response.</p>
<p>Over the weekend, Clinton placed U.S. Gulf-based troops on high alert, and United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali put off plans to implement a $2 billion oil-for-food plan to allow Iraq to export about 700,000 barrels of oil per day. This would have represented Iraq's return to oil markets after a six-year absence.</p>
<p>On Monday in London, October Brent crude jumped to a four-month high of $22.00 per barrel on the tensions -- its highest level since April 12 --  before settling at the end of the day at $21.99.</p>
<p>The oil market momentum was maintained on Tuesday as CNN reported that U.S. Air Force B-52 bombers had taken off from Guam carrying cruise missiles. CNN said there was no confirmation of any attack taking place or where the B-52s were heading.</p>
<p>The CNN report pushed NYMEX crude prices to the highs of the day and they dipped only marginally when a Japanese government spokesman said in the late morning that no military action had taken place against Iraq.</p>
<p>Oil traders said the market was being hit both by news of the escalating tensions and the fact that Iraqi crude sales -- which they had expected to start in September -- were on hold.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a short term thing. The market will be volatile,&quot; one trader said. &quot;The fact that it came after a long weekend did not help. But if the oil sales are put back on track then prices will come off.&quot;</p>
<p>But traders said the tensions have come at a sensitive time for the United States.</p>
<p>Stocks of petroleum products such as heating oil and gasoline were at very low levels. In addition, Clinton was heading into a presidential election in November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
