<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28498" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Markets flinch as US raids Iraq,impact muted.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Markets flinch as US raids Iraq,impact muted.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>World markets reacted predictably to the U.S. missile strike against Iraq with the oil price, gold and the dollar rising and stocks and bonds declining, but initial price action was in the main unspectacular.</p>
<p>The arms-length strike pushed oil prices up around 40 cents a barrel, gold up about 50 cents an ounce and the dollar up around half a pfennig, but in later trade all were tending to drift back down.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have seen are the usual knee-jerk responses you would expect in terms of a stronger dollar and stronger oil prices but not dramatically so on either front,&quot; said John Shepperd, Chief Economist at Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>United States officials said 27 cruise missiles were fired, about half by B-52 bombers at &quot;selected air defence targets in Iraq.&quot; The hit on targets in southern Iraq was in retaliation for Iraqi military attacks against Kurds in the north.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein was defiant and declared Western no-fly zones null and void and urged Iraqi troops to resist U.S. strikes.</p>
<p>But financial markets do not expect a major escalation of the U.S. action. &quot;This is not Gulf War 2,&quot; said one trader, noting that Saddam's military machine had been decimated five years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The difference this time around is that the air strikes have come at the start of European forex day,&quot; said Nick Parsons, Forex Strategist at Banque Paribas in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;Desert Storm was launched in the middle of the night so everyone had time to think about it and come in a buy dollars so there was quite a lot of momentum behind the dollar's upward move last time.&quot;</p>
<p>The move in the oil price was the main unsettling factor for other financial markets because of the inflationary and balance of payments impact is has on big oil importers.</p>
<p>Japan is perhaps the hardest hit -- dealers say Japan imports 101 percent of its oil because some leaks out of the tanker en-route -- with Germany also hit hard.</p>
<p>Market players were also talking about the economic and political impact of the raid with the U.S. election only two months away and U.S. interest rates poised to rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton must be punching the air,&quot; said David Coleman, Chief Economist at CIBC Wood Gundy. &quot;The economy is going right, the election is going well and now he's got a nationalistic foreign policy to wave in front of the American people.&quot;</p>
<p>While most in the markets already expect a Clinton victory these latest events may help to reduce some vague perceptions of political risk after the resignation of his close adviser Dick Morris last week following a sex scandal.</p>
<p>The U.S. economy is only likely to suffer in as much as 27 cruise missiles are quite expensive.</p>
<p>Analysts said while the Gulf War helped tip the U.S. economy into a small recession the chance of the situation deteriorating as far as it did in 1990 are extremely remote, so the U.S. bond market and Wall Street should be safe.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the dust settles, quite literally, I don't think we will see too much of a fallout from this in terms of the oil price and markets generally,&quot; Yamaichi's Shepperd said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
