<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28499" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Oil prices rocket as U.S. fires on Iraq.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Oil prices rocket as U.S. fires on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices shot briefly to post-Gulf War highs early on Tuesday after the United States launched missile attacks against Iraqi defence targets in retaliation for military incursions into the Kurdish safe haven.</p>
<p>October futures for international benchmark Brent blend shot to $23.50 a barrel in Singapore, the highest oil price since Iraq's invasion of Kuwait six years ago.</p>
<p>Brent later came back to earth but shortly after opening in London was still trading up 50 cents at $22.49, extending its gain of $1.21 on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going through a Gulf War instant replay,&quot; said analyst Charles Gray at broker Prudential Bache. &quot;The fear is that Middle Eastern supplies might be disrupted (but) oil supply is not at significant risk at present,&quot; said brokerage Gerald and National Inter Commodities.</p>
<p>U.S. defence officials said the cruise missiles were fired at military and communications targets in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein responded by declaring safe Western safe havens in Iraq null and void.</p>
<p>Baghdad's military activity in its northern Kurdish province prompted the United Nations on Sunday to put on ice a humanitarian oil-for-food exchange, delaying the first sales of Iraqi crude since the Gulf War.</p>
<p>The U.N. oil-for-food deal would allow Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of crude over six months to purchase humanitarian aid for its people, suffering sanctions imposed after Iraq invaded Kuwait.</p>
<p>The deal, signed in May, was expected later this month to start supplying tight world markets with about an extra 550,000 barrels per day (bpd) of crude at current prices.</p>
<p>But fearing for the safety of U.N. aid distribution and oil sale monitors, U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros Ghali said plans to begin their deployment had been put on hold.</p>
<p>Oil traders and analysts are now trying to guess when the oil-for-food sale might get back on track.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraqi oil is not on the agenda until after the U.S. election (in November),&quot; said Gray at Prudential Bache.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps Saddam thought he had nothing to gain by the oil sale so he took a gamble,&quot; said Geoff Pyne at Swiss bank UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;Now this could delay the oil sale indefinitely because the U.N. can argue they cannot guarantee the safety of the food distributors.&quot;</p>
<p>Delays to the oil sale came when crude, at $20 for Brent, was already $4 in advance of the same time last year, helped by Middle East tensions and low inventories in the West.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not just missiles that are propelling this market higher, it's panic buying on (petroleum) products,&quot; said Gray.</p>
<p>&quot;Those people who thought they would be bailed out by Iraqi oil are now having to rethink things.&quot;</p>
<p>Tensions in the region were already high after a truck bomb in Saudi Arabia killed 19 Americans at a military complex in June.</p>
<p>Saudi dissident Osama bin Laden, said to have influenced the Saudi nationals who carried out the attack, called last week for a holy war against U.S. troops in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Further market-moving attacks are certainly not out of the question and terrorist attacks against U.S. interests may follow,&quot; said broker GNI.</p>
<p>&quot;The return of Iraqi oil is very unlikely in 1996. The oil market is going to enter winter with historically low commercial stock levels, the absence of 700,000 barrels per day of Iraqi oil and increased political tension in the Middle East region, which all argues for a fairly tight oil market,&quot; said analyst Irene Himona at finance house SG Strauss Turnbull.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Sept 3	 Sept 2</p>
<p>						   (0945 GMT)    (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $22.74	 $22.24</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$22.49	 $21.99</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)     $23.85	   ---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
