<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28506" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Taiwan hopes for links to post-Mandela S.Africa.</title>
<headline>Taiwan hopes for links to post-Mandela S.Africa.</headline>
<byline>Juliette Saunders</byline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwanese Vice-Premier Hsu Li-teh said on Tuesday he was reassured that South Africa would continue to be the island's diplomatic ally even after the retirement of President Nelson Mandela.</p>
<p>Hsu told a joint briefing with South African Foreign Minister Alfred Nzo that he believed the Pretoria government would not dump Taiwan after Mandela retires in 1999.</p>
<p>Deputy President Thabo Mbeki is widely expected to succeed Mandela and Hsu said he was reassured by a meeting with the probable successor on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;He is a far-sighted statesman. He, of course, follows the policies of your president so in this regard I am very confident that he is very friendly to my country,&quot; Hsu said.</p>
<p>Mandela has said it would be immoral to cut ties with Taiwan after years of support from the island, which China has regarded as a renegade province since 1949.</p>
<p>Pretoria is the biggest of Taipei's 30 diplomatic allies but has publicly expressed its desire for relations with Beijing, which demands it cut ties with Taiwan first.</p>
<p>Aides said Mandela might offer South Africa's services to mediate between Taipei and Beijing.</p>
<p>Hsu said he believed South Africa had strategic importance as a partner for Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;We anticipate you are going to have a vital role to play in the future... You are destined to become the powerhouse, the locomotive, the operation centre of all Africa and it is our selfish interest to join hands with you and become strategic partners in your development,&quot; Hsu said.</p>
<p>Nzo repeated Mandela's belief that it would be &quot;immoral&quot; to break off ties with Taiwan and that the Pretoria government wanted China and Taiwan to solve their differences.</p>
<p>South Africa would help if asked to, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a possibility of the president meeting the president of the People's Republic of China, that would present an opportunity for a discussion on this question,&quot; Nzo said.</p>
<p>A senior South African Foreign Ministry source said officicals were trying to set up a meeting between Mandela and Chinese President Jiang Zemin.</p>
<p>&quot;It is something that is being worked on, but we don't have a date as yet,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hsu said South Africa was expected to present a proposal on a $3.5 billion petrochemical complex joint venture with Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;A petrochemical complex has been proposed to your government and businessmen. I think the chance is quite promising. We will let your government and your businessmen think further. I understand they are going to give us a proposal before the end of September.</p>
<p>He said that if the project went ahead Taiwanese experts expected about 80,000 jobs to be created in South Africa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
