<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28507" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares ease, seen challenging high.</title>
<headline>Polish shares ease, seen challenging high.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares eased in stable turnover on Tuesday but buying was stronger after price fixing and analysts said the market seemed strong enough to slowly approach its July 5 high this week or early next.</p>
<p>But they were uncertain whether the market would then keep on rising or fall in profit-taking after hitting its 27-month record at 14,282.2 points of the main WIG index.</p>
<p>&quot;We might have a tug-of-war between pessimists afraid the market could hit the high and fall afterwards and optimists believing it will keep rising,&quot; said Krzysztof Rogalski, an analyst at Bank Staropolski brokerage.</p>
<p>The WIG index fell 0.5 percent to 13,970.1 and turnover rose two percent to 101.3 million zlotys ($36.9 million) on both markets as 29 issues fell, 24 rose and 24 were flat.</p>
<p>Analysts said the news of the U.S. missile attack on Iraq was unlikely to affect Warsaw stock performance in the short term unless a more significant conflict ensued.</p>
<p>Analysts said stocks might also be affected next week by investors speculating ahead of companies' release of August earnings reports due in mid-September.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 73,000 million zlotys ($26,642) with bank BIG and industrial and trading conglomerate Elektrim, the only stocks trading, staying flat.</p>
<p>Mass privatisation NFI units rose 1.6 percent to 95.5 zlotys ($34.9) in 9.3-million-zloty ($3.4 million) turnover in the single price auction system and were flat at 95.5 zlotys ($34.9) in 1.1-million zloty ($0.4 million) continuous trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
