<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28503" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Boeing and Airbus lock horns on superjumbo.</title>
<headline>Boeing and Airbus lock horns on superjumbo.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aircraft giants Boeing Co and Airbus Industrie were locked in an angry war of words on Tuesday over their rival plans for a &quot;superjumbo&quot; passenger jet.</p>
<p>Their fierce rivalry enlivened Farnborough, one of the world's largest air shows and a crucial marketplace for both as they planned aviation strategy for the 21st century.</p>
<p>The European consortium, eager to loosen Boeing's monopoly at the top end of the market, is racing to deliver by the year 2003 its own plane, the A3XX, that would carry 550 passengers.</p>
<p>Its forecasts show that 25 percent of all airline revenues in the next 20 years will come from large-capacity planes as airports become more congested and runway space is put at a premium.</p>
<p>Boeing, which is mulling plans to develop its range from the current 747-400 jumbo jet and move up to 500 and 600 stretch versions, argues the market is not big enough for its rival to justify developing a completely new plane.</p>
<p>Boeing scored the first points in the propaganda war on Monday when questioning the ebullient optimism of Airbus.</p>
<p>Ron Woodard, President of the Boeing Commercial Airplane Group, said its forecasts showed the world will only need 500 large capacity aircraft over the next 20 years.</p>
<p>Boeing forecast it would cost $5 billion to develop a stretch version of its current jumbo jet &quot;workhorse&quot; while Airbus has put an $8 billion price tag on its A3XX project.</p>
<p>Woodard said: &quot;It is hard to imagine that Airbus can do a totally new airplane for an $8 billion investment...So that is why they feel compelled to forecast nearly 1,400 airplanes to economically justify the investment.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday, Airbus was literally deprived of the floor to reply to Boeing when the stage of the media briefing room buckled under the weight of reporters who went to the Boeing briefing.</p>
<p>Airbus, the consortium of France's Aerospatiale, British Aerospace Plc, Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace and Casa of Spain, was forced to delay its scheduled press briefing for a day as hasty repairs were conducted.</p>
<p>But Dick Evans, chief executive of Airbus partner British Aerospace, was quick to launch an attack of his own.</p>
<p>He accused Boeing of using profits from its current 747 jumbo jet range to discount prices on its smaller jets when competing for total fleet sales.</p>
<p>He said it was vital for Airbus to get its A3XX project off the ground to fill the gap in its production range at the top of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise Boeing are going to be there subsidising the bottom end of the market with 747 sales,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Airbus, whose own range of planes stops at a 350-seater, argues that competition from the European consortium has forced Boeing to come up with new models.</p>
<p>But here again the response was a frosty one from Boeing with Woodard rebutting the Airbus accusations and insisting: &quot;Big airplanes don't make extraordinary profits that somehow subsidise smaller airplanes.&quot;</p>
<p>Plans for a giant new 700-seater are on the drawing board at Boeing but once more Woodard poured cold water on any over-enthusiastic forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to make it clear that we do not see a market requirement that would permit a financially viable airplane programe for an airplane this size,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
