<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28513" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Politicians train guns on Iraq, not each other.</title>
<headline>Politicians train guns on Iraq, not each other.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. attack on Iraq shifted the focus of the campaign on Tuesday, as President Bill Clinton used his power as commander-in-chief and opponent Bob Dole gave his patriotic support to the president's policy.</p>
<p>The two rivals ignored each other and instead denounced Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>The Iraq situation enabled Clinton, who avoided military service in Vietnam, to appear as a bold and decisive commander. Wounded Second World War veteran Dole was left to support the president.</p>
<p>The United States launched the missile attack on Iraq in retaliation for Saddam's armed intervention in the Kurdish enclave of northern Iraq. Clinton also said he was expanding a no-fly zone over southern Iraq.</p>
<p>The White House played down the political aspects of the Iraqi situation and even injected a confident note of being &quot;above the fray&quot; by revealing that Clinton had telephoned Dole to personally advise him of the missile attack.</p>
<p>But the election is only nine weeks away and no actions by Clinton can be seen in a political vacuum.</p>
<p>The missile attack underscored Clinton's role as commander-in-chief, enabling him to somberly address the nation from the Oval Office, a setting with historical power and resonance that rival Dole cannot hope to match.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objectives are limited but clear: to make Saddam pay a price for the latest act of brutality, reducing his ability to threaten his neighbours and America's interests,&quot; Clinton said from behind his Oval Office desk.</p>
<p>Dole backed away from his weekend criticism that Clinton had shown &quot;weak&quot; leadership against Saddam.</p>
<p>But while addressing an American Legion meeting in Salt Lake City, Dole muted the critique of Clinton's foreign policy and instead offered non-partisan, patriotic support.</p>
<p>&quot;In matters like this, all of us think not as Republicans or Democrats, but as Americans. As Americans, we wish our troops success and safety,&quot; said Dole, who called Saddam &quot;an outlaw,&quot; &quot;a tyrant&quot; and &quot;a butcher.&quot;</p>
<p>His only jab at Clinton was a subtle one:</p>
<p>&quot;If there is one clear lesson of our century it is this: When aggression is tolerated it multiplies,&quot; Dole said. &quot;I trust this is the beginning of decisive action to limit the power and arrogance of Saddam Hussein.&quot;</p>
<p>In the short run, the Iraqi situation seemed likely to benefit Clinton, who is already well ahead in the polls.</p>
<p>The most recent survey, a USA Today/CNN/Gallup poll taken over the weekend and released on Tuesday, showed that Dole's boost from last month's Republican convention had evaporated. He was again trailing Clinton by 21 percentage points.</p>
<p>But if the Gulf crisis does not subside, it could spell trouble for Clinton.</p>
<p>&quot;Crises in the short run work to the president's advantage,&quot; said Stephen Wayne, a government professor at Georgetown University in Washington. &quot;Unresolved crises in the long run work to his disadvantage.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
