<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28514" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: S&amp;P says Mexican economy on recovery road.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P says Mexican economy on recovery road.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's issued a vote of confidence in Mexico's economic recovery Tuesday when the agency gave the country its first good news on its debt rating since the peso was devalued in December of 1994.</p>
<p>The agency cited Mexico's reduced vulnerability to potential political and external shocks and the recovery of economic stability since 1995 as it raised its outlook on about $63 billion in Mexican debt to stable from negative.</p>
<p>&quot;Because they stuck to the (economic) programme, the crisis is over,&quot; Lacey Gallagher, director of sovereign ratings at S&amp;P, told Reuters. &quot;Despite the fact there is widespread discontent, they have been able to stick to the programme.</p>
<p>In its statement, S&amp;P affirmed its BB rating on Mexico's long-term foreign currency obligations, including Brady bonds, and its BBB-plus rating on the country's long-term peso-denominated debt.</p>
<p>A BB rating is a speculative grade rating on the country's debt, indicating a higher risk of default than investment grade AAA-BBB ratings.</p>
<p>&quot;We now expect the economy to be performing smoothly over the next year or so,&quot; Gallagher said.</p>
<p>Critical to the rating revision was Mexico's liability management as the government of President Ernesto Zedillo reduced the country's vulnerablity to unexpected shocks, Gallagher said.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said Mexico's credit standing was supported by the government's strong commitment to budgetary balance, a manageable and well-structured external debt burden and the economic benefits of its relationship with the United States.</p>
<p>At the same time, in order to secure further improvements in its credit rating, Mexico would need to stay its course of economic policy, deepen reforms, bolster growth and pursue political liberalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;Macroeconomic stability really hinges on healthy public finances,&quot; Gallagher said. &quot;Now it's a question of going from a stabilisation and adjustment phase into a growth phase.&quot;</p>
<p>The challenges for Mexico are long-term issues, such as building domestic savings and developing a stronger financial system, Gallagher said.</p>
<p>Mexico's Brady bonds dipped slightly and the peso firmed after S&amp;P's action, although analysts said the markets had long factored a Mexican recovery into prices.</p>
<p>Mexican asset prices sank late last week when a rebel group conducted a series of strikes in southern and eastern states.</p>
<p>&quot;The rating was not a surprise to anyone in the market, but there had been some question as to whether S&amp;P might wait until the political turmoil settles down,&quot; said Joyce Chang, managing director at Merrill Lynch. &quot;It's very positive that they went ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts saw the S&amp;P action as in line with widespread indications of a Mexican recovery, highlighted by a report that second-quarter gross domestic product expanded by 7.2 percent in year-over-year terms.</p>
<p>&quot;If Mexico continues to grow with stability, I would bet that S&amp;P would look for an upgrade of the outlook in relatively short order,&quot; said Lawrence Krohn, Latin American economist at UBS Securities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
