<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28510" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oil surges as Iraq deal collapses on Kurd crisis.</title>
<headline>Oil surges as Iraq deal collapses on Kurd crisis.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices in New York surged nearly 5 percent Tuesday after the United States launched a cruise missile attack against Iraqi targets in response to Baghdad's attacks in Kurdish areas in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercantile Exchange crude oil for October delivery rose $2 to a four-month high of $24.25 a barrel, before ending at $23.40 a barrel, up $1.15.</p>
<p>The market reacted swiftly after the United States bombed military targets in Iraq in retaliation for weekend attacks on internationally protected Kurdish zones in northern Iraq, creating jitters about oil supplies and Mideast turmoil.</p>
<p>But the immediate reason for buying was the collapse of a United Nations deal to allow Iraq some $2 billion in oil sales on humanitarian grounds, which had been expected to start supplying world markets with 700,000 barrels a day this month.</p>
<p>Over the weekend United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali halted the deal due to Iraq's attacks on the Kurds.</p>
<p>&quot;It changes the dynamic for the fourth quarter for oil,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst John Saucer. &quot;Low refined products stocks promised higher refinery runs, and now there won't be the Iraq oil,&quot; Saucer said.</p>
<p>October unleaded gasoline closed 1.35 cents a gallon higher at 62.96 cents and October heating oil ended up 1.95 cents a gallon at 65.07 cents.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, U.S. envoy to the United Nations Edward Gnehm said the length of any delay to implementing the oil-for-food deal now depended on Saddam Hussein's actions.</p>
<p>He added that the terms of the ill-fated six-month oil deal would have to be re-examined in the wake of Baghdad's attacks and any resolution could take &quot;months and months.&quot;</p>
<p>The gains were held in check as the market looked ahead to the likely supply impact through December, the heart of the winter heating season.</p>
<p>&quot;The International Energy Agency is telling us that 1.7 million barrels a day of incremental oil is coming at us in the fourth quarter, excluding Iraq,&quot; said Philip Verleger, an analyst at Charles River Associates in Washington, DC.</p>
<p>&quot;If that arrives, and I think it will, then prices will be depressed,&quot; Verleger said.</p>
<p>Prices also gyrated wildly at the Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange in New York.</p>
<p>December coffee fell to a two-week low and closed 4.95 cents a pound lower at 113.30 cents after a biweekly government report released on Friday showed a massive build-up of speculative buyers recently just as commercial coffee firms had hedged or sold the market short.</p>
<p>The data from the Commodity Futures Trading Commission sparked an immediate sell-off since it indicated last week's price rally had a soft speculative core.</p>
<p>&quot;The CFTC showed the trade significantly short and the speculators significantly long,&quot; Refco Inc. analyst Ann Prendergast said. &quot;It was a formula for a sell-off.&quot;</p>
<p>December cocoa closed down $16 a metric ton at $1,336, its lowest settlement since March 27.</p>
<p>Analysts said optimism about supplies in leading producer Ivory Coast improved with summer rains and a record large physical delivery in the London market on Monday -- 212,500 tons accepted by one trade house -- eased supply concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;The record delivery in London shows there is a ton of cocoa out there for anyone who wants to buy,&quot; said Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka.</p>
<p>October world sugar futures soared to close up 0.40 cent a pound at 12.18 cents, the highest close since January 1995.</p>
<p>Traders said worries about Hurricane Fran and other storms possibly damaging sugar areas in the Carbibbean aided buying.</p>
<p>&quot;With production and consumption in approximate balance, the market will remain vulnerable to potential supply disruptions caused by production problems in one or more major origins,&quot; Prudential Securities analyst Arthur Stevenson said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
