<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28515" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Iraq attack, interest rate talk boost dollar.</title>
<headline>Iraq attack, interest rate talk boost dollar.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Rosenblum</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar gained against the Japanese yen and the German mark Tuesday as news of American military intervention in Iraq and talk of an imminent rise in U.S. interest rates fuelled demand for the U.S. currency.</p>
<p>But after the dollar climbed to seven-week highs against the yen, the rally fizzled and the currency was at 1.4840 marks and 109.25 yen in late trading, compared with 1.4820 and 108.90 on Friday.</p>
<p>American financial markets were closed Monday for the Labour Day holiday.</p>
<p>News that the United States had launched cruise missiles against Iraq in retaliation for Iraqi attacks on a Kurdish enclave spurred safe-haven dollar buying overnight in Asia, particularly against the yen, traders said.</p>
<p>The Iraqi move caused the United Nations to suspend a deal that would have let Baghdad sell up to $2 billion in oil to pay for food and medicine, pushing oil prices higher.</p>
<p>Oil prices spiked to their highest level since the Gulf War, propelling the yen to seven-week lows against the mark and the British pound.</p>
<p>Rising petroleum prices hurt the yen because Japan imports virtually all its oil.</p>
<p>The pound, meanwhile, rose against the dollar on the back of stronger crude prices, climbing as high as $1.5695. It settled at $1.5665, up from $1.5605 on Friday.</p>
<p>Britain, a net exporter of oil, stands to benefit from higher crude prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The impluse right now is to be slightly long dollars. It's the old adage of flight to quality in times of crisis and uncertainty,&quot; said Bill Marr, foreign exchange manager at Credit Commerciale de France.</p>
<p>&quot;If oil prices go higher that could hurt the yen and also benefit sterling.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar also received a boost from growing expectations that interest rates in the United States are set to rise.</p>
<p>A recent string of strong economic indicators may convince the Federal Reserve to raise short-term interest rates to keep the economy from overheating at the Sept. 24 meeting of the policy-making Federal Open Market Committee meeting, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>Supporting that view and helping to undergird the dollar was an article in Tuesday's Wall Street Journal that said the Fed was mulling a bigger-than-expected increase in official interest rates.</p>
<p>The newspaper said unidentified Federal Reserve policymakers indicated the central bank could raise official rates by 0.50 percentage point this month unless clear signs of slower growth emerge soon.</p>
<p>The dollar climbed to around 1.4910 marks and 109.45 yen in Europe before paring gains in U.S. trading as fears of higher interest rates trounced U.S. bond and stock prices.</p>
<p>The 30-year benchmark Treasury bond dropped 23/32 to yield 7.18 percent in early trading, while the Dow industrials briefly fell 53 points to 5,566.</p>
<p>But bond and stock prices later recovered to register healthy gains, while the dollar remained mired in narrow ranges.</p>
<p>The National Association of Purchasing Management's August index came in at 52.6, compared with an expected reading of 52.9 and helped calm fears of higher rates, taking pressure off stocks and bonds.</p>
<p>Traders said there was still good demand for the U.S. currency due to uncertainty over the situation in Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;There's still concern about how the situation will be resolved and therefore I think there will be support (for the dollar),&quot; said Steve Allen, manager of treasury services at the National Bank of Kuwait in New York.</p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar strengthened to 1.2080 Swiss francs from 1.2010 on Friday. It also rose to Canadian $1.3705 from C$1.3682.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
