<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28512" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Orange County, Calif., bankruptcy trial nears end.</title>
<headline>Orange County, Calif., bankruptcy trial nears end.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first criminal trial arising from the largest municipal bankruptcy in U.S. history neared an end on Tuesday as attorneys in Orange County presented their closing arguments.</p>
<p>Former Orange County Budget Director Ronald Rubino, 44, was indicted by a county grand jury in December for allegedly aiding former county Treasurer Robert Citron in diverting funds from other government agencies for the county's benefit.</p>
<p>Prosecution and defence attorneys were expected to complete their closing statements later on Tuesday. The jury could then begin its deliberations.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Jan Nolan wrapped up the county's case, challenging the defence assertion that Rubino did not know about the alleged diversions.</p>
<p>&quot;You get the idea that this was no big secret,&quot; Nolan told the jury in Santa Ana, California. &quot;They're skimming money ... and having meetings discussing how to do it. That's how cavalier things had become.&quot;</p>
<p>Defence Attorney Rodney Perlman said prosecutors failed to prove their case and asserted his client never thought to second-guess Citron, whom Rubino admired and respected.</p>
<p>&quot;Ron Rubino was an employee of county government ... getting information from a man beyond reproach with immense personal integrity and great success. That's the context in which all this takes place,&quot; Perlman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The evidence shows that while this diversion was going on it was not in any way done with Rubino's knowledge,&quot; he said. &quot;The government knows that and its evidence proves nothing.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubino, who has denied any wrongdoing, faces up to nine years in prison if convicted on the felony counts.</p>
<p>Rubino was one of several former and current county officials formally accused with wrongdoing in connection with the bankruptcy. He was the first to go on trial.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for protection under Chapter 9 of the federal Bankruptcy Code on December 6, 1994 after sustaining investment losses of more than $1.6 billion. The county emerged from bankruptcy in June of this year.</p>
<p>During the Rubino trial, which began in early August, the prosecution portrayed the former county budget director as an ambitious county employee who helped to divert millions of dollars away from unsuspecting cities and school districts.</p>
<p>The defence presented Rubino as an honest and highly-respected public servant.</p>
<p>In a surprising twist, Citron, who was expected to be a key witness against Rubino, testified during the trial that he never discussed with Rubino the alleged scheme to divert funds.</p>
<p>Citron pleaded guilty in April 1995 to several felonies related to the county's financial crisis and is awaiting sentencing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
