<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28518" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's 80s highflier De Benedetti quits Olivetti.</title>
<headline>Italy's 80s highflier De Benedetti quits Olivetti.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian financier Carlo De Benedetti, once golden star of the 1980s Milan stock market, found profits too elusive in the tough 1990s and bowed out from his position as chairman at his Olivetti group empire.</p>
<p>De Benedetti, 61, announced late on Tuesday he would fulfil a promise made early this year that he would step down if Olivetti, the company he transformed from producing typewriters to personal computer maker, failed to show positive results.</p>
<p>&quot;I declared if the company had not reached positive economic results in the course of 1996, I would respond with what I considered to be the appropriate steps,&quot; he said in a statement after Olivetti announced a loss for its 1996 first half.</p>
<p>Known as &quot;The Engineer&quot;, De Benedetti first came to prominence when in 1978 he took over the management of Olivetti, then a moribund, loss-making typewriter manufacturer, after his family's finance company, CIR, acquired a 15 percent stake.</p>
<p>The company's record made the task of saving it from bankruptcy seem impossible at the time. But he rapidly transformed it into Europe's biggest supplier of office automation equipment and one of the largest makers of personal computers after U.S. International Business Machines (IBM).</p>
<p>A high-flying stock in Milan in the 1980s, Olivetti has fared less well in the 1990s as international market conditions grew tougher. Its price hit a record low of 681 lire (45 cents) per share this July from 1986's all-time peak of 13,371 lire.</p>
<p>With PCs making no profits and Olivetti failing to break even since 1990, De Benedetti moved into the telephone sector. Olivetti's 41 percent owned mobile phone company Omnitel won Italy's second GSM mobile phone license and launched a service last December.</p>
<p>But the financier's credibility has crumbled rapidly in the last 12 months after he made a massive 2.26 trillion lire capital increase in October last year to restructure Olivetti and then announced higher charges at the start of 1996.</p>
<p>The sudden resignation in June of managing director Corrado Passera, with whom De Benedetti held the post jointly, indicated all was not well. In the same manoeuvre, De Benedetti stepped aside leaving the managing directorship to Francesco Caio.</p>
<p>This year has also seen a Milan appeal court sentence the financier to four and a half years in jail for his part in the fraudulent collapse in 1982 of Banco Ambrosiano, then Italy's largest private bank. That case now goes to Italy's highest court for a final hearing, a process that could take years.</p>
<p>While De Benedetti is unlikely to serve any part of the sentence pending appeal, immediately after the verdict he stepped down from the board of Italy's employers&quot; association Confindustria, saying he wished to avoid causing embarrassment.</p>
<p>De Benedetti's career at Banco Ambrosiano was shortlived.</p>
<p>He was vice-president briefly at the end of 1981 and left seven months before the firm collapsed with $1 billion of debt and bank chairman Roberto Calvi was found hanging below London's Blackfriars Bridge later in 1982.</p>
<p>De Benedetti also spent three months as managing director of industrial giant Fiat in 1976 before a clash of policy with the Agnelli family forced him to stand down.</p>
<p>In 1988 he tried to take over Societe Generale de Belgique, a preserve of the French and Belgian financial establishment. But the bid was thwarted by a rival block of French and Belgian firms and it took three years for him to sell his stake.</p>
<p>Heavy debts built up by his companies during a period of corporate raiding eventually became too great to sustain and he was forced to sell assets to ease the debt burden.</p>
<p>Born into a prosperous Turin Jewish home on November 14, 1934, De Benedetti is married with three sons.</p>
<p>$1=1,514 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
