<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28522" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Investors bail out of Italy's Olivetti.</title>
<headline>Investors bail out of Italy's Olivetti.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in troubled information technology group Olivetti slumped seven percent on the Milan bourse on Tuesday, close to a record low, as speculation mounted over state of the company's health.</p>
<p>The rumour-ridden stock fell to 711 lire per share (47 cents) before inching back to stand 5.76 percent down at 721 lire by 1250 GMT, not far above the 681 lire historic low hit at the end of July this year.</p>
<p>&quot;What the small investor is seeing is a kind of Titanic and everyone is trying to bail out,&quot; said Alberto Rolla, analyst at brokers Pasfin in Milan.</p>
<p>A source close to the company said the group's board had called a meeting for later on Tuesday although confirmation was not available from Olivetti itself.</p>
<p>Analysts and traders said concern centred on the financial health of the company after newspapers reported rumours of renewed losses of 300 billion lire ($198 million) for the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I've heard the rumour of a 300 billion loss for the first half which would be a staggering number. That's the worry -- that there's another nasty surprise in terms of earnings, or lack of them,&quot; said an analyst at a UK securities house who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Many analysts expect the Olivetti to make a loss in 1996, although the company said early this year it hoped to return to the black this year.</p>
<p>Il Sole 24 Ore financial daily cited the possibility the group would make provisions for further restructuring charges, which would weigh on the balance sheet.</p>
<p>Olivetti launched a 2.257 trillion lire rights issue nearly year ago to restructure and then announced at the start of 1996 its restructuring charge would be higher than first expected.</p>
<p>Il Sole speculated the company would exit the highly competitive personal computer sector once and for all, leaving further losses on its balance sheet.</p>
<p>The stock, which has been on a steady overall decline since April 1994, took a steeper turn for the worse last week in the wake of news foreign institutional investors with a 25 percent shareholding met to force the company to boost its share value.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all rumour driven, but you know in Italy the market is never completely wrong,&quot; one trader here said.</p>
<p>Olivetti has not broken even since 1990 and made a record loss of 1.589 trillion lire ($1.05 billion) in 1995.</p>
<p>It will report its first half 1996 results on September 26 but said back in July its PC company, widely regarded as the biggest thorn in its side, made a pretax profit in the second quarter after a loss in the first.</p>
<p>Market disgruntlement spread to De Benedetti family holdings, with CIR ordinary shares down 4.17 percent at 742 lire and Cofide 2.8 percent weaker at 447 lire.</p>
<p>Analysts cited talk of conflict between chairman Carlo De Benedetti and new managing director Francesco Caio, who took over earlier this year after Corrado Passera resigned suddenly.</p>
<p>So far no one has been available for comment at Olivetti headquarters in the north western town of Ivrea and analysts say this is part of the stock's problem, with several saying they had called the group for clarification and got no response.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not talking,&quot; Rolla said. &quot;The fact that they are leaving the market without any information means that the market is wondering what is really happening.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile traders said the silence meant selling had snowballed as players watched other players and jumped on the bandwagon.</p>
<p>Company sources later confirmed De Benedetti was stepping down as chairman and would be replaced by a member of the board of directors Antonio Tesone, but a spokeswoman for the Olivetti group declined to comment, saying a statement was due later.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares fell more than five percent on the Milan bourse on Tuesday as rumours abounded about the company's financial problems and on talk of conflict between De Benedetti and new managing director Francesco Caio, who took over from Corrado Passera in July.</p>
<p>ANSA news agency later reported that De Benedetti would also leave the Olivetti board.</p>
<p>It said Caio would be in charge of day to day management, while the company was expected to set up an executive committee.  </p>
<p>$1=1,514 lire (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
