<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="28530" id="root" date="1996-09-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY PART 10/14.</title>
<headline>REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY PART 10/14.</headline>
<text>
<p>FRIDAY, NOVEMBER 29</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - European Parliament hosts conference on &quot;Europe and its nations - before Maastricht II&quot;. Participants include: European Commission President Jacques Santer and Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene.</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 2</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation for December 13-14 Dublin European Council:</p>
<p>- Commission report on the coordination of the Community's economic and structural policies.</p>
<p>- EIB loans to third countries.</p>
<p>- Taxation issues.</p>
<p>- SEM 2000 (sound and efficient management) final report of personal representatives group.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Protection of the financial interests of the Community:</p>
<p>- Monitoring of national measures;</p>
<p>- Extension of administrative controls and sanctions.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Social Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Follow-up of the Essen European Council: draft single report to the European Council of Dublin.</p>
<p>- Directive proposal on posting of workers in the framework of services.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive on the burden of proof in sex discrimination cases.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive modifying directive 76/207/EEC (Kalanke European Court of Justice judgment).</p>
<p>- Amendment to regulation on civil servants and students (social security for migrant workers).</p>
<p>- Proposed regulation on modification of regulations (EEC) 1408/71 and 574/72 (social security of migrant workers: beneficiaries of pre-retirement benefits).</p>
<p>- Proposed regulation on various modifications of the regulations on social security for migrant workers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposed regulation on codification of the regulations on social security for migrant workers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Draft resolution on lifelong learning.</p>
<p>- Draft resolution on the future of social protection.</p>
<p>LISBON - Statistics Office of the European Community (SOEC) holds summit.</p>
<p>TUESDAY, DECEMBER 3</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Energy Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive concerning common rules for the internal market in electricity.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive concerning common rules for the internal market in gas.</p>
<p>- White paper on energy: Community strategy on renewables.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on ALTENER II.</p>
<p>- White paper on energy: proposal for a decision on analysis and forecasts.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on SAVE II programme.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive on energy efficiency requirements for households: electric refrigerators, freezers and combinations thereof.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a regulation on a SYNERGY programme.</p>
<p>- Report on the situation of oil supply, refining and markets in the European Community.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a directive to introduce rational planning techniques in the electricity and gas distribution sectors.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision on the conclusion of the Energy Charter Treaty.</p>
<p>- Euro-Mediterranean conference.</p>
<p>- Revision of Community law in the energy sector.</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, DECEMBER 4</p>
<p>LONDON (NEW ITEM) - Financial Times (FT) hold conference on &quot;Venture '96 Europe&quot; (To December 6). Main topics discussed: overview of venture capital and buyouts markets in Europe; update on eastern Europe; fund raising for European investments; technology-a hot investment sector; mezzanine and senior debt-a look at availability and terms; managing the European portfolio; deal flow channels; exit and IPO markets in Europe. Contact: FT conferences (44) 171 896 2626.</p>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Research Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Financial supplement to the fourth framework programme/task force.</p>
<p>- Action plan on follow-up to the green paper on innovation.</p>
<p>- Fifth RTD framework programme.</p>
<p>- Presidency initiative on the contribution of research to drug detection and prevention of abuse.</p>
<p>- International cooperation in the RTD field:</p>
<p>- Science and technology cooperation strategy with central and eastern European countries;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Bilateral S/T agreements with several third countries.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on the EU and space.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on agronomic research for development.</p>
<p>- SMEs.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Fusion:</p>
<p>- ITER;</p>
<p>- Evaluation report from the Commission on the fusion programme.</p>
<p>- High flux reactor (HFR) programme.</p>
<p>CASABLANCA - Euro-Mediterranean summit of industrial federations.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, DECEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation of Dublin European Council.</p>
<p>- Discussion of 53rd U.N. Commission on human rights (including definition of EU position on China).</p>
<p>- Approval of policy document on peacekeeping operations.</p>
<p>- Submission of report on European armaments policy.</p>
<p>- Adoption of common position on U.N. register of conventional arms.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Middle East.</p>
<p>- Mediterranean policy:</p>
<p>- Report on the follow-up to the Barcelona Conference;</p>
<p>- Algeria and Egypt: decision to sign agreements;</p>
<p>- Syria: Commission proposal for a negotiating mandate.</p>
<p>- Preparation of EEA ministerial council.</p>
<p>- Internal financial regulation on ACP.</p>
<p>- Radiation protection of persons undergoing medical examination or treatment.</p>
<p>- Negotiating directives for a nuclear cooperation agreement between EURATOM and Japan.</p>
<p>- Approval of mandate to negotiate an agreement on wine with Slovakia, Slovenia and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>- Agreement on steel with central and eastern European countries.</p>
<p>- Approval of negotiating mandate for a partnership and cooperation agreement with Turkmenistan.</p>
<p>- Asia:</p>
<p>- Decision to sign a protocol relating to the accession of Vietnam to ASEAN;</p>
<p>- Preparation for EU-ASEAN ministerial (February 1997);</p>
<p>- Follow-up to Bangkok ASEM and preparation for Singapore ministerial.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign framework agreement with Australia.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign mutual recognition agreements with Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>- Decision on signature of free trade agreement with South Africa. END OF DOCUMENT</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 9</p>
<p>SINGAPORE (EXPANDED ITEM) - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (To December 13).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- (NEW ITEM) European Commissioner Brittan presents report on integrating multilateral clothing and textile pacts under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</p>
<p>- Review of the implementation of Uruguay Round commitments.</p>
<p>- Endorsement of results of negotiations on services.</p>
<p>- Report from the committee on trade and environment.</p>
<p>- Any other trade-related issues.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Environment Council (To December 10).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council on the review of the European Community programme of policy and action in relation to the environment and sustainable development &quot;Towards sustainability&quot;.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 90/219/EEC on the contained use of genetically modified micro-organisms.</p>
<p>- Auto oil:</p>
<p>a) Draft directive relating to the quality of petrol and diesel fuels;</p>
<p>b) Draft directive on measures against air pollution by emissions from motor vehicules - amendment of directives 70/229//EEC and 70/156/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive concerning the quality of water intended for human consumption.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on waste policy.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council regulation (EEC) No 3254/91 prohibiting the use of leghold traps in the Community and the introduction into the Community of pelts and manufactured goods of certain wild animal species originating in countries which catch them by means of leghold traps or trapping methods which do not meet international humane trapping standards.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation establishing common rules and procedures to apply to the shipments to certain non-OECD countries of certain types of waste.</p>
<p>- Follow-up to the conference on climate change.</p>
<p>- Fifth session of the Commission on sustainable development.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To December 13).</p>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Transport Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- External relations:</p>
<p>- Relations with the United States in the field of air transport.</p>
<p>- Recommendation for a Council decision authorising the Commission to open negotiations on air transport agreements between the Community and Bulgaria, the Czech Republic, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Slovakia.</p>
<p>- Negotiations between the European Community and Switzerland on land and air transport.</p>
<p>- Other measures:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to green paper on the citizens' network.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to green paper on internalisation of external costs.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal for an European Parliament and Council directive on summertime arrangements.</p>
<p>- Surface transport:</p>
<p>a) Rail transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to the white paper on the future of the railways.</p>
<p>b) Road transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Access to the road haulage profession.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Taxation of goods vehicles to replace directive 93/89/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation laying down the conditions under which non-resident carriers may operate national road passenger transport services within a member state.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council directive and regulation on recording equipment in road transport.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation (EEC) No 684/92 on common rules for the international carriage of passengers by coach and bus.</p>
<p>- Air transport:</p>
<p>- Follow-up to white paper on air traffic management.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Follow-up to high level group on air safety.</p>
<p>- Proposal for the establishment of a single European authority for air safety.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal on airport charges.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation on air carrier liability in case of accidents.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Revision of regulation on slot allocation.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposals to update rules on denied boarding compensation and passenger protection.</p>
<p>- Maritime transport:</p>
<p>- (possibly) Licensing regime for roll-on roll-off ferry operations.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Compiling lists of passengers on roll-on roll-off ferries.</p>
<p>- Proposal for Council directive setting up a harmonised safety regime for fishing vessels of 24 metres in length and over.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Commission strategic document.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal to amend Council directive 94/58/EC on the minimum level of training of seafarers.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Proposal to amend Council directive 93/75/EEC concerning minimum requirements for vessels bound for or leaving Community ports and carrying dangerous or polluting goods.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Shipping agreements with third countries, especially China and India.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Report on competition in the multimodal sector.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, DECEMBER 13</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Irish presidency hosts European Council of heads of state and government (To December 14).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Council report on the development of tax systems within the Union, taking into account the need to create a tax environment that stimulates business and the creation of jobs and promotes a more efficient environmental policy.</p>
<p>- Commission and European Monetary Institute (EMI) report on progress in stage three of European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>- Commission report on subsidiarity.</p>
<p>- Presentation of draft revision of the treaties, addressing in particular:</p>
<p>* Bringing the Union closer to its citizens;</p>
<p>* Strengthening and enlarging the scope of the Union's common foreign and security policy;</p>
<p>* Assuring, in view of enlargement, the proper functioning of the institutions while respecting their balance of powers and the efficiency of the decision-making process;</p>
<p>* Simplification of the treaties.</p>
<p>- Commission report on appropriate initiatives for reinforcing regional cooperation in Europe.</p>
<p>- Report on the evolution of the trade policies and the preferential agreements of the Community in relation to the World Trade Organisation (WTO).</p>
<p>- Final European Commission report on the mutually beneficial effects of greater coordination of the Union's economic and structural policies.</p>
<p>- Review of December 1995 Madrid summit recommendations on fighting unemployment and on application of multiannual employment programmes.</p>
<p>- Joint ECOFIN/Social Affairs Council annual employment monitoring report.</p>
<p>- Review of progress in application of Madrid December 1995 drug experts group report on the fight against drugs.</p>
<p>- Territorial pacts for employment within the framework of the confidence pact for employment. END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
