<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31027" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Boeing and Airbus in air show sales bonanza.</title>
<headline>Boeing and Airbus in air show sales bonanza.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arch rivals Boeing and Airbus gave the aviation industry a major post-recession boost on Wednesday, announcing billion dollar orders at Britain's biggest airshow.</p>
<p>World leader Boeing added to bulging order books with a $1.18 billion deal to sell seven 747-400 jumbo jets to Philippine Airlines.</p>
<p>Not to be outdone in their fierce sales war, the European Airbus Industrie group said it expected another $5 billion of orders to be confirmed soon.</p>
<p>Total sales announced at the aviation showcase by the two top manufacturers alone have now topped $10 billion after just three days of spirited dealings.</p>
<p>This is in sharp contrast to the $3 billion total for the whole industry at the last Farnborough show in 1994.</p>
<p>Boeing and Airbus bickered over market share and argued over the value of producing a new &quot;superjumbo&quot;. But both agreed that business was brisk.</p>
<p>&quot;Traffic is up and airline profits are up,&quot; said Boeing Commercial Airplane Group President Ron Woodard.</p>
<p>Airbus's chief operating officer, Volker von Tein, echoed his optimism, saying: &quot;A number of airlines, after many years of deficit, are trading at a profit.&quot;</p>
<p>But with development costs soaring and competition stiff, the message from civil aviation and defence industry chiefs was the same -- mergers are vital to survival.</p>
<p>&quot;The projects of tomorrow are going to be very, very expensive,&quot; Britain's deputy prime minister, Michael Heseltine, warned when opening the show on Monday.</p>
<p>U.S manufacturers have bitten the bullet with a series of mega-mergers. Europe will have to follow suit to compete, industry chiefs say.</p>
<p>Britain gave the production go-ahead for 232 Eurofighter combat jets, a major boost for its joint venture with Germany, Italy and Spain that has been dogged by years of political wrangling and cost overruns.</p>
<p>With 70,000 jobs across the continent depending on the Eurofighter, trade unions urged Britain's three partners to sign up.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident the British decision will put pressure on our government to make its own decision,&quot; said German trade union spokeswoman Ingrid Lullmann.</p>
<p>In a joint statement, the unions also urged France and Germany not to abandon European industry plans to develop a rival to Lockheed's Hercules military transporter.</p>
<p>The members of the four-nation Airbus Industrie consortium are pressing ahead with plans to merge their civil aircraft production plants into one company.</p>
<p>But there are also aspirations within the group to take over and consolidate Europe's defence industry.</p>
<p>Airbus is a consortium comprising Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace, British Aerospace, Aerospatiale of France and Spain's CASA.</p>
<p>&quot;Potentially this is going to be the biggest industrial company in Europe,&quot; said Sir Richard Evans, chief executive of British Aerospace.</p>
<p>The Airbus consortium said it was pressing ahead with plans to build the world's biggest passenger jet despite warnings from Boeing that the &quot;superjumbo&quot; market was not big enough for both of them.</p>
<p>Boeing, weighing a $5 billion plan to build a stretch version of its 747 jumbo, said Airbus would be committing financial suicide with its $8 billion project, the 550-seat A3XX.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
