<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31033" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME options declaration calm despite early jitters.</title>
<headline>LME options declaration calm despite early jitters.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett-White</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The September London Metal Exchange (LME) options declaration passed smoothly on Wednesday despite an early scare when copper prices probed higher.</p>
<p>Options market makers were mostly short of calls at $2,100 a tonne, and when three months copper touched $2,070 on the pre-market September copper was valued at around $2,100.</p>
<p>Some futures buying emerged from the options market as a cover against the calls, but calm was quickly restored when the market drifted back.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a bit touch-and-go when we got to $2,100 early on, and options related buying emerged just prior to that,&quot; said one options trader. &quot;But in the end it was all very easy. Calm prevailed in the end,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;The declaration was dead after the intial small run up,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>In the event September copper was indicated at around $2,075 at declaration, comfortably between the $2,050 and $2,100 strikes. Calls at $2,100 were abandoned and puts declared.</p>
<p>Open interest on $2,100 calls was large at 2,169 lots (equivalent to 54,225 tonnes) as at the close of trade Tuesday.</p>
<p>There was also sizeable open interest on $2,000 calls (1,475 lots, or 36,875 tonnes) and $2,200 calls (1,050 lots, or 26,250 tonnes). Put open interest at $2,000 and $2,100 was smaller, but at $2,200 it was a hefty 1,838 lots (45,950 tonnes). Market makers were generally short of calls at the $2,100 and $2,200 strikes, helping to push copper values sharply higher on Monday when September copper briefly rose above $2,200.</p>
<p>&quot;Market makers were short of these calls and that is why we got such a violent move up and very soon after a move straight back down again,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>As well as covering on the futures market, dealers rushed to buy nearby options as an alternative source of cover, forcing volatilities sharply higher before they began to ease again.</p>
<p>September was said by some dealers to have traded as high as 75 percent volatility earlier this week.</p>
<p>The excercise was an expensive one for some players on the options market, many having lost large amounts of money during the plunge in prices in May and June.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one step forward, two steps back for a lot of options players at the moment,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Soon after the declaration copper prices fell back sharply, losing $30 during the official ring.</p>
<p>But options traders said the move was not obviously related to the options market.</p>
<p>The only other areas of interest at declaration were in aluminium and lead.</p>
<p>September aluminium values were indicated at $1,475 at the time of declaration, and calls at that strike were partially declared while puts were abandoned, traders said.</p>
<p>Open interest was not large and underlying futures prices have been stable throughout the morning session.</p>
<p>Call option open interest at $1,475 on Tuesday was 440 lots (11,000 tonnes) and on puts 429 lots (10,725 tonnes).</p>
<p>Lead calls at $825 were also partially declared, although open interest on those options was small at 80 lots (2,000 tonnes).</p>
<p>All other base metals settled between strike prices and failed to feature at declaration, options traders said.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 181 542 8057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
