<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31030" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Rangebound bourses cool on second U.S. raid.</title>
<headline>Rangebound bourses cool on second U.S. raid.</headline>
<byline>Eric Meijer</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European financial markets took news of a second U.S. attack on Iraq in their stride on Wednesday, marking stocks higher, the dollar steady and gold lower.</p>
<p>British shares, buoyed by a rebound in Wall Street stocks and bonds overnight, held opening gains which reversed the bulk of their previous day's losses.</p>
<p>An agreed 264 million pound ($412.1 million) bid by food distributor Booker for food wholesaler Nurdin &amp; Peacock also helped sentiment, sending the blue chip FTSE 100 index up 25 points.</p>
<p>Yet traders said the London market was likely to be quiet ahead of Wednesday's monetary meeting between Governor of the Bank of England Eddie George and finance minister Kenneth Clarke.</p>
<p>German shares hovered at higher levels mid way through bourse trade but were off earlier peaks.</p>
<p>Dealers said that trade was likely to be steady, but the focus was definitely on key U.S. non-farm payroll data for August due on Friday, which could set the tone for U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>In Paris, French stocks also opened higher, helped by firmer bond prices and Wall Street's strong close.</p>
<p>Oil stocks Total and Elf-Aquitaine, which have risen on the back of higher oil prices, extended their gains after Total confirmed investor expectations of good results by reporting a 45 percent jump in its first-half profit.</p>
<p>The CAC-40 index was up around 15 points, but still below the 2,000 level.</p>
<p>In currencies, the dollar was slightly firmer against the mark and off its earlier lows against the yen in a quiet European midsession.</p>
<p>Dealers said market attention had shifted from the U.S. attacks in Iraq to Thursday's German GDP data and, more importantly, Friday's U.S. jobs figures against a backdrop of growing expectations of higher U.S. rates near-term.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a waiting game now until Friday, no one's willing to stick their neck out ahead of the payrolls,&quot; said a dealer at a U.S. bank here. &quot;The Iraq story is still there but it's been moved very much in the background now.&quot;</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar was firmer from earlier levels but just below 109 yen.</p>
<p>The yen was also firmer against the mark as the initial impact of the U.S./Iraq tensions faded and earlier concerns eased over the effect of higher oil prices on Japan and its high dependency on dollar priced oil imports.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1100 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was trading at 1.4856 marks and 108.95 yen after 1.4837 marks and 109.25 yen on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1100 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was up 23.3 points at 3,879.2.</p>
<p>Frankfurt's 30-share DAX index was 21.16 up at 2,532.37. The IBIS DAX was up 4.90 at 2,533.63.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was up 15.56 at 1,987.10.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed at $385.95 against $386.60 on Tuesday afternoon and $387.20 in the morning. It dipped below $386 on London-based selling after showing little initial reaction to the second missile attack by the U.S. on Iraq. Silver was lower with gold at $5.15, down three cents. Platinum was off $1.00 at $394.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
