<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31036" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyd's rings the bell to celebrate rescue.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's rings the bell to celebrate rescue.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London celebrated the successful outcome of its recovery plan Wednesday as Chairman David Rowland and British Trade Minister Anthony Nelson joined to ring the Lutine bell, the market's traditional symbol.</p>
<p>The ceremony in the insurance market's modernistic building in London's financial district followed government approval of the plan, which will allow its long-suffering investors finally to walk free of past liabilities.</p>
<p>Rowland and Nelson together rang the bell, named after an 18th century French frigate from which it was salvaged, an unprecedented three times. The Lutine bell traditionally was rung once for bad news -- such as the loss of a ship at sea -- and twice for good news.</p>
<p>Hundreds of underwriters and brokers, many of whom were Names, as investors in Lloyd's are known, hung over balconies in the building to watch, along with corporation employees.</p>
<p>Rowland told the crowd that final agreement on the rescue plan, under which Lloyd's will reinsure billions of pounds in past liabilities into a new company, Equitas, was completed just before midnight on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Rowland said the first ring on Wednesday was for sorrow, to mark and remember an episode in Lloyd's history that has caused pain and suffering for many people. The second strike was for joy, and the unprecedented third ring signalled that the market was now moving into a new phase.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that no chairman will have to ring the bell three times again. The third strike is always to remind us what actually happened and never to forget it. We came close to disaster and we should never let it happen again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The plan won resounding support last week as 91 percent of Names voted to accept a 3.2 billion pound ($5 billion) settlement offer from Lloyd's. Government approval was the final hurdle to securing the market's future.</p>
<p>The plan had been opposed by 93 U.S. investors, but their appeal was rejected by a federal court last month.</p>
<p>Under the recovery plan, Lloyd's ends years of uncertainty over the scale of massive losses suffered by some investors as a result of unlimited liability to past claims, including those relating to U.S. environmental and asbestos insurance.</p>
<p>Lloyd's problems started in the 1980s, when a string of natural disasters, negligent underwriting and a reinsurance spiral led to over 8.0 billion pounds ($12.5 billion) in losses from 1988 to 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;The message will go out, not just to London and the country, but to the world today that Lloyd's has found a solution to its own problems,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
<p>The DTI said in a statement that it has required Lloyd's to provide up to an extra 100 million pounds ($156 million) to mitigate the effects on the reserves of Equitas of lower-than-projected interest rates or a shortfall in the contributions due from agents or brokers, if so requested by Equitas, in January 2002.</p>
<p>Rowland told reporters that Lloyd's was likely to decide closer to the time how it would fund this if asked to do so.</p>
<p>Equitas at the end of last year was expected to have 14.7 billion pounds  ($23 billion) in assets. Since then, up to three billion pounds ($4.7 billion) in claims have been paid off and an audit, which will assess the company as of Wednesday, will be completed by the end of this year.</p>
<p>Names have until the end of this month to pay final bills and those who have not accepted the plan yet have until September to do so.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
