<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31038" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DMG funds face heavy redemptions, confidence knock.</title>
<headline>DMG funds face heavy redemptions, confidence knock.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Substantial redemptions are expected in the Morgan Grenfell funds lifted from suspension to resume trade on Thursday, with doubts remaining about controls and valuation methods at the blue-chip investment house.</p>
<p>The three European funds were suspended on Monday pending an unofficial investigation by regulators into holdings of unquoted and pre-listed (those to be quoted within a year) stocks.</p>
<p>Fund managers said Deutsche Bank's announcement that it would cover all liabilities regarding the investigation and its purchase of some of the unquoted stock for its own account had reassured some of the 90,000 smaller investors.</p>
<p>&quot;They are doing the right thing,&quot; said an Edinburgh-based fund manager who declined to be named. &quot;Deutsche Bank will take it on the chin. But the funds must expect large redemptions (selling) in coming weeks because confidence has taken a knock.&quot;</p>
<p>Peter Jeffreys, director at Fund Research agrees.</p>
<p>&quot;They probably will face redemptions because the independent financial advisors will pull clients out. But it's panic selling. Morgan Grenfell has one of the strongest teams on Europe and they are acting impeccably.&quot;</p>
<p>The MG European Growth fund is AAA rated by Fund Reasearch.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank has already put up a sum thought to be around 200 million stg to buy the funds' unquoted stocks of &quot;questionable&quot; valuation and take them onto their own books.</p>
<p>So far there is no indication of exactly how that judgement, the focus of the UK regulatory enquiries, has been made. A spokesman for Morgan Grenfell said some unquoted stock remained in the funds but it totalled less than 10 percent. The funds were also now cash-rich because of the injection from Deutsche Bank and &quot;a strong positive cash flow from before&quot;.</p>
<p>That will allow incoming fund manager Stuart Mitchell some leeway, but other managers maintain he will be pressured if heavy redemptions force him into a fire sale of assets.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously unquoted and pre-listed stocks are not liquid but even the quoted stocks they have are not very liquid,&quot; noted a UK pension fund manager. &quot;Some have been marked down in the last few days already.&quot; Citing the end-May European Growth Trust report portfolio breakdown, he asked, &quot;What is a fund like this doing holding stocks in Cyprus, Malta, Canada and the British Virgin Islands?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A standard European unit trust is not the sort of vehicle to hold unquoteds -- they are difficult to keep track of. Maybe the rules allow it, but is it really defensible? It depends on what they have told investors but you have to ask where savvy stops and where trying to walk on water starts.&quot;</p>
<p>Other fund managers acknowledge they routinely buy prelisted stock as a way of adding value. &quot;If you can get in before flotation, you can get a bigger position and it's sometimes cheaper,&quot; noted one. &quot;But at MG it clearly got out of hand.&quot;</p>
<p>Stuart Mitchell has replaced Peter Young as manager of the European Growth Trust and the European Capital Growth Fund.</p>
<p>He joined Morgan Grenfell nine years ago and managed the offshore MG European Profound fund, which has been third out of 31 funds in its sector over the five years to end-September 1995.</p>
<p>The Morgan Grenfell spokesman said Mitchell would meet IFAs in the next three weeks. &quot;We hope they will listen to his strategy and give him an opportunity to deliver. The point is that since the bank stepped in, the price should not be affected too much at the start of trading tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>But one fund manager noted some investment houses are already offering free switches out of the Morgan Grenfell funds.</p>
<p>&quot;The vultures are gathering. Yes, it is an unhappy situation and it may be an aberration, but for someone it's an opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
