<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31041" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Autumn rise unlikely for most ex-UKair cargo rates.</title>
<headline>Autumn rise unlikely for most ex-UKair cargo rates.</headline>
<byline>Humphrey Hudson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Any general increase in ex-UK air cargo rates is now not expected this autumn with the next rises, mostly seen for April, although possibly in January for some carriers, a Reuter survey shows.</p>
<p>However this overall pattern does not exclude some changes on selected routes. Ex-London, Lufthansa is planning a three percent rise to Tokyo and five percent to Seoul from October, while American Airlines has introduced a five percent increase to the U.S. from September I.</p>
<p>Continental Europe has seen more announcements of increases reflecting the need by some carriers to rebuild yields. Lufthansa has said rates to Bangkok, Hong Kong and Singapore will go up by just under 10 percent with five percent to Brazil and Canada. Singapore Airlines and Varig have also announced ex-Frankfurt rises.</p>
<p>Korean Airlines is looking for 5 to 10 percent to Japan and Korea from Europe; Air Hong Kong is seeking a &quot;small&quot; increase from October and may be followed by Cathay Pacific in Europe -- but not London -- while Eva Air announced a 5 to 10 percent rise from September.</p>
<p>Industry sources said the UK market's attitude reflects the view amongst leading carriers that rates should not necessarily be increased at the first opportunity and also the importance of long-term relationships with key customers for whom stable rates are an important consideration.</p>
<p>By next year, many ex-UK rates will not have been formally increased for a year and even 18 months in some cases. The market was weak earlier in 1996 but a pickup in volumes, first to north-east Asia, then all of Asia as well as Latin America took place from June onwards, the sources added.</p>
<p>The market is now looking to the last four months of the year to provide its traditional upswing in demand. The first signs are that September is already holding its promises, and a further strengthening is expected from October onwards, the sources said.</p>
<p>Business to north Asia continues to maintain its strength with high cargo loads reported. Rates for 100 kg average around 1.95 stg a kg to Tokyo, against 1.92 stg on a fortnight ago. Seoul is slightly firmer at 1.82 stg compared to the previous 1.80 stg.</p>
<p>All Nippon Airlines' John O'Shea said there are &quot;no plans to put up rates for this calendar year. People are still cautious&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;August was a very steady strong month and the forecast for October and November demand is very good,&quot; said Tony Edwards, Japan Airlines cargo manager adding &quot;that the target for the next rate increase appears to be next April&quot;.</p>
<p>Korea continues to airfreight imports of industrial equipment from the UK, including machinery for the automobile industry. Korean Airlines cargo manager, Frank Smith said: &quot; We have been asked to consider an October increase but the general feeling is that rates will hold till April.&quot;</p>
<p>Asian carriers also report small but steady business in moving computer-industry related products from Ireland to the Far East, especially to Japan. One source said that a south-east Asian carrier might begin a service from Dublin to capitalise on the country's growing exports.</p>
<p>To Hong Kong rates are marginally lower on average at 1.18 stg a kg, but steady at 1.23 stg to Singapore.</p>
<p>Cathay Pacific's cargo manager, Mark Olney, said business was steady on all routes with the airline holding its market share despite more competition on the Hong Kong-London route.</p>
<p>He did not see &quot;rate increases till next April&quot; and then after discussions with freight forwarders and shippers. This could also be an opportunity for an extension of Cathay's longer-term contracts with its customers, he said.</p>
<p>Olney, as head of an airline stressing customer service, is behind an initial London meeting, planned for late September, between carriers, forwarders and shippers to discuss how to harmonise industry quality standards.</p>
<p>Thai's Mike Miller said &quot;business remains very good indeed, still extremely strong&quot; for virtually all its destinations. There is strong demand for transhipment business to Shanghai -- a trend seen in continental Europe -- at rates of around 1.50 stg.</p>
<p>&quot;Rates will probably be held till next April, the market needs a bit of breathing space,&quot; Miller added.</p>
<p>High load factors and stable rates were reported by Singapore Airlines and:&quot;We are not anticipating any increases this October,&quot; said cargo manager, Barry Gibson.</p>
<p>A decline in transatlantic cargo capacity, made available by the reduction in summer charter passenger flights, together with the expected seasonal strengthening in demand, means there is some modest optimism for North Atlantic routes.</p>
<p>But so far, other carriers have not followed American Airlines' five percent increase and industry sources have mixed views as how this will really impact on the market. They also note there is some &quot;predatory pricing at ridiculous levels&quot; by certain lower-tier or infrequent carriers.</p>
<p>Northwest Airlines cargo manager,Brian Mutton said:&quot;We're not planning any increases from October 1.&quot;</p>
<p>Average rates to JKF are still around 0.60 stg a kg compared to 0.62 stg previously. Los Angeles gains one pence to 0.71 stg and Chicago is steady around 0.68 to O.70 stg, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Tighter U.S. security regulations following the TWA disaster may also affect incoming bellyhold cargo on passenger aircraft, offering a potential benefit to all-freighter operations, the sources added.</p>
<p>There is an increasing trend towards using express airfreight for &quot;low-technology&quot; shipments, e.g. textile machinery, to the Americas, an Emery Worldwide executive said.</p>
<p>This enables exporters from the UK and Europe to compete on virtually equal terms with U.S.based competitors in meeting highly-competitive tight delivery times, he added.</p>
<p>Rates to Latin America are around the two stg to 2.05 stg level and despite some reports of weakness earlier in the year, business is supported by strong demand. This applies to Brazil -- partly stimulated by growing foreign investment in the automobile industry -- but also to Buenos Aires and Santiago in Chile, they added.</p>
<p>Mexico is another destination growing in importance, they said.</p>
<p>Cargo competition on these routes is also generated by the large number of holiday passenger flights to Miami and Orlando. Linked to onward shipment to Latin America by highly competitive U.S. carriers, cargo rates &quot;are cheap, in some cases less than one stg a kg,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>Iberia cargo manager Antonio Ares described business as &quot;quite encouraging.&quot; However the Spanish-based carrier &quot;is not planning any rates increase this autumn, as these will be reviewed towards the end of the year with any possible rise in January, he added.</p>
<p>Routes to the Middle East, are starting to show the first signs of the seasonal pickup in traffic expected between now and the year-end with the next couple of months already showing signs of good business. Business for the Far East via the Gulf is healthy, with Bangkok in demand.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no change in rates for the moment. They are valid till the end of October and will be reviewed at the end of the month, but I'm not anticipating any major increases&quot; said Emirates cargo manager, Ray Disson.</p>
<p>Average rates to Dubai and Bahrain remain steady at around the 0.70 stg and O.85 level respectively.</p>
<p>The inward South African cargo market, despite substantial capacity, continues to generate new inbound business. Virgin Atlantic Airways will start a scheduled services there in October and the market &quot;awaits their rates with interest,&quot; an industry source said.</p>
<p>Rates to Johannesburg range widely but have eased to around 1.68 stg a kg from the earlier 1.7I. However there is wide competition on the route with some top-name carriers quoting around 1.85 stg a kg and other lower-tier indirect airlines offering as low as 0.85 kg, a source said.</p>
<p>Bob Bingley, Lufthansa cargo manager, said the carrier has chartered a DC-8-55 freighter to operate a Saturday service from Gatwick to Nairobi, where cargo will be switched to Lufthansa Boeing 747 freighters en route to South Africa.</p>
<p>European markets recorded a mixed August, reflecting the holiday season and weak economies, but apart from the hoped-for seasonal recovery, there also signs that markets &quot;are stirring more than we expected.&quot; CIS states are seen as offering considerable potential as oil and mining explorations gets under way.</p>
<p>&quot;Rate changes are made purely to reflect inflation and if there are any, they could be in January or February&quot; said SAS cargo manager, Howard Jones. - Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 8982 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
