<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31048" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK warns Islamic rally not to support &quot;terrorism&quot;.</title>
<headline>UK warns Islamic rally not to support &quot;terrorism&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain has warned organisers of Sunday's Islamic &quot;Rally for Revival&quot; that it will not tolerate statements supporting guerrilla violence.</p>
<p>In a tersely worded statement, the Home Office (interior ministry) said on Wednesday that it would order the arrest of anyone who advocated violence and social unrest.</p>
<p>&quot;The British government condemns any statement made at the rally in support of terrorism, or violence more generally. We will ensure that the rule of law in this country is upheld,&quot; the government said.</p>
<p>&quot;This rally will be monitored and anyone who breaks the law, whether by their statements or actions, will face prosecution.&quot;</p>
<p>The rally is being organised by al-Muhajiroun, an organisation which had advocated a holy war against most governments in the Middle East. It is led by Sheikh Omar Bakri Mohammed, a militant Syrian who has called for a worldwide Islamic state.</p>
<p>Britain has been under pressure from foreign allies, including Egypt and Algeria which both face internal Islamic challenges, to ban the event in the Docklands financial district of the British capital.</p>
<p>Academics and representatives from most of the Islamic movements around the world are planning to attend the rally.</p>
<p>Some of the world's most wanted radicals including Omar Abdul-Rahman, the 65-year-old sheikh who was jailed for life for his alleged role in the bombing of the World Trade Centre in New York, are also expected to address the conference through pre-recorded videos.</p>
<p>Muhammad al-Masari, a London-based Saudi disssident who recently won his fight against deportation and has been criticised for comments about Jews, will also attend.</p>
<p>Jewish groups in Britain have voiced concern about the conference but the government insists it has no legal grounds on which to ban the event.</p>
<p>&quot;People who wish to hold conferences of course don't need to seek permission from the government in Britain,&quot; Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said during a visit to Pakistan on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
