<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31057" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Politicians and psychopaths cut from same cloth?.</title>
<headline>Politicians and psychopaths cut from same cloth?.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Politicians and criminal psychopaths share some important behavioural characteristics, a leading British psychologist said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Psychopaths lie easily. They get pleasure from duping people whereas politicians lie for a purpose,&quot; David Cook, a lecturer at Glasgow's Caledonian University, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Cook and graduate student, Lisa Marshall, presented the findings of a three-year study on the causes of psychopathic behavior to the British Psychological Society's annual conference in York, northern England.</p>
<p>They interviewed 105 repeat offenders in Scottish prisons and found that a combination of social and biological factors contributed to psychopathic behaviour.</p>
<p>&quot;Difficult childhoods tended to be a common thread,&quot; Cook said, adding that the purpose of the study was not to discover if politicians were psychopaths but to understand what factors triggered the behaviour.</p>
<p>&quot;To say politicians are psychopaths is a bit of a distortion,&quot; Cook said, but he acknowledged that the two groups appeared to share some similar behaviour patterns.</p>
<p>&quot;Psychopaths tend to be grandiose, they don't feel remorse, they don't feel guilt and they don't maintain stable relationships,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Marshall said people in high-powered careers such as politics and stockbroking shared enough characteristics to be defined as psychopathic.</p>
<p>&quot;They have the characteristics of psychopaths but without the criminal intent,&quot; she told the conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cook believes it will be difficult to scientifically prove that to be a successful politician or stockbroker a person needs to be a psychopath.</p>
<p>&quot;The trouble is there just isn't any data. Politicians and stockbrokers don't like to be studied,&quot; Cook said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
