<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31069" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Saddam's forces seen in poor shape.</title>
<headline>Saddam's forces seen in poor shape.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saddam Hussein's military machine is less than half the size it was when the Iraqi leader invaded Kuwait in 1990 and in worse fighting shape than before its crushing defeat in Operation Desert Storm.</p>
<p>Despite Baghdad's bellicose reaction to two days of U.S. cruise missile attacks, military experts believe that the Iraqi army and air force can take on Kurdish guerrillas but are ill-prepared for any encounter with forces equipped to Western standards.</p>
<p>The authoritative, London-based International Institute for Strategic Studies estimates the current strength of the Iraqi army at 350,000, including 100,000 men recalled from the reserves, compared with a total of 955,000 before the Gulf War.</p>
<p>The Republican Guard, comprising about 50,000 men deployed in four mechanised and three infantry divisions, remains Saddam's elite force, with better equipment and higher morale than the rest of the army, but that may not be saying much.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't suppose they are better trained now than they were during the the Gulf War and they didn't acquit themselves particularly well then,&quot; said Philip Mitchell of IISS.</p>
<p>Like the rest of the Iraqi armed forces, the Republican Guard mounted no credible resistance to the massive force of the U.S.-led coalition that defeated Iraq in 1991, knocking out most of the 42 divisions Saddam put into the battlefield.</p>
<p>The Republican Guard are equipped with a number of relatively modern T-72 tanks and it is thought likely that Saddam will have made it a priority to buy enough spares on the black markets of the former Soviet Union to keep them combat-ready.</p>
<p>The rest of the 2,700-strong tank force is likely to be poorly maintained and it is questionable whether they can be brought to the battlefield.</p>
<p>Iraq also has a number of old, British-made Chieftain tanks captured during its war with Iran during the 1980s and these are almost certainly unserviceable.</p>
<p>The remainder of the Iraqi army is poorly trained and equipped, tasked mainly with guarding towns and barracks, and lacking the necessary motivation to fight, Mitchell said.</p>
<p>The Iraqi air force now has just over 300 combat aircraft, compared with more than 500 in 1990.</p>
<p>IISS estimates that no more than 55 percent of the Iraqi air force's fighters and ground attack aircraft are operational, with its Western Mirages and F7s suffering from lack of spares more than the Soviet and Chinese built aircraft.</p>
<p>Despite media reports to the contrary, the IISS believes that sanctions-hit Iraq has not been able to find the cash to buy more combat aircraft or tanks on the black market to replace Gulf War losses.</p>
<p>Nearly 150 Iraqi combat aircraft which fled to neutral Iran at an early stage of the Gulf War have not been returned.</p>
<p>While Iraq has rebuilt part of the command and control structure that was knocked out in the Gulf War, the U.S. cruise missile attacks will probably have dealt it further damage, hampering Iraq's air force and air defence missile systems.</p>
<p>&quot;By sending in cruise missiles they want to degrade the Iraqi air defence set-up -- missiles and radar,&quot; said Ken Petrie of IISS. &quot;They are trying to blind them.&quot;</p>
<p>Moving the Western-imposed air exclusion zone further north towards Baghdad will further harm the effectiveness of the Iraqi air force because the zone now takes in two major air bases.</p>
<p>This could tempt the Iraqi air defence forces to &quot;have a go&quot; at patrolling Western aircraft, Petrie said. The response would be to attack Iraqi missile sites with missiles that fly down the radar beams used to target overflying aircraft.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
