<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31075" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Short-termism - Is it choking British industry?.</title>
<headline>Short-termism - Is it choking British industry?.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's industrial leaders have hotly refuted accusations that the UK financial system has damagingly short-term demands and hinders vital investment.</p>
<p>Leading UK employers group, the Institute of Directors, said the idea that Britain's financial system is riven with short-termism was a fallacy.</p>
<p>It noted the success of British pharmaceutical firms in recent years and the ease with which biotechnology firms have raised capital on the London Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;This provides clear evidence of the ability and willingness of the UK's financial system to raise finance for investments whose returns may take many years to be realised,&quot; said IoD executive Stephen Davies.</p>
<p>The main charge of short-termism is that financial institutions, who hold share stakes in many of Britain's major companies, consistently demand high short-term returns -- large profits generating hefty dividend payouts.</p>
<p>Share buybacks are also a popular ploy. There, a company spends millions of pounds buying back its own stock to boost the share price, thus keeping hungry shareholders happy and warding off the attentions of potential takeover predators.</p>
<p>The short-termism debate was ignited last year by Will Hutton, editor of Britain's Observer newspaper and author of the best-selling book, &quot;The State We're In&quot;. In it, he said the UK's economic performance was undermined by short-termism.</p>
<p>Be it high dividend payouts or share buybacks, capital that could be earmarked for much-needed investment, goes elsewhere. That, Hutton argued, is eating away Britain's industrial base.</p>
<p>Andrew Sentance, director of the London Business School's Centre for Economic Forecasting, said the pressure on managers to maximise short-term profits was probably greater in Britain than in other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;If you talk to British managers, there is undoubtedly a perception of pressures on them to think more short-term than in other countries such as Germany and Japan.&quot;</p>
<p>He said an at-best average investment performance gave some credence to the allegation of short-termism but to blame that entirely on stock market attitudes was a leap too far.</p>
<p>The volatility of UK economic policy, leading to a &quot;boom/bust&quot; economy in the 1970s and 1980s, had made long-term strategy difficult for British companies, he said.</p>
<p>He also highlighted the incentive for managers holding stock options and similar bonuses to ensure their company's share price does not drop for any significant period of time.</p>
<p>Davies at the IoD chose to view Britain's average investment performance as more of a sign of success than failure. Taking the share of fixed investment in gross domestic product as a measure, he said Britain hovered about mid-table compared with its major industrial counterparts.</p>
<p>Most experts agreed that short-termism is there in certain guises but it has positive as well as negative influences.</p>
<p>&quot;If a company is not generating profits short-term, the question would have to be whether it would long-term,&quot; Sentance said. &quot;To some extent, the pressure from the City and elsewhere helps ensure levels of efficiency.&quot;</p>
<p>Ian Fletcher, policy executive at the British Chambers of Commerce, said financing problems may be more acute for smaller and medium-sized UK enterprises (SMEs) than for high flyers on the FTSE-100 index of leading firms.</p>
<p>There, potentially high-return ventures attract floods of capital, while the rest are ignored.</p>
<p>&quot;For SMEs, expectations are very high, perhaps more so than for firms properly quoted on the stock market,&quot; Fletcher said. &quot;Investments can double or triple quickly but they are the exception. Many firms find it hard to attract finance at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Even the IoD acknowledged smaller firms in Britain may have a tough time luring funds looking for a quick return. It said the UK had a less effective framework for solving the funding problems of smaller businesses than in other European countries.</p>
<p>But overall, it stuck to it's guns. Hutton's charge that the stock market system demands high returns from companies at the expense of investment is unfounded. &quot;The truth is the opposite,&quot; Davies said. &quot;UK industry has actually achieved relatively low profits compared with its competitors.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
