<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31070" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia Aug fuel oil sales to Europe rise from July.</title>
<headline>Russia Aug fuel oil sales to Europe rise from July.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Shaxson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian fuel oil exports to Western Europe totalled 1.7 to 1.9 million tonnes in August, as much as five percent up on July but similar to last year's levels, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>One source familiar with Russian export patterns estimated that 1.2 million tonnes of mazut were exported out of Baltic ports and 500,000 tonnes from the Mediterranean. He said these levels were little changed from July.</p>
<p>An analyst at a major European oil company said he saw August exports five percent higher than in July.</p>
<p>He declined to give precise figures of his own, but a five percent increase on Reuters' July export level estimates would be roughly 1.9 million tonnes.</p>
<p>In August 1995 Russian fuel oil export levels were estimated at 1.85 million tonnes.</p>
<p>But exports for most of this summer have been sharply below year-ago levels due to a number of factors, most important of which was the priority given to exporters over refiners. Cash-rich exporters have been able to buy more crude this year, leaving less for Russian refiners to process which in turn has hit fuel production.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very complicated picture,&quot; the oil company analyst said. &quot;The refineries have been running a little less crude this year because they cannot pay for it as easily as the exporters. So fewer refined products have been available.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added that upgrading work at a number of Russian refineries has also led to a lighter product yield, lowering output of fuel oil.</p>
<p>European gasoline and naphtha traders have also recently noted increasing exports of Russian gasoline and naphtha into the region.</p>
<p>The flow has been uneven but gasoline exports into the Baltic region in August were estimated at around 50,000 tonnes in August, while 30,000 tonnes moved into the Black Sea.</p>
<p>In addition, some 50,000-75,000 tonnnes of mostly full-range naphtha were thought to have been sold into northwest Europe last month.</p>
<p>Precise monthly and yearly comparisons were not available but dealers said these figures represented large increases from historical levels.</p>
<p>Latest data from Russia's State Statistics Committee showed national output of heavy fuel oil in July was 38 million tonnes, 13 percent down on a year ago, while gasoline output was nine percent down at 16 million tonnes.</p>
<p>While it was not immediately possible to assess the full extent of all the recent refinery upgrading activity, the trend looks set to continue.</p>
<p>Interfax news agency this year quoted the deputy president of YUKOS, Russia's second largest crude producer, as saying that his company would spend $100 million in 1996 alone to upgrade its three refineries, all in the southern Samara region.</p>
<p>In addition, a $500 million catalytic cracker was due to be installed at one plant, he added.</p>
<p>Construction of a new catalytic cracker is also underway at the Yaroslavl refinery 200 miles north of Moscow, and various other upgrade plans were said to be in progress across the region.</p>
<p>While predicting export levels from Russia is a notoriously difficult task, the monthly flow is likely to decline sharply into winter, as in previous years, as domestic demand rises and riverine export routes freeze over.</p>
<p>But this winter export levels could be greater than in previous years.</p>
<p>Economy Minister Yevgeny Yasin said this week he was opposed to fuel oil export curbs this winter. Export bans in previous winters were responsible for slowing exports to Europe to a trickle.</p>
<p>-- Nicholas Shaxson, London newsroom +44 171 542 8167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
