<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31072" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Copper set for big 1996 and 1997 surpluses - GNI.</title>
<headline>Copper set for big 1996 and 1997 surpluses - GNI.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rising copper production and the possibility that consumption growth forecasts will be too optimistic put the market on course for surpluses this year and next, brokerage GNI Ltd said in a special report.</p>
<p>In the first half of this year output rose by 14.1 percent, year-on-year. Although growth will be slower in the second half of the year total production will be 12.338 million tonnes, rising again to 13.078 million in 1997.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, consumption is set to rise three percent this year and four percent in 1997 to 12.149 million and 12.631 million tonnes respectively, GNI said.</p>
<p>&quot;GNI believes that the world copper market will see a surplus of around 189,000 tonnes in 1996, 150,000 tonnes of which will come in the second half of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In 1997, preliminary indications suggest that the surplus will rise to around 450,000 tonnes,&quot; GNI said.</p>
<p>China remains the great unknown in the market place, following recent years of considerable activity with state reserve stockpile liquidation and re-purchase having become commonplace.</p>
<p>&quot;At present, there is talk of both the sale of 150,000 tonnes and gossip about the possibility of a large stock drawdown in September,&quot; GNI said.</p>
<p>However, the market should focus on stock movements on the London Metal Exchange (LME), as recent increases suggest an annualised rise of over 600,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;If stocks continue to build at this rate it will offset any movements made by China. By the end of 1997, LME stocks are likely to be at least double their current level and any kind of manipulation will require deep pockets,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Prices, meanwhile, are set to move lower, with the three months average price at $2,155 this year, sliding to around $1,700/$1,750 in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices could of course move outside these levels, but unless consumption growth is much lower than forecast, GNI believes that $1,600 should provide a reasonable trading target for a trading low next year.&quot;</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
