<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31071" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's mortgage lenders cautious on loan rates.</title>
<headline>Britain's mortgage lenders cautious on loan rates.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's leading mortgage lenders said on Wednesday another quarter-point cut in official UK interest rates would not necessarily lead to further falls in Britain's historically low mortgage rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Mortgage rates are at a 30-year low and I don't think they have much further to go,&quot; said Chris Somme, spokesman for Britain's biggest home loans group the Halifax Building Society.</p>
<p>Many lenders suggested that tight margins currently maintained between mortgage and savings rates left little room for manoeuvre.</p>
<p>&quot;We wouldn't necessarily follow suit if there was a cut,&quot; said Hilary McVitty, media relations manager at one of Britain's top 10 building societies, the Woolwich.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to be balanced and take into account the requirements of savers as well as borrowers, and interest rates for savers are relatively low at the moment anyway.&quot;</p>
<p>But most mortgage lenders said if an official rate cut transpired, they would wait to see how competitors reacted.</p>
<p>Some did not rule out the possibility of cutting mortgage rates if rivals did, with competition still fierce in the house lending market.</p>
<p>&quot;We are keen to maintain a competitive edge, so we would see how the rest of the market would act and then make sure our competitive position was maintained,&quot; said Vicky Hill, spokeswoman for the Nationwide Building Society.</p>
<p>The Nationwide has one of the lowest key mortgage rates of 6.49 percent following a 0.25 percent cut in July.</p>
<p>British Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke surprised financial markets in June with a quarter-percent cut in the official base rate to 5.75 percent, prompting many building societies to follow suit with cuts in their mortgage rates.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll found 13 of 20 economists forecast that Clarke would resist the temptation to cut rates again at his monthly meeting with Bank of England governor Eddie George on Wednesday, and many building societies agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the general view is that the trend in rates will be upwards. We'd be surprised if there was a cut in rates,&quot; said Chris Holland, public relations manager at Bradford and Bingley.</p>
<p>Building societies who have retained their mutual status said they would probably be in a better position to cut rates than those who had opted to become banks via stock market flotations, or those taken over by banks.</p>
<p>Holland said building societies who have converted into banks would find it tough to cut rates as they need to maximise profits and buoy share prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We've already cut our margins by an extra half percent to underline our mutuality position,&quot; he added of the Bradford &amp; Bingley, which has jealously guarded its mutual status.</p>
<p>Some mortgage lenders said they were unsure how effective another cut in rates would be for the housing market.</p>
<p>&quot;The confidence in the housing market seems to be returning so a further cut in interest rates would not have a significant impact on the housing market,&quot; said the Nationwide's Hill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
