<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31083" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Airbus poised to announce sales worth $5.0 billion.</title>
<headline>Airbus poised to announce sales worth $5.0 billion.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European planemaker Airbus Industrie said on Wednesday it may have lost the battle for new sales announcements at the Farnborough air show this week, but it had not lost the war against arch rival Boeing Co and expects to unveil new orders shortly worth some $5.0 billion.</p>
<p>Airbus had hoped to announce at least two more recently-signed deals which are together worth $3.5 billion but a company spokesman said the buyers were not ready to make a public announcement at the show.</p>
<p>&quot;Had the customers so wished we could have announced two more firm contracts which are together worth $3.5 billion,&quot; he said. He added that Airbus has letters of intent for a further $2.0 billion of sales which are expected to be confirmed before the end of September.</p>
<p>Noting that Boeing has so far announced new orders together valued at around $7.5 billion at the show compared with $3.0 billion by Airbus. But the European firm has complained that some of Boeing's announcements include preliminary agreements before they have firm contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a war of words, it is a war on clarity,&quot; a spokesman for Airbus said on Wednesday. &quot;If we had announced every letter of intent that we have we could have announced at least $8.5 billion of orders at Farnborough.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to comment on the new orders Airbus is waiting for clearance to announce.</p>
<p>Market sources told Reuters yesterday that South Korean airline Asiana is poised to give Boeing and Airbus Industrie two of their biggest orders this year for 777 and A330 widebody jets, in deals which could be worth over $2.0 billion apiece.</p>
<p>Airbus is a consortium comprising Germany's Daimler-Benz Aerospace, British Aerospace, Aerospatiale of France and Spain's CASA.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
