<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31089" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lucas to dominate LucasVarity management.</title>
<headline>Lucas to dominate LucasVarity management.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo-U.S. motor components manufacturer LucasVarity, created by the merger of Lucas Industries and Varity Corp, said on Wednesday its management would be derived chiefly from Lucas executives.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be 100 top jobs at LucasVarity and more will be going to Lucas management than Varity,&quot; Sarah Ward, corporate communications manager at Lucas, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Ward declined to give details and said Lucas was scheduled to release a statement on the changes later in the day.</p>
<p>Ward said a report in Wednesday's edition of the Financial Times, which said 50 managers would lose their jobs as part of a 115 million sterling ($180 million) cost-cutting drive, was overstated.</p>
<p>&quot;One hundred and fifty jobs will go into 100 but that does not necessarily mean redundancies...there may be other opportunities,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But she said the 450 job losses mentioned in the FT were a &quot;fair figure&quot;. The combined group employs around 56,000 workers. She declined to say whether more job losses were on the cards.</p>
<p>Ward confirmed the sales forecast in the FT report, which said LucasVarity was seeking to double annual sales to 10 billion stg by 2005.</p>
<p>Jonathan Storey, director of European Automotive Research, said the sales forecast was feasible and called the planned job cuts a bold and rapid move which could help generate the economies of scale needed to compete internationally.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect that sort of growth rate from developing markets and the target sounds feasible,&quot; he said, adding however that the potential for short-term growth in the Far East was often overstated.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't see big returns in five years, probably looking at a minimum of ten...The vehicles being built there are low cost, utilitarian and low margin,&quot; he said. ($ = 0.638 British Pounds Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
