<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31084" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Press says Iraq attack driven by U.S. election.</title>
<headline>Press says Iraq attack driven by U.S. election.</headline>
<byline>Robert Woodward</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. attacks on Iraq were driven by President Bill Clinton's desire for re-election and allowed him to act tough against the West's bogeyman without risking a full military campaign, the world's press said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton's decision to attack Iraq has more to do with U.S. politics than the Iraqi issue itself,&quot; said an editorial in South Korea's Joong-Ang Ilbo, summing up general opinion.</p>
<p>Newspapers in many countries agreed Saddam Hussein needed to be taught a lesson for his attacks on Kurds in northern Iraq. But they warned Clinton that continued attacks on Iraq could alienate already uneasy allies in Europe and elsewhere.</p>
<p>Diplomacy rather than missiles provided the best solution to problems in the Middle East, newspapers said. Only U.S. forces were involved in Tuesday's attack on targets in southern Iraq. Britain, Japan and Germany offered support but others were less convinced of the raid's necessity.</p>
<p>&quot;Operation Desert Strike fell far short of gaining the unanimous support of Washington's allies. France and Italy drew a clear line between themselves and Washington while Russia and China condemned the American action,&quot; said France's Le Figaro.</p>
<p>Clinton's decision to send in the B52s is, however, sure to go down well with U.S. voters. They like tough leaders, seeing their country acting as sheriff of the global village -- and vote for their next president in November, newspapers said. &quot;It is...not surprising that this action appears to many U.S. friends and allies to be driven by specifically U.S. interests and electoral politics,&quot; said the Irish Times.</p>
<p>If Clinton had not acted &quot;he would certainly have been accused by his domestic opponents of being a &quot;lame duck&quot;, according to the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung.</p>
<p>&quot;He showed once more that it is impossible to play tricks on the United States,&quot; Magyar Hirlap in Hungary said. But it added: &quot;It would be no surprise if after this attack President Clinton rises in the polls against his challenger Bob Dole.&quot;</p>
<p>Many editors warned Clinton that his tough line carried grave risks as Saddam -- described variously as &quot;the emperor of wrong decisions&quot; and &quot;an avid misreader of American domestic politics&quot;  -- was totally unpredictable.</p>
<p>&quot;(Clinton's) decision could enable him to rally his supporters around him, so long as his army does not find itself ensnarled in a long-term conflict with Iraq,&quot; said France-Soir.</p>
<p>&quot;Saddam...has gambled before on escalation and may well believe that in mid-election campaign, all he needs is a few body-bags to force American to a humiliating change of course,&quot; the London Times said. Poland's daily Rzeczpospoita noted: &quot;A missile attack is just a show of force. President Clinton has no desire to push the U.S. army into larger scale operations just two months before the elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Support for the U.S. action in major capitals could also dribble away if Washington carried on alone. Newspapers were commenting before the second attack on Iraqi targets. &quot;If the military action against Iraq escalated, the U.S. would become increasingly isolated in the international community,&quot; the China-backed Wen Wei Po said in Hong Kong. &quot;There is worrying unilateralism about it that could contribute to growing tension between U.S. and European governments, despite the support Mr Clinton has received from Britain and Germany,&quot; the Irish Times said. Cairo's Al-Hayat said: &quot;The U.S. is the adversary and arbiter in each confrontation with an Arab or Moslem country.&quot; Egypt's Asharq al-Awsat said Iran, another major concern for the U.S., could be the winner from the U.S./Iraq showdown.</p>
<p>Many said the need for a U.S. attack on Saddam showed how well he overcame his defeat in the 1991 Gulf War. That chance to alter the West's relationship with Baghdad had been wasted. &quot;It is now clear that the Saddams of this world will not simply be brought to reason by destroying their bridges, their command headquarters and their airports if one is afraid to go through the bloody route all the way to the end,&quot; said Sueddeutsche Zeitung of Germany. &quot;Saddam Hussein is really a big threat but the problems cannot be solved with Tomahawks (missiles). This is the lesson to be learned,&quot; Nepsabadsag, Hungary's biggest daily, said.</p>
<p>The London Guardian said Saddam would have taken a lack of reaction to his incursion into northern Iraq as a sign of weakness by the West.</p>
<p>&quot;The irony is that the act of launching them reveals a deeper weakness in the ability of the international community to do anything positive for the long term,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
