<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31087" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Deutsche earnings suffer from MGAM.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Deutsche earnings suffer from MGAM.</headline>
<byline>Joe Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, Germany's biggest, has moved quickly to try and limit the damage at its British fund management subsidiary, but analysts said on Wednesday its credibility and earnings are likely to be hit.</p>
<p>Late Tuesday, Deutsche stepped in with between 150 and 200 million pounds ($234 and 313 million) to buy problem securities out of three of Morgan Grenfell Asset Management's (MGAM) funds in which dealings had been suspended.</p>
<p>The securities, unlisted and illiquid, have gone onto Deutsche's own books and analysts are assuming this will be done at a lower value than Deutsche has paid.</p>
<p>MGAM said dealings in the funds, which total around 1.4 billion pounds, will resume on Thursday.</p>
<p>Jim Hyde, banking analyst at broker Williams de Broe, said that if the operation led to a loss of 100 million pounds, this would cut 23 pfennigs off his 4.72 marks earnings per share forecast for 1996.</p>
<p>Olaf Conrad, of Morgan Stanley, agreed that a write down of at least part of the cash that Deutsche has injected is likely but that it was too early to say how much this would be.</p>
<p>Conrad said he was looking for 4.5 marks per share earnings from Deutsche this year before any loss associated with MGAM.</p>
<p>&quot;There are two other risks,&quot; Hyde added. &quot;Firstly, that Morgan Grenfell Asset Management's credibility will be fatally flawed and secondly, that there could be a flight of some of its fund managers.&quot;</p>
<p>Loss of key personnel, one of an investment bank's most precious assets, is often cited as a problem when institutions are going through periods of uncertainty.</p>
<p>Hyde said the possible losses associated with the funds could wipe out any profits made by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell (DMG) in 1996 although Deutsche did not break out the investment bank's earnings separately at the half-year stage.</p>
<p>In 1995 DMG made 260 million marks ($175.1 million) with 63 million of this coming from MGAM.</p>
<p>The main problem with the funds is thought to the valuation of a portfolio of Scandinavian and German unlisted equity which is now in the process of revaluation by an independent house.</p>
<p>Industry sources say the clear implication is that the securities were overvalued and they expressed surprise this could happen at Morgan Grenfell, which trumpets its expertise so loudly.</p>
<p>The problems at MGAM, which with 70 billion pounds under management holds half of Deutsche's fund management portfolio, will certainly be seen as a blow to the bank's aggressive push into the London scene.</p>
<p>Deutsche, along, apparently, with every other banking group with a serious international presence, sees asset management as a major growth area.</p>
<p>Funds looking for a home are expected to show massive growth in the coming years as the European pensions industry develops and Deutsche along with its rivals is looking to be a strong competitor.</p>
<p>&quot;Reputation is all in this business and it may take some time for MGMA to restore their's,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;I doubt whether Deutsche is going to get much credit for biting the bullet on this one and doing what had to be done.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=.6382 Pound)</p>
<p>($1=1.4846 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
