<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31097" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BTR strategy worry remains, despite sale.</title>
<headline>BTR strategy worry remains, despite sale.</headline>
<byline>Edna Fernandes</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in British conglomerate BTR rose on Wednesday after it clinched a better-than-expected sale price for its Tilcon unit, though profit fears and strategic concerns remained to dampen sentiment, analysts said.</p>
<p>BTR sold its U.S. based building materials business Tilcon to Ireland's CRH Plc for 212 million pounds ($332.2 million), better than the 180 million anticipated by the market.</p>
<p>BTR's shares edged five and a half pence higher to 261, but analysts still expect a cut in dividend and profits when the group announces its interim results next Thursday.</p>
<p>Andrew Darke, analyst at Williams de Broe, said &quot;The majority of analysts are expecting a cut in the dividend of one third and falling profits.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the market welcomed the latest in a stream of disposals, which has raised 700 million pounds in 1996 excluding provisions, saying that this should improve the group's strained cash flow position.</p>
<p>Ian Strachan, BTR chief executive, said on Wednesday that the Tilcon sale proceeds would &quot;be invested in our key industrial and engineering operations.&quot;</p>
<p>BTR is in the throes of a major strategic review which aims to shake-out 20 percent of existing non-core businesses leaving it to focus on the areas listed by Strachan.</p>
<p>The issue of cash flow, which ABN Amro Hoare Govett says has turned from an 89 million pounds inflow in 1994 to a 253 million outflow last year, remains a key concern.</p>
<p>Analysts also want to know how the group is going to fund its expansion in core businesses like automotive parts and packaging.</p>
<p>The market sees the dividend as an obvious tradeoff in BTR's spending plans. &quot;It would be big news if they didn't cut the dividend,&quot; said Darke.</p>
<p>Future strategy on how BTR will expand its chosen core areas in industrial manufacturing and engineering is another unanswered question.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a myriad of unanswered issues,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;Strategy, dividend policy, restrcuturing. There is still quite a major information vacuum waiting to be filled,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite the uncertainy, many of these concerns have been priced in following a heated debate in the summer which led to a shareprice meltdown.</p>
<p>BTR shares hit a low for the year of around 225 pence compared with the annual high of 344 pence before the concerns set in. ($1=.6382 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
