<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31103" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK monetary meeting keeps markets on tenterhooks.</title>
<headline>UK monetary meeting keeps markets on tenterhooks.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK financial markets were awaiting the start of the monthly monetary meeting on Wednesday to see if Chancellor Kenneth Clarke will deliver a politically-inspired rate cut before the general election, which must be held by May.</p>
<p>An expected pick-up in growth in the 1996 second half could rob Clarke of an excuse to ease monetary policy if he waits. The consumer sector is forging ahead with high street sales and consumer credit is ratcheting upward.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, if Clarke wants to lower rates he has a closing window of opportunity as growth is likely to pick up quite strongly in the months ahead,&quot; said James MacKay, UK economist at PaineWebber.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, MacKay said &quot;We expect him to grasp the opportunity at one of the next couple of meetings.&quot;</p>
<p>The meeting is due to start at 1400 GMT, so markets will have to wait until Thursday morning to see the final outcome.</p>
<p>Clarke is under intense pressure from his Conservative Party to deliver a robust economy and a national sense of well-being before the election.The party is still trailing opposition Labour by over 20 points in opinion polls.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll on Monday found 13 out of 20 economists questioned forecast rates will stay on hold, but seven expected Clarke to cut rates for the fifth time since December.</p>
<p>Clarke could argue for a rate cut because the manufacturing sector still appears stagnant. The first official measure of output at the start of the third quarter is not due until Friday, but authorities will have the data before the meeting.</p>
<p>July manufacturing output was seen up 0.3 percent after June's 0.3-percent fall, but only up 0.1 percent on the year.</p>
<p>Clarke could also press for a cut by arguing that the inflation outlook is very benign.</p>
<p>Underlying inflation, excluding volatile mortgage costs, fell 0.5 percent in July to stand at 2.8 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>This is still above the official target of 2.5 percent or below, but falling upstream prices have yet to fully feed through and retail prices were expected to ease this year.</p>
<p>But a rate cut could lead Clarke into a full-blown argument with Bank of England Governor Eddie George, who strongly opposed the last cut in June and has since, taken a harder line.</p>
<p>At the time of the July inflation report, the Bank's chief economist Mervyn King said the next move in rates should be up and said Bank officials would discuss a pre-emptive rate rise before this week's meeting.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7715</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
