<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31113" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Palm oil remains firm, but seen looking vulnerable.</title>
<headline>Palm oil remains firm, but seen looking vulnerable.</headline>
<byline>Jim Ballantyne</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palm oil prices were holding steady on the European vegetable oil market on Wednesday but traders said they are looking increasingly vulnerable.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment is keeping the price of palm oil firm with traders in the Far East expecting further tenders, but this seems unlikely at the moment,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders said last Friday's rejection by India of all bids owing to the high price of palm oil should have sounded a warning to the market. So far this week there have been no tenders from India or Pakistan.</p>
<p>India is said to need to buy 250,000 tonnes of palm oil during the Hindu festival months of September and October to offset tightness in the local supplies, but traders doubt they will buy at any price.</p>
<p>&quot;India has already shown it won't pay current high prices and up to a point they can hold off until the price comes down to a more reasonable level,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Traders said they do not expected India to remain in the market much beyond October with the local vegetable oil crop becoming available during November.</p>
<p>Many players are still living in the hope of large buying orders from China but currently they seem unlikely to take any significant amount owing to the high price.</p>
<p>During the period January to July 1996 China imported 582,799 tonnes of palm oil, a figure well below the 1995 level.</p>
<p>&quot;China has been buying an average of 83,000 to 84,000 tonnes a month of palm oil between January and July which is well below last year's 100,000 to 150,000 tonnes, said one trader.</p>
<p>The increased tension in the Middle East following the Iraqi attack on the Kurdish city of Arbil and the resulting U.S. missile strikes against targets in the south of Iraq on Tuesday and Wednesday have had no immediate impact on the market.</p>
<p>But some traders felt it could be bearish for the market in the longer term.</p>
<p>Iraq's May 20 accord with the United Nations which permits Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil in order to purchase food, medicine and other goods for its people could be under threat following the attack on Arbil.</p>
<p>Iraq sent a delegation to Malaysia to negotiate possible purchases of palm oil soon after the U.N. agreed to the limited lifting of restrictions on there export of crude oil.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8062</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
