<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31124" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME prepared to take steps after Sumitomo - Bagri.</title>
<headline>LME prepared to take steps after Sumitomo - Bagri.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London Metal Exchange (LME) has had meetings with all sides of the metals industry following the Sumitomo Corp crisis and is prepared to act on any lessons learned, LME Board Chairman Raj Bagri said.</p>
<p>&quot;The LME appreciates that lessons have to be learned from the Sumitomo affair by all concerned and is itself ready and willing to take appropriate follow-up measures,&quot; Bagri wrote in the latest issue of &quot;The Ringsider', the LME's newsletter.</p>
<p>Sumitomo reported on June 13 it had lost $1.8 billion in unauthorised copper trading over 10 years and fired its former head trader Yasuo Hamanaka.</p>
<p>Bagri said the LME immediately took steps to hold wide-ranging consultations with the industry.</p>
<p>&quot;I have had personal contact at the highest level with major producers and mining interests and this process is continuing,&quot; Bagri added.</p>
<p>A broad cross-section of industry representatives from European copper smelters and consumers from Europe and Asia met in London in July to discuss the LME's current modus operandi. &quot;Discussions centred on issues of broad principal with the intention to discuss these issues in more detail in the coming months,&quot; Bagri said.</p>
<p>The LME continued to play its part in the inquiries currently being carried out by the various regulatory authorities.</p>
<p>&quot;We will...not hesitate to take such actions as may be deemed appropriate and will properly discharge our obligations as a Recognised Investment Exchange under the Financial Services Act,&quot; Bagri said.</p>
<p>The LME would also follow legislative developments in the U.S. which may have a bearing on the Exchange's members and its users.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
