<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31122" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Aerospace realities can't hide future vision.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Aerospace realities can't hide future vision.</headline>
<dateline>FARNBOROUGH, England 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Neil Winton, Science and Technology Correspondent</p>
<p>Imagine a military jumbo jet carrying pilotless fighter planes like some great alien mothership.</p>
<p>Supersonic transports without sonic booms.</p>
<p>1,000 seater airliners.</p>
<p>Gigantic, squat looking craft, more ship than plane, skimming across the Atlantic carrying 5,000 people at 500 miles (800 km) an hour.</p>
<p>That's the vision for aviation in the 21st century, as the world's aerospace movers and shakers gather at Farnborough this week for the biennial air show.</p>
<p>But don't expect early relief from delayed flights and crowded terminals. Aerospace technology is constantly improving but the pace is slow.</p>
<p>&quot;We're on a technology plateau with planes and technology at the moment. There are plenty of incremental benefits, but no quantum jumps like with the Boeing 747,&quot; said Chris Partridge, senior analyst at aviation consulting group Avmark.</p>
<p>There are no revolutionary changes looming for air travellers, but maybe 10 years away is the new supersonic replacement for Concorde carrying up to 250. The biggest subsonic planes then will carry about 1,000 people.</p>
<p>The fighter pilot's job will be in jeopardy, replaced by the computer which has the advantage of lightness, and being able to stand the kind of fierce manoeuvres the human body never could.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll see a new supersonic transport early in the next century,&quot; said Glyn Davies, professor of aerospace structures at London's Imperial College.</p>
<p>&quot;Concorde is hopelessly inefficient, and uses old military engines. The new plane will carry more than twice as many passengers, and will not have the shattering sonic boom.&quot;</p>
<p>New materials and design shapes will almost eliminate the boom, which has drastically curbed the use of Concorde, limiting it to routes over oceans. The development costs will be enormous though and will have to be shared between the U.S., Japan and Europe, Davies said.</p>
<p>And the glamorous, gung-ho fighter pilot is in danger of redundancy. Like millions of others, this job is under threat from the computer.</p>
<p>&quot;The (military) pilot is now under threat. Fighter planes with a computer could do a much better job without the pilot. If you get rid of the pilot you can halve the weight and make it do things which the human body couldn't stand up to,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next century you could send out a large jumbo jet like aircraft on a mission say 12,000 miles (19,000 km) away, and shoot out four pilotless aircraft to do their jobs,&quot; Davies said.</p>
<p>That's how things may look in the next century, but planemakers now have more mundane problems to solve. How to keep the airline business growing, when skies are clogging up and airports reaching capacity. Larger planes and computerised air traffic control are seen as the answer.</p>
<p>Boeing may announce plans to start building its 550 seater 747-600X at the Farnborough show this week. The European consortium Airbus Industrie is also believed to be about to set in motion a double decker stretched A340, the A3XX, which would also seat 550. The largest plane currently in use is the Boeing 747-400 which, with its stretched upper deck, seats about 420.</p>
<p>&quot;And there's talk of a 1,000 seater. There is this difficulty though. You have to use existing runways, no one can afford to extend, and it has to take off on the same length and width,&quot; said Davies.</p>
<p>Regular air travellers will be all too familiar with delays caused by air traffic congestion, and these could be mitigated by more computerisation.</p>
<p>Aircraft on trans-continental routes often waste huge amounts of fuel while following criss-cross routes rather than direct ones. This is sometimes because of political disagreements about air space rights.</p>
<p>&quot;Computer control, if the political will is there, will mean planes can always fly the shortest route. FANS -- Future Air Navigation System -- will automatically navigate the plane using satellites,&quot; said Avmark's Partridge.</p>
<p>Airlines serving routes of up to 500 miles (800 km) will also come under threat from high speed trains, particularly in western Europe, and the eastern United States.</p>
<p>New trains will soon use magnet levitation technology. These trains are raised slightly from the tracks by magnetic force, and pushed frictionless to speeds of up to 500 miles (800 km) an hour.</p>
<p>Looking like a huge barge with stubby wings, the Ekranoplan is also on the fringe of development.</p>
<p>This machine was developed in the 1960s by the old Soviet Union as a way of sending thousands of commandos storming into action across seas, flat terrain and deserts. It was called the &quot;Caspian Sea Monster&quot; by U.S. intelligence when it was spotted by spy planes. The Pentagon couldn't tell if was somekind of jumbo jet or a ship.</p>
<p>The wings compress air under the craft. Jet engines drive it forward about 10 feet (3.048 metres) from the ground, riding on the air. The machine, known as a &quot;wingship&quot; in the U.S., could be used as a fast freighter, ferry, or even provide a service reminiscent of the steam liners of the 1920s and 1930s, only more than 10 times as fast.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is still looking at the Ekranoplan's potential; there's talk of a factory being set up in Ireland to do just that,&quot; said Paul Beaver, spokesman for defence publisher and analyst Janes.</p>
<p>&quot;They could go across the Atlantic, but initially shorter distances, moving large amounts of freight quickly, or taking people on cruises. They could be a competitor to the jumbo jet across the Atlantic,&quot; said Beaver.</p>
<p>Partridge said there will many small improvements for air travellers.</p>
<p>&quot;But I really don't see any quantum leaps in the next 10 to 15 years. I'd like to see a pill for a long flight. You'd fall asleep, and wake up when you arrived with no jet lag. That really would be something,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARNBOROUGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
