<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31138" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Sept 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>-- CASH FOR MORGAN GRENFELL FUNDS</p>
<p>Following the announcement Tuesday of the suspension of three investment funds operated by Morgan Grenfell Asset Management (MGAM) pending an investigation by regulators, Deutsche Bank, owners of MGAM, has injected 200 million stg in cash into the three funds to reassure their 90,000 investors. Trading in the three funds is expected to resume on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- BROADCASTERS MAY FACE NEW TAX UNDER LABOUR</p>
<p>The Labour Party is said to be considering a number of options on taxing the broadcasting industry should it win the next election. The most likely outcome is a 'spectrum tax', which could be as high as 14 percent of revenue, imposed on all commercial broadcasters including satellite venture BSkyB. The levy will be an attempt to redistribute government charges to broadcasters more equitably. The present system of regional licences, which were won in a controversial tendering round in 1991, has left some broadcasters paying just 2,000 stg a year while others pay over 42 million stg. (Financial Times p.1)</p>
<p>-- NOMURA-LED GROUP WINS CONTEST FOR MOD HOMES</p>
<p>A 1.6 billion stg bid from a consortium led by Japanese securities house Nomura is the likely winner of the contest to buy 58,000 Ministry of Defence homes. The controversial sale of the armed services' living quarters has drawn opposition from Conservative back-bench MPs, prompted by security fears of service families currently occupying the buildings. Other members of the Nomura-led group include Amec, Hambros, Midland Bank and Royal Bank of Scotland.</p>
<p>-- USAIR OFFERS DEAL IN EFFORT TO END ACTION AGAINST BA</p>
<p>USAir has offered to settle its legal challenge to the planned merger between British Airways and American Airlines (AA) on condition that BA help it establish its own service to London Heathrow airport. USAir, in which BA has a 24.6 percent stake, launched its challenge in July following news of the planned BA-AA alliance. Other US carriers are also opposed to the alliance which, they fear, would monopolise trans-Atlantic traffic.</p>
<p>-- BIGGER ROLE IN UK FOR FOREIGN GROUPS</p>
<p>A study for the Economic and Social Research Council has revealed that one in three of Britain's 100 biggest manufacturers is now foreign-owned, and that one quarter of the country's manufacturing output is accounted for by foreign-owned companies. Between 1986 and 1993, the number of foreign-owned manufacturing companies among the UK's 100 largest manufacturers rose from 18 to 35, mostly due to an influx of large multinationals from the European Union.</p>
<p>-- ELECTROLUX LOOKS TO FLEXIBLE WORKING</p>
<p>Swedish-owned household appliances manufacturer Electrolux is considering introducing flexible working systems in its UK plants to cope with fluctuations in demand. The system under discussion with unions involves staff agreeing to spread a set number of working hours over a year, to fit with highs and lows of demand. The aim is to reduce the company's reliance on temporary staff, who are seen as less committed and have been blamed for lowering output quality.</p>
<p>-- UNION REACHES STALEMATE IN ROYAL MAIL DISPUTE</p>
<p>The postal workers' union the CWU has failed to agree whether to call further strikes in its dispute with the Royal Mail. The full executive of the union will meet on Thursday to consider the next move, following comments by the government that any further disruption could force a three-month suspension of the Royal Mail's monopoly on letter delivery. The union is under pressure from the Labour party and postal management to ballot its members on the latest Royal Mail offer.</p>
<p>-- LLOYD'S RECOVERY NEARS APPROVAL</p>
<p>Insurance house Lloyd's of London expects to get approval from the Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) on Wednesday for the final stage of its recovery plan, the establishment of Equitas, a reinsurance company which will take over billions of pounds of outstanding liabilities on old insurance policies. At the same time, Lloyd's deputy chairman John Charman is said to be considering radical changes to the system of Names by which Lloyd's raises capital, the proposal being to replace individual Names by corporate investors.</p>
<p>-- LUCAS/VARITY TO CUT 30 PERCENT OF TOP MANAGERS</p>
<p>Motor components manufacturer LucasVarity, which was created this summer by the merger of the UK's Lucas Industries and Varity Corporation of the US, is planning to cut one third of its senior management as part of a 115 million stg cost-cutting strategy. An announcement on the loss of 50 management jobs is expected Wednesday. The new group has said it aims to double annual sales to 10 billion stg by 2005.</p>
<p>-- P&amp;O CRITICISED FOR SALE OF UNIT</p>
<p>P&amp;O has been criticised by the head of a former subsidiary sold off on Tuesday as part of the group's 1.0 billion stg divestment programme. The sale of P&amp;O Oilfield Services was the first disposal of the campaign, but the company's managing director, Howard Stapleton, has claimed that it should not have been sold because of its outstanding profitability.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
