<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31137" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK Labour says no plans to up top tax rate.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK Labour says no plans to up top tax rate.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party has made no plans to raise the top rate of income tax, party leader Tony Blair said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no proposals to raise the top rate of tax,&quot; Blair told BBC radio. &quot;When the government publishes their tax figures in the budget, we will make a considered response to that.&quot;</p>
<p>Blair said he wanted to see what state public finances were in at November's budget before making pledges on tax, adding that the size of the public sector deficit meant there were tough and difficult decisions to face.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't start making promises to every single interest group under the sun,&quot; said Blair.</p>
<p>&quot;But what people will know is that when they go into the general election we will be absolutely clear...what we're saying about the issue of tax,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He added that the Labour Party wanted a 10 percent starting rate for income tax as a long-term objective. &quot;But it has to be done as resources allow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Blair was speaking before a Labour Party forum with UK business leaders, to be held in London on Wednesday, intending to allay business fears about a Labour government.</p>
<p>&quot;Today, we will be setting out proposals as to how we can assist business in the areas of skills and education, reforming our welfare system, better use and access to new technology, better transport infrastructure, how we help small businesses, how we play a more constructive role in Europe,&quot; Blair said.</p>
<p>He said Britain could not compete internationally, on the basis of a low-wage, low-skill economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We can only compete if we are adding quality, adding value to our goods and that requires a highly-skilled and proficient workforce.&quot;</p>
<p>He said increasing numbers of British business leaders were now supporting the Labour Party.</p>
<p>Opinion polls tip Blair to defeat Prime Minister John Major in the general election, which must be held by May next year. But Labour's lead has slipped to just over 20 points from nearer 30 and all sides are predicting a bitter and extended campaign.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
