<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31139" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - BRITISH BUSINESS PRESS.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BRITISH BUSINESS PRESS.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared by The Broadcast Monitoring Company for Reuters.</p>
<p>			  DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- FEARS OF CITY JOB CUTS OUTSIDE EMU DISMISSED</p>
<p>Financial experts have dismissed claims that thousands of City jobs would be lost if Britain did not participate in a single currency. It is believed that the Germans and the French are using scare stories to pressurise Britain into signing up. The experts believe that given London's pre-eminence in areas such as foreign exchange it is more likely that Paris and Frankfurt will lose out rather than London.</p>
<p>-- REFUGE UNDER PRESSURE TO REVISE MERGER TERMS</p>
<p>Refuge and United Friendly, the insurance giants, are being forced to rethink their 1.5 billion merger by institutional shareholders. At the centre of the dispute is a claim by shareholders that they could miss out on any surplus that might arise from the company's ordinary branch business. With just five days to go before shareholders vote on the deal the Refuge board and advisers Phoenix Securities are working on a compromise that would assure the institutions their company is not being undervalued.</p>
<p>-- NOMURA TEAM WINS MoD HOMES BID</p>
<p>The Annington Homes consortium, led by Japanese investment bank Nomura and Amec, the construction and engineering group, has won its bid for the privatisation of the Ministry of Defence's 58,000 married quarters estate. It is believed that the consortium offered more than 1.5 billion pounds stg for the estate.</p>
<p>			  THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- MG FACES LOSSES OF 150 MILLION POUNDS ON FUNDS</p>
<p>Morgan Grenfell is set to face losses of up to 150 million stg when dealings resume in three investment funds being investigated by the Investment Management Regulatory Organisation.  Many investors are waiting to redeem their money at the first opportunity. The losses to Morgan Grenfell are likely to come if the managers are forced to sell the most liquid holdings to meet the redemptions.</p>
<p>-- WIMPEY PLEDGES HIGHER PROFITS</p>
<p>George Wimpey, the housebuilder, promised to restore full-year operating profits to their highest level since 1990 despite reporting half-year losses before tax of 8.6 million stg.</p>
<p>Chairman Joe Dwyer said the company was enjoying the first signs of sustained improvement in the UK housing market for many years.</p>
<p>-- BLUE CIRCLE FIGURES BUOYED BY STRONG DEMAND FROM OVERSEAS</p>
<p>Blue Circle, the building and heating group, unveiled a 12 percent rise in first-half profit. The results were buoyed by strong demand overseas, including the United States and Malaysia. The company said that there was little sign of improving demand in either its UK cement business or its European bathroom and heating operations. Pre-tax profits were in line with expectations at 116.3 million stg.</p>
<p>			  THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- BRITISH AIRWAYS, CATHAY INTERESTED IN SUPERJUMBO</p>
<p>British Airways and Cathay Pacific both confirmed interest in the new generation of superjumbo aircraft and saw a need for very large passenger aircraft. Cathay Pacific managing director Peter Sutch said the company was in the market for the Superjumbo, but not yet. BA chief executive Bob Ayling hinted that the airline's need for bigger aircraft could arise before the planned launch date of 2003 of the A3XX being developed by Airbus.</p>
<p>-- LABOUR URGES RAIL PENSIONS INQUIRY</p>
<p>The Labour Party demanded an investigation into how confidential details of the railway workers' pension fund were given to bidders for rail franchises by the government actuary. The shadow transport secretary said that the disclosure of the fund's surplus represented a breach of trust. The surplus is large enough to ensure that successful bidders may not have to make any pension contributions during the seven-year franchise period.</p>
<p>			  THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- MERCEDES WARNS UK IS SCARING AWAY INVESTORS</p>
<p>Helmut Werner, chief executive of Mercedes-Benz, claimed that Britain's lack of commitment to the European Monetary Union is scaring away potential investors. He warned that earnings on investments in Britain, if it stayed out of the single currency, would become more unpredictable than in countries belonging to EMU and that a free floating pound would not support the British economy. He added that Britain would be a very interesting country for Mercedes to invest in if it took part in a single European currency.</p>
<p>-- STORES SUFFER AS ICELAND EARNINGS DIVE</p>
<p>Iceland, the frozen foods chain, repeated its profits warning for the year and reported a bigger than expected fall in pre-tax profits for the six months to the end of June of 29.8 million stg, down by 11.3 per cent. Shares in Iceland fell by nearly 10 per cent and dragged the food retailing sector with them.</p>
<p>-- AIRBUS UNVEILS 3 BILLION DOLLARS ORDERS TO UPDATE FLEETS</p>
<p>Airbus revealed orders for up to 38 planes estimated to be worth $3 billion. This offers further evidence of the recovery in the market for civil aircraft as carriers replace outdated fleets. Airbus revealed its first order with Korea's Asiana Airlines, for 18 medium haul planes.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC</p>
<p>+44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
