<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31144" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST - UK July industrial output seen rising.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - UK July industrial output seen rising.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK industrial production data, due on Friday, should show a modest rise in July after June's surprising plunge and confirm that the worst is over for manufacturers, analysts said.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll of economists forecasts July industrial production to rise 0.5 percent after a 1.1-percent drop in June, to produce a year-on-year increase of 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>Manufacturing output is expected to put its gloomy performance of recent months behind it. The consensus forecast is for a 0.3-percent gain after a 0.3-fall in June.</p>
<p>Year-on-year manufacturing output is forecast to rise 0.1 percent in July. In June, manufacturing was running 0.5 percent below year ago levels.</p>
<p>Economists said the return of normal weather in July after an unusually hot June should be a key factor in boosting total industrial output.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect a weather-related bounce back in utility output after a huge fall in June because of the exceptionally hot weather that month,&quot; said Philip Shaw, economist at Union Plc.</p>
<p>An improvement in manufacturing output should also boost the overall figures.</p>
<p>&quot;There seems little doubt that the worst is now over for manufacturers with a steady, if unspectacular, improvement in prospect,&quot; said Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Midland.</p>
<p>Loynes predicted July manufacturing output would rise 0.3 percent, assisting a rise in industrial output of 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>Signs the manufacturing sector may be picking up gained further weight with a strong UK Purchasing Managers Index on Monday. The index rose to 51.8, the highest level this year.</p>
<p>On top of that, the last quarterly Confederation of British Industry survey, released in July, showed orders and output up and the first rise in business confidence since April 1995.</p>
<p>But Loynes said the CBI survey showed demand had come entirely from the domestic side, with the export orders balance slipping to its weakest level since February 1994 in June.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to envisage a meaningful acceleration in output without stronger demand from overseas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British manufacturing output has been the weak link in the economic recovery and has narrowly avoided recession this year. The sector has been hit by erratic demand for goods overseas and by a large stock overhang.</p>
<p>Loynes said the detailed stocks release for the second quarter provided promising evidence manufacturers had started to tackle the overhang, with the first unwinding of stocks seen since the third quarter of 1993.</p>
<p>But economists at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell still expected any rise in industrial production to be constrained by the continuing need to reduce stocks.</p>
<p>They anticipated a modest 0.2-percent rebound in July manufacturing output, with a pick up in coming months as consumer demand continues to feed through.</p>
<p>If the data confound forecasters and show another sharp fall in manufacturing output, analysts said a case for a further cut in interest rates could be made.</p>
<p>June's surprise quarter point UK rate cut was attributed largely to the weakness of UK manufacturing.</p>
<p>-- Merissa Marr, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
