<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31142" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: T-notes ease in London, wary of upcoming payrolls.</title>
<headline>T-notes ease in London, wary of upcoming payrolls.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries eased slightly in London on Wednesday and are set for more losses, analysts said.</p>
<p>With little for the market to focus on until Friday's August payrolls data, the session so far had been quiet, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had a short-covering rally off yesterday's lows but I don't trust the market,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. bank in London.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm bearish about Treasuries and I think there is more downside to come,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The 30-year benchmark bond was at 96-02 by 0931 GMT, yielding 7.07 percent, compared with 96-05 at the Tokyo and New York closes.</p>
<p>At the short end of the curve Treasuries were also easier.</p>
<p>Two-year T-notes were at 99-20, unchanged from Tokyo and down 1/32 from the New York close. While five-year T-notes were at 99-05, down from 99-06 in Tokyo and 99-07 in New York.</p>
<p>An economist at a British bank in London was also inclined to favour the downside.</p>
<p>&quot;Treasuries had a good day yesterday,&quot; he said. &quot;The market will be slightly easier today but there is not a lot going on.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. construction spending for July, due at 1400 GMT, is forecast to fall 0.2 percent compared with a rise of 1.2 percent in June.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not much on the economic front today. We've got construction spending to look forward to later but the non-farm payrolls on Friday will attract most of the attention,&quot; the trader said. &quot;A lot of people are on hold until Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>August non-farm payrolls are expected to come in at plus 244,000 compared with plus 193,000 in July.</p>
<p>By 0938 GMT, December T-bond futures were at 107-14 in automated trade, up 2/32 from the Chicago settlement.</p>
<p>-- Deepthi Wickremasinghe, Bonds Unit +44 171 542 4041</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
