<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31150" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Manders shares lower after profit fall.</title>
<headline>Manders shares lower after profit fall.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in printing inks and coatings specialist Manders Plc fell sharply in early dealing on Wednesday after it reported a 53 percent drop in interim pretax profit.</p>
<p>Shares in the group were down 33-1/2 pence at 200 pence by 0855 GMT after it said depressed market conditions and intensified competition hit profit margins across the company.</p>
<p>A market-maker in Manders, which was marked down 36 pence at the opening, said volumes were thin. He said the fall reflected &quot;sentiment after the figures&quot;, which showed pretax profit of 2.6 million stg compared with 5.5 million a year before.  </p>
<p>Kleinwort Benson analyst Jeremy Chantry said Manders had been the victim of a price war in specialist inks &quot;with too many people chasing the business&quot;, exacerbated by an inability to pass on rises in raw material costs.</p>
<p>But Chantry said, &quot;We could be over the worst.&quot; He is predicting a 30 percent pick-up in pretax profit in 1997 from 1996 levels, despite very competitive market conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;They don't lack anything in technology generally,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Manders pointed to a &quot;marginal improvement&quot; in second-half sales, although it said results for the period will be affected by an estimated one million stg restructuring charge.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Birt, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
