<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31159" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Man shot in N. Ireland Republican feud.</title>
<headline>Man shot in N. Ireland Republican feud.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of a breakaway Irish Republican guerrilla group was shot dead overnight in a feud which has killed six people including a nine-year-old girl, police said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hugh Torney, 41, was shot several times as he left a house in Lurgan, south of Belfast, where he had been in hiding since the Irish National Liberation Army (INLA) feud erupted in January with a wave of killings.  </p>
<p>A man who was with him was being treated for gunshot wounds to the stomach and was seriously ill, police said. His identity was not disclosed.</p>
<p>The shooting highlighted the danger of tensions in Northern Ireland's rival pro and anti-British guerrilla groups on the eve of resumed Northern Ireland peace talks which are supposed to remove the guns from the province's fractious politics.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland Secretary, Sir Patrick Mayhew, and Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring meet in Dublin on Thursday to try to give the September 9 talks some fresh impetus after months of procedural wrangling and deadlock.  </p>
<p>They hinted on Tuesday that they might suspend the participation of Protestant Loyalist parties because of a death threat against Billy Wright, a maverick leader opposed to their policy of maintaining a 23-month ceasefire.</p>
<p>Loyalists are allowed to take part in the talks because of the truce called by their umbrella group, the Combined Loyalist Military Command, but Spring and Mayhew said the threat broke principles of non-violence all talks participants must make.  </p>
<p>Sinn Fein, poltical arm of the Irish Republican Army (IRA), is excluded from the talks until the guerrillas call a new truce and the INLA, which broke away from the IRA in 1975, has never publicly declared a ceasefire.</p>
<p>Torney, known as &quot;Cueball&quot; in the Irish underworld, was on the run from police in the Irish Republic where he faces charges in connection with arms possession.</p>
<p>He has also been on the run from the INLA, a small but fanatic guerrilla group, since its leader, Gino Gallagher, was shot dead in January at the start of the blood feud.  </p>
<p>Its victims included nine-year-old Barbara McAlorum who was hit when gunmen sprayed her father's north Belfast home with automatic gunfire.</p>
<p>Irish Republicans, who want an end to British rule of Northern Ireland, believe that Torney ordered Gallagher's killing after setting up a splinter INLA faction.</p>
<p>The INLA is the most radical of Irish Republican groups.Its vimctims included Conservative Party Northern Ireland spokesman Airey Neave, blown up in the car park of the British parliament in 1979.</p>
<p>It is seen as an extreme left wing group opposed to anything less than the end of British rule in Northern Ireland and the merger of the province with the Irish Republic. It opposes any talks with Britain that fall short of this.</p>
<p>Torney was arrested after police found a large consignment of arms being taken from the Irish Republic to Belfast. He was charged but freed on bail and has been in hiding ever since.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
