<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31166" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Booker makes agreed bid for Nurdin &amp; Peacock.</title>
<headline>Booker makes agreed bid for Nurdin &amp; Peacock.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British food wholesaler and distribution group Booker Plc on Wednesday announced an agreed 264 million pound ($412.1 million) bid for rival Nurdin &amp; Peacock Plc.</p>
<p>Under the offer, Nurdin shareholders will receive 14 new Booker shares and 154.53 pounds in cash for every 100 Nurdin shares. Based on a Booker share price of 360.5 pence a share the offer values Nurdin shares at 205 pence.</p>
<p>Booker said Nurdin shareholders may choose a full cash alternative of 201 pence a share or take additional shares in place of all or part of the cash offer.</p>
<p>The deal marks a significant rationalisation of the British food wholesaling sector, which has come under increasing pressure from food superstores such as Tesco Plc and ASDA Group Plc.</p>
<p>Nurdin chairman Richard Fulford said, &quot;It has been clear for some time that the food wholesaling industry must undergo a process of rationalisation and consolidation to respond to the growing pressures from food retailing multiples.&quot;</p>
<p>Booker expects to make annual cost savings of about 10 million pounds in the first financial year after the merger and it sees these more than doubling in the following two years.</p>
<p>&quot;The combined food wholesaling businesses will have major opportunities to improve its buying efficiency, reduce its costs and reduce its working capital,&quot; the companies said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>To achieve the savings Booker estimates it will need to make a one-off provision for restructuring of about 52 million pounds. It expects the deal to enhance earnings in the first full financial year.</p>
<p>Nurdin's shares jumped on news of the bid and were up 73 pence at 202.5 pence. Booker's shares were 25 pence higher at 385 pence. ($1=.6406 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
