<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31178" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cadbury up on H1 results, positive outlook.</title>
<headline>Cadbury up on H1 results, positive outlook.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Cadbury Schweppes Plc firmed in pre-market trading after reporting first half results at the top end of market expectations, analysts said.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profits rose 12 percent in the six months to June 15 against forecasts ranging from 218 to 232 million stg. The dividend was raised to 5.2p, again at the top of expectations. The outlook for the year as a whole was positive with further growth expected for both business streams, said the soft drinks and confectionery group's chairman Dominic Cadbury .</p>
<p>By 0706 GMT Cadbury shares were indicated 7p higher at 518-1/2p.  </p>
<p>&quot;The results were at the upper end of the market range and will be well received,&quot; said Paribas analyst John Campbell.</p>
<p>The company said that the Dr Pepper/Seven-Up acquisition was fulfilling expectations with the Dr Pepper brand outpacing the growth in the U.S. market while Seven-Up was responding to its new marketing support and volume growing.</p>
<p>&quot;Beverages in the Americas if anything were stronger than my expectations,&quot; said Campbell.</p>
<p>The sale of the company's 51 percent interest in Coca-Cola &amp; Schweppes Beverages for 622.5 million stg will produce a substantial one-off gain in the full-year.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8712</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
