<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31185" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cadbury upbeat on outlook for full year.</title>
<headline>Cadbury upbeat on outlook for full year.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dominic Cadbury, the chairman of British confectionery and soft drinks company Cadbury-Schweppes, said he was positive about expectations for the group's full year performance.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the year as a whole is positive with further growth expected for both business streams,&quot; he said in a statement.  </p>
<p>In the half year to June 15 the company reported a 12 percent rise in pretax profits to 231 million pounds ($360.6 million) on sales up 13.3 percent to 2.293 billion pounds. Analysts' forecasts for pretax profits ranged from 218 million to 232 million, after restructuring costs, up from 206 million last time.</p>
<p>The group reported trading profit of 198 million from its beverages business and 105 million from confectionery, with its American Dr Pepper/7UP business, acquired in January 1995 for $1.71 billion, providing most of the profits growth.</p>
<p>The group set aside 35 million pounds for the restructuring of its Schweppes France operation -- reflecting the decision to set up in partnership with San Benedetto, the Italian producer of mineral water and soft drinks -- to build a new plant and close down two existing older ones.</p>
<p>The company has reached agreement to sell its 51 percent stake in Coca-Cola &amp; Schweppes Beverages for 622.5 million which will produce a substantial one-off gain in the full year and greatly reduce its debt. ($1=.6406 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
