<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31189" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Morgan Grenfell funds to resume Thursday.</title>
<headline>Morgan Grenfell funds to resume Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morgan Grenfell Asset Management, the fund management arm of Germany's Deutsche Bank AG, said trading will resume on Thursday in its three European funds suspended on Monday.</p>
<p>The three funds -- the 788 million stg MG European Growth Trust, the 134 million stg MG Europa and the 445 million stg Dublin-listed MG European Capital Growth -- were suspended pending investigation into what DMG called &quot;possible irregularities centring on certain unquoted securities.&quot;  </p>
<p>MGAM said fund managers will meet their liabilities &quot;in respect of any irregularities identified in the course of the investigation into the three funds.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's Investment Management Regulatory Organisation (IMRO) has said it is investigating the management of the funds in conjunction with MGAM.</p>
<p>The company said its parent bank Deutsche Bank has bought some of the securities in the funds for its own account with a view to protecting investors' interests. It said that after taking this action, the prices at which the funds recommence dealing should not be affected by such irregularities.&quot;  </p>
<p>MGAM said enquiries centre only on the three funds and that dealing in all other Morgan Grenfell investment funds are unaffected.</p>
<p>MGAM confirmed that Peter Young the manager of two of the funds -- MG European Growth Trust and MG European Capital Growth -- has been suspended and said he has been replaced by Stuart Mitchell who until February 1996 was manager of its offshore MG European Profund.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for IMRO said it had been working hard with MGAM to remove investors in the three funds from the state of limbo they had been in since Monday.  </p>
<p>IMRO said it was far too early to tell when the investigation into the funds would be complete.</p>
<p>The investigation is thought to centre on the level of unquoted securities in the fund and their valuation. These include stock in some high-tech Scandinavian companies.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Deutsche Bank may have spent around 150 million stg buying securities for its own account and thus removing them from the funds.</p>
<p>The sources said the theory behind the action was that, with the suspect securities removed, the funds should resume dealing at prices close to where they were suspended.</p>
<p>But the sources said that the 150 million stg spent by Deutsche would not be lost because the stock does have a certain value which remains to be set. -- Joe Ortiz, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8864</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
