<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31194" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lloyd's recovery plan go-ahead seen shortly.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's recovery plan go-ahead seen shortly.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London may shortly secure the necessary approval from the British government for the insurance market's recovery plan to go ahead, industry sources said.</p>
<p>They said there may be news of the approval on Wednesday, although last-minute finalising of details could see an announcement put off until Thursday.</p>
<p>Lloyd's has been waiting for approval from the Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) since declaring a 3.2 billion pounds ($5 billion) settlement offer to investors last Friday.</p>
<p>It said then it had the support of 91 percent of its more than 34,000 investors worldwide, called Names, for the offer, which is crucial to the success of the recovery plan.</p>
<p>Under the recovery proposals, the insurance market would reinsure billions of pounds in liabilities into a new company called Equitas.</p>
<p>Once the DTI gives the green light, events are likely to move quickly. All pre-1993 claims and liabilities will be transferred to Equitas from Lloyd's, allowing the market to trade on and loss-making Names to leave.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.6406 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
