<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31195" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Mind-reading dogs prepare a welcome.</title>
<headline>Mind-reading dogs prepare a welcome.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British researcher has proved what dog owners have long suspected -- that their pets know when they're coming home from work.</p>
<p>The research showed that 46 percent of dogs started preparing to welcome their owners up to an hour before they got home, even if they worked irregular hours, Thursday's Times newspaper reported.</p>
<p>The animals usually become agitated and go to the window to watch for the owner's return.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people might call this weird, but for many pet owners it is perfectly normal,&quot; said researcher Rupert Sheldrake, former director of cell biology and biochemistry at Cambridge University.</p>
<p>Some cats and other pets showed the same psychic bond with their owners, said Sheldrake, who collected 1,500 case studies from around the world and carried out a survey of more than 400 pet-owning households in Britain.</p>
<p>One mynah bird would begin shouting &quot;Robbie's Coming Home&quot; when its owner was returning from an overseas trip, the Times said.  </p>
<p>And a report by an independent think-tank on Monday said Britain's lack of preparation for the single European currency could cost up to 20,000 jobs in industry and the City of London's financial district.</p>
<p>The letter was signed by the chief executive or chairman of B.A.T Industries, British Aerospace, British Petroleum, BUPA, Burson-Marsteller/Europe, Coopers &amp; Lybrand, Glaxo Wellcome, Guinness, Northern Foods, Rentokil, Shell Transport and Trading , Unigate, Unilever and Vauxhall Motors.</p>
<p>&quot;Many aspects of monetary union remain to be resolved. Leaving an empty chair at the table would mean that British interests would be unrepresented as crucial decisions were taken,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>It said such a gesture &quot;could leave British businesses at a competitive disadvantage for years to come&quot;.</p>
<p>Continued participation in the preparation for a single currency would ensure Britain could protect its own interests as well as reassuring inward investors, the industrialists said.</p>
<p>Such investors would &quot;perhaps rightly, interpret any decision to rule out membership as the first act in a process of disengagement from one of the largest markets in the world&quot;.  </p>
<p>The Financial Times said there was pressure on Major to rule out British participation in monetary union, either at the start date of 1999 or in the five-year life of the next parliament.</p>
<p>It said the Treasury had been sent a copy of the letter, adding that only about half of the businessmen approached had agreed to sign the letter, with large clearing banks among those unwilling to add their names.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I92300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
