<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31199" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Zell launches hostile $400 million bid for Chateau.</title>
<headline>Zell launches hostile $400 million bid for Chateau.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>A company led by Chicago property developer Sam Zell Wednesday launched a $400 million hostile takeover bid for manufactured home park operator Chateau Properties Inc.</p>
<p>The bid was the latest of several for Michigan-based Chateau, a real estate investment trust that manages communities made up of manufactured homes, and analysts said Zell's chances of success were good.</p>
<p>Zell's Manufactured Home Communities Inc. offered $26 a share in cash for Chateau's outstanding common shares, operating units and options, or about $400 million.</p>
<p>The bid comes after Chateau did not respond to an earlier, similar bid by Zell that offered cash or stock. The latest bid competes with a stock offer from Sun Communities Inc. worth about $372 million.</p>
<p>Chateau's stock closed Wednesday at $26.375 a share, up 25 cents, on the New York Stock Exchange. Manufactured Home's shares closed at $18.50, down 12.5 cents, also on the NYSE.</p>
<p>Analysts who specialise in real estate investment trusts said Zell had a good chance of success.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he probably has a pretty good shot at it,&quot; said William Acheson, an analyst for Smith Barney. &quot;It's difficult for a board to nix an all-cash deal that is very attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They've (Manufactured Home) said all along that if the board sends signals that it's not going to be accommodating, they would take it straight to shareholders,&quot; said BT Securities analyst Kevin Comer.</p>
<p>Chateau officials were not immediately available for comment. In the past Chateau has said that its articles of incorporation prohibit any entity or person from owning more than 7 percent of its outstanding common shares without board approval.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, said the 7 percent rule was designed to assure the company maintains its tax-preferred status as a real estate investment trust (REIT). To maintain such status, the five largest investors cannot own a total of more than 50 percent of the company, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The intention is to keep the tax-preferred REIT status, and it is not intended to be a defence mechanism whatsoever,&quot; said one analyst who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Chateau's board members are mainly holders of operating partnership units. Although Manufactured Home's offer includes those board members, capital gains tax would keep the $26 cash offer from being attractive, analysts said. Manufactured Home's earlier stock offer was valued at about $21 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the board's hiding behind the 7 percent (rule) would subject them to some legal ramifications,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;I think it's a good deal.&quot;</p>
<p>The tug-of-war in the industry began in July when Chateau and Colorado-based ROC Communities Inc. agreed to merge into one company, Chateau Communities.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home, based in Chicago, followed with an offer of $26 a share in cash, or 1.15 Manufactured Home shares per Chateau share, worth about $21 a share.</p>
<p>Just days later Sun Communities Inc. offered 0.892 share per Chateau share, currently valued at about $25 a share, or about $372 million.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home said it believes its offer provides a &quot;substantially greater&quot; value to Chateau's shareholders than the proposed ROC transaction or Sun Communities' bid.</p>
<p>The four companies operate sites for pre-fabricated homes. Most of the high-quality properties have already been taken up, and it is difficult to secure zoning for manufactured housing, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so few large portfolios left out there,&quot; Smith Barney's Acheson said.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home said it has received overwhelming support from Chateau shareholders, but it is still hoping for a friendly deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd still like to work out a deal,&quot; Manufactured Home Chief Executive David Helfand said in an interview. &quot;We're committed to this because it makes sense.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
