<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31192" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Rural British town mourns loss of innocence.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Rural British town mourns loss of innocence.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LAUNCESTON, England 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>For as long as anyone can remember there hasn't been a murder in this quiet country town tucked between the Atlantic and English channel coasts in the centre of Cornwall.</p>
<p>There is the occasional petty robbery, some vandalism and the odd bit of graffiti but serious crime is virtually unheard of in this quiet backwater.</p>
<p>So when news broke that a 13-year-old girl from its only secondary school had been raped and murdered during a school trip to France, Launceston's 6,500 residents felt as if they had been collectively violated.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially there was deep shock. People couldn't believe this could happen. Quite a lot of families are related through marriage so it hit the entire area,&quot; said Tim Newcombe, the local vicar.</p>
<p>The nature and mysterious circumstances surrounding the death of Caroline Dickinson on July 18 only added to the horror. But worse was to come as police gradually turned their attention from France to Caroline's schoolmates.</p>
<p>While sleeping in the same room as four of her friends in the youth hostel in Pleine-Fougeres in Brittany, the quiet blonde was raped and smothered.</p>
<p>No one heard the intruder enter the room or commit the crime. Her roommates did not realise she was dead until they were unable to wake her in the morning.</p>
<p>French police were quick to cordon off the area, question the 39 children on the trip and other guests at the hostel and take DNA samples from the male teachers and bus driver.</p>
<p>When a French vagrant, Patrice Pade, was arrested and confessed, all of Launceston breathed a sigh of relief that the murderer had been caught and the nightmare would finally end.</p>
<p>But Pade was released after DNA tests showed he could not have raped Caroline. French police arrived in Launceston to interview the children again and to take DNA samples from the five schoolboys who also stayed at the youth hostel.</p>
<p>The tests proved negative but the fact that they were necessary and the police presence in Launceston forced the children to relive the crime and prolonged the town's sorrow.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody feels they have had enough. There was a sense of relief (that the boys were cleared),&quot; said Alan Wroath, headteacher at Launceston Community College.</p>
<p>Lawyer Katharine Parnall, who acted as legal representative for the boys who were tested, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;No one ever believed they could possibly be defendants, just the certainty of elimination was a relief because it meant a possible end to the trauma,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Mayor Barry Jordan said the DNA tests would put to rest any suspicions about the boys but the horror still continues.</p>
<p>&quot;The circumstances of the crime are what is keeping everyone's thoughts alive on the subject because it is such a mystery. It's an Agatha Christie novel. How did it happen in such circumstances? This is what everyone wants solved.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to know how and why it could have happened. I think when the person is caught only then will we know the true story.&quot;</p>
<p>Arrest, release, more questions and tests and differences between British and French police procedures have added to the confusion and frustration felt by the people.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a measure of misunderstanding,&quot; admitted Newcombe. &quot;Our systems are so very different. Ignorance led to frustration. People couldn't understand why their police didn't act like our police.&quot;</p>
<p>But he was quick to add that there was no amimosity towards French officials handling the case. Nor did he think it would harm relations with the youth hostel where students from Launceston have stayed for more than 15 years.</p>
<p>French police have been questioning new suspects and their British counterparts are investigating a possible link with an attack on another girl at around the same time.</p>
<p>But more than a month after the crime, police seem no closer to catching Caroline's killer. Newcombe believes that only when the murderer is caught and convicted will the town's wounds begin to heal, but its former innocence will be gone for good.</p>
<p>&quot;The sense of shock and sadness will linger. There will always be something different in Launceston.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUNCESTON, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
