<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31208" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti seesaws on De Benedetti departure.</title>
<headline>Olivetti seesaws on De Benedetti departure.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in loss-making Italian information technology group Olivetti seesawed on Wednesday after the sudden resignation of chairman Carlo De Benedetti and as the group turned in another half year loss.</p>
<p>The share price jumped nearly 13 percent in early trade as the market reacted positively to what was seen as De Benedetti's defeat in a fierce duel for control with new managing director Francesco Caio.</p>
<p>But the stock rapidly subsided to close three percent up as initial enthusiasm waned and caution over the future of the group, particularly its problematic PC company, set in.</p>
<p>&quot;Olivetti's problems have not been addressed, a lawyer has taken over as chairman...and the results were awful,&quot; said one share trader in Milan.</p>
<p>&quot;De Benedetti's resignation is positive but once people understand the complete value of Olivetti then the price fluctuation is more likely to be minus 10 than plus 10 percent,&quot; said broker Robert Meier of Pasfin Securities in Milan.</p>
<p>Later Olivetti said director-general Renzo Francesconi, appointed in July, had resigned and would be replaced by Piero Nardi, former managing director of shipping group Serra/GTA.</p>
<p>The group scheduled a phone-in conference for analysts late on Wednesday, with prime questions expected to be on the depth of losses and the future for the loss-making PC operations.</p>
<p>Olivetti said on Tuesday it made a 440.2 billion lire ($290.6 million) pre-tax loss for the first half of 1996, after a full year consolidated loss of 1.598 trillion in 1995.</p>
<p>It also made a 200 billion lire provision for restructuring and divestments deriving from its decision to &quot;accelerate the reduction of its presence in the hardware sector.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts took this to mean it wants to exit from the competitive PC sector, the area that made De Benedetti's name in the 1980s but proved a burden in the tougher 1990s climate.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares had a jerky opening after the 61-year-old tycoon resigned late on Tuesday, soaring 10 percent from near record lows previously and triggering automatic suspension.</p>
<p>Stock market authorities widened fluctuation bands to 15 percent and the share climbed to 820 lire (54 cents) per share before slipping back to close at 749 lire.</p>
<p>The stock lost around nine percent on Monday and Tuesday, coming close to a record low of 681 lire hit last July as rumours abounded about conflict between De Benedetti and Caio, 39, who took over as managing director in July and is viewed as favoured by disgruntled foreign institutional investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Carlo De Benedetti has lost the duel for Olivetti,&quot; the Italian newspaper Il Corriere della Sera wrote. It called the demise of &quot;The Engineer&quot; after nearly 20 years with the company &quot;the start of a new phase in the history of Olivetti&quot;.</p>
<p>La Repubblica daily said after three days of clashes between De Benedetti and Caio they reached a compromise, with the financier made honorary chairman, but off the board, and new chairman De Benedetti's lawyer Antonio Tesone. De Benedetti's son Rodolfo will be part of an executive committee.</p>
<p>Union leaders at Olivetti's personal computer factory in Scarmagno called a one-hour stoppage on Wednesday, citing their concern for the future of their jobs.</p>
<p>Guglielmo Epifani, joint secretary general of the CGIL trade union, told Italian television: &quot;What we have here is an ownership made up of foreign shareholders and an Italian bank.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamental question is whether this new ownership group is capable of indicating for the future of Olivetti a strategy which will allow 30,000 workers in Italian information technology to play a role in that future,&quot; Epifani said.</p>
<p>($1=1515 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
