<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31201" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Man defrauds Barclays to buy racing cars.</title>
<headline>Man defrauds Barclays to buy racing cars.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>An investment advisory firm employee has been arrested for defrauding Barclays Bank of up to $11 million to buy 30 autos, including a Porsche, a Lamberghini, a Jaguar and several Grand Prix racing cars, federal prosecutors said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Trevor Hunt, 31, is accused of falsely representing for the past two years that he was acting on behalf of Manhattan-based Sass Investor Services when he instructed Barclays to wire the funds into a Sass profit-sharing account held for Sass by Bear, Stearns &amp; Co.</p>
<p>The federal complaint against Hunt alleges he sent faxes to Bear Stearns directing the investment firm to transfer the funds received from Barclays to various bank accounts Hunt had opened under his and his brother's name, as well as various corporations.</p>
<p>Hunt allegedly used a photocopied signature of Sass' chief financial officer on the faxes.</p>
<p>The complaint alleged that he used the same method to remove an additional $1.5 million in Sass' assets.</p>
<p>Hunt used the mony to buy the cars, several homes, Georgio Armani suits and other expensive clothing and electronic equipment, the complaint charged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
