<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31207" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq no-fly zone enforced, explosions in Baghdad.</title>
<headline>Iraq no-fly zone enforced, explosions in Baghdad.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States unleashed a second wave of cruise missiles at Iraq on Wednesday and began enforcing an expanded no-fly zone on Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's airforce.</p>
<p>In Baghdad, heavy explosions were heard in the city after dark but the cause was unclear. There was heavy anti-aircraft fire but the United States denied it was involved.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said Iraqi forces twice challenged the new zone after it took effect at noon Baghdad time -- sending two MiG fighters toward U.S. planes before turning off and tracking a U.S. F-16 fighter with radar until it retaliated with a missile.</p>
<p>But Perry said the missile raids and its readiness to engage any Iraqi challenge showed &quot;we will take whatever action is necessary to enforce the no-fly zone.&quot;</p>
<p>Enforcement of the no-fly zone for Iraqi planes came hours after the United States fired the second wave of missiles in two days at targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Four ships fired 17 cruise missiles in a &quot;mop-up&quot; operation ordered by President Bill Clinton, U.S. officials said. The mission, which Iraq said killed one person and wounded seven, was to destroy Iraq's ability to attack aircraft enforcing the expanded no-fly zone.</p>
<p>The second wave was aimed at targets in southern Iraq not destroyed in an attack by 27 missiles on Tuesday which Baghdad said killed five people and wounded 19.</p>
<p>Clinton ordered the attacks in retaliation for its offensive in support of one Kurdish faction against a rival Kurdish rebel group in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Saddam on Tuesday vowed to resist the attacks and Iraq's official newspapers, including Babel which is run by Saddam's eldest son Uday, reiterated on Wednesday that Baghdad would ignore restrictions on Iraqi flights.</p>
<p>&quot;Once again we say to the ungodly Americans in a loud voice ...from today there are no more imaginary parallel lines...from today there will be no (part) of Iraqi territory off limits to us whether in the north or the south,&quot; said Babel.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall defend our sovereignty with our nails and teeth.&quot;</p>
<p>Saddam met air defence commanders on Wednesday, the Iraqi News Agency (INA) reported.</p>
<p>However, the United States said Iraq had obeyed a warning to withdraw aircraft from the expanded no-fly zone or leave them on the ground, removing more than half the planes in the zone before the dealine. A Western military source said Iraq flew out some 30 planes, including Russian MiG and Sukhoi jets.</p>
<p>U.S. Air Force General Joseph Ralston, deputy chairman of the military Joint Chiefs of Staff, said U.S., British and French aircraft began patrolling the new no-fly zone in southern Iraq in an operation called &quot;Southern Watch&quot;.</p>
<p>The U.S. decided on Tuesday to extend the air exclusion zone in southern Iraq to the 33rd parallel, on the outskirts of Baghdad, from the 32nd parallel where it was fixed after Iraq's defeat in the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Residents of Arbil, which was captured on Saturday by combined Iraqi-Kurdish forces to start the crisis, were trying to return to normal.</p>
<p>But a spokesman for the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK), which was driven from Arbil, said Iraqi troops had resumed shelling its positions near the northern town of Chamchamal and the main road leading to the PUK stronghold of Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>There was no independent confirmation of the report. Iraq said at the weekend it was pulling its forces out of Kurdish areas of northern Iraq while U.S. officials were sceptical.</p>
<p>World markets reacted calmly to the second wave of missile strikes, which briefly boosted oil prices in Asia.</p>
<p>But diplomatic criticism of the U.S. missile attacks mounted and members of the U.S. Congress expressed concern that U.S. allies had not shown the support given when Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>The European Union postponed issuing a joint statement on the U.S. attacks on Iraq, underlining the division in Europe over the American action, EU diplomats said in Brussels.</p>
<p>They said Britain had pushed on Tuesday for a strong statement of support for U.S. action but others, notably France, had resisted.</p>
<p>France, a U.S. Gulf War ally, called for negotiations to ensure a U.N. resolution allowing Iraq to use the proceeds of oil sales for food and medical supplies takes effect as soon as possible. Washington had said it must be delayed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
