<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31204" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubbermaid buys Graco; stock plunges on profit warning.</title>
<headline>Rubbermaid buys Graco; stock plunges on profit warning.</headline>
<dateline>WOOSTER, Ohio</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rubbermaid Inc. said Wednesday it agreed to buy Graco Children's Products Inc. for $320 million in cash, but Rubbermaid's stock fell after it warned that its earnings for the latest quarter will be flat.</p>
<p>The Wooster, Ohio-based maker of plastic and rubber products, said it was buying Graco, a manufacturer of infant strollers, portable play yards, and other infant products, from a privately owned group of investors.</p>
<p>News of the acquisition of Elverson, Pa.-based Graco, failed to spark enthusiasm for Rubbermaid's stock, which plunged $3.50 to $23 on the New York Stock Exchange, after the company said its third-quarter sales and earnings per share will be comparable with a year-ago.</p>
<p>In last year's third quarter, Rubbermaid earned 32 cents a share, or $50.3 million on sales of $641.5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;People were expecting that the quarter could be up 15 to 20 percent,&quot; said Eric Bosshard of Midwest Research-Maxus Group.</p>
<p>Continued softness in the sales of large, outdoor juvenile products will offset gains in other parts of the company, Rubbermaid said.</p>
<p>The company said a jump of more than 50 percent in the cost of plastic resin -- the raw material used in making plastics -- had hurt Rubbermaid's results.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite significant gains in lowering our cost structure, higher costs for resin and lower-than-expected unit volume will prevent us from continuing to attain the growth in profitability we had been expecting this year,&quot; said Chairman and Chief Executive Wolfgang Schmitt.</p>
<p>Analysts said Rubbermaid was acquiring Graco in an effort to limit its dependence on plastic and to diversify its raw material base.</p>
<p>&quot;They are so reliant on this one raw material and its been obvious that resin costs have been going against them,&quot; said Eric Bosshard, an analyst at Midwest Rsearch-Maxus Group.</p>
<p>Another analyst who did not want to be identified said he had anticipated Rubbermaid's third quarter sales to rise about 6 percent from a year-ago.</p>
<p>Analysts said the impact of higher resin prices is likely to carry into the fourth quarter, which typically is weaker than the third quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WOOSTER, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
