<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31214" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti shares surge after De Benedetti quits.</title>
<headline>Olivetti shares surge after De Benedetti quits.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Olivetti surged 10 percent on Wednesday after chairman Carlo De Benedetti quit the loss-making Italian information technology group, triggering an automatic suspension to their trading on the Milan bourse.</p>
<p>Shares had begun 7.44 percent higher at 780 lire per share before being suspended at 798 lire shortly after 0810 GMT.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares had fallen around nine percent, close to all-time lows, on Monday and Tuesday as rumours swept the stock market about conflict between top managers and on concern about the company's financial health.</p>
<p>Under an automatic suspension, a stock is suspended for a set period and resumes trading if there are price quotes below the 10 percent ceiling. Alternatively stock market authorities can decide to widen the trading bands.</p>
<p>De Benedetti, hailed in the mid-1980s as the tycoon with the Midas touch, announced late on Tuesday that he had resigned as chairman and from the board of the group he transformed from an ailing typewriter maker to a personal computer pioneer.</p>
<p>The sudden decision by the 61-year-old entrepreneur ended his period of almost 20 years at the helm.</p>
<p>De Benedetti, in a statement, said he was resigning as chairman and board member in line with a declaration he made linked to the successful outcome of a massive 2.26 trillion lire ($1.49 billion) capital increase concluded in early 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;I declared that if the company had not reached positive economic results in the course of 1996, I would respond with what I considered to be the appropriate steps,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Olivetti, which has failed to break even since 1990, announced a further pre-tax loss for the first half of 1996 of 440.2 billion lire after making a full year consolidated loss of 1.598 trillion in 1995.</p>
<p>De Benedetti first came to international prominence in 1978 when he took over the management of Olivetti, then a moribund, loss-making typewriter maker, after his family's finance company, CIR, acquired a 15 per cent stake.</p>
<p>It seemed a doomed enterprise but the industrialist transformed the company into Europe's biggest supplier of office automation equipment and one of the largest makers of personal computers after International Business Machines Corp (IBM).</p>
<p>On Tuesday, with the announcement of his departure as chairman, De Benedetti left Olivetti a far bigger company than the one he rescued but one still mired in debt.</p>
<p>The board named board member Antonio Tesone as the new chairman at a meeting held in Milan late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Francesco Caio remains managing director after his appointment in July and the board also proposed creating an executive committee of Tesone, Caio and two other board members.</p>
<p>Olivetti shares spun seven percent lower on the Italian bourse and closed on Tuesday five percent weaker at 726 lire. Their all-time low of 681 was set in late July.</p>
<p>Rumours abounded all day of conflict among Olivetti top management and traders sold on concerns losses would be greater than forecast previously. The company had been due to announce first half results on September 26.</p>
<p>Olivetti said its operating loss was 80.8 billion lire in the 1996 first half while the net loss was 147.9 billion.</p>
<p>The board also approved a 200 billion lire provision against possible charges stemming from divestments and restructuring &quot;deriving from the decision of the company to accelerate the reduction of its presence in the hardware sector,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>($1=1515 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
