<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31213" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asia markets shrug off latest Iraq attack.</title>
<headline>Asia markets shrug off latest Iraq attack.</headline>
<byline>Marguerite Nugent</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States' second missile attack on Iraq gave Asian oil prices a brief boost on Wednesday but other markets shrugged off the raid, with traders seeing it as a mopping up exercise and not an escalation.</p>
<p>In Singapore, North Sea Brent crude oil futures rose after news the U.S. Navy fired 17 Tomahawk missiles at air defence targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The action came a day after the United States launched 27 of the precision weapons at similar targets in the area.</p>
<p>October Brent rose to $22.50 a barrel on the news then eased to $22.12 in late trading, down nine cents from its last close on the London's IPE, well down from Tuesday's peak of $23.50 a barrel in Singapore.</p>
<p>Iraq had been expected to resume oil sales this month for the first time since its 1990 invasion of Kuwait but the United Nations delayed the plan after Iraqi troops moved against Kurds in Iraq's north. &quot;The (oil) market is nervous and cautious. Reaction to the second missile attack seems to be relatively calm after a similar situation yesterday,&quot; an oil trader in Tokyo said.</p>
<p>In foreign exchange trading, the dollar was little changed against most currencies and was quoted at 109.18/23 against 109.24/31 at the close in New York on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see the typical dollar-buying in a crisis because it isn't a crisis,&quot; said Koji Asano, senior manager at Fuji Bank.</p>
<p>Gold prices in Hong Kong and Tokyo showed little reaction to the latest attack. Bullion ended in Hong Kong at US$385.70/386.20 an ounce on Wednesday against New York's previous close of US$386.15/386.55.</p>
<p>Most regional equities markets recovered early losses and ended slightly higher.</p>
<p>In Tokyo, the key Nikkei 225-share index ended up 3.72 points, or 0.02 percent, at 20,201.87 after clawing its way back from a low of 20,066.02 after news of the second attack.</p>
<p>&quot;Wall Street as well as Tokyo thought the fiasco was over and just part of President Clinton's election campaign. Anxiety was fading when the second round came,&quot; said Keiji Arai, a strategist at Sanyo Securities.</p>
<p>Hong Kong stocks rose on expectations the conflict would not escalate and hurt corporate earnings.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index finished 119.77 points, or 1.09 percent, higher at 11,076.95.</p>
<p>South Korean shares seemed oblivious to the Gulf conflict and the composite index ended up a provisional 21.84 points, or 2.84 percent, to 791.64, on heavy volume.</p>
<p>Dealers said a rush to buy blue-chip shares ahead of next month's expansion of the foreign shareholding limit drove the market higher.</p>
<p>Thai stocks continued their recent falls on jitters over the U.S. attack and concerns about the domestic economy. In late trade, the SET Index was down 1.38 per cent to 1,049.74 points. It fell two percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A firmer ending on Wall Street helped sentiment when trading resumed in Asia, some traders said.</p>
<p>After steep early falls, U.S. stocks recovered when a fresh batch of economic data did not prove as strong as feared.</p>
<p>The news dashed fears the Federal Reserve would push interest rates higher.</p>
<p>But while the news was encouraging, traders noted that most of the 32-point gain in the Dow Jones Industrial Average reflected a rise in the price of energy company stocks, which are benefiting from the higher oil prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
