<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31218" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Refuge moves to allay life merger concerns.</title>
<headline>Refuge moves to allay life merger concerns.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British life assurer Refuge Group has moved to stave off a shareholder revolt over a proposed merger with United Friendly, proposing to issue a security giving shareholders access to future surplus assets from its ordinary branch.</p>
<p>Refuge chief executive John Cudworth told Reuters on Wednesday that the firm's shareholders suggested such a move would be a positive addition to the deal with United.</p>
<p>He added that an extraordinary general meeting to vote on the merger has been postponed to September 26.</p>
<p>&quot;This addresses the issue of the orphan assets of Refuge.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It means that should there be any future surplus of assets of Refuge, it would be issued to the present generation of Refuge shareholders,&quot; said Cudworth.</p>
<p>The company hopes that by doing this it will win the solid support of some major shareholders who were wavering on whether or not to back the merger.</p>
<p>It is not so much the logic of the deal, but the valuation of Refuge'a assets that has upset several of them.</p>
<p>In particular, one at least has said publicly that, during discussions with the British government, Refuge could have unlocked more &quot;orphan&quot; assets for shareholders from its ordinary branch of business, not just the 430 million pounds identified in the industrial branch when the merger was announced last month.</p>
<p>However, Refuge does not think in the light of its talks with the Department of Trade and Industry, that any more value will be released to shareholders from its with profit life fund.</p>
<p>It also emphasised the merger terms have not been changed.</p>
<p>Two big shareholders, Prudential Corp and Britannic Assurance, were believed by industry sources to have had reservations about the orphan asset issue.</p>
<p>Britannic last week said this was complex, while Prudential is also in discussions with the DTI over the distribution of its own surplus assets. Neither could be reached for comment, but both were earlier in the day still considering their decisions.</p>
<p>Perpetual, which owns 7.2 percent Refuge and which along with the much smaller 0.2 percent block of shares owned by First Marathon, has said it would vote against the merger at the original meeting on September 9, was unavailable.</p>
<p>First Marathon earlier on Wednesday gave seven reasons why it, as a Refuge shareholder, was against the deal and also the proposed terms that would be acceptable to it.</p>
<p>It said the terms did not properly reflect financial considerations over and above embedded value and the enlarged group should be equally split. Under the current terms, Refuge shareholders would hold about 47 percent of the new firm.</p>
<p>SBC Warburg said in a research note it did not dispute the merger's logic, but said, &quot;failure to quantify costs and savings and the inability to repatriate excess capital to shareholders means that the benefits of the deal are not overwhelming.&quot;</p>
<p>It added that holders of United Friendly ordinary shares, which carry with them voting rights, have been treated disproportionately favourably.</p>
<p>The two companies did not quantify cost savings when they unveiled the merger, but analysts estimated a planned 25 percent cut in the 7,000 combined workforce and other measures could lop 60 million pounds off the current 208 million annual cost base.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
