<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31221" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gold dips on lack of response to U.S./Iraq tension.</title>
<headline>Gold dips on lack of response to U.S./Iraq tension.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices turned lower in early European trading on Wednesday as the market, disappointed that U.S. missile strikes on Iraq failed to spark a serious price rally, sold off existing positions.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed at $385.95 an ounce, against $386.60 on Tuesday afternoon and a London close of $386.95.</p>
<p>&quot;The general tone is quite bearish,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold blipped up 50 cents yesterday when the first missiles went out and people went long. But they started getting out when they saw the (Mideast) Gulf had no effect on gold,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Otherwise business was fairly quiet and likely to remain so until mid-September when the seasonal lull ended, dealers said. Gold had popped slightly higher early on Tuesday on news of the first U.S. cruise missile attack on Iraq. But prices then drifted back to previous levels during the European trading day.</p>
<p>The second U.S. missile attack early Wednesday morning had elicited little initial reaction in Asian markets, before prices eased in European trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Time and time again the market expects gold to soar on political, economic or financial crises,&quot; analyst Nick Moore of Flemings Global Mining Group said in a commentary.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations of such a response hark back to the good old days, which were probably the anomaly, rather than to gold's more measured role in today's world markets,&quot; Moore added.</p>
<p>Some dealers said they suspected a further easing in gold prices near term, with $383-$384 as the target.</p>
<p>&quot;I would rather be bearish at this point,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>But others said a sizeable movement was unlikely at this point and the broader $385-$390 trading range would hold steady.</p>
<p>Silver prices followed gold lower to be indicated at $5.16 an ounce, down two cents from Tuesday's London close.</p>
<p>Platinum was indicated off $1.00 at $395.25 while palladium was down $0.50 at $125.25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
