<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31229" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe eases limit on foreigners' equity stakes.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe eases limit on foreigners' equity stakes.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's central Reserve Bank on Wednesday lifted the ceiling for foreign participation on the local stock market as part of the southern African country's efforts to attract investment.</p>
<p>&quot;As part of ongoing efforts to improve the investment climate, the present limit of 35 percent foreign investor participation on the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange (ZSE) is raised, with immediate effect, to 40 percent,&quot; Reserve Bank governor Leonard Tsumba said in a statement.</p>
<p>In measures previously urged by stock market analysts and brokers to stimulate growth of the local bourse, Tsumba said single investors were now allowed to own 10 percent, up from the previous five percent, of equity in a listed company.</p>
<p>The bank last eased the limit on foreign participation in December when it allowed foreign investors to buy up to 35 percent of total equity of a company on the ZSE from 25 percent.</p>
<p>Brokers and market analysts were unavailable for comment on Wednesday as Tsumba's statement came after trade on the ZSE -- which soared to new levels on the back of falling short-term money market rates -- had ended for the day.</p>
<p>Tsumba also announced measures to curb money supply growth which he said had remained stubbornly high at above 22 percent.</p>
<p>He said that with immediate effect all foreign currency accounts were now eligible for a 17.5 percent reserve requirement in Zimbabwe dollars and the central bank would, beginning this month, pay for gold purchases in foreign currency.</p>
<p>He said the Reserve Bank would also accommodate unsecured overnight advances (for accounting errors only) for banks and discount houses up to Z$1 million. Beyond that level, it would demand a formal explanation and justification of error.</p>
<p>&quot;These measures, together with current open market operations, will ensure that money supply grows at no more than 22 percent per annum, sufficient to support private sector credit growth of at least 20 percent,&quot; Tsumba said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
