<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31238" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares fall, seen entering correction.</title>
<headline>Polish shares fall, seen entering correction.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares fell for the second session running and analysts said Wednesday's higher turnover which accompanied the unexpected fall and strong selling after price fixing signalled they could enter a correction phase.</p>
<p>The main market's WIG index fell 0.6 percent, to 13,882.3 and turnover rose 8.9 percent to 110.3 million zlotys ($40 million) on both markets as a total of 48 issues fell, 15 rose and 14 were flat.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that despite earlier expectations of a possible testing of the July 5 high of 14,282.2 of WIG, the market could fall to 13,000 points on profit-taking after the 11.6 percent rise since mid-August.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's session shows that the market might enter a correction phase,&quot; said Ryszard Wojnowski, an analyst at Bank Gdanski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said the correction was likely to be brief and that the market might rise again and challenge the July 5 high. But they were divided whether it would keep on rising afterwards or fall.</p>
<p>They were surprised by the garment maker Bytom's 10-percent surge in a 1.1-million zloty ($0.4 million) turnover.</p>
<p>Continuous trade turnover was at 0.8 million zlotys ($0.3 million) with Bank Przemyslowo-Handlowy (BPH), the only stock trading, staying flat.</p>
<p>Mass privatisation NFI units rose 2.6 percent in a heavy 18.5-million zloty ($6.7 million) turnover in the single price auction system and rose 3.1 percent in a 2.1-million zloty ($0.8 million) continuous trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
