<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31248" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Trouble mars Philippine government biddings.</title>
<headline>Trouble mars Philippine government biddings.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Espina</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two more high-profile Philippine privatisation projects ran into snags this week but analysts said on Wednesday these were normal &quot;birth pains&quot; for an economy just beginning to open up.</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely these bidding problems have a discouraging effect on potential investors but the confusion also stems from the fact that we are just starting to open up our industries,&quot; Jonas Ferrer at Pryce Securities told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They may be considered as birth pains,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, President Fidel Ramos ordered a re-evaluation of all bids for the privatisation of a container port at Subic Bay, a former U.S. naval base north of Manila.</p>
<p>The order was the result of a protest by International Container Terminal Services Inc (ICTSI), the highest bidder, after the Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority (SBMA) decided to award the project to a unit of Hutchison Whampoa Ltd</p>
<p>SBMA said it disqualified ICTSI, which operates the Manila international container terminal, because of a government ruling prohibiting monopolies.</p>
<p>Analysts added that one of the problems was the government's failure to clarify the rules prior to the bidding.</p>
<p>&quot;If ICTSI was not qualified because of government rules on monopoly, why then did SBMA prequalify the company?&quot; said Spencer Yap at BPI Capital.</p>
<p>Controversy also erupted over the privatisation of Camp John Hay, a former U.S. military recreation camp in the northern hill resort of Baguio.</p>
<p>ML&amp;H Corp, a Thai-Philippine joint venture, submitted a 1.58 billion peso tender to win a 25-year lease on the camp, four times more than the next highest bidder. But it has now decided it will not sign the lease agreement until its concerns over the exact area of land covered by the deal are resolved.</p>
<p>ML&amp;H president Sulficio Tagud said that the bid documents said the land covered 247 hectares but a due diligence study showed that only 122 hectares were available for development.</p>
<p>Analysts said most major privatisations have run into snags, including refiner Petron Corp, the prestigious Manila Hotel and the National Steel Corp.</p>
<p>In the power sector, state-run National Power Corp (NPC) was in hot water last year when Consolidated Electric Power Asia Ltd contested its decision to conduct a re-bidding of a 1,200-megawatt gas-fired power project in Batangas, south of Manila.</p>
<p>Despite the problems, analysts said the Philippines remains an attractive investment destination, partly as a result of government liberalisation policies.</p>
<p>&quot;Only conservative investors may be driven away but the more aggressive ones will still pursue the Philippines because the good returns are a sufficient come-on,&quot; Yap added.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the hassles, there is still good money to be made in the Philippines,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
