<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31241" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean economy to lose some of its luster in 1997.</title>
<headline>Chilean economy to lose some of its luster in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO, Chile</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chilean economy will see a soft landing in 1997 from years of heady growth, with a slower expansion and the lowest inflation since the early 1960s, the head of the Central Bank said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Weak prices for Chile's No. 1 export, copper, will nearly triple the trade deficit to $900 million from a projected $350 million this year, said interim Central Bank President Jorge Marshall.</p>
<p>In the bank's annual presentation to Congress, Marshall painted a picture of unspectacular growth, fiscal prudence and adverse conditions for Chilean exports.</p>
<p>&quot;For 1997, we expect to continue with gradual reduction in inflation, accompanied by economic growth that will be significant but below the trend over the last few years,&quot; Marshall said.</p>
<p>&quot;This will allow us to continue on the path of stability, growth and development,&quot; he told Congress in Valparaiso.</p>
<p>The economy will grow next year by 5.5 to 6 percent, down from over 7 percent this year, and inflation will sink to 5.5 percent from a projected 6.5 percent this year, said Marshall.</p>
<p>If achieved, the inflation rate will be Chile's lowest since 1960, when it reached 5.5 percent. Although next year will be Chile's 15th consecutive year of economic growth, the projected rate will be the slowest since 1990.</p>
<p>He signalled the Central Bank would continue with its restrictive monetary policies &quot;to encourage a more moderate pace in GDP and spending growth ... that is coherent with a medium and long-term equilibrium.&quot;</p>
<p>Santiago stocks took Marshall's address as a clear sign the bank had no intention of loosening interest rates and that it saw mediocre growth into next year as the price for lower inflation, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Santiago Stock Exchange's blue-chip index, which has posted no real growth this year as a whole, edged down 0.01 percent to 96.03 points by the close of the day.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO, Chile"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
