<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31245" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks follow bonds to higher close.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks follow bonds to higher close.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market closed on a strong note on Wednesday as the bond market climbed off the floor after Tuesday's solid selloff.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index rose 13.9 points to 2258.5 while September share price index futures contract rose 26 points to 2,263, a 4.5 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said the Dow's rebound off its day's lows, after the U.S. bond market was rescued by weaker than expected economic data, had proved sufficient incentive for local players.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken a guide from New York,&quot; said dealer Peter Struk of brokerage Reynolds and Co, noting that reasonable buying had underpinned the day's strength.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been good buying and we have held our ground.&quot;</p>
<p>Other traders made similar sentiments, saying the Dow's recuperative powers had allowed the local market to gain ground.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a pleasing showing,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;With the Dow showing some resilience, bonds have given us the impetus to go ahead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Caution was evident from both traders, though, as they pointed to continuing concerns over U.S. interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;It is still very much wait and see. People are still jittery about the U.S.,&quot; Struk noted.</p>
<p>Banks stole the limelight, rebounding as bond markets recovered. The banking index outperformed the rest of the market, adding 1.67 percent on the day compared to the benchmark All Ordinaries' gain of just 0.62 percent.</p>
<p>Other strong performances came from Kerry Packer-controlled television and magazine group Publishing and Broadcasting which scored highly with investors after a 50 percent higher full year net profit of A$225.4 million (US$178 million).</p>
<p>Among others, Qantas Airways shares ended off a couple of cents as oil prices jumped in response to the Iraqi crisis.</p>
<p>Other results came from transport and logistics group TNT which saw its shares end firmer, despite a sharply lower A$9.84 million full year net profit.</p>
<p>Oil and gas major Woodside saw its shares close stronger after nearly doubling its first half net profit to A$84.38 million, while coal miner QCT Resources also ended higher after more than doubling its full year net profit to A$71.47 million.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about nine to seven, while about 32 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>(A$=US0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
