<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31240" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech Skoda offers barter in MD fighter bid.</title>
<headline>Czech Skoda offers barter in MD fighter bid.</headline>
<byline>Jan Lopatka</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech engineering group Skoda a.s., a local agent for U.S.-based McDonnell Douglas Corp. (MD) is proposing a barter deal be used to encourage the Czech government to buy MD's F/A-18 &quot;Hornet&quot; fighter aircraft.</p>
<p>Skoda's spokesman Karel Samec said on Wednesday his firm would provide trucks made at Skoda's troubled Tatra a.s. and other goods in return for planes which the cash-strapped Czech military is considering in an upgrade its fleet.</p>
<p>&quot;McDonnell Douglas chose us as intermediator, but it depends on the Czech government and the Defence Ministry which has to decide if they want to buy any planes at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a barter deal. They would supply the fighters, and we would supply Czech goods to the States, namely Tatras and other things... And I know from the American side that this project has the support of the U.S. government,&quot; Samec added.</p>
<p>The Czechs along with former Warsaw Pact allies Poland and Hungary, all seen as frontrunners to join NATO, want to upgrade their fleets to be compatible with the military alliance.</p>
<p>McDonnell Douglas is competing against U.S. Lockheed Martin , makers of the F-16, Sweden's SAAB, which makes the &quot;Gripen&quot;, France's &quot;Mirage&quot;, and other groups to update a fleet of ageing Soviet-made Mig-21 planes.</p>
<p>However, the Czech government has delayed a decision on buying the planes as proposed cuts in defence spending have clouded the debate over the upgrading the army's aging fighters.</p>
<p>A spokesman at the Defence Ministry was not immediately avbailable for comment.</p>
<p>The Czech military has said it would need about 24 fighters to replace its old MiG-21s, while Hungary said it needs around 30 and Poland 100.</p>
<p>Samec said the deal would be for new or used F/A-18 &quot;Hornets&quot;, and would help the heavily-indebted Tatra, whose production has fallen to a fraction of communist-era levels.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a penetration (for Tatra) into the world's most important market... and it is advantageous because the Tatras have Detroit Diesel motors, so it could be used perhaps in the U.S. army,&quot; said Samec.</p>
<p>None of the fighter producers has publicly stated a price at which they would sell their planes to the Czech government.</p>
<p>Analysts say the planes typically cost over $20 million a piece new without supplementary equipment and technology. A cheaper option would be to buy second-hand planes at a fraction of the cost.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
