<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31243" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican stocks close down on rates, politics fear.</title>
<headline>Mexican stocks close down on rates, politics fear.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks failed to haul themselves out of the doldrums at the close of trade Tuesday amid expectations of a rise in interest rates and some political unease.</p>
<p>The bourse's leading index was off 42.59 points, or 1.29 percent, to stand at 3,266.99 at the close.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations that primary rate hikes of 100-150 basis points on the benchmark (28-day) Cetes (Treasury bill) rate affected the market from midday on,&quot; said Hector Chavez, an equity analyst at the Obsa brokerage house.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market's support at 3,250 points stood up very well,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The market's leading indicator closed slightly above a mid-session low of 3,259.84 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Early trading was definitely affected by the fall in the Dow Jones and increased 30-year Treasury bond rates following the U.S. air attack on Iraq,&quot; a floor trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nonetheless, the (Zapatista) guerrilla's withdrawal from talks with the government was a pretext for taking more profits,&quot; he added, referring to news the Chiapas rebels had suspended talks with the government.</p>
<p>The trader said the market broke through its 26-day moving average on the downside during the session, so that the bourse's support level is now at 3,100 points.</p>
<p>A total of 78.72 million shares changed hands in 3,101 trades held during the session. The market scoreboard showed 59 losers and 15 winners, with the remaining 17 stocks unchanged.</p>
<p>Telmex L shares gained a scant two centavos (half a cent) to 12.40 pesos ($1.64) on arbitrage due to peso losses, while its ADRs traded in New York closed 1/8 down at $32-3/4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
