<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31258" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan calls for Iraqi withdrawal from Kurd areas.</title>
<headline>Japan calls for Iraqi withdrawal from Kurd areas.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan, the world's biggest importer of Middle East oil and a strong backer of U.S. action against Iraq, on Wednesday called for Baghdad to immediately withdraw its forces from Kurdish areas of the country.</p>
<p>Speaking minutes after the United States announced its second missile attack on Iraq, deputy government spokesman Kazo Watanabe said the crisis could only be settled by an Iraqi withdrawal.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan strongly hopes for Iraq to withdraw from the northern areas (of Iraq) in order to settle the situation at the earliest possible instant,&quot; Kazo told a news conference.</p>
<p>In comments earlier on Wednesday before the second U.S. attack, Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto said he was concerned at the size of forces Iraq was moving into Kurdish areas.</p>
<p>&quot;Although I haven't actually seen everything on a satellite or anything, I am concerned that the Iraqis are moving thousands of military men and hundreds of tanks to the Kurdish area,&quot; Hashimoto said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
