<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31259" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Crude prices jump in Asia on second attack on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Crude prices jump in Asia on second attack on Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia jumped 30 cents on Wednesday after the United States said it launched a second missile attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>The benchmark October futures contract on the New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX), trading on the screen-based ACCESS system during Asian hours, jumped to $23.65 per barrel from the price of $23.35 it was at when news of the second missile attack first broke.</p>
<p>A U.S. administration official said the United States launched a second cruise missile attack on Iraq but did not immediately provide details.</p>
<p>The October futures price reached on Wednesday, however, was still well below the $24.25 high for the contract seen on Tuesday after the United States' first missile attack.</p>
<p>The first attack involved 27 cruise missiles fired by U.S. Navy warships and B-52 bombers at military targets in southern Iraq. It was a retaliation for the incursion of Iraqi forces into the northern Kurdish region where the United Nations operates a no-fly zone.</p>
<p>Defence officials said privately that the first missile attack on Iraqi air defence targets in the south of the country had not done the damage expected.</p>
<p>Tsutomu Toichi, director of Institute of Energy Economics (IEE) in Tokyo, said: &quot;I don't think NYMEX light crude will rise as high as $30 unless there is a major escalation in the confrontation. But it could top the high of yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the October Brent crude contract, trading on the Singapore International Monetary Exchange (SIMEX), rose as high as $22.50 per barrel after the news on Wednesday, up 29 cents from the London close.</p>
<p>One broker said the latest escalation of hostilities could push the October Brent contract to match its day-earlier high of $23.50, which was also the highest for any prompt month Brent contract since the Gulf War of 1991.</p>
<p>But he said he expected traders to be cautious about over-reacting.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be as much panic today as yesterday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By late Tokyo morning trade, October NYMEX crude was last traded at $23.44 and October Brent was last traded at $22.31.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
