<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31256" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China sees housing as new engine to drive economy.</title>
<headline>China sees housing as new engine to drive economy.</headline>
<byline>Mark O'Neill</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's State Council, or cabinet, is drawing up policies to encourage private buying of homes, which it wants to become one of the main engines of economic growth over the next five years, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Heavy spending on homes is necessary to absorb a dangerously high level of individual bank savings and buy thousands of empty apartments, while cars -- the next step on the consumer ladder -- remain too expensive and restricted, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Residents of coastal cities already have television, refrigerators and other domestic appliances,&quot; said Wu Zhengtong, deputy secretary-general of the Shanghai Housing Authority.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying a home will be the next major item. This will stimulate industries like construction materials and steel and be a new engine of growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate of individual savings is too high and at a dangerous level -- what if there were to be fluctuations and people took their money out of the banks?&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As of the end of June, individual bank savings in China reached a record 3.546 trillion yuan ($427 billion), an increase of 38.7 percent over a year earlier, official figures show.</p>
<p>On August 28, Shanghai announced measures to stimulate its housing market, halving the house purchase tax to 0.5 percent, raising rents on public homes by 50 percent to 1.8 yuan a square metre and allowing non-Shanghai people to obtain city residence permits if they buy apartments in certain areas of the city.</p>
<p>Shanghai is a leader in China in selling public housing, with 609,000 families having bought them as of the end of June, accounting for half the public housing area in the city.</p>
<p>But many people do not want to buy homes because their rents are low, they are waiting for their work units to allocate them a better home, the purchase prices are too high or because of restrictions on resale of homes they could buy from the state.</p>
<p>The State Council is working on a set of policies to address these issues, said a housing official who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Changes under consideration include making it easier to resell public homes, more bank loans to buy homes, lowering construction costs to bring prices closer to what people can afford, and charging people for new homes allocated to them by their work unit instead of getting them free as at present, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our estimate is that a price of 2,000 yuan per square metre is acceptable to ordinary people,&quot; Wu said. &quot;This can be funded by loans from bank and the public housing fund.&quot;</p>
<p>This fund consists of money contributed by state-run work units and their employers.</p>
<p>One aim of the policy is to reduce the enormous stock of empty housing. China has 50.31 million square metres of empty commercial housing, of which 36.18 million square metres is non-luxury, the Economic Information Daily said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It quoted vice minister of construction Mao Rubai as urging local governments and real estate enterprises to accelerate sales of empty houses.</p>
<p>The government should lower land prices to reduce the costs of developers, allowing vacant homes to be sold to low-income buyers at cost price, it quoted Mao as saying.</p>
<p>($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
