<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31260" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Second attack on Iraq jars Japan markets.</title>
<headline>Second attack on Iraq jars Japan markets.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese stock and oil markets were jolted on Wednesday by the second United States missile attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>Stockbrokers said they were surprised as the market had thought Tuesday's attack was a one-off incident.</p>
<p>Administration officials said the U.S. military launched a second cruise missile attack on Iraq. The officials, who asked not to be identified, provided no immediate details but said the new attack was authorised by President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>The key Nikkei was down 30.24 points, or 0.15 percent, to 20,167.91, having earlier risen from Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>But the dollar, which rose after Tuesday's attack, showed little reaction on Japanese markets.</p>
<p>Crude oil futures prices in Asia jumped 30 cents a barrel in the minutes after the initial report on CNN that the United States launched a second missile attack against Iraq.</p>
<p>The prompt New York Mercantile Exchange (NYMEX) October crude futures contract, trading in Asia on the ACCESS screen system, rose to $23.65 per barrel from the $23.35 it was at before the report.</p>
<p>Japan government bonds and Euroyen interest rate futures also dipped slightly on the news of the second attack. However, there was no reaction in trading on the key United States 30-year treasury bond.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
