<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31266" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi withholds support for U.S. raids on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Saudi withholds support for U.S. raids on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia, the United States' chief strategic ally in the Middle East, on Wednesday withheld public support for U.S. missile attacks on Iraq.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the Arab world the American raids drew wide criticism and outright condemnation.</p>
<p>Only Kuwait, liberated from Iraqi occupation by a U.S.-led international military coalition in the 1991 Gulf War, openly supported the attacks.</p>
<p>But Saudi Arabia, the main base for U.S. forces in the Gulf since the 1990-91 Gulf crisis, maintained an official silence.</p>
<p>&quot;The Saudis have been extremely quiet on this,&quot; a Western diplomat in Riyadh said by telephone. &quot;They may well not want to respond if they can get away without making an official statement.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 12 hours after air- and sea-launched U.S. cruise missiles slammed into Iraqi air defence targets, Saudi state television reported Tuesday's attack as the 10th item in its main evening news bulletin without comment.</p>
<p>It quoted a CNN television report that said Saudi Arabia had not agreed to the idea that the U.S. operation be launched from its soil.</p>
<p>Any Saudi support for the United States was likely to be in private, the Riyadh diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;We suspect they do support the American action as long as it doesn't involve them in any shape or form.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of launching the attacks from here or involving coalition assets based here was just simply too much to be negotiated within the time available,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, the world's largest oil exporter, wealthiest arms customer and the dominant military power in the Arabian peninsula, served as the launch pad for the coalition against Iraq in 1991 when up to half a million American troops were stationed in the kingdom.</p>
<p>The U.S. presence caused resentment among some Saudis critical of the royal family's pro-Western tilt and growing American influence in the cradle of Islam.</p>
<p>Two bombs targeted at the U.S. military killed 24 Americans and two Indians within the last year.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia remains highly sensitive to any publicity about the American presence in the kingdom, where families of some of the 5,000 U.S. armed forces stationed there were ordered to leave recently because of threats of more attacks.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton telephoned King Fahd and other Arab leaders on Sunday to muster backing for a strike against Iraqi President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>Two senior American officials had earlier visited Riyadh and other Arab capitals seeking support for retaliation against Saddam's assaults on Kurds in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>In Jordan, the officials -- Joint Chiefs of Staff Chairman General John Shalikashvili and State Department Middle East specialist Robert Pelletreau -- met King Hussein and were told Jordan would not allow its territory to be used for any action against its eastern neighbour.</p>
<p>Tuesday's attack provoked condemnation of the United States in language seldom seen in Gulf Arab newspapers to describe the region's main defender.</p>
<p>Dubai-based Gulf News said Clinton's action had violated the territorial integrity of a sovereign Arab country.</p>
<p>&quot;Arabs must draw a lesson from what has happened and take warning against over-dependence on the U.S., especially when its leaders show no respect for principles,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
