<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31263" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Anti-aircraft fire in Baghdad, US denies attack.</title>
<headline>Anti-aircraft fire in Baghdad, US denies attack.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Large explosions were heard in Baghdad on Wednesday evening and heavy anti-aircraft fire lit up the night-sky, witnesses said.</p>
<p>It was not immediately known whether the explosions were caused by incoming U.S. bombs or by outgoing anti-aircraft missiles.</p>
<p>Reporters in their offices said they heard about a dozen large explosions in Baghdad. The ground was shaking in some areas, a Reuters correspondent said.</p>
<p>The night-sky was lit up with anti-aircraft fire. Air-raid warning sirens blared.</p>
<p>A U.S. defence official said U.S. forces had not provoked the anti-aircraft firing in Baghdad. &quot;It's not us,&quot; the official said. &quot;It's not precipitated by anything that U.S. forces are involved in.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States launched 17 cruise missiles against what Washington called military targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday morning, after firing 27 cruise missiles on Tuesday in retaliation for Iraq's military offensive into Kurdish-held areas of northern Iraq at the weekend.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day thousands of Iraqis brandishing pistols and AK-47 assault rifles marched in the streets of a district of Baghdad, vowing revenge for the U.S. attacks in the south.</p>
<p>&quot;We are with you until death, Saddam. With our souls and blood we shall defend you,&quot; read a banner in support of President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>As the demonstrators shouted death to America and President Bill Clinton, state-run radio read a second communique from the General Command of the Armed forces, referring indirectly to attacks by U.S. warplanes on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Your cowardly American enemy is testing the bitterness of defeat...Here come their planes and missiles flinging their cursed lava across hundreds of kilometres,&quot; the communique said.</p>
<p>Iraq's radio and television ran special programmes on the latest military confrontation between Baghdad and Washington. They conducted interviews with intellectuals and ordinary people who urged Saddam and his comrades not to give in to U.S. threats.</p>
<p>Baghdad demonstrators came from one quarter of the Iraqi capital. Western reporters covered the demonstration under official escort.</p>
<p>Some raised fists in the air and many carried portraits of Saddam. &quot;To Washington and London we say, your missiles we disdain,&quot; several hundreds shouted together.</p>
<p>State television showed pictures of several thousand demonstrators from across the country. They hoisted their guns in the air as women demonstrators shouted the Husa or war cry.</p>
<p>Iraq on Wednesday appeared ready to confront a U.S. decision to expand the amount of the country closed to Iraqi aircraft, raising the spectre of an escalating military confrontation.</p>
<p>The Iraqi News Agency (INA) reported that Saddam met air defence commanders in what seemed to be a review of Iraqi options in defying the U.S. and allied air patrols in the areas off limits to Iraqi planes.</p>
<p>A U.S decision to extend  the southern no-fly zone to the outskirts of Baghdad went into effect at noon Baghdad time (0800 GMT).</p>
<p>On Baghdad streets, Iraqis cursed Clinton for suspending their country's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations, which has led to a fall in the value of their currency and surge in prices of essential commodities.</p>
<p>Stunned shoppers saw prices of some essential commodities more than double in under 24 hours. By the afternoon it took 1,750 dinars to buy a U.S. dollar, from 1,500 in the morning and as little as 450 earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton's missiles are hitting every Iraqi in the heart and we the ordinary people are the victims. I hate him, hate him, hate him. Why is he taking our food away,&quot; said Um Marwan.</p>
<p>Um Marwan came to Shorja, Baghdad's commercial hub, to buy sugar, but went home empty handed when told that the price of a kilogram (2.2 lb) of sugar had shot up from 600 dinars two days ago to about 1,300.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
