<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31276" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar falls as focus shifts to U.S. economy.</title>
<headline>Dollar falls as focus shifts to U.S. economy.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Rosenblum</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar fell against the Japanese yen and the German mark on Wednesday as the market focus veered away from the conflict in Iraq to American economic fundaments and upcoming U.S. jobs data.</p>
<p>Overnight in Asia, the currency market largely shrugged off a second round of American missile strikes against Iraq.</p>
<p>The second wave was aimed at Iraqi military targets not destroyed by U.S. cruise missiles early on Tuesday in retaliation for Iraq's incursion into a Kurdish enclave.</p>
<p>The dollar had jumped on news of the initial U.S. attack but spent most of Wednesday relinquishing those gains.</p>
<p>Late on Wednesday the dollar was lower at 1.4805 marks and 108.78 yen, compared with 1.4840 and 109.25 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It skidded to the day's low of 1.4783 marks in afternoon trading before clawing back some losses as President Bill Clinton announced the U.S. mission in Iraq had been achieved.</p>
<p>&quot;The flurry of dollar buying we saw over the past two days has dissipated. The market had already priced in an early cessation of hostilities,&quot; said Elliott Dix, assistant vice president at Signet Bank.</p>
<p>In Asia, option-linked dollar selling and technical resistance at 109.50 yen and above 1.4900 marks stalled the U.S. currency's rise, setting the stage for later declines.</p>
<p>Some traders focused on selling the Japanese currency against the Australian dollar and the British pound, but the yen later pared losses as jitters over high oil prices waned.</p>
<p>Japan depends on imports for all its oil. The yen has suffered from a surge in crude prices in the wake of the U.S. attack on Iraq. The pound, on the other hand, has benefited due to Britain's status as an oil producing country.</p>
<p>While a prolonged fight between Washington and Baghdad could potentially have a further dampening effect on the yen, traders said the U.S. military intervention had largely faded as a market-moving factor by European trading time.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue of buying dollars on the conflict in the Middle East is probably over,&quot; said Mark Gargano, chief dealer at First Union National Bank.</p>
<p>Even before Clinton's announcement, the market's focus had shifted to upcoming economic data from the United States and its implication for U.S. interest rates, traders said.</p>
<p>American unemployment numbers for August, due out on Friday, will be key in determining whether the Federal Reserve hikes official interest rates when its policy-making committee meets later this month, analysts said.</p>
<p>Traders said caution ahead of the jobs data had spurred dollar sales against the mark and the yen.</p>
<p>&quot;The jobs data has surprised the market more often than not this year, and the market is duly cautious about it,&quot; said Marc Chandler, senior currency analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts on average expect non-farm payrolls to rise by 224,000 in August, compared with July's 193,000 increase, while the unemployment rate is seen edging lower to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The (jobs) data is the biggest piece of the puzzle yet to go that describes the U.S. economy before the next Fed meeting,&quot; said Signet Bank's Dix. &quot;A very strong number this time around is what a lot of people think will kick the Fed into action.&quot;</p>
<p>In other trading, the British pound rose to $1.5672 from $1.5665 on Tuesday. The dollar fell to 1.2060 Swiss francs against 1.2080.</p>
<p>It eased to Canadian $1.3695 from $1.3705.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
