<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31273" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. faces trouble resolving Japan insurance spat.</title>
<headline>U.S. faces trouble resolving Japan insurance spat.</headline>
<byline>Donna Smith</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States and Japan agreed Wednesday to resume talks this month on a dispute over foreign access to Japan's lucrative insurance market that U.S. officials said is proving difficult to resolve.</p>
<p>U.S. Ambassador to Japan Walter Mondale told a National Press Club luncheon that he was worried about the dispute that involves deregulation of Japan's $382 billion insurance market and a 1994 trade agreement between Washington and Tokyo that would open up that market to more U.S. firms.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really worried about the insurance issue because we have an agreement and those agreements should mean something when they are signed,&quot; Mondale said.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally they do, but this one is proving to be very difficult,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Efforts to resolve the dispute by July 31 failed after a last minute round of marathon negotiations in Vancouver, British Columbia, ended in no agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very difficult negotiation,&quot; a U.S. trade official told reporters separately. &quot;The changes we are seeking are significant changes in Japan.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. Trade Representative senior negotiator Ira Shapiro and Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Japanese Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau, met in Washington Wednesday and agreed to resume insurance negotiations in September.</p>
<p>But a trade official told reporters after the meeting no firm date has been set for the talks.</p>
<p>The United States has accused Japan of reneging on the 1994 insurance agreement by allowing subsidiaries of Japanese insurance companies to move into the small non-life and speciality insurance market, in which foreign companies have a strong presence, before deregulating the primary life and casualty markets controlled by Japanese firms.</p>
<p>Mondale said the move would put unfair pressure on foreign companies in the speciality insurance sector, which represents about 5 percent of Japan's insurance market.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of them would be driven out,&quot; Mondale said. &quot;This is not good for the Japanese insurance consumers. Today, Japanese insurance tends to carry the same rates, the same terms. There's no competition in many of these areas.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the 1994 agreement calls for deregulation of the primary markets before the so-called third sector market can be significantly changed.</p>
<p>A U.S. trade official said Japan's proposals on primary sector deregulation have been inadequate. He said the United States was looking to open opportunities for foreign companies to provide different kinds of products and to be able to charge different rates as a way to compete.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
