<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31280" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. aims to protect oil more than Kurds.</title>
<headline>U.S. aims to protect oil more than Kurds.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington's main fear that Babhdad will again lunge for the vulnerable oil-producing states to its south explains why the U.S. military response to Iraqi moves against Kurds in northern Iraq has been missile strikes in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Cruise missiles have been fired twice this week at air defence facilities in southern Iraq, and the Western powers have extended a no-fly-zone there northwards to the outskirts of Baghdad. Nothing similar has happened in the north.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton said on Wednesday the U.S. mission in Iraq &quot;has been achieved&quot; following the second cruise attack and Iraq had withdrawn its forces from a northern Kurdish area at least for the time being. But he said it was too soon to rule out further U.S. military action.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said there were tactical concerns that made military action difficult in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>One major worry would be that attacks on Iraqi troops who marched into the Western-protected Kurdish region last Saturday in support of one of the Kurdish factions there could accidentally hit the Kurds themselves.</p>
<p>But U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry has made clear that Washington has a broader strategic interest in the south -- to protect the Gulf states which were targeted by Iraq's invasion of Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern is that if (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein is emboldened by what he would see as a success in the north, he might strike out in areas which are of greater strategic importance to him, as well as to us, in the south,&quot; Perry told a briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;Our vital national interests in Iraq are in the south, not in the north,&quot; Perry said later in a television interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objectives, first of all, are protecting our vital strategic interest, which means protecting our friends and allies in the region -- Israel, Jordan, Kuwait, Saudi Arabia. Secondly, keeping the free flow of oil from the Gulf.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Iraq's army was badly mauled when a U.S.-led coalition drove it out of Kuwait in February 1991, it has since been rebuilt and U.S. policy-makers believe Saddam has not given up his designs on the Gulf states.</p>
<p>Those concerns have been heightened by signs of instability in Saudi Arabia itself, including a massive truck bomb blast that killed 19 U.S. servicemen in the oil-producing city of Dhahran in June.</p>
<p>Twice -- in 1994 and 1995 -- U.S. forces have moved to deter Iraqi troop buildups in the south. And the fighting in Kurdistan has given the U.S. military the chance to again wreck installations that would support any southward thrust.</p>
<p>Iraq has less opportunity to cause regional instability in the north. Its military powerful northern neighbours Syria, Turkey and Iran are well able to take care of themselves.</p>
<p>And, while the United States and its allies took on a moral obligation after the Gulf War to protect the Kurds from repression by Baghdad, any U.S. attempt to do so directly has been obstructed by the complex politics of the Kurdish area.</p>
<p>It was the latest outbreak of fighting between the two main Kurdish factions, the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) and the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK), that led Baghdad to intervene, prompting the U.S. missile strikes.</p>
<p>U.S. officials admit that the fact that KDP leaders invited Iraq to support them against the Iranian-backed PUK complicated any U.S. effort to take action in the area.</p>
<p>To Washington, Iran and Iraq are equally odious, and State Department officials say they are pursuing diplomatic efforts to wean the KDP and PUK away from their regional backers and make peace under U.S. auspices.</p>
<p>Clinton's statement that Iraq's withdrawal from the northern city of Arbil spelled the accomplishment of the U.S. mission acknowledged the Kurdish issue as the formal reason for the U.S. strikes.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said Washington was demanding that the Iraqis pull back south of the 36th parallel, which marks the southern limit of the Kurdish area patrolled by U.S., British and French warplanes.</p>
<p>But a critic of Clinton's foreign policy, Republican Senator John McCain, said he saw a &quot;disconnect&quot; between the Iraqi move into Arbil and the decision to extend the no-fly-zone in the south.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to question why were the cruise missiles launched now if the real purpose of these strikes was to protect our friends in the south from Iraqi incursions?&quot; McCain told Fox television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
