<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31285" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Canadian workers most committed; UK among least - study.</title>
<headline>Canadian workers most committed; UK among least - study.</headline>
<dateline>INDIANAPOLIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Workers in Canada, Finland, Spain and the United States have the highest levels of commitment to their employers, while those in Germany and the United Kingdom have the lowest, according to a study released Wednesday.</p>
<p>Walker Information said its survey of 7,500 workers from large companies in 13 countries asked 97 questions about &quot;workplace culture to determine employees' commitment to their companies.&quot;</p>
<p>The questions focused on workers' perceptions of their companies' emphasis on customers, quality and employees, and whether they saw better job opportunities elsewhere.</p>
<p>Canadian workers ranked highest in company commitment with a score of 4.19 out of a possible 5.0; German and British workers tied for the lowest score at 3.53.</p>
<p>Finnish (4.15), Spanish (4.14) and U.S. (4.06) workers scored high, as well. Middling marks were posted by workers in South Africa (3.92), the Netherlands (3.84), Japan (3.84), Italy (3.82), India (3.77), Australia (3.76) and a composite of Asian nations excluding Japan (3.70), Walker said.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to revealing that employee commitment differs by country, the study found that what drives commitment changes from country to country,&quot; said Walker, a market research firm based here that did the study in conjunction with its CSM Worldwide Network of corporate clients.</p>
<p>For example, workers in Canada are more committed to their companies when the companies show a focus on employees, the survey found.</p>
<p>In contrast, Asian workers tend to be more committed to employers that focus on product and service quality.</p>
<p>&quot;In the U.S., we found that employee focus is the main driver of employee commitment,&quot; said Curt Carlson, a researcher with Walker.</p>
<p>Each country included in the survey results provided a minimum of 400 interviews. Survey data were collected using methodologies differing by market. Sample sizes were weighed relative to the total population of each country to ensure proportional representation based on census data, Walker said.</p>
<p>Scores were adjusted to reflect another finding, Walker said, which was that workers in different countries react differently to surveys using response scales that ask for rankings of feelings or opinions.</p>
<p>For this reason, Walker said, multinational corporations surveying employees in this way should be careful when comparing responses between countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDIANAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
