<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31282" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. corp bonds off with Treasuries, light trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. corp bonds off with Treasuries, light trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. high-grade corporate bonds were off at midday tracking U.S. Treasuries in light trading, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We saw some trading activity on the offered side of the market and there's generally a good bid for corporate paper,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>High-grade corporate dealers said spreads across most maturities were one to two basis points tighter.</p>
<p>Other dealers said the market was in a holding pattern in the absence of any fresh economic data and post holiday doldrums.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're in a holding pattern,&quot; said one trader. &quot;There's no riveting news today...people are focusing on Friday's jobs report.&quot;</p>
<p>In the new issue arena, Associates Corp of North America, a Ford Motor unit, stirred up some activity in an eerily quiet primary market pricing $400 million in two-year notes via lead manager Merrill Lynch &amp; Co.</p>
<p>The AA3/AA-minus rated 6.50 percent notes were priced at 99.954 to yield 6.525 or 17 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasuries.  </p>
<p>Still, primary and secondary corporate bond activity is expected to remain quiet ahead of the highly anticipated U.S. employment report later this week, dealers added.</p>
<p>On Friday, the U.S. Labor Department is scheduled to release the August employment report at 0830 EDT/1230 GMT.</p>
<p>In a Reuter poll, U.S. economist predicted an increase of 244,000 in nonfarm payrolls and expect the unemployment rate to dip slightly to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in the high-yield market, prices were quoted off 1/8 to 1/4 in quiet dealings, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
