<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31288" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Staples buying Office Depot for $4.28 billion.</title>
<headline>Staples buying Office Depot for $4.28 billion.</headline>
<dateline>WESTBOROUGH, Mass. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Staples Inc. said Wednesday it agreed to acquire Office Depot Inc., one of its chief rivals in office products retailing, for about $4.28 billion in stock.</p>
<p>The combined company, to be known as Staples The Office Depot, will have more than 1,100 store locations and some $10 billion in revenues, making it by far the biggest office products store chain in North America.</p>
<p>The firms will also combine their mail order and contract printing businesses.</p>
<p>The two retailers said in a statement that Office Depot stockholders will receive 1.4 share of Staples common stock for each share they own in a tax-free transaction.</p>
<p>Based on Staples closing price of $19.50 on Tuesday and Office Depot's 156.6 million outstanding shares, the deal would be worth about $27.30 for each of Office Depot's shares, which closed at $15.75 Tuesday, or about $4.28 billion.</p>
<p>The shares of both companies did not begin trading when the stock markets opened Wednesday.</p>
<p>The companies, which both helped revolutionise the office products industry by offering low prices to small business customers, said in a joint statement that they expect that the merger will have a positive impact on earnings.</p>
<p>They also said they expect the combined company to be able to create &quot;a significant number of jobs&quot; through further store openings and expanded administrative opportunities.</p>
<p>David Fuente, currently chairman and chief executive of Office Depot, will be chairman of the new company. Thomas Stemberg, chairman and chief executive of Staples, will serve as CEO, and Martin Hanaka, president and chief operating officer of Staples, will retain those roles.</p>
<p>The corporate headquarters for Staples/Office Depot will be located in Framingham, Mass., where Staples now has its headquarters. However, the company also intends to maintain a significant presence in Delray Beach, Fla., where Office Depot is now based.</p>
<p>The transaction is subject to customary closing conditions, including the approval of the stockholders of both companies and required regulatory approvals.</p>
<p>Staples currently operates 517 office products superstores in over 100 markets across the United States and in Canada. It is also a joint venture partner in start-up office supply store chains in Britain and Germany.</p>
<p>Office Depot operates 539 stores, including 532 office supply superstores in the United States. It also operates 32 superstores in Canada and has operations in Mexico, Israel, Poland, Thailand, France, Colombia and Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WESTBOROUGH, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
