<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31286" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Union challenges U.S. move to allow ValuJet to fly.</title>
<headline>Union challenges U.S. move to allow ValuJet to fly.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A ValuJet Airlines union Wednesday asked the Transportation Department's inspector general to investigate the department's tentative decision to allow the low-cost airline to resume operations.</p>
<p>The Association of Flight Attendants said in a letter to the inspector general that the department's decision was made despite a faulty application by ValuJet, which it said had misrepresented itself in an effort to get back in the air.</p>
<p>It also said the department was unduly influenced by congressmen and ValuJet officials.</p>
<p>Atlanta-based ValuJet was grounded on June 17 because of a series of safety shortcomings uncovered after the crash of its flight 592 on May 11 in Florida, killing 110 people.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, the Federal Aviation Administration said ValuJet had met its tighter safety standards and could resume flying, pending department approval of the safety and competence of ValuJet management and its economic health.</p>
<p>It gave the low-cost airline tentative approval last Thursday and asked for comment before making the decision final.</p>
<p>The flight attendants said they would make a formal objection to the tentative decision, but meanwhile called for the investigation into the department's action by the independent inspector general's office.</p>
<p>Flight attendant officials said an investigation by the inspector general could delay final department approval.</p>
<p>The union said ValuJet mispresentated the qualifications of a senior safety official and that another safety post was still being held by the official who occupied it when the FAA uncovered the original ValuJet safety shortcomings.</p>
<p>It added that two other safety posts were listed as unfilled in the carrier's application to resume flying.</p>
<p>The union also said the department engaged in prohibited communications with congressmen seeking quick approval of the ValuJet application.</p>
<p>It cited reported letters from congressmen from ValuJet's home base, Georgia, and Virgina, where it has major operations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
