<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31296" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Olivetti faces more friction.</title>
<headline>Italy's Olivetti faces more friction.</headline>
<byline>Charlotte Cooper</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian information technology group Olivetti, whose chairman Carlo De Benedetti quit suddenly this week, was set for more convulsions on Thursday after the bourse watchdog called a meeting on the company.</p>
<p>Stock market regulator Consob called the meeting in Rome with former Olivetti director general Renzo Francesconi, who resigned on Wednesday, and the legal representative of the group, ANSA newsagency reported. No time was specified.</p>
<p>No one was available from Consob to confirm the report but ANSA quoted a Consob spokesman as saying Thursday's meeting had been called to get &quot;explanations as to the situation which has been created following the resignation of Francesconi and his declarations about the half year data released yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>Olivetti released its half year results for 1996 at the same time as announcing De Benedetti's resignation on Tuesday. It made a 440.2 billion lire ($292 million) pretax loss.</p>
<p>Francesconi was quoted as saying Olivetti's future looked very difficult and he did not agree with some results released.</p>
<p>However Francesco Caio, chief executive of the troubled information technology group, said he was surprised both at the content and form of Francesconi's statements.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures at June 30 1996 have a strict accounting base and contain provisions which reflect in a correct and considered fashion evaluations in relation to strategic business decisions and the restructuring carried out by the company,&quot; Caio said.</p>
<p>Olivetti has been at the heart of a power struggle this week between De Benedetti, who built it up from an ailing type-writer producer, and Caio, who took over as managing director in July.</p>
<p>De Benedetti relinquished his grip suddenly late on Tuesday after nearly 20 years with the company, and the share price, which had fallen nine percent in two days, bounced from near to record lows to end up three percent at 749.4 lire on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Caio, speaking in a telephone conference call with equity analysts late on Wednesday, said Olivetti's loss-making personal computer company, whose future has been a source of much market talk, would not reach break-even in 1996.</p>
<p>The market has speculated Olivetti would try to exit from the highly competitive personal computer sector, either selling off or closing down the PC company which made its name in the 1980s but has not turned a profit for several years.</p>
<p>Michael Pacitti, Italian analyst at London brokers James Capel, said: &quot;Olivetti wanted to emphasis 1996 will not be a year of recovery. It's going to reflect continuing restructuring.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said Caio stressed strategic rather than operational issues, although he noted two of Olivetti's five companies made profits in the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>He said the systems and services division, which accounts for 65 percent of Olivetti's group sales, made an operating profit of 49 billion lire while office equipment maker Lexikon made a 39 billion lire operating profit.</p>
<p>Olivetti's 41.3 percent-owned Omnitel mobile phone consortium, which was launched in December and is widely seen as its best hope for the future, had also increased the number of subscribers to its GSM network to 500,000 by the end of August and Caio said growth had been &quot;explosive.&quot;</p>
<p>$1=1,510 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
