<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31305" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norwegian shares recover but sentiment fragile.</title>
<headline>Norwegian shares recover but sentiment fragile.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian shares traded higher on Wednesday to recapture day-earlier losses, but sentiment among investors remained fragile, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a lot of confusion and uncertainty in the market. Domestic and foreign investors are cautious,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>The uneasy situation in the Middle East, the U.S. presidential elections, U.S. payroll data at the end of the week and a rise in interest rates were all contributing to the uncertainty, the broker said. &quot;There's also total confusion over macroeconomic indicators, one minute we're heading for recession, the next it's boom time.&quot;</p>
<p>The Total share index added 10.49 points, or 1.28 percent, at 829.55 points versus a fall of 0.9 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Turnover at almost 10 billion crowns, a staggering figure, included 9.4 billion crowns from the merger of Transocean with U.S. drilling group Sonat Offshore to form a new company Transocean Offshore.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was down one percent yesterday so it's up one percent today. It's over-reaction and psychology that's running this business,&quot; another broker said.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
