<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31309" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares close up, seen lacking strength.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares close up, seen lacking strength.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares trudged higher on Wednesday, taking their cue from overall buyoant European markets, but failed to hold on to the day's highs.</p>
<p>Traders said volumes remained thin and there was little indication the market could muster up the strength to attack a strong technical resistance level at 1,040 points in the ATX this week.</p>
<p>The blue-chip index rose 7.86 points or 0.8 percent to close at 1,030.23, down from the day's high of 1,035.13. Among its constituents, 16 gainers outnumbered five decliners.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the market to swing back and forth between 1,020 and 1,040 points,&quot; said one trader. The index has been stuck in that range for more than six weeks now.</p>
<p>Traders noted strong interest, particularly by German investors, in privatisation candidate Creditanstalt, for which the Austrian government has demanded to receive a final offer by midnight Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's certainly enough customers who want to jump on the bandwagon before that date,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Creditanstalt's preferred shares rose five schillings to 484, while its common stock was up six at 666 schillings.</p>
<p>Energy and chemicals group OMV rse 18.50 to 1,027.50 in above-average turnover. Traders said the gains were a delayed reaction to Tuesday's rise in international oil stocks.</p>
<p>Luxury hosiery maker Wolford led the day's decliners, falling 60 schillings to 2,490.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna bourse index rose 2.62 points or 0.65 percent to close at 403.27.</p>
<p>On the Vienna futures and options exchange, ATX contracts for September delivery were up six points at 1,026.0.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
