<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31300" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Transocean, Sonat complete merger.</title>
<headline>Transocean, Sonat complete merger.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO, Norway</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sonat Offshore Drilling Inc. of Houston completed its acquisition of Norway's Transocean ASA Wednesday to form Transocean Offshore Inc., one of the world's largest drilling companies.</p>
<p>The new company came to life after Sonat's stock offer expired Tuesday, capturing 94 percent, or 50.9 million shares, of the outstanding equity in the Norwegian driller and offshore service company.</p>
<p>Sonat beat out rival suitor Reading &amp; Bates in June when Transocean's largest shareholder, Tiger Management Corp., switched allegiance to Sonat after initially recommending R&amp;B's bid.</p>
<p>Sonat said it would move quickly to begin a mandatory offer for the remaining 6 percent stake in Transocean, in accordance with Norwegian securities regulations.</p>
<p>Reidar Lund, president and chief executive officer of the former Transocean group, said the company had achieved a long-held goal.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a strategic goal we have been pursuing since 1990 when we were first listed,&quot; Lund said in an interview. &quot;Since then we have gone through several mergers in Norway and, to a certain extent, consolidated the Norwegian drilling industry.</p>
<p>&quot;But to be a major international player we had to find a foreign partner. Now we are creating the absolute premier harsh-environment, deep-water drilling company in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>In the exchange, Sonat will issue around 22.9 million shares of Sonat common stock and about $207 million in cash. Transocean shareholders requesting cash will receive $27.25 per share, while the remaining shareholders will receive $3.43 in cash plus 0.4633 shares of Sonat's common stock.</p>
<p>Sonat will offer a cash price of $28.74 per share for the remaining shares under the mandatory bid.</p>
<p>The new company has one of the most modern fleets with 27 rigs operating in the North Sea, the Gulf of Mexico, Brazil and West Africa.</p>
<p>The corporate headquarters for Transocean Offshore will be in Houston. The company will also have offices in Tananger, near the Norwegian oil capital of Stavanger, to oversee activities in the North Sea, Europe and Africa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
