<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31302" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FOCUS - Limited price rise hits Gas Natural.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Limited price rise hits Gas Natural.</headline>
<byline>Elisabeth O'Leary</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Spain's Gas Natural tumbled nearly 10 percent on Wednesday after the government approved much more modest hikes in gas prices than stock market analysts had expected.</p>
<p>Natural gas prices will rise 1.5 percent from this month through July 1997, when they will decline for one year by 0.5 percent, an Industry Ministry spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts said they had been anticipating an annual nominal rise of two to three percent in the gas tariff effective this month, followed by a one-year rise next July of one to 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>Shares of 3.8 percent state-owned Gas Natural nosedived on the news, closing down 9.93 percent, or 2,380 pesetas, at 21,580, marginally above the day's low.</p>
<p>Repsol, which has a stake of around 45 percent in Gas Natural, closed down 35 pesetas at 4,035.</p>
<p>&quot;Up to now the state has always protected Gas Natural. This price rise means that it is not as interested in that now but rather in fighting inflation,&quot; one energy analyst said.</p>
<p>Another analyst said he was revising down his profits estimate over the next three years by two percent, four percent and seven percent, respectively, starting in 1996.</p>
<p>He now expects the energy firm to increase net profit by 22 percent this year, 13 percent next year and 15 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>A Gas Natural spokesman said the price decision should not impact profits, because supply costs from next year will fall as a gas pipeline from Northern Africa comes onstream.</p>
<p>It also stands to benefit from recent government legislation via which companies are allowed to update the value of fixed assets on their balance sheets. This will boost cash flow, he said.</p>
<p>The fact that the hike is less than anticipated &quot;is a sacrifice that we all have to make but from next year we'll have cheaper costs with the Mahgreb-Europe pipeline and the effect of the (law to) update balance sheets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But analysts were sceptical, saying the lower-than-expected price hike could well hit the group because the share price already reflected these cost reductions.</p>
<p>One trader said despite the day's fall in the stock being exaggerated, there could be longer-term effects on the share.</p>
<p>&quot;People will lose confidence in the stock. It will become clear that at the end of the day (the company) relies on the state,&quot; he said. -- Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
