<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31306" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU states must vet U.S. gene-modified corn imports.</title>
<headline>EU states must vet U.S. gene-modified corn imports.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union countries will have to check this year's U.S. corn (maize) imports for gene-modified strains which are not authorised for sale in the bloc, raising the prospect of further bilateral trade friction.</p>
<p>&quot;European member states have to ensure...that (unauthorised maize) is not put on to the market on their territory,&quot; a European Commission spokesman told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A U.S. farm official in Brussels said it was tricky to spot the difference between genetically engineered and normal maize and that gene-modified products from this year's harvest might end up going for export.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no means of guaranteeing it won't get into export channels,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>U.S. maize exports to the EU were worth $530 million in 1995/96 when world prices were very high. Exports are normally worth $300 million, the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know if there will be a trade problem...but it has the potential to be really ugly,&quot; the official added.</p>
<p>The Commission spokesman played down suggestions that checks were impractical or risked sparking an EU-U.S. row similar to the one on U.S. hormone-treated beef exports.</p>
<p>&quot;To say it's the start of a trade war is to put the cart before the horse,&quot; he said, adding that most U.S. imports comprised unmodified grains which would face no barriers.</p>
<p>&quot;(EU countries) will have to ensure that they comply with the EU legislation for the residual amount.</p>
<p>News of the checks, which will kick in once imports of this year's U.S. harvest arrive in Europe, came as the 15-country bloc grapples with a French request to allow the sale of a genetically-modified maize produced by Swiss company Ciba-Geigy on EU markets.</p>
<p>Ciba's &quot;Zea mays L&quot; maize strain, which has U.S. clearance, has modified properties intended to repel the corn borer pest and to increase its tolerance to certain weed killers.</p>
<p>France sought approval for the strain earlier this year but found its request blocked in June when several countries raised concerns about product labelling and the effects of the maize on human health and the environment.</p>
<p>Three EU scientific committees are now to review the file and report back to Commission &quot;within several months&quot;, the Commission spokesman said.</p>
<p>The repeated delays highlight the confusion about the EU law on approving the release of genetically modified organisms.</p>
<p>Officials' interpretations of the 1990 rules have raised the legal absurdity that rejection or amendment of an approval request is possible only by the Commission or when all 15 EU member states agree unanimously. Such agreement between countries is unlikely given that one of them will have sponsored the original request.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the current rules were due for a review which, given the problems which have occurred, could turn into a proposal for a new directive. The review was not due to conclude before the end of the year, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G156">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
