<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31301" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: No rate cut seen at Buba meeting Thursday - analysts.</title>
<headline>No rate cut seen at Buba meeting Thursday - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A clear majority of German economists said on Wednesday they believed the Bundesbank would leave interest rates unchanged after its monthly council meeting on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank took the market by surprise at its August 22 meeting when it cut the securities repurchase rate to three percent from 3.30 percent, when most commentators had predicted a smaller change.</p>
<p>Discount and Lombard rates have remained unchanged since April 19 at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent.</p>
<p>Many economists based their opinions on comments on Monday from the Bundesbank chief economist, Otmar Issing, who said the repo cut in August sent a clear signal to the markets and that the current repo rate had now reached an &quot;an all-time low&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We have created clarity for the foreseeable future,&quot; he said, echoing similar comments by Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer.</p>
<p>&quot;With this clear step we are signalling that the level has been reached,&quot; Issing said.</p>
<p>Christophe Weil, economist at Commerzbank, said he expected no changes in fixed or variable rates.</p>
<p>&quot;In principle, we think any change in the variable rate would could signal that interest rates are set to rise, so we expect no change,&quot; said Weil.</p>
<p>Craig Shute, economist at Bear Stearns in London, said: &quot;The Bundesbank meeting will be a non-event. It has made clear it will keep rates steady. The Bundesbank will continue to announce fixed repo rates at two week intervals and there will be no return to a variable rate.&quot;</p>
<p>A Reuters poll of economists in Frankfurt and London earlier showed that the majority said the Bundesbank will keep interest rates on hold not just tomorrow, but for the rest of the cycle.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the first time I can remember where everyone is saying no cut this week,&quot; said David Brickman, Yamaichi's European economist.</p>
<p>Stephen Lewis, director of research at London Bond Broking (LBB) said&quot; &quot;Having moved rates at the last meeting, the Bundesbank is very unlikely to feel that a further change in policy is necessary so soon,&quot;</p>
<p>Over half of the 10 respondents in a poll conducted from London expected rates to remain unchanged for the forseeable future as a stronger German economy made a rate cut unnecessary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
