<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31315" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Reuters buys majority in French health firm.</title>
<headline>Reuters buys majority in French health firm.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reuters Holdings Plc said on Wednesday it had taken a 75 percent stake in France's leading supplier of electronic health information services for doctors, Distal.</p>
<p>Distal sells software used by about 6,000 doctors in France to record information about patients and their own professional data on personal computers. The French government is encouraging doctors to computerise their records as part of a drive to control healthcare costs.</p>
<p>Reuters, which has a wholly-owned subisidiary, Value Added Medical Products (VAMP), providing similar health information services in Britain, did not disclose the price but said it was &quot;not material in the context of Reuters group net assets&quot;.</p>
<p>The world supplier of news and information said Geoffrey Sanderson, managing director of Reuters Health Information, would become chairman of Distal. The original owners, David and Meyer Benchetrit, will stay on as managers.</p>
<p>Jean-Claude Marchand, Reuters managing director for Continental Europe, the Middle East and Africa, said: &quot;We want to provide our expertise in data management also to professionals outside our traditional markets of finance and the media.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5331</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
