<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31313" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX starts higher as rebound continues.</title>
<headline>German DAX starts higher as rebound continues.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's blue chip DAX index opened strongly ahead in bourse trade on Wednesday, continuing its technical rebound from lows hit Tuesday on concern at the crisis in Iraq.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX was up 24.79 points, or around one percent, at 2,535.40 points at 0849 GMT. The level represents a rise of about seven points from the close of the post-bourse electronic trade session on Tuesday, when the rebound began.</p>
<p>Dealers said sentiment on the market was largely favourable and blamed a lack of strong buying interest on uncertainty ahead of economic data due from the U.S. later this week, particularly Friday's employment data.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying interest is not great but then we certainly have no selling pressure either. This is more of a wait-and-see attitude,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Among stocks to benefit from the rebound was Deutsche Bank AG, Germany's leading commercial bank, which had come under pressure amid concern that three funds at its London Morgan Grenfell asset management unit had been suspended.</p>
<p>Deutsche shares were up 42 pfennigs at 72.67 marks in early bourse trade, but were off a session high of 72.95.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure how far that rebound will go. There is still some concern about how much this will cost,&quot; warned one dealer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
