<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31319" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Foreign funds help Bombay shares end higher.</title>
<headline>Foreign funds help Bombay shares end higher.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Selective buying by foreign institutional investors (FIIs) and short covering pushed Bombay shares to finish in positive territory on Wednesday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The 30-share BSE index closed 32.57 points, or 0.93 percent, higher at a provisional 3,517.25 after sliding to 3,456.42 in early morning trade.</p>
<p>Short covering forced by a market holiday for the BSE on Thursday was the big factor for the late surge, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;People did not want to keep open positions,&quot; a trader said. &quot;They squared off their outstandings after yesterday's selling spree.&quot;</p>
<p>He said hopes of some tax reliefs and incentives to investors before the 1996/97 budget is passed next week helped the short covering.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram was expected to make a statement about the budget proposals on Wednesday but parliament was adjourned until Friday after noisy scenes following political developments in western Gujarat state.</p>
<p>The BSE is closed on Thursday for a Hindu religious holiday. But the NSE will stay open.</p>
<p>Traders believe a relaxation of a controversial minimum tax on firms would trigger a short rally in stocks.</p>
<p>The 50-stock NSE index gained 5.03 points to a provisional 1,028.03 after falling to 1,012.31.</p>
<p>The 500-share CRISIL index rose 1.79 points to a provisional 691.03, the day's highest level.</p>
<p>Traders said FIIs bought BPCL, Ranbaxy, TVS Suzuki, Crompton Greaves, BHEL, SBI and MTNL.</p>
<p>Hind Lever gained 13.75 rupees to 825.75, MTNL 7.0 to 221.75, TELCO 6.25 to 507.25, Indian Hotel 5.50 to 777.50, SBI 3.75 to 280, TISCO 1.50 to 195 and Reliance 1.25 to 208.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
