<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31321" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Slowdown seen in foreign fund investment in India.</title>
<headline>Slowdown seen in foreign fund investment in India.</headline>
<byline>Shyam Kumar</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political and economic uncertainty in India is likely to deter any immediate recovery in investment by foreign funds which fell sharply last month, fund managers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Net foreign portfolio investment on Indian bourses fell sharply to $66.7 million in the first 29 days of August from $302.4 million in July, the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Most traders attributed the fall to the summer holidays in Europe and the U.S., but some fund managers said growing uncertainty in Indian politics could signal a slowdown in overseas investment in Indian stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The summer holidays should not be discounted,&quot; said Robert Jackson, director of Jardine Fleming Broking in Bombay. &quot;But new, disconcerting developments over the last few months have given rise to investor anxiety,&quot; he said without elaborating.</p>
<p>Subra Subramanian, director of Hoare Govett (India) Securities, cited several factors contributing to the slowdown, including the disappointing July budget.</p>
<p>He noted that in recent months foreign funds had preferred to invest in global depositary receipts issued by some of India's leading firms.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't think it is the beginning of a trend,&quot; Subramanian said, adding he expected a slow recovery in the flow of funds.</p>
<p>The July budget imposed a 12.9 percent minimum tax on corporate profits and investment firms reacted by downgrading earnings forecasts.</p>
<p>Mukarram Bhagat, head of research at Birla Marlin Securities, said his firm had downgraded earnings estimates of the 30 constituent companies of the Bombay Stock Exchange index by four percentage points.</p>
<p>Bhagat said the new minority government, formed in June after inconclusive general elections, had postponed crucial structural reforms.</p>
<p>In addition, accusations of bribery in the dispensing of telecommunications contracts by the previous administration could slow down investment in this sector.</p>
<p>He said fears of a slowdown in the Indian economy, as evidenced by a drop in imports of capital goods, was also worrying investors.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of direction, you will see a slowdown in foreign investments up to January 1997,&quot; Bhagat said.</p>
<p>Sanjeev Sanghvi, chief dealer at James Capel B&amp;K in Bombay, said the fall in net foreign investment in August was due to large redemptions and withdrawals and did not reflect falling trading volumes.</p>
<p>Sanghvi and Bhagat said there was also a sense of disenchantment with emerging markets in general.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
