<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31328" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: AKZO NOBEL TARGETS CHINESE FIBRES VENTURE.</title>
<headline>AKZO NOBEL TARGETS CHINESE FIBRES VENTURE.</headline>
<dateline>DRESDEN, Germany 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch chemicals group Akzo Nobel NV said late on Tuesday it had agreed with China's Wuxi Taihi Ltd to prepare a joint venture in industrial polyester fibres in the city of Wuxi near Shanghai.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the joint venture to come together in April 1997,&quot; Akzo board member Friedrich Froehlich told journalists.</p>
<p>Wuxi Taihi is China's leading industrial polyester fibres producer with annual capacity of 9,000 tonnes (valued at an estimated 80 million guilders), but it wanted Akzo's know-how to help it expand to 15,000-20,000 tonnes by 2000, he said.</p>
<p>China's total output of these fibres was currently 20,000 tonnes, but this would expand rapidly to around 80,000 tonnes in the years to come on the back of the emerging automobile industry which uses the fibres for tyres, Froehlich said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wuxi is prepared to accept that Akzo will take 60 percent of the shares in the joint venture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Akzo produces roughly 100,000 tonnes of industrial polyester fibres a year, 40,000 tonnes of which in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese output will come on top of that,&quot; Froehlich said, describing this type of fibre as one of Akzo's more lucrative yarns, generating 25 percent of Akzo fibre sales.</p>
<p>The Dutch group is currently struggling with its fibres business unit, which is markedly less profitable than its other businesses -- chemicals, coatings and pharmaceuticals -- due to cut-throat price competition with emerging east European rivals.</p>
<p>One the main victims is Akzo's viscose textiles. The company is carrying out plans to transfer labour intensive processing activities from German and Dutch plants to Gorzow in Poland.</p>
<p>&quot;Labour costs in Poland are around one-tenth of those in Holland or West Germany and one-fifth of those in East Germany and Britain,&quot; chairman Cees van Lede said.</p>
<p>Van Lede said that Akzo needed to cut costs dramatically and thus improve profitability to make it worthwile continuing viscose production.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't act, more efficient producers will take over our market share. We need to restructure our business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The reason behind Akzo expanding in China was not so much a low-wages decision, but that it was following its German and U.S. rivals, as well as the automobile industry, into Asia, Froehlich said.</p>
<p>-- Lucas van Grinsven, Amsterdam newsdesk +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I26000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DRESDEN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
