<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31324" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Water issue to dominate India minister's Dhaka visit.</title>
<headline>Water issue to dominate India minister's Dhaka visit.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bitter dispute over water sharing, a trade gap and New Delhi's plea for transport links through Bangladesh will dominate the Indian foreign minister's visit to Dhaka this week, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said Dhaka would strongly plead for an immediate end to the water dispute that has long affected the lives of about 40 million Bangladeshis.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be seeking a long-term agreement with India by next December,&quot; one foreign ministry official said.</p>
<p>I.K. Gujral is due to arrive in Dhaka on Friday on a four-day visit to neighbouring Bangladesh. He will be the highest level official to visit Dhaka since Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina took office in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime issue of his talks with his Bangladeshi counterpart will be the sharing of water. Other issues likely to feature are the proposal for transit and narrowing down of the trade gap,&quot; one South Asian diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Things appear to be moving towards a solution, but the water agreement will come first,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bangladeshi officials declined to specify what issues Gujral would discuss with his counterpart Abdus Samad Azad.</p>
<p>Sharing of water, especially from the Ganges river, called Padma in Bangladesh, has long been a major irritant.</p>
<p>Dhaka says India's Farakka barrage, 18 km (12 miles) from Bangladesh's northern border, obstructs the river's flow and deprives this country of its fair share of water.</p>
<p>Officials say more than 40 million people in northwestern Bangladesh have faced gradual desertification of their land since the Farakka was commissioned in 1974.</p>
<p>India has said it favoured a concrete solution to the water dispute. The latest water sharing agreement expired in 1988 and attempts to renew it have since failed.</p>
<p>Indian exports to Bangladesh are worth $1 billion a year, while India imports goods worth only $50 million a year from its neighbour, trade officials in New Delhi said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
