<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31336" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: ANTENNA HUNGARIA TO START FIRST DIGITAL BROADCASTS.</title>
<headline>ANTENNA HUNGARIA TO START FIRST DIGITAL BROADCASTS.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's national broadcasting company Antenna Hungaria Rt is to start its first digital satellite broadcast on September 10, company officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have signed an eight-year contract to broadcast TV3's programme to cable operators countrywide,&quot; Istvan Mate, general director of Antenna Hungaria, told a news conference.</p>
<p>Antenna Hungaria in which the state has an 83.2 percent stake, broadcasts all transmissions of Hungarian state television and radio.</p>
<p>Andras Feuer, general director of TV3, a commercial station for Budapest launched in November 1994, said the deal will give his channel the opportunity to reach a larger audience, said</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to reach some three million viewers as a results, and we are targeting a 10 percent advertising market share,&quot; Feuer said.</p>
<p>With an estimated 1.5 million viewers per week, the station is still in the red, and Feuer said this is in line with plans.</p>
<p>&quot;We have spent some two billion forints and our original plans included a three-year loss-making period. Now, he have the chance to start making a profit earlier than envisaged,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The MPEG-2 encoded programme would be broadcast on a channel of satellite AMOS-1, rented by Antenna Hungaria.</p>
<p>Both Antenna Hungaria and TV3 declined to give a figure on the deal, but Mate said the costs they charge are about as much as would be for ground-based coverage of the capital, Budapest.</p>
<p>He added that Antenna Hungaria was aware of TV3's financial position when negotiations started and has received satisfactory guarantees that the station would be able to pay the agreed transmission fees.</p>
<p>Antenna Hungaria is reported to have debts totalling more than three billion forints, mainly as a result of arrears in transmission fee payments from state-owned channels.</p>
<p>Since 1990, several dozen local commercial television stations have mushroomed in Hungary, but the two national channels dominate the advertising market.</p>
<p>Ten-year concessions for national channel MTV2 and a third presently unused broadcasting band are expected to be offered by the end of the year.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
