<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31342" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-SPAIN THRASH FAROES IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SPAIN THRASH FAROES IN WORLD CUP QUALIFIER.</headline>
<dateline>TOFTIR, Faroe Islands 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Group favourites Spain had little difficulty trouncing the Faroe Islands 6-2 in a group six World Cup qualifying match on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the plucky home side withstood their mighty opponents for more than half an hour and even managed an early second-half equaliser.</p>
<p>Luis Enrique Martinez put Spain 1-0 ahead after a frustrating 37 minutes for the visitors who might have expected an easy ride.</p>
<p>Local hero Todi Jonsson quickly equalised at the start of the second half to keep the North Atlantic islanders in the game.</p>
<p>In the 63rd minute Alfonso Perez Munoz, brought in as substitute for Juan Antonio Pizzi, scored the first goal of a hat-trick, signalling the beginning of the end for the Faroes.</p>
<p>Oli Johannesen, with an own goal in the 70th and Fernando Ruiz Hierro in the 85th completed the Spanish scoreline.</p>
<p>But the Faroes did manage a consolation goal in the final minute of the match through substitute Uni Arge.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Faroe Islands - Jens Martin Knudsen, Oli Johannesen, Jens Kristian Hansen, Allan Joensen, Oessur Hansen, Allan Moerkoere, Julian Johnson, Henning Jarnskor, Jan Allan Mueller (Uni Arge, 74th minute), Todi Jonsson, John Petersen (Simun Eliasen, 89th).</p>
<p>Spain - Andoni Zubizarreta, Alberto Belsue, Agustin Aranzabal (Julen Guerrero, 72nd), Rafael Alkorta (Abelardo Fernandez, 46th), Miguel Angel Nadal, Fernando Ruiz Hierro, Josep Guardiola, Luis Enrique Martinez, Juan Antonio Pizzi (Alfonso Perez Munoz, 59th), Kiko Narvaez, Serge Barjuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FAEROE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOFTIR, Faroe Islands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
