<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31344" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH PLAYERS FLEX MUSCLES IN POWER STRUGGLE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH PLAYERS FLEX MUSCLES IN POWER STRUGGLE.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>England's top rugby players took a calculated gamble on Wednesday as they defied the Rugby Football Union (RFU) and allied themselves with the breakaway clubs who intend to declare independence from Twickenham next month.</p>
<p>By refusing to turn up for an RFU training session and attending a meeting organised by the English Professional Rugby Clubs (EPRUC), the 43-man squad finally made their move after months of wrangling over who controls their destiny in the new professional era.</p>
<p>A brief statement, released without further comment by EPRUC chairman Donald Kerr, said the players had decided &quot;the best way forward for the game is to agree in principle with EPRUC's vision of the future.&quot;</p>
<p>None of the squad would talk afterwards, many of them leaving the hotel where the meeting took place by an underground entrance but EPRUC, who represent the first and second division clubs, claimed the message to the RFU was unanimous.</p>
<p>&quot;If you want to read into this that England players agree to the breakaway, then fine,&quot; conceded Kerr. He refused to confirm when EPRUC and the players would meet again, and the ball now appears to be firmly at the feet of the RFU.</p>
<p>The union expressed &quot;disappointment the clubs have seen fit to use the players as a negotiating tool&quot; in the continuing struggle over power and money in English domestic rugby, but now face the sobering possibility of losing their top players as well as their Five Nations status by early next week.</p>
<p>The other four nations are set to meet in Dublin on Monday with England expected to be thrown out of the tournament in a row over television revenue. Even if they are granted a late reprieve, however, the players' latest move could mean the official England team bears no resemblance to the one supporters have cheered in recent seasons.</p>
<p>RFU secretary Tony Hallett is likely to restate the union's case on Thursday, but the situation is fast slipping away from him. The players' international contracts ran out last weekend and they have been swiftly reminded it is the clubs not Twickenham who are currently their sole paymasters.</p>
<p>Many have signed contracts worth at least 50,000 pounds for their clubs, although they have the potential to earn at least double that through their England involvement.</p>
<p>It was always unlikely the traditionally conservative RFU would find it easy to make the transition to a professional sport, but the players now find themselves caught in the middle of a bitter dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;We are being used as pawns,&quot; admitted forward Tim Rodber. &quot;We would rather be playing or training, but the meeting was necessary to find out our position.&quot;</p>
<p>With Welsh clubs and Scottish players also involved in disputes with their unions, British rugby is descending rapidly into farce.</p>
<p>England coach Jack Rowell and other RFU staff turned up as scheduled for the lunchtime training session, only to find they had no players to work with.</p>
<p>A scrummaging machine was driven through the gates of Bisham Abbey, normally home to the England soccer team, only to be towed back out again within half an hour as the managament opted to retire for lunch instead.</p>
<p>There were even claims on Wednesday that former England captain Will Carling could be playing rugby league for Bradford Bulls next year, as part of the deal which has brought New Zealander Robbie Paul to London club Harlequins.</p>
<p>Carling, omitted from the 43-man training squad but still in England contention, is unlikely to be thrilled by the Bradford offer but he, like everyone else in rugby, is fast discovering the new commercial realities.</p>
<p>These were summed up when millionaire Sir John Hall, owner of Newcastle United's soccer team and a member of the EPRUC board, revealed he had interrupted his holiday in Spain to attend the negotiations with the players.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very satisfying to realise that the players have stayed away from training,&quot; he said. &quot;We are sticking together for the good of the game.&quot;</p>
<p>The RFU might dispute that, but sports minister Iain Sproat is among the thousands of supporters whose frustration is growing. Speaking from Westminster on Wednesday, he called for someone to &quot;knock some heads together&quot; to end what he called a &quot;fiasco&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
