<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31345" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-CHELSEA SAVED BY WISE INTERVENTION.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHELSEA SAVED BY WISE INTERVENTION.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chelsea's all-star collection of international talent were saved by a last-minute goal from Londoner Dennis Wise which salvaged a thrilling 3-3 draw with Arsenal in the English premiership on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Chelsea had looked set for for a convincing win over their London rivals when Frank Leboeuf and Gianluca Vialli scored first-half goals, only for Arsenal to claim a 3-2 lead with 13 minutes to play through Ian Wright.</p>
<p>Just seconds remained when Wise, one of the few Englishmen in Chelsea's first-choice side under Ruud Gullit, collected a lofted ball from John Spencer and crashed a left-foot shot past John Lukic, back in the Arsenal goal in place of David Seaman.</p>
<p>The result maintain Chelsea's unbeaten start to the season, but could not prevent Aston Villa leapfrogging over them into second place after a 1-0 win at Everton.</p>
<p>Manchester United could only draw for the third match in succession, 1-1 at Derby, while Newcastle were also forced to come from behind to beat Sunderland 2-1 with goals from Peter Beardsley and Les Ferdinand.</p>
<p>Wimbledon's Vinnie Jones was sent off for the 12th time in his turbulent career after an hour of his side's 1-0 victory over Tottenham.  </p>
<p>The only sobering note for Chelsea's loyal fans came when Leboeuf was taken off on a stretcher with a back injury in the second half.</p>
<p>The happiest supporters in the country were probably to be found in the north-east where Newcastle and Middlesbrough are both praying for great things this season.</p>
<p>Kevin Keegan's Newcastle side, already wobbling after two defeats in their first three league games, went behind to a Martin Scott penalty in the 20th minute but Beardsley, preferred to Colombia's Faustino Asprilla, headed them back level seven minutes into the second half.</p>
<p>Ferdinand then rose above the defence to head home in the 63rd minute and offer a partial answer to the club's early-season critics.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough's Italian striker Fabrizio Ravanelli was on target again in the 4-1 win over West Ham but the most spectacular contribution came from Emerson, the club's other big pre-season overseas signing.</p>
<p>The Brazilian scored a superb opening goal from 30 metres to earn his new club their first league win of the season.</p>
<p>Manchester United produced little to worry Juventus before next week's champions' league encounter, barring another excellent long-range goal from England midfielder David Beckham in the 38th minute, his second of the season.</p>
<p>There was a sense of familiarity too about Jones's behaviour. He appeared to swap punches with Tottenham's Colin Calderwood in the centre circle when play was stopped and when his flying boot caught Anderton in the chest a couple of minutes later referee Steve Dunn had no option but to send him off.</p>
<p>There was rather more to admire from recalled England international Matthew Le Tissier who crowned a fine individual performance with a last-minute equaliser to give Southampton a 2-2 draw with Nottingham Forest.</p>
<p>Another England man, Ugo Ehiogu, steered Villa to their success, striking the winner in the 62nd minute after starting and finishing a glorious move. The defender scored only one premiership goal all last season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
