<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31355" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS TURN TO FRENTZEN TO COUNTER FERRARI.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS TURN TO FRENTZEN TO COUNTER FERRARI.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Williams Formula One team, fearing a Ferrari renaissance, named Heinz-Harald Frentzen on Wednesday as their replacement for championship leader Damon Hill.</p>
<p>The 29-year-old German joins Canadian Jacques Villeneuve next year, ousting Hill from the team just when the Briton is within touching distance of his first Grand Prix drivers' title.</p>
<p>Hill is 13 points clear of Villeneuve with three races to go and could clinch the drivers' crown in Sunday's Italian Grand Prix at Monza.</p>
<p>Williams, who has developed a reputation for brutally parting company with successful drivers, gave no reason for the decision to drop Hill, who had been with the Anglo-French team for six years.</p>
<p>But in an interview published in the British magazine Motoring News on Wednesday, Frank Williams spoke of his fear of a renaissance at rivals Ferrari, spearheaded by twice world champion Michael Schumacher.</p>
<p>&quot;In all this you must recognise one thing: you have not seen the best of Michael,&quot; he said. &quot;The nightmare is to picture Michael in a car next year that is as competitive as the Williams presently is. We will all have to go to church on Sunday and pray for unreliability.&quot;</p>
<p>The German previously transformed the Benetton team, beating Hill to the world drivers' title with them in 1994 and 1995, before joining Ferrari.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not on the agenda today, but of course I would love to see Schumacher in a Willliams like we always wanted to see Ayrton (Senna) in one,&quot; Williams added. &quot;He is a phenomenon in a Grand Prix car...he is quite remarkable.&quot;</p>
<p>Frentzen, currently with Sauber, has not won a Grand Prix, but is regarded as one of the fastest drivers on the circuit and a fitting challenger for Schumacher.</p>
<p>He has become known on the Grand Prix circuit as &quot;the other German&quot;, especially as his former girlfriend left him in 1991 for Schumacher. She is now Schumacher's wife.</p>
<p>Frentzen won the German junior championship and other titles between 1980 and 1985 before climbing via Formula Ford and the Opel Lotus series to finish as runner-up in the German Formula Three series in 1989.</p>
<p>He has been a target for the Anglo-French Williams team for some time despite the fact that this season he has managed only six world championship points and is just 11th in the standings.</p>
<p>For Hill, who was dropped by Williams after contract negotiations broke down last week, a move to the British Jordan team appears the most likely option.</p>
<p>The 35-year-old plans to give a news conference at Monza on Thursday to talk about his plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
