<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31360" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-WEST HAM TURN DOWN OFFER FOR CROAT BILIC.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WEST HAM TURN DOWN OFFER FOR CROAT BILIC.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>English premier league side West Ham have rejected a lucrative offer for Croatian midfielder Slaven Bilic.</p>
<p>According to newspaper reports Tottenham Hotspur are willing to pay 2.5 million pounds sterling ($3.9 million) for Bilic.</p>
<p>&quot;If you have world-class players there will constantly be inquiries and, yes, we have had one for Slaven,&quot; West Ham managing director Peter Storrie said. &quot;But I can't say which club it is, and anyway, we have turned it down.</p>
<p>&quot;If Slaven left it would have to be on the basis that we wanted to let him go, and that is not the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>While Bilic looks set to stay at West Ham, Dean Holdsworth may be leaving fellow Londoners Wimbledon.</p>
<p>The striker, valued at around 4.0 million pounds ($6.3 million) has put in a transfer request after being dropped for his side's league match against Leeds last week.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I'm concerned, if he wants to go I will not stand in his way,&quot; manager Joe Kinnear said after the match. &quot;You can't compete with egos so I'll just sit by the phone and wait for offers.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
