<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31361" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: SOCCER-KANU CASE MAY PROMPT HEALTH CARE REVIEW IN NIGERIA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-KANU CASE MAY PROMPT HEALTH CARE REVIEW IN NIGERIA.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The heart problem which threatens to end the soccer career of Nigerian and Internazionale striker Nwankwo Kanu is likely to make clubs in his home country pay more attention to health, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;To be honest, we lack proper and adequate medical facilities in this country. This Kanu case should make the NFA (Nigerian Football Association) ensure our clubs sit up and adopt a more medical and scientific approach to soccer,&quot; soccer analyst Godwin Dudu-Orumen said.</p>
<p>Cardiologists at Italian Serie A club Internazionale have diagnosed &quot;a valvular insufficiency of the aorta&quot; and said on Monday that Kanu may never play again.</p>
<p>Kanu, 20, was a key player for Dutch team Ajax, who won the European Cup in 1995, and for Nigeria's gold-medal winning Olympic soccer team.</p>
<p>Some managers may now push for Nigerian clubs to conduct medical check-ups and keep medical dossiers on players.</p>
<p>&quot;The Kanu case will now make all clubs have good doctors, listen to medical advice and ensure they store records on players in case of reference to their medical history,&quot; Uche Ejimofor, manager of Kanu's former club Iwuanyanwu Nationale, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Analysts believe the NFA will now compel its almost 1,000 club sides to pay more attention to providing adequate health facilities.</p>
<p>It is not the first time health problems have surfaced among Nigerian players.</p>
<p>In 1995 Amir Angwe, a star player of local team Julius Berger, collapsed and died on the pitch during a match in Lagos.</p>
<p>In 1989 Samuel Okwaraji collapsed while playing for the national team. He later died.</p>
<p>Akin Amao, head of Nigeria's medical team at the Olympic Games said: &quot;I'm intrigued by Kanu's case. It's surprising that neither us nor Ajax were able to detect his cardiac anomaly. But in the medical field anything can happen.</p>
<p>&quot;His medical records do not show he's had this anomaly. However, this will make the soccer authorities ensure the clubs here have proper medical staff and facilities at their disposal to make us know everything about players.&quot;</p>
<p>The NFA said it had yet to come to terms with the news of Kanu's illness and said they would send a medical officer to Milan to investigate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
