<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31372" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-BECOMING NUMBER ONE IS NOT CHANG'S TOP GOAL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-BECOMING NUMBER ONE IS NOT CHANG'S TOP GOAL.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Chang can become number one in the world if he wins the U.S. Open this weekend but the number three-ranked player has a different goal in mind.</p>
<p>&quot;I have had a certain mentality of going out and just giving my best and working hard and trying to improve, and I don't thing I should really get away from that,&quot; said the second-seeded Chang after reaching the U.S. Open semifinals for the first time in four years.</p>
<p>Chang turned back the spirited challenge of unseeded Spaniard Javier Sanchez 7-5 6-3 6-7 6-3 Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;For me it is knowing that I gave it my best because life is too short to be stressing out on a lot of other things.&quot;</p>
<p>Chang is happy in his low-key role in comparision to such more renowned American rivals as the world number one and defending champion Pete Sampras or the former world number one and 1994 Open winner, flamboyant Andre Agassi.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not important to necessarily be in the public eye or to gain the fame or the popularity or stuff like that,&quot; said Chang.</p>
<p>&quot;For me I am happy just going about my business to do things more along the lines like Stefan than maybe a guy like Andre,&quot; Chang said of Stefan Edberg, the classy 30-year-old Swede who is retiring at the end of this year.</p>
<p>Chang had a meteoric climb to prominence in 1989 when at the age of 17 he became the youngest men's Grand Slam champion by beating Edberg to win the French Open.</p>
<p>Chang has not won another major, though he came close when he lost the 1995 French Open final to Thomas Muster and lost this year's Australian Open final to Boris Becker.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it is necessarily so important to win a Grand Slam to prove anything to anybody,&quot; said Chang, who went out in the first round at Wimbledon this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very content at where I am and obviously I am striving for bigger and better things, but I think that if I have a mentality as far as trying to win a Grand Slam just to prove something, I don't think that is the right attitude.&quot;</p>
<p>Chang's gung-ho attitude of never surrendering a point has helped him get this far.</p>
<p>In the third round against Vince Spadea, Chang rallied in five sets after his young opponent had served for the match in the fourth set.</p>
<p>Chang also could have gotten dispirited after failing to hold onto a 3-0 third set lead to let Sanchez back into the match, but he didn't.</p>
<p>&quot;He fights a lot and he stays all the match playing and fighting every point and that is pretty tough,&quot; Sanchez said after the grueling two hour, 49 minute match.</p>
<p>Chang was forced to adopt his relentless playing style due to the limitations inherent in his diminutive size.</p>
<p>&quot;I realise that being 5-9 (1.75 metres) I am not going to be a pure power player,&quot; Chang said.</p>
<p>Looking for some extra punch in his game, Chang is the only top player to use a racket that is one inch (2.5 cm) longer than the standard racket. But Chang has never lost sight of what works the best for him.</p>
<p>&quot;Tennis is not decided by who can hit the hardest and I think my strength has always been my groundstrokes and the ability to be able to move and also to be able to think on the court,&quot; said Chang.</p>
<p>&quot;It is still a thinking man's game out there.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
