<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31373" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-GRAF'S FOCUS AMAZES OPPONENTS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-GRAF'S FOCUS AMAZES OPPONENTS.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Steffi Graf isn't talking about her father's tax evasion trial, which begins on Thursday in Germany, but her opponents are amazed at the world number one's singular ability to keep her focus on the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't think of anybody who is having a more difficult time,&quot; said Austrian Judith Wiesner after losing a quarter-final to Graf 7-5 6-3 on the eve of Peter Graf's trial.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what she is thinking, but sometimes I am amazed how anybody can shrug off all that stuff and just go out and play that well. It must be very difficult, but obviously she can.&quot;</p>
<p>The top seed and defending Open champion was tight-lipped when asked to comment on her father's plight, brushing off questions with a brusque, &quot;I don't want to talk about it.&quot;</p>
<p>But the situation has to be weighing heavily on her mind as she struggles at times to keep her focus on tennis.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess for some reason it's a little difficult at the moment to focus very well on the (tennis) court,&quot; she said aluding to the trial without ever mentioning it.</p>
<p>Peter Graf has been improsioned since last August and faces a 10-year jail sentence if convicted of failure to pay taxes on approximately $13 million of his daughter's tennis earnings from 1989-93.</p>
<p>The 27-year-old tennis superstar, who had always allowed her father to handle her vast earnings, herself remains under investigation and could still be called as a witness in the upcoming trial.</p>
<p>Neverthless, Graf has managed to keep playing great tennis during the entire ordeal, having won all three Grand Slams she has played since her father was jailed just prior to last year's U.S. Open.</p>
<p>Natasha Zvereva, Graf's third-round victim, suggested that the tennis court is a sanctuary for the troubled Wimbledon and French Open champion.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody needs what I call a getaway and maybe the tennis court is her getaway,&quot; Zvereva said.</p>
<p>Graf said it was a simple matter of concentration that enables her to keep her mind from wandering too far from the tennis court.</p>
<p>&quot;I try to focus on the next point,&quot; she said. &quot;Sometimes it works. Sometimes it doesn't.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
