<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31370" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-OWNERS' MEETING PUT OFF, PANEL TO DISCUSS LABOR TALKS.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-OWNERS' MEETING PUT OFF, PANEL TO DISCUSS LABOR TALKS.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The long wait for a baseball labour agreement got a little longer on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Major League Baseball owners put off a quarterly owners' meeting scheduled for next week in Seattle at which it had been hoped there would be a labour agreement to ratify.</p>
<p>Instead, acting commissioner Bud Selig announced that the Major League Executive Council would meet with the Labour Policy Committee next Wednesday to discuss the labour issue at an as yet undetermined site.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important to bring the labour situation to the Executive Council for review,&quot; Selig said. &quot;There still are several outstanding issues that must be settled.</p>
<p>&quot;This deliberation is necessary in order to get a fair and equitable labour deal for all concerned. We are hopeful that soon after the subject is reviewed by the Executive Council, we can bring it to the full ownership.&quot;</p>
<p>The main issue left in the negotiations towards a collective bargaining agreement is service time credited to players for games missed after they went on strike in 1994.</p>
<p>Union boss Donald Fehr rejected the latest proposal, which was to restore service time to all but 20 of the striking players.</p>
<p>Five owners, most notably Jerry Reinsdorf of the Chicago White Sox and Wayne Huizenga of the Florida Marlins, have opposed giving the players credit for the 75 games missed due to the strike. To ratify an agreement, 75 percent of the 28 owners must vote in favour of it.</p>
<p>The union indicated there would be no agreement without a return of lost service time, for which players have received credit after every previous strike settlement.</p>
<p>Stars such as Chuck Knoblauch, Bernard Gilkey, Moises Alou and Alex Fernandez would become free agents at the end of this season with the restored service time.</p>
<p>In return for crediting players for time lost during the 232-day stoppage that began August 12, 1994, owners could receive certain legal guarantees or a break in salary arbitration.</p>
<p>Baseball has been without a labour agreement since December 31, 1993, alienating fans along the way. The 1994 players' strike and subsequent owners' cancellation was the biggest blow, wiping out the World Series for the first time since 1904 and knocking 18 games off the start of the 1995 season.</p>
<p>The major issue -- the implementation of a &quot;tax&quot; on higher payrolls -- apparently has been agreed upon through 1999.</p>
<p>The proposal includes a luxury tax of 35 percent in each of the first two years and 34 percent in the third year. The tax would take effect at a threshold of $51 million in 1997, $55 million in 1998 and $58 million in 1999.</p>
<p>The proposed luxury tax would hit about five teams with big payrolls, with the money going both to small-market teams and a joint revenue fund.</p>
<p>The stoppage ended only after a March 31, 1995 injunction was issued by United States District Court Judge Sonya Sotomayor ordering play to be resumed under terms of the previous agreement. No new contract was reached, however.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
