<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31379" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-REDS' BURBA, SHAW COMBINE TO ONE-HIT BRAVES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-REDS' BURBA, SHAW COMBINE TO ONE-HIT BRAVES.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dave Burba and Jeff Shaw combined on a one-hitter -- a leadoff homer by Marquis Grissom -- as the Cincinnati Reds scored a 5-1 win Tuesday over the powerful Atlanta Braves, who have lost a season-high four in a row.</p>
<p>Burba (9-13) surrendered Grissom's 21st homer and not much else over six innings. He walked four and struck out seven before leaving for Shaw, who set down nine in a row for his fourth save.</p>
<p>&quot;The last time I faced them, they hit three home runs off me,&quot; Burba said of the Braves. &quot;It was a slap in the face. Last time I only made one pitch that should have been hit out. I don't know how I compare it, I'm just happy I did it.&quot;</p>
<p>Barry Larkin snapped a 1-1 tie with his 26th homer, a two-run shot off Mike Bielecki (4-3), who replaced Greg Maddux in the rotation. Maddux missed his scheduled start with a hamstring injury but the four-time Cy Young Award winner should return this weekend.</p>
<p>Larkin, who has 35 steals, needs just four homers to become the first shortstop in major-league history with 30 homers and 30 steals in the same season.</p>
<p>Despite the loss, the Braves still have the best record in the majors, 84-54.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Todd Stottlemyre allowed four hits over eight innings and Brian Jordan, Gary Gaetti and Luis Alicea each had two hits and two RBI as the Cardinals moved back into first place in the National League Central Division with a 12-3 rout of the Houston Astros.</p>
<p>Royce Clayton also drove in two runs for the Cardinals, who beat Houston for the 10th time in 12 meetings this season to return to the top spot for the first time since August 19. They lead the second-place Astros by one-half game.</p>
<p>Stottlemyre (12-10) gave up two runs, walked two and struck out nine for just his third win in 10 starts since July 13. With his 95th career victory, he and his father, Mel, broke the all-time father-son win total with their 259th. The Stottlemyres had shared the record with Dizzy and Steve Trout.</p>
<p>Gaetti put St Louis ahead for good in the fourth with his 18th homer, a two-run shot off starter Shane Reynolds (16-8). St Louis padded its lead in the sixth when Reynolds balked home Ron Gant, who reached on a one-out double. Astros manager Terry Collins was ejected for arguing the balk call.</p>
<p>In New York, shortstop Rey Ordonez's throwing error allowed pinch-runner Chad Fonville to score, snapping an eighth-inning tie as the Los Angeles Dodgers held off the Mets 7-6 to move into a first-place tie with San Diego in the National League West.</p>
<p>Pinch-hitter Dave Clark's grounder was fielded in the hole by Ordonez, who tried to force Greg Gagne at second. Second baseman Alvaro Espinoza was not covering the base and Fonville scored from second to give the Dodgers a 4-3 edge.</p>
<p>Raul Mondesi hit a three-run homer in the top of the ninth for the Dodgers and Bernard Gilkey hit one in the bottom of the ninth for the Mets.</p>
<p>Scott Radinsky (3-1) got the win as the Dodgers won for the fifth time in six games. Doug Henry (2-6) took the loss.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, rookie Scott Rolen, who entered the game in a 1-for-30 slump, homered and drove in a season-high four runs as the Phillies defeated the San Diego Padres 8-2 for just their third win in 10 games.</p>
<p>Mike Mimbs (2-7) gave up one run on one hit in five innings with three walks and three strikeouts. Ken Ryan allowed one hit over two scoreless innings for his seventh save.</p>
<p>Gregg Jefferies also homered for Philadelphia.</p>
<p>At Florida, Scott Servais' two-run single in the fifth inning snapped a tie and Jaime Navarro survived five rocky innings to notch his seventh consecutive victory as the Chicago Cubs defeated the Marlins 11-3.</p>
<p>Navarro (14-9) allowed three runs and eight hits, walking one and striking out eight.</p>
<p>Ryne Sandberg and Gary Sheffield exchanged two-run homers in the first inning. Sandberg's was his 29th for the Cubs while Sheffield's was his 39th, leaving him one behind injured Cubs right fielder Sammy Sosa for the league lead.</p>
<p>In Montreal, David Segui hit a pair of two-run homers and Pedro Martinez struck out 11 over 7 2/3 innings as the Expos won their fourth straight, 9-2 over the San Francisco Giants.</p>
<p>Martinez (12-9) allowed two runs, nine hits and one walk. He has struck out 23 over his last two starts.</p>
<p>Mark Gardner (10-6) surrendered five runs and seven hits in 4 1/3 innings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
