<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31371" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-TEEN SENSATION HINGIS INTO OPEN SEMIS AGAINST GRAF.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-TEEN SENSATION HINGIS INTO OPEN SEMIS AGAINST GRAF.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>She was given a champion's name at birth, and 15-year-old Martina Hingis displayed grown-up groundstrokes and nerves of steel worthy of her namesake Wednesday in seizing a semifinal berth at the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>The 16th-seeded Swiss sensation, named after the legendary Martina Navratilova, picked off seventh-seeded Czech Jana Novotna 7-6 6-4 to earn a semifinal showdown with world number one and defending champion Steffi Graf.</p>
<p>Steffi vs Martina in a Grand Slam semifinal -- a familiar ring with a fresh face.</p>
<p>&quot;I played a great match today and it's a great feeling,&quot; said Hingis, the third 15-year-old to reach the U.S. Open semifinals after Andrea Jaeger in 1980 and Jennifer Capriati in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a great honour to be in the semis of a Grand Slam,&quot; said the Czech-born Hingis.</p>
<p>Olympic bronze medalist Novotna, 27, was left impressed by the youngster's versatile game.</p>
<p>&quot;When she needed it she came up with a good passing shot of a great topspin lob. She was good from the net, she was good from the back...She's able to basically do anything on the court.&quot;</p>
<p>Hingis also showed the brand of big-match courage that Novotna has too often lacked in a history of Grand Slam collapses.</p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday Graf managed to put aside her personal problems to record her 40th consecutive Grand Slam match win and reach her 11th U.S. Open semifinal.</p>
<p>On the eve of her father's trial for tax evasion, Graf struggled some to find her rhythm and concentration, but called on her vast championship experience to pull off a 7-5 6-3 win over unseeded Austrian Judith Wiesner.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't really have the most positive attitude out there. I'll definitely have to work on that,&quot; said Graf, who may be called on to testify at her father's trial in Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe I haven't played the best tennis in these past few rounds,&quot; said the four-time champion. &quot;But I know that when it gets down to the important matches I'm usually up there so hopefully it will be the same again.&quot;</p>
<p>She will need to be &quot;up there&quot; against the go-for-broke Hingis, who already beat one U.S. Open champion this week in third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in the semis now. I have nothing to lose against her,&quot; said the astonishingly poised teenager, who handed Graf one of her three losses this year at the Italian Open but fell to the German superstar during Graf's championship run at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>The busy Swiss prodigy is also through to the semis of the women's doubles and mixed doubles with a chance to become the first player since Navratilova in 1987 to win all three.</p>
<p>In the bottom half of the draw, second seed Monica Seles and fourth seed Conchita Martinez advanced on Tuesday to set up a rematch of one of last year's semifinals.  </p>
<p>Novotna, who relies heavily on her serve, had trouble with her delivery, putting just 50 percent of her first serves into play.</p>
<p>&quot;My serve wasn't working at all. I didn't have any easy points on my serve so I really had to work very hard to win every single point,&quot; the seventh seed said.</p>
<p>Novotna also gave Hingis a multitude of free points with 38 unforced errors to just 17 by the 16th seed.</p>
<p>That was never more obvious than in the tie-break, which Hingis won 7-1 without hitting a single winner as Novotna produced backhand errors, forehand errors and a double fault.</p>
<p>&quot;She helped me a lot in the tie-breaker,&quot; noted Hingis with a sly grin.</p>
<p>The second set was close with the two combatants twice trading service breaks before Novotna drilled a forehand down the line to hold serve for a 4-3 lead.</p>
<p>That was when Hingis raised her game in a manner belying her lack of big-match experience.</p>
<p>She reeled off the next 11 points, coming up with one terrific passing shot after another to leave Novotna lunging for no-hope volleys, or expertly moving the Czech out of position before depositing her next shot into a wide-open court.</p>
<p>Hingins reached triple match point with a rare ace.</p>
<p>Novotna managed to save the first two before Hingis unleashed a powerful forehand pass that the seventh seed was barely able to get her racket on.</p>
<p>Finally Hingis looked her age, her face aglow with youthful joy and her fists thrust skyward.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
