<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31374" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-ON EVE OF FATHER'S TRIAL GRAF FIGHTS INTO SEMIS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-ON EVE OF FATHER'S TRIAL GRAF FIGHTS INTO SEMIS.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>With her heart and mind in Mannheim, where her father is set to stand trial, world number one Steffi Graf still managed to book her place in the semifinals of the U.S. Open on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Struggling at times to find her rhythm and concentration, and pushed hard by unseeded Austrian Judith Wiesner, the defending champion called on her vast champion's experience to fashion a 7-5 6-3 quarter-final win.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess for some reason it's a little difficult at moment to focus very well on the court,&quot; Graf said on the eve of her father's tax evasion trial, a trial in which Graf herself may be called upon to testify.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't really have the most positive attitude out there,&quot; she admitted. &quot;I'll definitely have to work on that.&quot;</p>
<p>Like she did last year when she won the Open with her father, Peter, newly behind bars, Graf was still able to come up with the big shots on the big points.</p>
<p>Whenever she found herself in trouble, Graf was able to raise her game just enough to come through.</p>
<p>She saved three break points in the first game of the match and five more in the opening game of the second set to record her 40th consecutive Grand Slam match win and move within two victories of her 21st career major title.</p>
<p>But the win looked nothing like co-number one Monica Seles's Tuesday night demolition of Amanda Coetzer, and the German superstar knows she will have to play a lot better if she is to claim her fifth U.S. Open crown on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Knowing that I have so much experience being in the semis and finals of the Grand Slams I think definitely will help me a lot,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The skies at the previously sun-drenched Open were for the first time gray and overcast.</p>
<p>And the 30-year-old Wiesner, the first Austrian woman to reach the quarters in the open era here, looked sharp and aggressive early, controlling points and moving Graf around the court.</p>
<p>The 24th-ranked Austrian failed in her early chances to break Graf, but broke through in the fifth game as the German put a forehand into the net for one of her uncharacteristic 43 unforced errors, nearly twice that of Wiesner.</p>
<p>Graf can still belt those forehand winners even when her mind is elsewhere, however, and she broke back in the eighth game and again in the 12th to take the set.</p>
<p>Although she faced five break points before holding to open the second set, Graf was now on a roll, winning nine of 10 games to grab a 4-0 lead before Wiesner came up with her second and last service break of the one hour and 24 minute match.</p>
<p>The Austrian, who reached her first  career Grand Slam quarter-final this year at Wimbledon, continued to force Graf to concentrate on the matters at hand with strong play and saved two match points to hold for 5-3.</p>
<p>But Graf followed with a love game, ending the contest with one of her trademark thundering forehands deep into the open corner.</p>
<p>The German now awaits the winner of Wednesday's later quarter-final between 15-year-old Swiss wunderkind Martina Hingis and seventh-seeded Czech veteran Jana Novotna.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe I haven't played the best tennis in these past few rounds&quot; Graf said. &quot;But I know that when it gets down to the important matches I'm usually up there so hopefully it will be the same again.&quot;  </p>
<p>Second seed Michael Chang, the little guy with the big racket, made life difficult for himself before grabbing the first semifinal berth in the men's competition with a 7-5 6-3 6-7 6-3 win over surprising Spaniard Javier Sanchez.</p>
<p>Apparently on a straight sets roll after romping through the second set and going up two breaks in the third, Chang ended up in a four-set war with the lowest ranked player left in the tournament at 67th.</p>
<p>&quot;Javier was playing some great tennis. It was definitely a dog fight,&quot; said Chang, who practically had to run a marathon the way Sanchez made hin race around the court in the two-hour and 49-minute baseline battle.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm just really pleased to be in the semifinals,&quot; added Chang, who reached his second career U.S. Open semifinal without facing a player ranked higher than 50th in the world.</p>
<p>Sanchez was serving for the first set when Chang won the next seven games to seize control of the match.</p>
<p>But he must have felt a false sense of security, relaxing a little too much after going up 3-0 with two breaks in the third set.</p>
<p>Sanchez, who had lost in the first round of eight of his previous nine Grand Slams, started playing inspired tennis.</p>
<p>The older brother of fallen women's third seed Arantxa Sanchez Vicario took Chang to a tie-break and dominated it, 7-2, to send the match into fourth set before the American reasserted his control of the proceedings.</p>
<p>&quot;You just can't do that in a Grand Slam,&quot; Chang, the Australian Open runner-up, said of his let-down.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good lesson for me.&quot;</p>
<p>In the semifinals, Chang will face the winner of Wednesday night's eagerly-anticipated grudge match between sixth seed Andre Agassi and third seed Thomas  Muster.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
