<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31376" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-EASTERN CONTENDERS STUMBLE ON WEST COAST.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-EASTERN CONTENDERS STUMBLE ON WEST COAST.</headline>
<dateline>OAKLAND, California 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The three American League Eastern Division contenders all stumbled on the West Coast Tuesday, while the Chicago White Sox continued their wild-card drive.</p>
<p>In Oakland, Tony Batista's one-out single scored Ernie Young to snap a seventh-inning tie, lifting the Athletics to a 10-9 victory over the New York Yankees.</p>
<p>Reliever Brian Boehringer (1-3) took the loss as Oakland won for the first time in five home meetings with the Yankees this season. Mark Acre (1-2) got the win and Doug Johns got the last four outs for his first major-league save.</p>
<p>Paul O'Neill and Tino Martinez homered for New York and Scott Brosius homered off Yankee starter Doc Gooden in the first.</p>
<p>The Yankees remained four games ahead of second-place Baltimore in the American League East because in Anaheim,  Pep Harris got his first major-league win and Tim Salmon had four hits and three RBI to lead the California Angels to a 10-2 romp over the Orioles.</p>
<p>Harris (1-0) over seven innings allowed two runs and six hits with two walks and a strikeout. The 23-year-old right-hander was making his fifth appearance and third start.</p>
<p>The Orioles' Brady Anderson tied the American League record with his ninth leadoff homer of the season. Rickey Henderson hit nine leadoff homers for the Yankees in 1986. Bobby Bonds holds the major-league mark with 11 in 1973.</p>
<p>Jim Edmonds smacked his 26th homer for California.</p>
<p>In Seattle, Mark Whiten homered and drove in five runs and Salomon Torres won for the first time in more than a year as the Mariners defeated the Boston Red Sox 11-9.</p>
<p>Whiten, who has hit in 15 of 17 games since being acquired from Atlanta, has seven homers and 17 RBI over that span.  His three-run homer in the seventh off Eric Gunderson gave the Mariners an 11-4 lead.</p>
<p>They would need all the runs as Boston rallied in the ninth and had the tying run at the plate but Norm Charlton retired Jeff Manto and Mike Stanley for his 15th save.</p>
<p>Torres (1-1) allowed three runs and seven hits over 5 1/3 innings, walking two and striking out three. The victory was his first since July 9, 1995.</p>
<p>Red Sox starter Tom Gordon (10-7) had a 10-game winning streak against the Mariners snapped, surrendering eight runs and nine hits in 4 1/3 innings.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Robin Ventura hit a three-run homer in the sixth to lift the White Sox to a 6-4 victory over the Detroit Tigers, their fifth win in six games.</p>
<p>Mike Bertotti (2-0) allowed one run and one hit over 1 1/3 innings for the win. Roberto Hernandez struck out one in a perfect ninth inning for his 35th save.</p>
<p>Omar Olivares (7-10) took the loss.</p>
<p>Chicago leads Baltimore by one game, Seattle by two and Boston by 3 1/2 in the wild card race. The White Sox trail Cleveland by seven games in the Central Division.</p>
<p>In Milwaukee, Scott Karl scattered nine hits for his first win in eight starts and Mike Matheny punctuated his return to the majors with a homer as the Brewers defeated the Cleveland Indians 8-2 for their fourth win in five games.</p>
<p>Karl (11-7) walked two and struck out three in his second complete game of the season. He had not won since July 23.</p>
<p>Matheny, recalled from Triple-A New Orleans earlier in the day, snapped a 1-1 tie in the fourth off Orel Hershiser (14-8), who had a four-game win streak snapped.</p>
<p>Marc Newfield drove in three runs and Jose Valentin had two RBI and scored once for Milwaukee, which tied the season series at 6-6 against the Central Division leaders. Cleveland has lost four of five.</p>
<p>At Texas, Mickey Tettleton homered and drove in a season-high four runs and Bobby Witt won for the sixth time in seven starts as the Rangers defeated the Minnesota Twins 9-7.</p>
<p>Tettleton hit a three-run double to cap a four-run first inning against starter Frank Rodriguez (13-11) and added his 19th homer in the sixth for the Western Division leaders.</p>
<p>Witt (14-9) allowed five runs and eight hits over five innings, walking three and striking out two. The bullpen held the Twins in check over the next three innings and Mike Henneman tossed a perfect ninth for his 27th save.</p>
<p>In Toronto, Kevin Appier pitched a seven-hitter and Jon Nunnally capped a four-RBI effort with a three-run homer in the eighth, giving the Kansas City Royals their fourth straight win, 5-2 over the Blue Jays.</p>
<p>Appier (12-10) snapped a three-game losing streak with his fifth complete game. He outdueled Pat Hentgen, allowing two runs with two walks and 12 strikeouts. Appier passed Hentgen into second place in the American League with a 3.31 ERA.</p>
<p>Hentgen (17-8), the A.L. Pitcher of the Month for July and August, had his four-game winning streak broken and lost for only the second time in 12 decisions since July 1. He gave up five runs and 11 hits in eight innings, snapping his streak of five consecutive complete games.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAKLAND, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
