<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31388" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-AJAX DROP POINTS WITH GOALLESS DRAW IN KERKRADE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AJAX DROP POINTS WITH GOALLESS DRAW IN KERKRADE.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defending champions Ajax Amsterdam dropped two precious points in the battle for the Dutch league title when they drew 0-0 at Roda JC Kerkrade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Amsterdam side started with Jari Litmanen, Marc Overmars and Marcio Santos, all back from injury, but their lack of rhythm hampered the style that gave Ajax three Dutch titles in a row and a European Cup title.</p>
<p>Athough Ajax worked hard and had chances to take the match they went home with only one point.</p>
<p>Ajax have dropped five points, all in away games, in four matches and are ranked seventh with seven points and only two goals scored.</p>
<p>Their big rivals PSV Eindhoven, who play against RKC Waalwijk on Thursday, still have a 100 per cent record with nine points from three matches.</p>
<p>Feyenoord Rotterdam lead the Dutch first division with 10 points from four matches after they easily beat Fortuna Sittard 2-0 on Tuesday with goals from Swedish international Henke Larsson and Ronald Koeman from the penalty spot.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
