<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31381" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SAMPRAS SERVES UP BIG WIN AGAINST PHILIPPOUSSIS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SAMPRAS SERVES UP BIG WIN AGAINST PHILIPPOUSSIS.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Top-seeded defending champion Pete Sampras turned the expected serving showdown against Mark Philippoussis into a runaway jaunt into the U.S. Open quarter-finals Tuesday.</p>
<p>Much had been made of potency of the Philippoussis serve and by the fact that he had toppled the world number one in the third round of the Australian Open earlier this year.</p>
<p>But Sampras was neither bothered by the Australian's 17 aces nor by their mutual history as he relied on his own serving prowess and experience as a seven-time Grand Slam singles champion for a methodical 6-3 6-3 6-4 victory.</p>
<p>&quot;To beat him in straight sets with all the media hype is pretty solid,&quot; Sampras said of a victory under the National Tennis Centre stadium lights that raised his nightime record at the Open to 11-0. &quot;This was the best match of the Open for me.&quot;</p>
<p>The three-time Open champion was near the top of his game in almost every department. The 25-year-old American had 11 aces, faced one break point and was sound from the backcourt where he rifled 10 winners.</p>
<p>&quot;I looked on it as a very dangerous match,&quot; Sampras said of the rubber match in the Grand Slams against Philippoussis this year after beating him in the second round at Wimbledon. &quot;It was a match where you needed to stay on your toes and that was my mindset.&quot;</p>
<p>A key to the mindset was to remain unrattled by a barrage of Philippoussis aces.</p>
<p>&quot;You just have to hang in there, if he serves two, three aces a game so be it,&quot; Sampras said. &quot;You just have to stay patient with him.</p>
<p>Patience of another sort might be required for Sampras in his upcoming match against unseeded Spainish baseliner Alex Corretja, a 6-4 6-3 7-6 winner over French veteran Guy Forget.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a match that I'm going to need to keep the balls back and serve well, come in a little bit,&quot; Sampras said.</p>
<p>Philippoussis, though, lost his patience, trying to load up too much on his first serves. He managed to get in just 49 percent of his first deliveries.</p>
<p>&quot;I tried to go for a bit too much instead of getting into the match,&quot; said Philippoussis, ranked 22nd in the world.</p>
<p>That inexperience also showed on the only break point the 19-year-old had. Trailing 3-1 in the final set, he overhit a forehand service return into the bottom of the net.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt like I really had to do something with it, put too much pressure on myself,&quot; said Philippoussis.</p>
<p>Sampras climbed on top quickly when Philippoussis committed four double faults in the third game of the match. The last, on break point, put him behind to stay, except when he briefly held serve for a 1-0 lead in the final set.</p>
<p>&quot;It was pretty much an uphill fight,&quot; said Philippoussis. &quot;I really wanted to do well. He was just playing some good tennis.&quot;</p>
<p>The Stefan Edberg farewell bandwagon rolled merrily on as the 30-year-old unseeded Swede rallied to beat unseeded Englishman Tim Henman 6-7 7-6 6-4 6-4 to reach the quarter-finals here for the first time since winning his second of his consecutive titles in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Now starts the rally tough matches,&quot; Edberg, who has announced this will be his last Grand Slam, said of taking on fourth-seeded Goran Ivanisevic next.</p>
<p>Riddling the court with 20 aces, Ivanisevic beat unseeded Ukrainian Andrei Medvedev 6-4 3-6 6-3 7-6 to put him into the final eight for the first time in his career.</p>
<p>&quot;This is my best tournament ever here and now anything is possible, even winning,&quot; said the confident Croatian.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
