<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31383" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-EDBERG ENJOYING HIS FINAL GRAND SLAM RIDE.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-EDBERG ENJOYING HIS FINAL GRAND SLAM RIDE.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>After picking off the reigning Wimbledon champion in the first round and stopping the future of British tennis in the fourth, Stefan Edberg is beginning to really enjoy his final U.S. Open.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a special year. It's my last Grand Slam. It's great that I can perform and win these matches,&quot; the 30-year-old Swede said after beating rising British star Tim Henman 6-7 7-6 6-4 6-4 to move into the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Edberg, who has decided to retire after this year, is playing his record 54th consecutive Grand Slam event.</p>
<p>He owns six major titles, including two U.S. Open crowns. But a tournament that started as something of an Edberg death watch -- which match will be his last Grand Slam contest? -- has suddenly turned into an inspirational run toward the final weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw my chance here since beating Krajicek,&quot; he said of his win over the fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion that helped capture the imagination of the  New York tennis fans.</p>
<p>&quot;The draw has opened up a little bit but you still have to win your matches. I had to fight really hard to win today,&quot; he said of his more than three-hour struggle with the 21-year-old Henman.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel good about my game. I feel I have a chance in my next match. That's all I need,&quot; added the soft-spoken Swede who next takes on fourth-seeded Croatian ace master Goran Ivanisevic.</p>
<p>With his every match being played on centre court and with the fans hanging on every swing of his racket, Edberg acknowledged that he is feeding off the energy of the raucous New York crowds.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the way you want to finish. You want to finish strong,&quot; he said of his swan song.</p>
<p>&quot;I sort of see the light at the end of the tunnel. I know I've got so much time to push myself. I'm ready to push myself,&quot; he promised.</p>
<p>Edberg's longtime coach Tony Pickard, who reunited with the Swedish star this summer, feels he is calling it quits prematurely.</p>
<p>&quot;I told him I thought he was three years too soon,&quot; Pickard said.</p>
<p>But even if Edberg's run ends with a fairytale victory on the final Sunday, he insists he will not return to defend the title.</p>
<p>&quot;I make a decision, I stick to it. You can't go on forever,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe I'll come back next year and watch.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
