<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31385" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-EMMITT SMITH JOKES ABOUT SCARY INJURY AFTER TESTS NEGATIVE.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-EMMITT SMITH JOKES ABOUT SCARY INJURY AFTER TESTS NEGATIVE.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dallas Cowboys running back Emmitt Smith, back home Tuesday after a scary injury the night before in Chicago, was able to joke about it after tests found no serious damage.</p>
<p>Smith was injured Monday night with under four minutes to go in a 22-6 loss to the Chicago Bears when he dove across the scrimmage line as a decoy and landed awkwardly on his helmet and shoulder pads.</p>
<p>&quot;I did it to myself, no one else did it to me,&quot; Smith said with a laugh after a serious of tests proved negative for a variety of permanent, serious injuries such as brain or spine damage.</p>
<p>Smith was immobilized, carted off the field and kept overnight at Chicago's Northwestern Memorial Hospital before returning to Dallas in the private jet of Cowboys owner Jerry Jones.</p>
<p>Still wearing a neck brace and his hospital clothes -- including turquoise-blue cloth shoes -- Smith told a Chicago television station of his frightening injury.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a lot of pain shooting through the back. I started moving at first. All of a sudden my left arm went numb and my left leg started going numb. From that perspective, that's when I got scared -- when I couldn't feel my fingers, my leg.&quot;</p>
<p>Smith joked about the hospital shoes but added: &quot;That was a serious time for me.&quot;</p>
<p>Smith was to be examined daily, but various broadcast reports said doctors considered it unlikely he would be ready to play Sunday when the Cowboys host the New York Giants,</p>
<p>Jones said Smith did not suffer any serious injuries but still had a sore neck and back. The owner would not rule out a return to the lineup Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Emmitt will play, but whether or not he will play this week we don't know yet,&quot; Jones told a Dallas radio station.</p>
<p>&quot;They (doctors) were concerned about any number of potential injuries but after an extensive night of tests, he's cleared to go,&quot; said Jones. &quot;He had a long night. No sleep at all.&quot;</p>
<p>In his career, Smith has missed just one game due to injury and two because of a contract holdout.</p>
<p>Smith finished Monday night's game with 70 yards on 18 carries and caught two passes for five yards.</p>
<p>The Cowboys already were without two key players, suspended wide receiver Michael Irvin and injured tight end Jay Novacek.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
