<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31391" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-KANU SAYS HIS CAREER NOT YET OVER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-KANU SAYS HIS CAREER NOT YET OVER.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigerian striker Nwankwo Kanu, whose soccer career is under threat because of a heart problem, said on Wednesday he had not given up hope.</p>
<p>&quot;My sporting career is not finished. I will go to the best specialists in the world in order to play again,&quot; the 20-year-old Inter Milan player told reporters after a second series of tests confirmed the diagnosis.</p>
<p>&quot;For me, at the moment, I cannot imagine giving up soccer,&quot; he said. &quot;I'll fight to the end before giving up.&quot;</p>
<p>Cardiologists said on Monday that tests had shown that the Nigerian had a &quot;valvular insufficiency of the aorta&quot; and said that in their opinion he could not play again.</p>
<p>Italian newspapers praised Inter for taking a stance that may have saved Kanu's life. But they criticised his Dutch former club Ajax for failing to notice the condition before he transferred to Milan during the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;Ajax Shame,&quot; declared the Gazzetta dello Sport, quoting leading cardiologist Bruno Caru as saying that he found it hard to believe that the club had not known.</p>
<p>But Inter president Massimo Moratti told Italian television on Wednesday that he believed Ajax were too big a club to have deliberately misled the Italians.</p>
<p>Milan's Dutch defender Michael Reiziger, himself signed from Ajax over the summer, said Dutch clubs had a very different approach to Italian clubs over medical tests.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the player who takes responsibility for his physical condition, not the club,&quot; he explained. &quot;I had various tests but nothing like the ones I had when I came here.&quot;</p>
<p>Kanu, who twice won the European Cup with Ajax and whose skills helped Nigeria to win the Olympic soccer gold medal in Atlanta, said it was hard to describe the nightmare he had gone through since his problem was diagnosed.</p>
<p>&quot;I only hope that those who support me -- the media, the fans -- will understand that if I don't want to appear in public it's because before I say anything I want to have a clear picture of my future,&quot; the player explained.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
