<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31399" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-GRAF'S FATHER GOES ON TRIAL FOR TAX EVASION.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-GRAF'S FATHER GOES ON TRIAL FOR TAX EVASION.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>World number one Steffi Graf's father and adviser Peter Graf goes on trial for tax evasion in the southwest German town of Mannheim on Thursday, facing a possible 10-year prison sentence if convicted.</p>
<p>Peter Graf, 58, and family tax adviser Joachim Eckardt have been charged with evading taxes totalling 19 million marks ($13 million) -- just under half Steffi Graf's earnings between 1989 and 1993.</p>
<p>The pressure is by no means off the player herself, hoping to clinch her 21st career Grand Slam title in New York.</p>
<p>The world number one is herself still under investigation in the affair and has been questioned several times. Eckardt's lawyer said on Tuesday he would call her as a defence witness.</p>
<p>Germany's top sporting darling has displayed astonishing nerves on court, winning three Grand Slam titles in the 13 months since her father was taken into custody.</p>
<p>But she has often been reduced to tears by intense media pressure in the last 18 months. Last week she said she thought about skipping a U.S. Open title defence in New York because of the trial.</p>
<p>&quot;I was afraid that my thoughts would keep straying away from the tournament out of fear of the press and the way the public would react to the trial,&quot; she told the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung.</p>
<p>&quot;But now I was have been able to share my worries with others and that helped me to feel freer.&quot;</p>
<p>It is a feeling her father has not had for more than a year.</p>
<p>Taken into custody on August 2, 1995 because prosecutors feared he would flee the country or distort evidence, Peter Graf is said to be in poor health.</p>
<p>The man who went from used car salesman to Germany's best-known jet-setter, accompanying Steffi to tournaments around the world, now faces a charge sheet running to 237 pages.</p>
<p>Exacerbating the humiliation for him has been a deluge of media reports detailing his alleged weaknesses for alcohol, pills and women.</p>
<p>&quot;Father Graf and his Dark Secrets&quot; read the banner headline on Tuesday's Bild newspaper, the country's best-selling tabloid, over a report that said Peter Graf's own lawyers may blame the alleged tax evasion on his dependence on alcohol and pills.</p>
<p>Steffi Graf, whom her father began coaching when she was just four, says she made her father responsible for her financial affairs from the start of her career and took little interest in her own income.</p>
<p>Prosecutors say they have no reason to detain her and also have no plans to call her as a witness for the trial, expected to be spread over 30 court dates through the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Attorneys for Eckardt, who has been in jail since September 1995, criticise the prosecution for its decision not to put Steffi in the stand, and say a fair trial is inconceivable without her testimony.</p>
<p>&quot;It is obvious in a tax case that the taxpayer needs to be questioned and that is Steffi Graf in this instance,&quot; Friedrich Schultehinrichs, one of Eckardt's attorneys, told the Bonner Rundschau daily. &quot;She played a part and needs to be questioned.&quot;</p>
<p>Ironically, Graf is one of the few top-earning German sports stars not to have fled abroad from Germany's high taxes.</p>
<p>She and her father could have been spared the humiliation had they followed fellow tennis star Boris Becker or racing driver Michael Schumacher to Monaco or Switzerland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
