<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31398" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: CYCLING-SPANISH PAPER SAYS INDURAIN READY TO RETIRE.</title>
<headline>CYCLING-SPANISH PAPER SAYS INDURAIN READY TO RETIRE.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five times Tour de France champion Miguel Indurain may retire this year according to sources close to his Banesto team, the sports daily As reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Indurain, 32, whose contract expires in December, failed to record a sixth successive win in the Tour this year but won gold in the Atlanta Olympics time trial.</p>
<p>&quot;Miguel Indurain is determined to give up cycling this winter,&quot; As said. &quot;According to sources close to the Banesto team, Indurain has already shared his decision with close friends.</p>
<p>&quot;Although they are trying to convince him against it, the announcement could be made public in a few days.&quot;</p>
<p>A Banesto spokesman said it was too soon to comment on Indurain's future but his manager Francis Lafargue said he would not compete for another season just for the money.</p>
<p>&quot;Miguel is a honest man. His engine is as powerful as ever and he is only 32 years old,&quot; Lafargue told the French Sud-Ouest newspaper. &quot;But if he feels he can no longer be his former self, he won't do one more season just for the money.&quot;</p>
<p>The Banesto spokesman said: &quot;We are focusing on the Tour of Spain and when the moment comes to renew the contract we will see.&quot;</p>
<p>Last month Indurain said he was not keen to race in the three-week Tour starting in Valencia on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't particularly want to do it but the team decides,&quot; he said. &quot;Physically I am well but mentally I'm not.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
