<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31409" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FUND SQUEEZE PROMPTS NEW SAFRICA TRANSPORT PLANS.</title>
<headline>FUND SQUEEZE PROMPTS NEW SAFRICA TRANSPORT PLANS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Limited budgets were forcing the South African Transport Department to consider innovative ways of ensuring safety at sea, patrolling the coast and keeping roads repaired.</p>
<p>Director-General Ketso Gordhan told the parliamentary public accounts committee on Wednesday that this included setting up agencies controlled by government but run by the private sector and the pooling of the resources of several government deparments.</p>
<p>Gordhan said that because of the low salaries he could offer ship surveyor's, &quot;we currently survey about four percent of the ships that enter our waters.</p>
<p>&quot;The international average that is regarded as a healthy percentage is 25 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As a result, his department was investigating the establishment of a Maritime Safety Agency which would be government controlled but run by the private sector.</p>
<p>&quot;It will have to operate mainly on a user charge principle with some element of a grant from the government,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The report on the feasibility of the agency would be completed by April 1997 and it would then be put to government.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that is the only channel available to use if we want to ensure safety at sea in South African waters,&quot; Gordhan said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the current trend continues we could end up with one or two very expensive disasters costing a lot more than improved salaries for surveyors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A similar approach was being considered to maintain and develop the national road network with the establishment of a National Roads Agency that would be controlled by users and funded through a dedicated fuel levy of six cents a litre compared to the present four cents.</p>
<p>He envisaged that the agency should be established by April 1998.</p>
<p>Asked what progress there had been in establishing a South African coastguard, Gordhan said that he had earlier this year convened a meeting between the Navy, the police water division and the departments of environment affairs and transport.</p>
<p>They had agreed to work on a joint proposal for a coast guard, which would not be an independent entity but a co-operative venture using their joint resources.</p>
<p>Given government's limited resources, this was seen as the best solution as it would be &quot;prohibitively expensive&quot; to equip a conventional coastguard to patrol South Africa's long coastline.</p>
<p>-- Parliamnetary office +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
