<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31406" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: ANGLO UNHAPPY AT ZAMBIA'S ZCCM PLANS.</title>
<headline>ANGLO UNHAPPY AT ZAMBIA'S ZCCM PLANS.</headline>
<byline>Jowie Mwiinga</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo American Corp, the minority shareholder in Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines Ltd (ZCCM), was unhappy with the Zambian government's privatisation plans which would see the mining concern split up into separate units, an Anglo spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Anglo's Lusaka representative, Anderson Mazoka, told Reuters the South African mining giant did not want the company split up into four tranches before it was sold off by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;If we had a choice, we would have done it differently but the Zambian government -- who are the main shareholders -- want to split up the company,&quot; Mazoka said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken a position on the demerits of splitting up the company,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Zambia's Privatisation Agency said last week bidding for ZCCM's assets up for sale would start on February 28, 1997.</p>
<p>The government intended to sell ZCCM's assets in four tranches, with the Konkola mine and concentrator, and the Mufulira mine, concentrator, smelter and refinery forming one package.</p>
<p>The Nchanga mines, tailings leach plant and concentrator, the Nkana mines, concentrator, smelter and cobalt plant would make up a second package.</p>
<p>The Baluba and Luanshya mines and concentrator, the decommissioned Luanshya smelter, Ndola refinery and the Chambishi cobalt plant would make up a third package.</p>
<p>ZCCM's power transmission, distribution and generation assets would make a fourth package.</p>
<p>Anglo has pre-emptive rights in the purchase of ZCCM's assets.</p>
<p>Zambia's state-owned Financial Mail reported on Wednesday that Anglo had objected to the sale of the power generation assets as a separate unit.</p>
<p>Mazoka said Anglo was continuing its negotiations on the development of Konkola Deep mine with the Zambian government.</p>
<p>&quot;The negotiations for Konkola Deep are definitely in progress,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Anglo hopes to lead a consortium, which includes South Africa's Gencor Ltd , to develop Konkola Deep.</p>
<p>Developing the 350 million tonnes Konkola Deep ore body is seen as crucial to the future of Zambia's copper mining industry.</p>
<p>Zambia produced around 380,000 tonnes of copper last year, making it the world's seventh largest producer. The government said in June it expected copper output to treble following privatisation.</p>
<p>-- Lusaka office, +2601 222689</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
