<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31405" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: TWO S.AFRICAN BUSINESS BODIES IN CO-OPERATION DEAL.</title>
<headline>TWO S.AFRICAN BUSINESS BODIES IN CO-OPERATION DEAL.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's mainly white Afrikaans and black business chambers on Wednesday signed a co-operation agreement to work as a single body.</p>
<p>In a joint statement, the presidents of the two bodies -- the National African Federated Chamber of Commerce (Nafcoc) and the Afrikaanse Handelsinstituut (AHI) -- pledged to develop policies and lobby government to promote the economic interests of their members and of the country.</p>
<p>Under the agreement the two bodies would share resources and promote joint ventures to ensure the empowerment and development of mainly black entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>Nafcoc president Joe Hlongwane said although the agreement could be seen as a &quot;building block&quot; for black business, the move should not be seen as a merger.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't think we are going to merge. Not yet. We will cooperate on all issues of business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mof Terreblanche, AHI president, said: &quot;AHI must get partners and get the economy moving. We must show the outside world that we can work together because that will be best for South Africa&quot;.</p>
<p>The agreement came after the two organisations met in August this year where they received the mandate to go ahead with the partnership intiative.</p>
<p>After a joint council meeting on February 13, 1997, where views would be shared on prospects for the economy, labour market and policy environment, the first conference of both groups' members would be held in September next year.</p>
<p>Nafcoc represents about 100,000 members, while AHI has 20 of South Africa's largest corporations in its fold and includes 120 business chambers across the country.</p>
<p>-- Durban newsroom, +27 31 307-1877</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
