<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31403" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN FINANCE COMMISSION SEES SPENDING CUTS.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN FINANCE COMMISSION SEES SPENDING CUTS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African spending on a range of items would have to drop 4.7 percent in real terms in 1997/98 partly because of over-ambitious budget deficit targets, the country's Financial and Fiscal Commission (FFC) said on Wednesay.</p>
<p>FFC director Pundy Pillay, addressing a parliamentary finance and public accounts committee, also criticised government agencies for hiding financial data.</p>
<p>He said his estimates on government revenue and spending were based on calculations made by the commission, which is mandated to decide how national spending is split between the provinces.</p>
<p>Pillay said the FFC predicted total tax revenue and borrowings would decline 1.4 percent on 1996/97 figures.</p>
<p>He said 33 percent of total government expenditure of about 185 billion rand would be swallowed up by items like debt servicing and improved pay and conditions for the civil service.</p>
<p>What was left would be split between national spending and provincial spending, but the size of the 33 percent &quot;top slice&quot; meant these budgets would suffer.</p>
<p>&quot;Our figures show that excluding the top slice, national and provincial spending together will have to decline 4.7 percent in real terms,&quot; Pillay said. &quot;National spending will drop 17 percent in real terms and provincial spending will decline 6.7 percnt.&quot;</p>
<p>This had serious implications for such programmes as defence, the provision of running water to deprived communities, education, health services and the fight against crime, Pillay said.</p>
<p>He said it was extremely difficult to obtain spending figures from the government.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to be a case of not wanting people to know, there is a lack of transparency,&quot; Pillay said. &quot;I can't emphasise enough how hard it is to work with a state agency that is either incompetent or obstructive, or both.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there was a lack of clarity about plans to improve conditions in the civil service.</p>
<p>&quot;This was to have been paid for out of the downsizing of the public service. The service hasn't been downsized, but wages have increased anyway,&quot; Pillay said.</p>
<p>He said the FFC objected to the speed at which the government's macro-economic strategy, unveiled in June, planned to reduce the budget deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to slow it down. We think the deficit should be cut by half a percentage point per annum,&quot; Pillay said.</p>
<p>-- Anton Ferreira, Cape Town newsroom, +2721 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
