<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31408" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICAN BLACK BUSINESS SEEKS PRIVATISATION BOOST.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICAN BLACK BUSINESS SEEKS PRIVATISATION BOOST.</headline>
<byline>Paul Richardson</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fresh from winning control of conglomerate Johnnic , black South African businessmen are looking at ways to increase black power in the corporate mainstream -- among them through privatisation.</p>
<p>The National Empowerment Consortium (NEC), grouping several trade union interests and black-owned businesses, recently took over Johnnic in the largest corporate acquisition yet by black South African investors.</p>
<p>Cyril Ramaphosa, a leader in the takeover talks, says privatisation of state assets could enhance black interests.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you will find that many black companies will be very keen to look at opportunities that will be available through privatisation. It offers a good chance for enhancing the whole process of black economic empowerment,'' he said in an interview.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa, a former leader of the ruling African National Congress and the National Union of Mineworkers, was given much of the credit for South Africa's transition to democracy.</p>
<p>Now he is deputy chairman of New Africa Investments Ltd (Nail), an investment holding company owned by Corporate Africa Ltd with interests in the media and life assurance.</p>
<p>Analysts also believe that as preferential partners in programmes to improve their lives after four decades of racial oppression, black-led firms have a chance of winning good deals.</p>
<p>Nail is in a consortium bidding for one of several radio stations being sold by the state broadcasting corporation, but Ramaphosa would not be drawn on other possible future interests.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at a whole range of things... Some of them are good business, the radio stations, the smaller airlines,'' he said. &quot;But sometimes it is good to do things quietly...''</p>
<p>The government's privatisation process, which has come under fire from trade unions, is expected to start in March with the sale of a stake in the state telecommunications utility Telkom.</p>
<p>Nail chairman Nthato Motlana said in the company's annual report that this is one area of interest.</p>
<p>Other black companies are also eyeing Anglo American Corp of South Africa's 47.4 percent stake in mining company JCI Ltd.</p>
<p>Anglo, the country's largest company, has said it intends to split off JCI and finance director Michael King said five black-led groups had separately expressed interest: Nail, Real Africa Investments Ltd , African Renaissance, Thebe Investments and Capital Alliance.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa said blacks would have a meaningful stake in the economy when they control over 30 percent of the Johannesburg Stock Exchange's capitalisation, which could take 10 years.</p>
<p>The acquisition of Johnnic gives the NEC roughly 10 percent of JSE market capitalisation.</p>
<p>Ramaphosa dismissed suggestions that the potentially volatile mix of unions and business might lead to disunity in the NEC, harming Johnnic and possibly future ventures.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they will be able to maintain cohesion because once everyone has put money on the table, the commonality of interest begins to converge.''</p>
<p>He declined to say how the NEC partners would pay for their share of Johnnic or who the main shareholders would be. NEC plans to secure funding from pension and provident funds, institutions and from its own funds.</p>
<p>The NEC would hold Johnnic's chairmanship, but Ramaphosa would not say who would control the management.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
