<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31414" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - SEPT 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SOUTH AFRICA - SEPT 4.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- South African fuel prices are likely to rise in early October after the U.S. strike against Iraq put pressure on oil prices.</p>
<p>- Grinaker Holdings overcame competitive pressures to post a 24 percent increase in earnings before exceptionals in the year to June.</p>
<p>- The Automobile Manufacturers Employers' Organisation, the National Union of Metalworkers of SA and the SA Workers' Union on Tuesday signed an agreement for a 8.5 percent wage increase.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Randgold and Exploration Co Ltd has consoldiated its West African foothold by buying BHP Holdings Inc's Mali operations, including control of the Syama gold mine.</p>
<p>- Standard Bank Corp signed a 10-year agreement worth more than one billion rand with EDS to outsource a large portion of its card division activities in the biggest deal of its kind in South Africa.</p>
<p>- Fraud at petrol pumps in South Africa could be worth a hefty 3.5 billion rand a year and ranks second to armed robbery in terms of serious economic crime.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- A South African National Defence Force member was among four people arrested on Tuesday in connection with the murder of former footballer Eliakim &quot;Pro&quot; Khumalo during a car hijacking.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
