<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31417" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - BULGARIA - SEPT 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - BULGARIA - SEPT 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- A Bulgarian chartered aircraft with 150 passengers and eight-member crew on a flight from Beirut to Varna was hijacked on Tuesday afternoon by a Palestine terrorist 10 minutes before landing. The passangers were released at the Varna airport.</p>
<p>The terrorist demanded a passage to Oslo but after negotiations with the pilot he agreed to land in Varna and release the passangers. After refueling the plane took off for Oslo at 18:08 local time.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's air traffic controllers said they postponed a planned one-hour warning strike on Tuesday due to the hijack of the Bulgarian plane.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Socialist party nominated late last night the culture minister Ivan Marazov and deputy foreign minister Irina Bokova as the party's new candidates for the presidential elections due on October 27.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court blocked on Monday the presidential candidacy of the party's initial nominee Georgi Pirinski because he was born in the U.S.</p>
<p>-- Japan has said it could extend a $300 million credit for upgrading of Bulgaria's largest oil refinery Neftohim but details of the deal are yet to be negotiated, Industry Minister Lyubomir Dachev said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's August monthly inflation is expected around 15 percent and cumulative inflation for the first eight months about 109.1 percent, National Statistics Institute preliminary data shows.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet doubled tobacco's minimum purchasing prices in a bid to stimulate producers, cabinet official said.</p>
<p>-- The Privatisation Agency is expected to approve today the sale of 75 percent stake in the debt-ridden Plama oil refinery, initially slated for liquidation, to Bulgaria's Euroenergy holding.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet approved the sale of 67 percent of the five-star Sheraton Sofia Hotel Balkan to the South Korea's giant Daewoo Corp for $22.3 million in cash.</p>
<p>The cabinet also approved the sale of 55 percent of the Lovech-based Eltos electric tool maker to the Germany's Sparky Trading GmbH for 11.5 million German marks.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- The Supreme court is expected to overrule today the Central Electoral Commission's decision to refuse registration to the main anti-communist opposition nominees for country's presidential elections.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria is expected to launch by mid-September a scheme for bank privatisation, central bankers told International Monetary Fund's mission leader Ann McGuirk.</p>
<p>-- The International Monetary Fund will extend to Bulgaria the next $115 million tranche under a funding agreement signed in July only if the cabinet's structural reform programme is fully implemented, Ann McGuirk said. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
