<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31412" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA AG URGES BETTER MANAGEMENT OF CONSULTANTS.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA AG URGES BETTER MANAGEMENT OF CONSULTANTS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Auditor-General Henri Kleuver on Wednesday strongly criticised the increasing reliance by government on overpaid consultants who were not properly managed.</p>
<p>In a special report tabled in Parliament, Kleuver suggested a wide range of measures that should be taken to ensure the economic, efficient and effective use of consultants.</p>
<p>He and his office's corporate executive manager Louis van Rooyen told the public accounts committee they could not yet quantify the amount of money that had been spent on consultants, but wanted to alert government to the dangers involved.</p>
<p>The committee commissioned the report in 1992 and Van Rooyen said the problem with consultants was clearly illustrated earlier this year when Mpumalanga province reported that it had paid two consultants 15,000 rand a day.</p>
<p>&quot;The extent to which consultants are made use of in the public sector could not be determined cost-effectively during the audit,&quot; Van Rooyen said.</p>
<p>He said this was because government departments did not budget for consultants separately and there was no clear definition of what consultants did.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear, however, that the annual amount paid by government...in respect of consultancy services is very significant,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In some cases, consultants were appointed on a permanent basis, but on better conditions of service than permanent staff. The South African Defence Force, for example, had paid out 127 million rand extra in this way in 1994/95 to the Atlas Aircraft Corporation.</p>
<p>The conditions of service of consultants were also not always clearly stated in their contracts and their services were not always properly controlled or their services properly used.</p>
<p>The services of some consultants were duplicated in several provinces. For example, two provinces paid the same consultant more than two million rand each to implement a management system for a hospital under their control.</p>
<p>Kleuver recommended that clearer guidelines and policies on the employment of consultants should be adopted and that departmental accounting officers be made responsible for ensuring that they were implemented.</p>
<p>Ironically, many departments have employed consultants because they could not offer attractive enough salary packages to retain skilled staff.</p>
<p>Committee members said that the government should insist that when consultants were employed, they should help train existing staff to build up skills levels.</p>
<p>The Director-General of State Expenditure Hannes Smit told the committee that he had also received approval to advertise the full packages attached to senior posts, which would make them more attractive. At present, only salary grades are advertised.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom, +27 21 252-238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
