<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31410" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE DOLLAR ENDS FIRMER ON MOST KEY UNITS.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE DOLLAR ENDS FIRMER ON MOST KEY UNITS.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Zimbabwe dollar registered gains on most key units on Wednesday largely on the back of export inflows which provided relief from more than two weeks of battering due to import pressure, dealers said.</p>
<p>A meeting between commercial banks and the central bank had resolved to bring runaway spreads of about ten points gradually back to the normal two points, also lending stability to the market, dealers added.</p>
<p>&quot;Basically we saw some good two-way interbank trade today and we had some big receipts from customers. I think we might be back to normal spreads by tomorrow (Thursday),&quot; one dealer commented.</p>
<p>Dealers disclaimed any link between the local currency's previous woes and a fortnight-long strike by civil servants pressing for salary increments. One explained the co-incidence between the unit's recovery and government's decision on Tuesday to reinstate employees fired for defying a call to return to work as &quot;purely accidental&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The strike had no impact on our market which is mainly driven by the demand and supply of foreign currency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At Wednesday's close, the Zimbabwe unit was quoted firmer on the U.S. dollar at 10.2000/2700 from 10.2200/3000 but was easier against sterling at 15.9790/16.0775 compared to 15.9700/16.1320 the previous day.</p>
<p>It edged up to 6.8700/9120 from 6.8760/9450 against the mark and to 2.2720/2870 against South Africa's rand from 2.2770/3010. --Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
