<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31416" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - SEPT 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - POLAND - SEPT 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights from Polish newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>RZECZPOSPOLITA</p>
<p>- A Polish MIG 21 jet fighter aircraft crashed near Malbork, Elblag province. The pilot ejected and survived.</p>
<p>- Pork prices have grown from 2.7 zlotys a kg at the start of June to 3.5 zlotys and will reach four zlotys by the end of 1996, some experts say. This is due to higher grain prices.</p>
<p>- Poland's Kredyt Bank (KB) has applied to the Lithuania's central bank to open a branch there, KB's president Stanislaw Pacuk said. KB has representative offices in Vilnius and Kaliningrad and a 13.3 percent stake in the Ukrainian Kiev International Bank.</p>
<p>- An August report by the Economic Development Institute of the Warsaw School of Economics said Polish firms have reported increased output, growing domestic and foreign orders and an improved general financial condition. But industrial capacity utilization was not much higher than in July and salaries grew by five points in August.</p>
<p>- The BALTEPXO '96 marine economy exhibition has begun in Gdansk. Foreign ship industry firms take up half the stands.</p>
<p>- Poland's Anti-monopoly Office suspects a trust agreement among the country's coal producers following a recently announced coal price raise and will examine the issue, it said.</p>
<p>- Daewoo Heavy Industries will buy a 13 percent stake in the Andoria SA diesel engine plant from the National Investmet Fund (NFI) 13. By end-1995 Andoria's assets were worth 86.67 million zlotys and annual net profit was 894,300 zlotys.</p>
<p>NOWA EUROPA</p>
<p>- Poland's Constitutional Tribunal agreed with the Ombudsman's statement that the National Investment Fund scheme discriminates against citizens without permanent residences.</p>
<p>- The opposition Union for Freedom (UW) accused the ruling ex-communist coalition of taking over public television. The coalition wants to use the public media in the coming parliamentary elections, UW spokesman Andrzej Potocki said.</p>
<p>- South Korea's LG Group will hold a development strategy meeting in Warsaw to discuss its future operations in Central and Eastern Europe, an LG Group representative said.</p>
<p>- The listed BIG bank and Elektrim foreign trade company closed flat in Warsaw bourse continuous trade on Tuesday in a turnover of 73,000 zlotys down from 79,800 zlotys on Monday.</p>
<p>GAZETA WYBORCZA</p>
<p>- Katowice-based Kolmex foreign trade company and Malaysian Darian Motors signed a letter of intent for purchasing Polish-type rolling stock production licence. Malaysia wants to invest $100 million in the rolling stock venture.</p>
<p>- The European Rubber Journal said Poland's Stomil and Debica are among the world's 30 biggest tyre makers.</p>
<p>- More than 12 motor industry firms have obtained car part import permits from the government, foreign trade ministry representatives said.</p>
<p>- James Capel brokerage house analysts recommend holding BFK cable maker's shares, despite their present high price, as they expect boom in the cable industry.</p>
<p>ZYCIE WARSZAWY</p>
<p>- Poland's Central Statistical Office (GUS) data showed that real per capita income grew by seven percentage points in the first half of 1996 compared with the same period last year.</p>
<p>- Poland's milk consumption has declined by 30 percent in the last six years and keeps falling, maybe because pasteurised milk quality has been so low for so long that Poles distrust it, Warsaw School of Agriculturer researcher Antoni Pluta said.</p>
<p>PARKIET</p>
<p>- Dutch firm Kema International B.V. has granted the International Standards Organisation (ISO) 9002 quality certificate to the listed ZML Kety light metals maker. The certificate will hopefully increase the Polish firm's orders, ZML deputy president Jan Kryjak said.</p>
<p>- The listed Exbud construction firm's Warsaw branch will build houses for Warsaw's Radarowa housing cooperative. The contract is worth 27 million zlotys and will be carried out over the next two years.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
