<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31422" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH GOV'T SENDS MINISTERS TO PROBE BANK FAILURE.</title>
<headline>CZECH GOV'T SENDS MINISTERS TO PROBE BANK FAILURE.</headline>
<byline>Jan Lopatka</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech government on Wednesday directed three of its ministers to oversee an investigation into the failure of the bank Kreditni Banka a.s., Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus said.</p>
<p>The move comes after the press and opposition questioned official banking oversight in the case of the Plzen-based bank which was shut by the central bank last month after reportedly losing about 12 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Klaus told a news conference after a cabinet meeting that Czech National Bank (CNB) Governor Josef Tosovsky would join Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik, Justice Minister Jan Kalvoda, and Interior Minister Jan Ruml in overseeing the probe.</p>
<p>&quot;Bearing in mind the extraordinary importance of this matter, the govenrnment authorised the group of three ministers to specially inquire into this issue, using all existing standard mechanisms,&quot; Klaus said.</p>
<p>He said authorities have been investigating the Kreditni case since the central bank rescinded its licence in August.</p>
<p>Findings from the investigation might lead to changes in Czech legislation, Klaus said.</p>
<p>Local media reports have placed the blame for the failure of Kreditni Banka, majority owned by the largest Czech insurer Ceska Pojistovna a.s. , on a series of murky loans made to interests connected to shareholders.</p>
<p>The leader of the opposition Social Democrats, Milos Zeman, last weekend blamed Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik and his ministry for lax supervision of the banks.</p>
<p>After Klaus's announcement, the central bank issued a statement on Wednesday, saying it welcomed the group of ministers looking at whether there was any criminal actions involved in Kreditni's failure.</p>
<p>It said combining the investigatory organs with, tax, legal, banking oversight, and capital market authorities, would help in &quot;uncovering illegal activity&quot; and determining its punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;The CNB believes that through this work it will be possible to solve other cases as well in which the banking supervision has submitted a number of criminal reports on the basis of its knowledge gained in other banks,&quot; the central bank's statement said.</p>
<p>Eleven banks have fallen under CNB authority since the liberalisation of the sector began in earnest in 1992.</p>
<p>Klaus attributed the failures of the banks -- all of them small or medium sized -- to growing pains in the still-transforming post-Communist Czech economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I am 100 percent persuaded that the dominant cause of these phenomenona... is the difficulity, fragility, complexity of banking in the transformation phase,&quot; Klaus said.</p>
<p>Klaus, in numerous previous speeches has declared that the &quot;transformation phase&quot; was over and the economy was &quot;in the fitness centre building muscle&quot;.</p>
<p>But Klaus has been under pressure by opposition deputies who have demanded answers on the banking failures.</p>
<p>&quot;The government condemns the way of politicising of this important situation by the opposition, which could intendidly or not, lead to the destabilisation of the the whole banking system,&quot; Klaus said.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
