<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31421" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND SACKS FOREIGN TRADE MINISTER BUCHACZ.</title>
<headline>POLAND SACKS FOREIGN TRADE MINISTER BUCHACZ.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's president sacked Foreign Trade Minister Jacek Buchacz on Wednesday after inspections revealed a problem over the granting of export guarantees, the government information office said in a statement.</p>
<p>It said Buchacz was fired by President Aleksander Kwasniewski on a motion by Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz.</p>
<p>&quot;The motion of the head of cabinet in this matter is linked with a need to guarantee better care over the interests of the state treasury,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Buchacz is a member of the Polish Peasant Party (PSL) smaller partner in a tense two-party ruling coalition with the ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD), to which Cimoszewicz belongs.</p>
<p>Heads of the two parties gathered for a crisis meeting after the announcement at a Warsaw government building, but PAP news agency said the Peasant delegation quickly left the meeting.</p>
<p>The statement said the sacking of Buchacz was closely related to results of inspections by the Supreme Auditing Chamber (NIK) and the Cabinet Supervision Office -- two powerful official oversight bodies.</p>
<p>It said the probes concerned &quot;the involvement of the treasury in ventures concerning export guarantees, in which state and private property is connected in a way that lacks sufficient clarity.&quot;</p>
<p>The PSL and the SLD have recently clashed over the distribution of cabinet posts during a reorganisation of central government due this year, but had appeared to settle their differences.</p>
<p>An official source, who asked not to be named, told Reuters that Cimoszewicz had surprised the Peasant party with the motion to oust Buchacz.</p>
<p>The move looked set to place new strains on the coalition -- which has been trying to stay together at least until parliamentary elections due in September next year.</p>
<p>Buchacz has been foreign trade minister for since early 1995. He was appointed by the previous Prime Minister Jozef Oleksy and inherited the portfolio in the current cabinet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
