<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31435" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA SOCIALISTS NAME NEW PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA SOCIALISTS NAME NEW PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's ruling Socialists named current culture minister Ivan Marazov as their new bid in the October 27 elections after the Supreme Court blocked the candidacy of Georgi Pirinski two days ago, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Art historian Marazov started the campaign with Pirinski as his vice-presidential candidate. Marazov, 54, was nominated during a night meeting of the Bulgarian Socialist Party (BSP) high council, composed largely of former communists.</p>
<p>&quot;Marazov seemed an appropriate choice as he is already familiar to our supporters from the election campaign with Pirinski, which started last month,&quot; said a BSP pressofficer.</p>
<p>Marazov will be flanked by deputy foreign minister Irina Bokova as vice-presidential nominee. Bokova was responsible for relations with the European Union.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's Supreme Court on Monday blocked the presidential candidacy of Socialist Georgi Pirinski on the grounds that he was born and spent his early childhood in the United States.</p>
<p>Pirinski, current foreign minister, was born in New York in 1948 of a Bulgarian father and American mother. His family moved in the mid-1950s to Bulgaria where Pirinski made a career in the old ruling communist party.</p>
<p>But the Bulgarian Supreme Court upheld a ruling by the Central Electoral Commission (CEC) that Pirinski, who has a Bulgarian passport, be disqualified from the presidential race because he was not born in Bulgaria.</p>
<p>The constitutional court ruled in July that the country's president must be a Bulgarian citizen by birth.</p>
<p>BSP officials had believed the father's nationality would be sufficient to determine Pirinski junior was also a Bulgarian.</p>
<p>&quot;Marazov is a reasonable choice. I will do my best to contribute to the BSP presidential campaign,&quot; Pirinski told reporters.</p>
<p>Presidential candidates can submit papers and amendments to their applications in CEC until September 22.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court is expected to rule later on Wednesday on CEC's refusal to register the presidential candidate of the anti-communist opposition because of legal inconsistencies.</p>
<p>Petar Stoyanov, a lawyer who beat incumbent President Zhelyu Zhelev in Europe's first primary election in June, has had difficulties in having his application papers signed after one of the opposition coalition of parties backing him, sacked its leader.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
