<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31448" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: NEW DEMOCRACY'S MANOS BLASTS GOVT ON PROCUREMENT CONTRACTS.</title>
<headline>NEW DEMOCRACY'S MANOS BLASTS GOVT ON PROCUREMENT CONTRACTS.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former National Economy Minister and conservative MP Stephanos Manos, blasted what he called the socialist government's pressure on OTE telecom to sign long term procurement contracts for its digital networks.</p>
<p>Development Minister Vasso Papandreou said on Wednesday the socialist government would go ahead and pass legislation for long term procurement contracts with Greek firms.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not alone in the battle against corruption. I am joined by the New Democracy party and thousands of OTE shareholders who have incurred losses on their shares because of PASOK policies,&quot; he said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Earlier Papandreou had criticised Manos for favouring international tenders for public procurements during a visit to OTE headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;How about the millions of OTE's clients pay who end up paying dearly for its services because OTE buys expensive ...(communications equipment). We know OTE pays 30 percent higher prices for digital procurements,&quot; Manos said.</p>
<p>Greek prosecutors have laid charges against unknown individuals for bribery and other criminal and misdemeanor acts in connection with a 1994 digital switches deal between OTE and telecoms manufacturers Intracom and Siemens Hellas.</p>
<p>OTE is weighing whether to call an international digital switches procurement tender or exercise an option in the 1994 contract to get 300,000 switches from its two main suppliers. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
