<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31458" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNLINES SEES IMPORTS HELPING PROFITS.</title>
<headline>FINNLINES SEES IMPORTS HELPING PROFITS.</headline>
<byline>Ilkka Virtanen</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish cargo shipping company Finnlines Oy said on Wednesday it can maintain its profits in 1996 as increasing imports and transit cargo to Russia will offset a negative result impact caused by a slump in exports.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is now better than during the period of strong growth in exports in 1992 and 1993 as the balance of our business has improved,&quot; Finnlines president and CEO Antti Lagerroos told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;In the shipping business we must always watch not only exports but also imports and the balance between the two.&quot;</p>
<p>Lagerroos repeated the forecast given by the company in June, which said the full-year 1996 profits were expected to match a 315 million markka profit before extraordinaries in 1995, &quot;barring any significant changes in the group's business environment&quot;.</p>
<p>In January-April, Finnlines' profit before extraordinaries and taxes was 217 million markka, up from 103 million markka in the first tertial last year.</p>
<p>Lagerroos said the recent favourable development on the home market would boost shipments of import cargos.</p>
<p>&quot;Households' purchasing power has increased and they are more willing to buy durable goods, for example cars. This is good news for us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>According to the Board of Navigation, Finnish January-July imports through ports fell to 19.5 million tonnes from 20.4 million in the first seven months in 1995, and exports fell to 18.9 million tonnes from 20.7 million.</p>
<p>Some 80 percent of total Finnish foreign trade go through ports.</p>
<p>Transit transports through Finland to Russia have also turned back into a rise after a slump ahead of the presidential election in July, Lagerroos said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outcome (Yeltsin's victory) of the election was an encouraging signal for cargo flows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was very difficult to forecast how exports of Finland's major export product, paper, would develop this autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;A slight recovery may probably be seen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked about growth prospects, Lagerroos did not rule out acquisitions as Finnlines has a lot of financial room to manoeuver after steady growth in profits since 1990.</p>
<p>He also left the door open for an increase in the company's stake in Bilspedition Transport &amp; Logistics (BTL) from the current 20 percent it acquired last spring.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment we are satisfied with our 20 percent, but there is no reason to rule out any options,&quot; he answered the question whether Finnlines was planning to increase its holding in BTL.</p>
<p>BTL was a valuable strategic holding with a leading position in land cargo in most Baltic Sea countries, Lagerroos said.</p>
<p>Finnlines' 1996 investments will remain below last year's 619 million markka. Thanks to its currently &quot;young&quot; fleet -- an average ship age of seven years -- ther was no immediate need to invest in new ships, he said.</p>
<p>Despite its healthy financial position Finnlines was not planning to diversify from the unit cargo business or to expand its businesses geographically from its main markets in the Baltic Sea and the North Sea, Lagerroos said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not interested in bulk cargo or in tankers, and we are not planning to expand extensively into the passenger ship business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Lagerroos said experience from its combi ro-ro ships launched in 1994, which can carry both freight and some passengers, had been good, and these ships could easily be modified to carry more passengers than the current maximum of 120.</p>
<p>Finnlines will release its January-August results on September 27.</p>
<p>--Helsinki newsroom +358-0-6805 0248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
