<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31468" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - SEPT 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREECE - SEPT 4.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>FINANCIAL KATHEMERINI</p>
<p>-- Unexpected pressure from oil prices. The U.S attack on Iraq sends oil prices higher. The rise of the dollar and oil prices affect inflation adversely</p>
<p>-- Normalcy at Greek money markets</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>-- The Athends bourse is going to propose a draft law for the essential creation of a second parallel market with the Thessaloniki stock exchange as its centre</p>
<p>-- Inflationary pressures are being fed by the Gulf events. A small drop of inflation in August</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>-- The markets want autonomy from politics</p>
<p>-- Premier Simitis says the era of the state-protector is gone</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>-- Secret IMF report about the economy says it is on positive course and urges privatisations to proceed</p>
<p>-- The four private casinos had profits of 80 billion drachmas in the first eight months of 1996</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>-- The current account and inflation are causes for concern. The current account deficit in the first five months of this year is estimated to reach $2.0 billion</p>
<p>-- Greek industrialists are optimistic and forecast an increase of 34 percent in industrial production according to a EU survey conducted last March and April --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
