<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31460" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: ETLA UPS 1997 GDP FORECAST TO 3.5 PCT FROM 2.5 PCT.</title>
<headline>ETLA UPS 1997 GDP FORECAST TO 3.5 PCT FROM 2.5 PCT.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Research Institute of the Finnish Economy (ETLA) rised its forecast for Finnish 1997 gross domestic product growth to 3.5 percent from 2.5 percent forecast in June, ETLA said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>ETLA left its GDP forecast for 1996 unchanged at 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>Its other main forecasts were unchanged too.</p>
<p>&quot;Current information indicates that the EU countries are pulling out of their slump and growth is picking up,&quot; ETLA said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be justified to expect a relatively swift recovery in the economies of the EU countries since unemployment is high, meaning there are idle resources available, inflation pressures are low and monetary policy is expansionary,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But ETLA said the tight fiscal policy stance in the EU could jeopardize economic growth in Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible that fiscal policy will have to be tightened further if it appears that otherwise the criteria for the European economic and monetary union (EMU) will not be fulfilled,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>ETLA forecast the paper industry exports would pick up slightly in the second half of 1996. </p>
<p>It said the overall volume of exports would increase by a few percent in 1996 on 1995. ETLA left its forecasts for exports unchanged at three percent for 1996 and five percent for 1997.</p>
<p>ETLA's jobless rate forecast for 1997 was also unchanged at 16 percent, down from 16.5 percent seen this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though aggregate output will grow faster than last year, the unemployment rate will decline by the same margin as this year,&quot; ETLA said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is because GDP growth will be driven next year more by manufacturing production, where jobs will not be created in the same proportion, it added.</p>
<p>Key figures in ETLA's 1996/2 forecast:</p>
<p>			  1996	 1997	  1995 actual</p>
<p> GDP		    +2.5	 +3.5		+4.2</p>
<p> Exports (goods)	+3	   +5		+7.6</p>
<p> Imports (goods)	+5	   +6		+4.6</p>
<p> Consumption	  +2.5	 +2.5		+3.1</p>
<p>   --private	    +3	   +3		+3.8</p>
<p>   --public	     +2	 +1.5		+1.3</p>
<p> Investment	     +7	   +9		+7.7</p>
<p>   --private	    +7	   +9	     +10.9</p>
<p>    --public	    +5	  +10		-6.1</p>
<p> Industry output	+3.5	 +4		+8.7</p>
<p> CPI			+1	   +2		+1.0</p>
<p> Wage level	     +4	   +3		+4.7</p>
<p> Unemployment	  16.5	  16		17.2</p>
<p> C/A (FIM billion)   N/A	  N/A	     +24.7</p>
<p> C/A, pct of GDP	+4	   +4		 4.5</p>
<p>*Public sector</p>
<p> deficit, pct of GDP 3.3	  2.5		5.2</p>
<p>*Public sector gross</p>
<p>  debt, pct of GDP   63.0	 63.3	    60.0</p>
<p> 3-mth Helibor	 3.5	  3.5		5.8</p>
<p>NOTE - * relevant for third stage of Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), which</p>
<p>Finland wants to join from its scheduled start in 1999.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 0 - 680 50 248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
