<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31486" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - September 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - September 4.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected  Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- U.S. launches second attack on Iraq: Clinton defends missile strikes against Hussein for incursion into northern region of country.</p>
<p>- Witness balks in stowaway case: Filipino sailor tells hearing for accused officers that his family has been threatened. A key witness in the extradition hearing of seven ship's officers accused of murdering Romanian stowaways refused to testify in a Halifax court yesterday.</p>
<p>- U.S. isolation weakens its hand: Resolution used to start action against Iraq vaguely written.</p>
<p>- Universities on trail of private money: With government support shrinking, privatization is a hot postsecondary issue.</p>
<p>- Golf wunderkind attracts fame and fortune: Tiger Woods hasn't won a professional tournament yet, but he has already become a superstar in the world of greens, sponsorships and television.</p>
<p>Report on Business Section:</p>
<p>- Iraq strike spurs oil-price surge: U.S. attack sets stage for buoyant prices, higher profits and royalties for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>- Cancelled contracts cost Ottawa millions: Concern over large computer deals prompts policy to keep within budget.</p>
<p>- Potash Corp building empire: Shareholders set to gain, but farmers worry about prices.</p>
<p>- Computer buyers in New Brunswick granted tax break: Government wants a PC in every home.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- One master seen for brokers: Toronto Stock Exchange wants out of the broker regulation business and the Investment Dealers Association is willing to take it on, perhaps on a national scale.</p>
<p>- Potash Corp's US$1 billion Arcadian buy spurs anxiety, applause.    -- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
