<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31480" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: DBRS maintains Potash Corp under review.</title>
<headline>DBRS maintains Potash Corp under review.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dominion Bond Rating Service said on Wednesday it maintained the under review status of Potash Corp of Saskatchewan, with developing implications, following the company's US$1.2 billion offer to acquire Arcadian Corp.</p>
<p>DBRS said the acquisition is favorable strategically, adding Arcadian's large ammonium-based business to PCS's existing potash and phosphate operations.</p>
<p>The acquisition will make Potash Corp the world's largest fertilizer company, the bond rating service said.  </p>
<p>DBRS said debt related to the acquisition will result in the weakening of the balance sheet in the short to medium term. Total debt added net of Arcadian's US$300 million of cash is expected to be near US$800 million, with the remaining acquisition costs expected to be funded from the issue of Potash Corp common shares.</p>
<p>Post acquisition, relative debt levels are expected to approach 45 percent of capitalization, from a previous level of 35 percent, while interest coverage and cash flow coverage ratios will decline as well, DBRS said.</p>
<p>It said the combination of strong operating results, from healthy demand and pricing for fertilizer, as well as moderate capital expenditure requirements is expected to allow the company to generate substantial free cash for debt repayment.</p>
<p>DBRS said the outlook for the North American farm sector should support reasonable earnings for the company through 1997, although volatility in offshore demand, primarily for potash fertilizer, and the softening of ammonia prices are concerns for the year ahead.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau  (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
