<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31489" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - Nash starts work on back injury.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - Nash starts work on back injury.</headline>
<text>
<p>CHRISTCHURCH, Sept 5 - While his New Zealand team-mates returned home after a squad training session last week, Dion Nash is back at the New Zealand Cricket (NZC) Academy at Lincoln University, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>Nash, 24, is taking the first tentative steps toward a return to the game after being sidelined since April with a back injury.</p>
<p>Nash is working with academy director Dayle Hadlee to overcome a problem which was never clearly pinpointed but forced him out of New Zealand's West Indies tour and the English county season with Middlesex.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are just starting working on a few basics,&quot; said Hadlee yesterday.</p>
<p>&quot;With his bowling, he is just walking then jogging through, taking it very easily. We are having a look at technique comparing his bowling technique today to that when he took 11 wickets in the test at Lord's.&quot;</p>
<p>Nash will spend this week in Christchurch before returning home to his Northern Districts base where he will work on a rehabilitation programme devised by physiotherapist Graham Nuttridge and fitness expert Paul Carpinter.  </p>
<p>Hadlee said Nash will return at regular intervals to monitor his progress.</p>
<p>The aim is for Nash to gradually increase the workload on his body, from bowling 100 balls this week at 25-40 percent pace to 300 a week in six weeks' time at 60-85 percent intensity.</p>
<p>&quot;The person is more important than performance.&quot;</p>
<p>Hadlee said it would be unlikely Nash would be available for the New Zealand team's first tour this season to Sharjah and Pakistan.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will not be rushing him into anything. If he was ahead of schedule he could be available, but we will keep the New Zealand selectors informed.&quot;</p>
<p>Hadlee said Nash was one of the players to represent the future of the game here and had the potential for 10 years at the top.</p>
<p>Nash is not the only player working to overcome injury, with fellow pace bowler Danny Morrison recovering from an off-season groin operation and batsman Blair Pocock getting over a shoulder problem which has troubled him for the past two years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
