<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31492" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ SPORT - Waikato All Blacks change positions.</title>
<headline>NZ SPORT - Waikato All Blacks change positions.</headline>
<text>
<p>HAMILTON, Sept 5 - Waikato's All Blacks Scott McLeod and Matthew Cooper were last night quickly coming to grips with playing positions that in recent weeks have become a little foreign to them, NZPA reports.</p>
<p>McLeod was named at second five-eighths and Cooper at centre in the only changes to the Waikato team that will challenge Taranaki for both the Ranfurly Shield and NPC first-division points at New Plymouth on Sunday.</p>
<p>McLeod takes the place of Aaron Collins while Cooper, who will also take over the goal-kicking, nudges Damien Karauna into the reserves.  </p>
<p>The pair are in positions where they have played the bulk of their games for Waikato but in South Africa Cooper was exclusively a fullback for the mid-week team, after being called over as a replacement for the injured Adrian Cashmore, while McLeod played the last two of his three mid-week games at centre.</p>
<p>Cooper said the change was just part of his career-long yo-yo around various backline positions but added he was looking forward to combining with McLeod in midfield.  </p>
<p>&quot;He was playing at centre and I was at fullback over there (South Africa), so I'm used to being outside him and it will be great to link up with Fossie (first five-eighth Ian Foster) again,&quot; Cooper said.</p>
<p>&quot;I've played enough games now to be used to centre.&quot;</p>
<p>McLeod said it was never easy coming back after so many weeks away from a team, especially as Waikato had formed a good pattern during that period, and he would just try to slot in as smoothly as he could.  </p>
<p>&quot;I really enjoyed playing centre in South Africa because it gave me a little bit more freedom and there are a few more things I can do with the ball there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The last game I had there (at second five-eighth) I didn't play too well against Eastern Province so I'm looking to redeem myself at second-five,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Waikato coach John Boe said he had opted for the two All Blacks to stiffen up the midfield as he had wanted to retain 20-year-old Bruce Reihana at fullback to utilise his tremendous speed coming into the backline.</p>
<p>Taranaki will name their team tonight.  </p>
<p>Waikato: Bruce Reihana, Wayne Warlow, Matthew Cooper, Aisea Tuilevu, Scott McLeod, Ian Foster, Rhys Duggan, Deon Muir, Duane Monkley, Mark Cooksley, Steve Gordon (capt), Scott Miller, Murray Driver, Greg Smith, Michael Collins. Reserves: backs, Damien Karauna, Tommy Hayes, Simon Crabb; forwards, Nick Holten, Tiwini Hemi, Craig Stevenson, Richard Kirke.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
