<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31490" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST -Australian Sports News - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Hawthorn's anti-merger lobby has hit out at accounting firm Price Waterhouse for releasing the details of a study into the planned merger between AFL clubs, the Hawks and the Demons. Head of the anti-merger group Don Scott released his own calculations, estimating A$1.7 million is needed for the Hawks to survive independently. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The outstanding career of Hawthorn defender Andy Collins may have ended prematurely, with the AFL tribunal last night denying him the opportunity to take the field in the play-offs against Sydney this weekend after being found guilty of a striking charge. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The coach of the ARL's Brisbane Broncos, Wayne Bennett, has been forced to add forward Steele Retchless to the finals squad, after doubts increased yesterday over the availability of prop Glenn Lazarus. Page 22.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The much publicised and long-awaited re-match between world tennis champion Pete Sampras and Aussie Mark &quot;the scud&quot; Philippoussis, following the upset in the Australian Open, resulted in the scud missing the mark, 6-3, 6-3, 6-4 at the US Open. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Rugby Union is worried that Australia may lose players to the financially strong European clubs, with all of Australia's Super 12 rugby teams reporting increasing number of foreign offers. The bargaining power of southern hemisphere rugy is handicapped by the SANZAR payment agreements. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Three AAMI rugby clubs - West Harbour, Parramatta, and Penrith - have agreed in principle to form a single &quot;super club&quot; for Sydney's west, again raising the debate over a national club competition for Australian rugby. Page 46.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Carlton is considering a court challenge against the AFL after the league yesterday moved to prevent clubs becoming involved in rival codes such as soccer and rugby. Carlton was planning to field a team in the National Soccer League. Page B8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Alexander Ross has passed away. A private service was held for the European Tourist of 1927, regarded as one of the greatest Wallaby fullbacks of his generation. Ross died peacefully last Friday. Page B7.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Newcastle trainer Darren Smith last night loaded Pimpala Prince on a float bound for Melbourne in light of the continued withdrawal of competitors from Saturday's Ascot Vale Stakes at Flemington. With Paint, Clang and Armidale gone, the gelding from Newcatle may come into the equation. Page B6.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Footscray will go through its biggest shake-up since the AFL club's failed merger with Fitzroy. A new seven-man board is expected to be installed following the appointment of a task force to manage the struggling club. This follows the resignation of chie executive Dennis Galimberti. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Classy Caulfield Cup second favourite Eureka Jewel has broken down and may not race again, according to news from the champion Hayes stable. The news has reshuffled the market for the October 19 Cup with Filante now clear 6-1 favourite. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Essendon coach Kevin Sheedy last night declared rover Sean Denham certain to be recalled for the qualifying final against Brisbane at the Gabba tomorrow night. Joe Misti, however, is reportedly recovering from injury faster than expected and must also come into calculations. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>Rugby league faces a national broadcasting blackout next year with the ABC planning to dump its radio coverage, abandoning bush listeners. The ABC is currently televising club rugby's match of the round in the AAMI Cup, rather than league, and will now drop Optus Cup from the airwaves too. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Manly centre Craig Innes is pleading with the ARL to let him play for New Zealand, after being identified by Kiwi &quot;super league&quot;-aligned selectors. Also named were Jarrod McCracken, Dave Watson and Darren Rameka for a Test against Great Britain and PNG. Pge 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Greater Private Schools eclipsed Combined (State) High Schools 37-7 at North Sydney Oval yesterday. Although the traditional class was displayed from the oldest schools rugby association, CHS halfback Tim Rapp had AAMI club selectors impressed with good pivotal work rewarded with a try. Page 82.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
