<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31512" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer exit seen roiling Gibraltar.</title>
<headline>Placer exit seen roiling Gibraltar.</headline>
<byline>Cynthia Osterman</byline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Dome Inc's decision on Wednesday to sell its 30.8 percent stake in Gibraltar Mines Ltd creates new uncertainties for Gibraltar's already fraught efforts to raise financing for its Lomas Bayas copper project in Chile, analysts said.</p>
<p>Placer said it retained Nesbitt Burns to &quot;identify strategic buyers&quot; for the stake because Gibraltar, a copper company, did not fit with its focus on gold.</p>
<p>A Placer spokesman said the gold giant had already had contacts with potential buyers but declined to identify them.  </p>
<p>It aims to sell the stake to a single buyer at a share price &quot;substantially above&quot; Gibraltar's current market value, he said. Gibraltar shares were up 0.15 at 6.20 in Toronto.</p>
<p>The Gibraltar stake of about 10.1 million shares was worth about C$63 million at Wednesday's market value. Placer carries the interest at US$41 million on its books.</p>
<p>Placer shares were down 0.05 at 33.25</p>
<p>Although Placer was expected to exit from Gibraltar over time, the announcement today caught analysts and even Gibraltar off guard.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm a little surprised...I don't know why they are doing this now. I'm trying to find out myself,&quot; said Gibraltar chief executive Bill Myckatyn, who said he learned of Placer's decision late Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Placer spokesman said the catalyst for the announcement was Gibraltar's success last week in securing a commitment from underwriters for a US$140 million primary debt offering for Lomas Bayas after a previous failure.</p>
<p>But several analysts were puzzled by the timing, saying it could hurt Gibraltar's efforts to arrange another US$55 million in financing for Lomas Bayas.  </p>
<p>&quot;The surprise component is that Gibraltar is in the midst of trying to finance a new mine...For Placer to be a seller does not send a good message to the market,&quot; said Gordon Capital analyst Barry Allan.</p>
<p>Also, analysts said Placer would have been likely to get a higher price for the stake if it waited for a recovery in the copper market. Placer, which until 1993 owned 68 percent of Gibraltar, set no target date for the sale to be finalized.</p>
<p>Myckatyn said Placer's decision &quot;obviously is going to impact&quot; Gibraltar's financing efforts for Lomas Bayas. It will review its options, which included issuing subordinated debt to a customer, sale of part of the property or an equity issue.  </p>
<p>An equity offering may be more difficult due to the sudden availability of Placer's stake, Myckatyn said.</p>
<p>Lomas Bayas was delayed in July after a collapse in copper prices derailed Gibraltar's financing plans.</p>
<p>The property is slated to be an open pit mine and processing plant with capacity of 60,000 tonnes of copper cathode a year. Total mineable reserves are 2.277 billion pounds of copper at a grade of 0.36 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was unclear who would be interested in buying Placer's stake since it would not give the buyer control of Gibraltar.  </p>
<p>Yorkton Securities analyst Doug Leishman said potential buyers might include Japanese smelters but he doubted Placer would be able to sell the stake above market value.</p>
<p>Other analysts speculated that the buyer might also take up a new equity issue from Gibraltar, thus gaining a control position. If the buyer were a strong backer of Gibraltar's plans, it would be positive because Placer had not been viewed as a strong champion of Gibraltar, they said. Moreover, Placer's presence might have been large enough to discourage new investors, they said. &quot;It could be positive going forward,&quot; said Allan.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
