<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31527" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi army defiant over latest rebel attacks.</title>
<headline>Burundi army defiant over latest rebel attacks.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army remained defiant in the face of the latest round of attacks by Hutu rebels and threatened to &quot;neutralize&quot; any assault on the capital on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the rebels attack tonight (Wednesday) or on Thursday they will be neutralised. They will never be allowed to attack the capital,&quot; army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Longin Minani told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Burundi's army on Wednesday used two helicopters mounted with machine guns and a single-engine plane to strafe and rocket an area a few kilometres (miles) to the east of the city, according to eyewitnesses.</p>
<p>Hutu rebels from the Forces for the Defence of Democracy (FDD) fired mortars at Bujumbura on Tuesday in the first attack on the capital since an army coup on July 25 brought ethnic Tutsi Pierre Buyoya to power.</p>
<p>Residents of the Mutanga north, the suburb closest to the hills where the fighting took place, were on Wednesday evening anxiously awaiting a second night of fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;We are terrified. The army have been using helicopters and a plane to repel the rebel attack. You can hear them fighting,&quot; one resident told Reuters.</p>
<p>Earlier the United States flew out 31 Americans and expatriates from Bujumbura on a giant C-141 Starlifter.</p>
<p>The plane was grounded for nearly seven hours after Tanzania refused to give it permission to overfly its airspace on the grounds that this would be sanctions busting, diplomats said. The plane eventually received clearance to overfly Rwandan and Ugandan airspace towards the Kenyan capital Nairobi.</p>
<p>The World Food Programme (WFP) said it was looking after 16,000 people, mainly Tutsis, displaced by fighting in the last five days in northern Kayanza province.</p>
<p>One soldier and 10 Tutsi civilians were killed during a rebel attack at Gahombo in Kayanza on Tuesday, Minani said.</p>
<p>Rebels killed four people when they ambushed a beer truck at Rutegama, Kayanza, on Wednesday, according to a senior local government official. Burundi's main northern roads are virtually impassable after a series of attacks by rebels in the last week.</p>
<p>The leaders of the mainstream Hutu party Frodebu on Wednesday announced they were were backing the FDD and called on party leader Jean Minani to make an official announcement to that effect.</p>
<p>The FDD and its political wing the National Council for the Defence of Democracy (CNDD) are both led by former Frodebu interior minister Leanord Nyangoma.</p>
<p>Political analysts said Hutus who constitute 85 per cent of Burundi's six million people were more likely to back Nyangoma's military solution since Frodebu was ousted in the coup.</p>
<p>Julius Nyerere, the international mediator on Burundi, said a CNDD-Frodebu alliance might &quot;clarify&quot; the Hutu leadership.</p>
<p>Nyerere, Tanzania's former president, has tried in vain to get all sides in Burundi's conflict to peace talks. The conflict has claimed 150,000 lives since October 1993.</p>
<p>Buyoya and the army want the rebels to renounce violence first, while CNDD says the army must return to its barracks before talks can take place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
