<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31523" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: U.S. plane in Burundi to evacuate westerners.</title>
<headline>U.S. plane in Burundi to evacuate westerners.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. transport plane landed in Burundi's capital Bujumbura on Wednesday to evacuate U.S. citizens and other westerners after a night of fierce fighting between the army and Hutu rebels, a senior U.S. diplomat said.</p>
<p>The C-141 Starlifter landed at 10.30 a.m. (0830 GMT) after Hutu rebels of the Forces for the Defence of Democracy (FDD) announced they hit army positions in Bujumbura overnight.</p>
<p>The diplomat denied widespread rumours that among those set to fly out of the war-torn central African nation was ousted Hutu president Sylvestre Ntibantunganya who has been holed up at the U.S. ambassador's residence since the Tutsi army staged a coup on July 25.</p>
<p>Burundian troops immediately guarded the plane after it landed.</p>
<p>&quot;We landed the plane in order to pull out people who wanted to leave and the plane will be going back to Nairobi (the Kenyan capital),&quot; the American diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>Wednesday's evacuation of the unspecified number of westerners came after a night of fierce fighting outside Bujumbura between the army and Hutu rebels of the FDD.</p>
<p>&quot;My aid operation has been closed down, so I am being pulled back to Europe. There isn't much for me to do here now,&quot; said a Belgian aid worker as he waited to board the American plane.</p>
<p>Shaken Bujumbura residents said the FDD attack was the fiercest engagement since Tutsi military strongman Pierre Buyoya seized power in a bloodless coup on July 25.</p>
<p>Innocent Nimpagaritse, spokesman for the exiled National Council for the Defence of Democracy (CNDD), told Reuters the CNDD military wing used rocket-propelled grenades to attack the army in a stepped-up campaign against the military government.</p>
<p>In Bujumbura, army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Longin Minani told Reuters that the army had repelled the rebels after heavy fighting at Tshiangano commune, a few kilometres (miles) outside the city.</p>
<p>&quot;They (rebels) were firing from Tshiangano. We sent our military and we fought them back. How many we killed, we don't know,&quot; said Minani, adding there were no military casualties.</p>
<p>The fighting started at curfew, 10 p.m. (2000 GMT), and gunfire could also be heard in at least two other locations in the city's eastern suburbs.</p>
<p>Hutu rebels earlier launched three 60mm mortar bombs at the university, injuring no one and causing slight damage, according to military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Isaie Nibizi.</p>
<p>Burundi's capital has been largely free from violence since the army coup.</p>
<p>But the city is slowly grinding to a halt because of economic and transport sanctions imposed by regional African leaders to force Buyoya to return the country to constitutional legality.</p>
<p>Analysts said the rebels were taking advantage of the crippling sanctions to pile pressure on an army without much resources.</p>
<p>Tanzania, Kenya, Rwanda, Uganda, Ethiopia, Zaire, Cameroon and Zambia are signatories to the sanctions package agreed in the northern Tanzanian town of Arusha on July 31.</p>
<p>Regional analysts fear Burundi may go down the same path as its northern neighbour Rwanda where a million people were slaughtered in genocidal killings in 1994.</p>
<p>Around 150,000 people, mainly civilians, have died in ethnic fighting in Burundi since 1993 when the country's first democratically elected president, Melchior Ndadaye of the Hutu majority, was murdered by renegade soldiers of the Tutsi minority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
