<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31526" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Hutu rebels attack army positions in Burundi.</title>
<headline>Hutu rebels attack army positions in Burundi.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hutu rebels said on Wednesday they had attacked army positions in Bujumbura overnight in the fiercest engagement since a July 25 coup but the country's Tutsi-dominated army said the rebels had been repelled.</p>
<p>Innocent Nimpagaritse, spokesman for the exiled National Council for the Defence of Democracy (CNDD), told Reuters the CNDD military wing used rocket-propelled grenades to attack the army in a stepped-up campaign against Burundi's Tutsi military junta.</p>
<p>Shaken Bujumbura residents said the battle was intense and frightening. It appeared to be the first fight close to Bujumbura, which is now inhabited by Tutsi. The Hutu who used to live in the capital have fled.</p>
<p>Nimpagaritse said the CNDD's military wing -- Forces for the Defence of Democracy (FDD) -- had taken the battle to the capital after driving the army out of Burundi's Kayanza region, a scene of heavy fighting in the last five days.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forces moved from positions in hills surrounding Bujumbura and attacked the putschists (army) in the city. We are stepping up pressure on the regime. We have already driven them out of Kayanza region,&quot; Nimpagaritse said.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall not lay down our arms until the Tutsi military returns power to the democratically elected government of Burundi. But we have no intention of seizing Bujumbura. We just want drive them to the negotiating table,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In Bujumbura, army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Longin Minani told Reuters that the army had repelled the rebels after heavy fighting at Tshiangano commune, a few kilometres (miles) outside the city.</p>
<p>&quot;They (rebels) were firing from Tshiangano. We sent our military and we fought them back. How many we killed, we don't know,&quot; said Minani, adding there were no military casualties.</p>
<p>Minani said that fighting took place far beyond the city, but residents of the Muntanga north suburb which faces the hills where fighting took place said that bullets landed in the city itself.</p>
<p>&quot;Bullets were landing in this area and we hid in our houses when we heard the fighting. Last year there was gunfire all the time but these days we hardly hear any so we were very scared,&quot; one Muntanga resident told Reuters.</p>
<p>There was a heavy military presence in Muntanga north suburb on Wednesday morning, but Bujumbura city came to life as usual with residents flocking to work.</p>
<p>The fighting started at curfew, 10 p.m. (2000 GMT), and gunfire could also be heard in at least two other locations in the city's eastern suburbs.</p>
<p>Hutu rebels earlier launched three 60mm mortar bombs at the university, injuring no one and causing slight damage, according to military spokesman Lieutenant Colonel Isaie Nibizi.</p>
<p>Burundi's capital has been largely free from violence since military strongman Pierre Buyoya, an ethnic Tutsi, came to power in an army coup d'etat in July that ousted a Hutu president.</p>
<p>The city, which is Tutsi-controlled after a bout of ethnic cleansing last year, is considered highly vulnerable to attack from Hutu rebels because of its position between the north east shore of lake Tanganyika and a range of steep hills.</p>
<p>Around 150,000 people -- mainly civilians -- have died in inter-ethnic fighting in Burundi since 1993 when the country's first democratically-elected Hutu president was killed in an attempted coup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
