<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31537" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: S.African farmers to trek to Mozambique this month.</title>
<headline>S.African farmers to trek to Mozambique this month.</headline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>White South African farmers are to start up new homes on September 15 in neighbouring Mozambique in a 1990s version of their ancestors' 19th century Great Trek, the Mozambique News Agency said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a deal signed in May by Mozambican President Joaquim Chissano and South Africa's President Nelson Mandela, land farmed by the South Africans would remain the property of the Mozambican government, while control of it would be vested in a joint company, Mosagruis, split equally between the two states.</p>
<p>The scheme, under which white South Africans will farm underdeveloped areas of aid-dependent Mozambique, has been billed as a repeat of the Great Trek north from the Cape by white Afrikaners which started in 1835.</p>
<p>The first group of 20 farmers will settle in the Lugenda Valley in the northern province of Niassa, the agency said.</p>
<p>Niassa provincial governor Aires Aly told the agency he would visit Johannesburg this week to &quot;fix the final details concerning the arrival of the farmers&quot;.</p>
<p>Many South African farmers have expressed interest in this scheme and similar ones in countries such as Angola, Zaire and Zambia, saying they fear President Nelson Mandela's government might force them to give up their farms to landless blacks.</p>
<p>Aly led a delegation of Niassa farmers and traditional leaders to South Africa in July to study the methods of South African farmers and to discuss plans for integrating Mosagrius into an overall programme for the development of Niassa.</p>
<p>Niassa, the largest but least populous of Mozambique's 11 provinces, has 12 million hectares (30 million acres) of fertile arable land, only one percent of which is being farmed, mainly to grow cotton, sunflower, beans, potatoes, maize and other grains.</p>
<p>The 10-year renewable agreement gives the South African farmers the possibility of settling in areas with few land disputes, mainly in the north of the country.</p>
<p>During the apartheid era South Africa aided the rebel Renamo movement fighting the then Marxist Frelimo government in Maputo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
