<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31538" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian oil shares gain in moderate trade.</title>
<headline>Nigerian oil shares gain in moderate trade.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Petroleum marketing company shares made a strong showing in moderate Wednesday trading on the Nigerian stock exchange.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 6,158.09 from 6,146.99 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Mobil and African Petroleum gained 15 kobo each to close 35.30 naira and 28.00 naira respectively. National Oil rose 12 kobo to 27.02 naira.</p>
<p>Bank shares were active, with Union Bank closing 10 kobo higher at 6.80 naira while UBA closed at 5.42 naira, up two kobo.</p>
<p>In the construction sector G. Cappa gained six kobo to 4.52 naira while Impresit Bakolori finished two kobo higher at 1.60 naira.</p>
<p>West African Portland Cement, Ashaka Cement and Benue Cement were all five kobo higher at 27.85 naira, 14.90 naira and 3.78 naira respectively.</p>
<p>Industrial Gases finished 10 kobo up at 11.10 naira, Cadbury rose by eight to 23.28 naira while Flour Mills of Nigeria advanced by five kobo to 8.50 naira.</p>
<p>Northern Nigerian Flour Mills announced a decline in full year profit to end-March 1996 but proposed the same 50 kobo dividend as last year. The shares went ex-dividend immediately, closing at 9.11 naira.</p>
<p>Conglomerate CFAO dropped five kobo to 5.80 naira. Nigerian Breweries fell two kobo to 13.73 naira.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
