<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31536" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela's island prison to be freedom museum.</title>
<headline>Mandela's island prison to be freedom museum.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela's cabinet decided on Wednesday that Robben Island, the sandstone prison where he spent 18 of his 27 years in jail, should become a Museum of the Freedom Struggle of South Africa.</p>
<p>The cabinet approved recommendations by Mandela's friend and fellow island inmate, Ahmed Kathrada, for the future of the flat, sandy island in Cape Town's Table Bay.</p>
<p>Robben Island, 11 km (seven miles) long and up to five km (three miles) wide, has served as a lunatic asylum, leper colony and prison throughout the 340 years since European settlers arrived at the Cape.</p>
<p>One prisoner disappeared on a surf-ski stolen from the home of a warder, but there was never a confirmed successful escape from the high-security prison complex near the small harbour.</p>
<p>&quot;Robben Island should be developed as a World Heritage Site, National Monument and National Museum which can become a cultural and conservation showcase for the new South African democracy,&quot; the cabinet said in a statement.</p>
<p>The development should enhance the economic, tourism and educational potential of the island without allowing what the cabinet called &quot;crass commercialism&quot;.</p>
<p>Proposals for the future of the island have included a casino, a holiday resort and a novelty hotel with Mandela's tiny cell as the prime attraction.</p>
<p>&quot;Robben Island should be run as a site museum, where the total environment is conserved in an integrated way...and the ex-political prison (should) be converted into a Museum of the Freedom Struggle in South Africa,&quot; the cabinet said.</p>
<p>The island, named after the Dutch word for seals, also has a thriving colony of endangered jackass penguins.</p>
<p>The proposal by the cabinet, which includes three of Mandela's prison colleagues, calls for him to head a trust that would raise funds and oversee the development of the island.</p>
<p>Prison governor Colonel Elsa Jones told Reuters by telephone that she welcomed the decision to close the prison by the end of 1996 and to develop it as a cultural site, saying:</p>
<p>&quot;I fully agree with the plan, I'm very pleased with it.&quot;</p>
<p>Jones said only 113 prisoners were still held on the island, which has held close to 1,000 prisoners at times, mainly to maintain roads, waterworks and the small harbour.</p>
<p>She said 83 staff families remained on the island, which has its own primary school, but would begin to leave later this month as the prison winds down.</p>
<p>The prison service decided not to renovate the maximum- security &quot;B wing&quot; in which Mandela and other African National Congress leaders were held, initially under inhumane conditions.</p>
<p>In his first years after arriving on the island in 1964, Mandela was given only a shirt and short trousers, shoes without socks, two blankets and a mat to sleep on the concrete floor.</p>
<p>Prisoners worked in a lime quarry, which harmed the health of many including Mandela, now 78, who has had eye surgery to partially correct the damage that still causes him pain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
