<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31544" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's currency and bond markets ended a quiet day steady with dealers in both markets reporting limited activity ahead of the release of gold and foreign exchange reserves and U.S. payrolls data on Friday.</p>
<p>The data was expected to provide much needed direction to the financial markets which were expected to consolidate until then.</p>
<p>Bond traders said yields fell in early trade on the back of an overnight recovery in the U.S. lonn bond to 7.05 percent in the morning from over 7.15 percent on Tuesday after the U.S. attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>However, after players had squared positions yields drifted up throughout the day to end at 15.33 percent in trade characterised by jobber activity.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutions kept to the sidelines and trade was dominated by jobbers. There's quite a bit of uncertainty in the market and everyone is waiting for reserves and U.S. payrolls on Friday for direction,&quot; a senior trader said, adding that he expected the market to consolidate until then.</p>
<p>Dealers said volumes were thin and players would be watching U.S. Treasuries on Thursday which drifted lower during the day after initially recovering overnight.</p>
<p>At 1426 GMT the benchmark R150 stock was trading at 15.33 percent from 15.38 percent late on Tuesday, while the E168 was at 15.48 percent from 15.54 percent overnight.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net buyers of 32.28 million rand of South African bonds on Tuesday after selling 188.5 million rand of on Monday.</p>
<p>Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 4.66 billion rand on Tuesday after 4.09 billion rand on Monday.</p>
<p>The rand ended a sluggish day unchanged from its previous closing levels at 4.4830/4860.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been very quiet with exporter selling being met by importer demand. Volumes were small and we expect some consolidation tomorrow (Thursday) and possibly a test of the higher levels at 4.52 before renewed strength sets in,&quot; a trader at a foreign bank said.</p>
<p>Dealers said a test of 4.45 was still being talked about but it would probably take a couple of days to get there.</p>
<p>At 1426 GMT the local unit was quoted at 4.4830/4880 on the dollar from 4.4830/4860 late on Tuesday. Against the crosses, it was trading at 7.0212/0312 on sterling from 7.0291/0383 and at 0.3302/3307 marks from 0.3308/3313 marks previously.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs were unchanged at between 15.90 to 16.05 percent, while 90-day BAs were also steady at between 15.30 to 15.50 percent.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank put the money market shortage at 8.551 billion rand on Tuesday from 8.141 billion rand on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Vera von Lieres, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
