<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31545" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: INTERVIEW- Rates, laws undermine Nairobi bourse.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW- Rates, laws undermine Nairobi bourse.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of one of Kenya's top banks said on Wednesday high interest rates, restrictive laws governing foreign investment and a lack of research were the main impediments to faster growth of the Nairobi Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Peter Geer, managing director of Barclays Bank of Kenya Ltd, told Reuters in an interview that the other hindrance to Kenyan bourse development was a lack of public awareness.</p>
<p>Geer said there was a feeling two years ago economic reforms would lead to a flood of foreign investors and the market had gone up on the basis of that anticipation &quot;which never happened&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to realise that foreign investors think very cautiously before they enter a market. It can take them a year or two to make up their minds,&quot; Geer said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Kenya was unfortunate in that our entry into the emerging markets scene tended to coincide with the collapse in Mexico. So, emerging markets became a very difficult subject.&quot;</p>
<p>He said one of the major problems in Kenya was that blue chip companies such as Barclays and Standard Chartered Bank were not available to foreign investors because they already had a large percentage of foreign shareholding.</p>
<p>&quot;Of those that are left, quite a few of the shares are what we call 'closely held'. That means there is one very dominant shareholding and the rest is in the hands of a minority who may not feel they have any control or any say in the running of the company. Foreign investors are conscious of that,&quot; Geer said.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;The number of shares on the market that foreign shareholders can participate in is fairly small. That has to be increased if we are going to see more investment coming in.&quot;</p>
<p>Foreign investors are allowed a 40 percent holding in local firms quoted on the Nairobi Stock Exchange. Where a company is already majority foreign-owned, no more shares can be available.</p>
<p>Some 32 percent of Barclays Bank is floated on the Nairobi bourse while 68 percent is held by Barclays Bank Plc of London.</p>
<p>Geer said he thought research was a problem: &quot;We need more research on shares on the Nairobi bourse. Very little is done here that gives us more public information.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What we are going to see eventually is tie ups between local broking companies and international broking companies; when that is permitted international broking companies would be able to provide people to do research,&quot; Geer added.</p>
<p>Geer said it was evident that there was a different attitude towards investing in Kenya compared to Hong Kong or Singapore. In the Far East, many ordinary people knew about the workings of stock exchanges compared to the contrary in Kenya.</p>
<p>&quot;(In the Far East) there is a very large speculative element and if you were to ask a taxi driver in Singapore what the stock market was doing, they would tell you. I don't think the average Kenyan would (tell) because the average Kenyan doesn't participate in the stock market,&quot; Geer said.</p>
<p>Geer called for a broadening of the base of people involved in the stock market. He said privatisations of government companies on the bourse -- such as the successful June flotation of Kenya Airways -- would help in that direction.</p>
<p>Geer said high interest rates undermined the equities market.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates have a large measure to play. If you can get a return of 20 percent on deposits or on (government) treasury bills, you are less likely to keep money in shares,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Interest rates in Kenya are in the range of 22 to 26 percent.</p>
<p>Geer said he saw no problems with the disclosure standards of companies on the Nairobi bourse &quot;but that can be improved upon&quot;.</p>
<p>Established in 1954, the Nairobi bourse had a market capitalisation of 105 billion shillings ($1.8 billion at 1995 rates) at end-December 1995. It has 59 listed companies.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom +=254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
