<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31541" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa Manuel defends gradual fx control easing.</title>
<headline>S.Africa Manuel defends gradual fx control easing.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Finance Minister Trevor Manuel on Wednesday rejected opposition calls for a &quot;big bang&quot; approach to the abolition of remaining exchange controls, but said they would be phased out as planned.</p>
<p>&quot;The authorities favour a gradual approach to the elimination of exchange controls,&quot; Manuel told parliament during a mini-debate on the subject.</p>
<p>&quot;The abolition of exchange controls is part of a major economic restructuring programme and it is only with high risk that such an important element of the overall programme could be stepped up and implemented ahead of the rest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ken Andrew, finance spokesman for the opposition Democratic Party, said the gradualist policy had failed and warned that the continued application of exchange controls was undermining investor confidence in South Africa.</p>
<p>&quot;South Africa is getting the worst of both worlds and we have become a currency speculator's paradise. We should bite the bullet and get it over with,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Manuel said the volatility of the South African rand, which has lost more than 20 percent of its value since February, underlined the need for a cautious approach to deregulation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important that both the spot and the forward exchange rates of the rand should reflect the underlying market conditions, including expectations about future exchange rate movements.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to proceed along, sequencing the steps that we take, taking account, as we said before, of the confluence of a number of factors.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not about fear, it's not about uncertainty. It's about keeping trend with the best possible advice in the world and I believe that we are on track to provide the most stable arrangement for the phasing out of exchange controls,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South Africa has lifted all controls on non-residents, but retains controls on the export of funds by South African nationals and residents.</p>
<p>The government has repeatedly promised to drop remaining controls and wrote the undertaking into the macroeconomic strategy for growth, employment and redistribution published by Manuel in June.</p>
<p>But the abolition of exchange controls and implementation of the government's promise to partially or fully privatise many state assets are regularly cited as reasons for the lack of long-term capital investment in post-apartheid South Africa.</p>
<p>Manuel denied on Wednesday, however, that exchange controls were a factor in foreign investor confidence, calling the issue &quot;a figment of the imagination of people who fear their own existence in this country.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not something that the international community and the international investor community cares about at all.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom, +27 21 252-238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
