<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31559" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ERITREA: Eritrean currency launch seen in '97 - central bank.</title>
<headline>Eritrean currency launch seen in '97 - central bank.</headline>
<byline>Victoria Engstrand</byline>
<dateline>ASMARA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The long-awaited Eritrean currency, the nakfa, is being printed and may be in circulation next year, the country's central bank governor said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is in process. We are printing it now. It may be released in mid-1997,&quot; Tekie Beyene, acting Governor of the National Bank, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Since its independence from Ethiopia in 1993, Eritrea has used the Ethiopian currency, the birr, but declared its intention to introduce its own currency.</p>
<p>The nafka, named after a town in northern Eritrea that was important to the guerilla movement during the 30-year war with neighbouring Ethiopia's former rulers before victory in 1991, is central to government plans to attract foreign investment and create a liberal economic climate in the northeast African area.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have to do our homework,&quot; Tekie said. &quot;A lot of issues concerning the currency have to be discussed.</p>
<p>&quot;The exchange rate may be fixed, it may be floating. We don't know how tightly the nakfa will be tied to the birr, even though there will be some kind of a free trade area between Eritrea and Ethiopia.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to disclose details about the nakfa, such as where it is being printed, which denominations will be used or what the design will look like.</p>
<p>&quot;Let it be a surprise to the people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tekie said before year end, a Banking Act would be promulgated.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe there will be one or two more Eritrean banks apart from the Commercial Bank we have now. There are people who are now thinking about it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will also be a Capital Market Act, so that stocks, securities and shares can be exchanged openly in the country,&quot; he said, adding there might be a stock exchange operating in Asmara by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ERTRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASMARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ERITREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
