<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31551" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwean shares soar on lower money market rates.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwean shares soar on lower money market rates.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean shares soared to new levels on Wednesday on heavy buying inspired by softening short-term money market rates, brokers said.</p>
<p>The key industrial index jumped 4.2 percent -- or 247.93 points, its biggest ever one-day gain -- to break through the psychological 6,000 barrier, closing at a record high of 6,165.26.</p>
<p>&quot;The bull-run is a product of falling interest rates on the money market,&quot; one broker said. Rates have fallen to the lower 20 percent area over the past two months from their 27-30 percent ranges at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>The brokers said the two-week strike by civil servants, which finally ended on Wednesday after the government reinstated thousands of the strikers, and tensions between the United States and Iraq had had no effect on local stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The private sector kept out of the strike which was something the government had to settle,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>On the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange on Wednesday, clothing retailer Edgars surged 500 cents to 2,700, blue-chip conglomerate Delta jumped 200 cents to 2,900, while sugar refinery ZSR at 950, bankers FMB at 3,200, chemical firm Chemco at 850 and pottery producer Ariston at 1,100 all rose 100 cents.</p>
<p>Bankers Barclays gained 40 cents to 2,050, winery Afdis climbed 30 cents to 300, sugar producer Hippo at 725, multi-industrial group Tedco at 275 and Alloys at 825 all rose 25 cents, while clothing retailer Truworths added 20 cents to 670 and cement producer Porthold put on 15 cents to 1,140.</p>
<p>Only two counters went against the trend, multi-industrial group IHL which dropped 25 cents to 3,650 and tyre company NTS which shed 10 cents to 500.</p>
<p>Minings were mixed with nickel producer Bindura adding five cents to 1,080 and Wankie Colliery gaining 10 cents to 330. Other counters traded at previous levels. The seven-counter mining index edged 2.29 points up to end at 1,319.60.</p>
<p>-- Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
