<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31550" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Bass unit in S.Africa gaming machine deal.</title>
<headline>Bass unit in S.Africa gaming machine deal.</headline>
<dateline>DURBAN, South Africa 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British brewery group Bass Plc subsidiary Bass Leisure said it had finalised a 250 million rand deal with two South African black business organisations to manufacture and distribute gaming machines by early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached agreement with two influential partners to build a gaming machine company in Bloemfontein that will provide jobs in manufacturing, management and sales,&quot; Bass Leisure South Africa director Roger Withers told a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of the investment will initially be 100 million rand and the total investment over the next couple of years will be 250 million rand,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The partners are the National African Federated Chamber of Commerce and the Foundation for African and Business Consumer Services. Both will share 49 percent of the holding, Withers said.</p>
<p>Construction of the plant could begin as early as October with production earmarked to start early next year depending on how quickly the government granted the company a licence to manufacture the machines, he said.</p>
<p>The Bloemfontein manufacturing plant would create jobs for about 500 people and the sales office in Gauteng province would create further employment, he said.</p>
<p>Withers warned that if the government imposed a tax of more than 10 percent on the capital generated by the machines it would adversely affect the growth of the business.</p>
<p>&quot;The taxation on gaming machines produces good tax revenue but we need the government to set the rate at a sensible level and not kill the industry before it starts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bass Leisure, an international company with an annual turnover of about eight billion rand, is a subsidiary of Bass Plc which is listed on the London and New York stock exchanges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DURBAN, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
