<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31566" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOZAMBIQUE: Love blooms for African liberators Mandela, Machel.</title>
<headline>Love blooms for African liberators Mandela, Machel.</headline>
<byline>Iain Christie</byline>
<dateline>MAPUTO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's not hard to understand why Nelson Mandela fell for Graca Machel.</p>
<p>The widow of Mozambique's late president Samora Machel, who led his country to liberation, exudes charm and warmth.</p>
<p>Coming up for her 51st birthday next month she retains much of the physical beauty of her youth.</p>
<p>She is fiercely intellectual and she is part of the African independence struggle, epitomised by the 78-year-old Mandela.</p>
<p>But Graca says she will not marry South Africa's hero-president, despite the warmth of her feelings for him.</p>
<p>In an interview this week in Maputo with a Reuters correspondent who has known her for more than 20 years, Graca said she speaks to Mandela by telephone twice a day.</p>
<p>But she added: &quot;I belong to Mozambique. I will always be the wife of Samora Machel. I like being called Mrs Machel. It's the only way I can keep my husband alive.&quot;</p>
<p>President Machel was killed in a plane crash over South Africa near the Mozambican border in October 1986.</p>
<p>At his funeral, her face was twisted by anguish, and she wore mourning for a full five years afterwards.</p>
<p>Graca described her relations with Mandela as affectionate. Asked if that meant amorous she replied in a whisper: &quot;Yes&quot;.</p>
<p>Was she in love with Nelson? &quot;This is very embarrassing,&quot; she said with a giggle that said, Yes but I'm not telling.</p>
<p>Long an open secret in government circles, the affair was acknowledged this week by a presidential spokesman after a Sunday newspaper splashed the story of their romance.</p>
<p>Mandela let it be known that he and Graca plan to spend two weeks a month together from now on.</p>
<p>In strait-laced South Africa, the affair has raised some eyebrows. Desmond Tutu, former Anglican archbishop, is reported to have told Mandela he risked setting a bad example to youth.</p>
<p>&quot;I can understand that Nelson, being head of state, would have to set a kind of example,&quot; Graca Machel acknowledged.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have problems, both of us, and we have discussed this very thoroughly. We made a decision. We are not getting married,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Mandela's controversial ex-wife Winnie stood by him through 27 years in jail but the couple were divorced in March. The president admitted his loneliness over the past six years of life with a woman who, he said, never came to his bed unless he was asleep.</p>
<p>South Africans were overwhelmingly sympathetic, and public reaction to the revelation that Mandela has a new love in his life has been generous.</p>
<p>&quot;He's such a lovely man and he deserves a companion,&quot; one woman was quoted as telling the Johannesburg Star newspaper, which sampled reaction.</p>
<p>&quot;What's age got to do with it? The man's in love, can't you see?&quot; a schoolgirl told the paper.</p>
<p>Graca was born on October 17, 1945, in southern Mozambique.</p>
<p>She studied in Lisbon in the late 1960s, graduating in modern languages, then went to Tanzania to join Machel's Frelimo guerrillas fighting Portuguese colonialism.</p>
<p>She never fired a shot in anger but her education took her to the top. She served as Minister of Education and Culture for 14 years -- the only woman in the cabinet.</p>
<p>In 1986, four years before the political earthquake that began with the release of South Africa's most potent political prisoner, Graca received a message of condolence from the Mandelas on the death of her husband.</p>
<p>&quot;My husband was murdered in just one day, in just one fateful moment,&quot; she replied to Winnie Mandela. &quot;Your husband is being murdered every day, every hour. My sister, thank you for having the strength to console me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOZAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAPUTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOZAMBIQUE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
