<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31560" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Index eases at Nairobi bourse in dull trading.</title>
<headline>Index eases at Nairobi bourse in dull trading.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 20-share index dropped at the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) in a dull and directionless market, floor dealers and brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has still not seen any news that could force a consistent pattern in movement either way,&quot; a floor dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had a few days of an upward shift, but as previously indicated, that did not necessarily mean a real change in market fortunes -- the market was reacting to nothing,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The index fell 19.12 points to close at 3072.47.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted at 6,728,300 shillings on 248,621 shares compared to 8,262,341 shillings on 317,112 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Some 290 deals were made from 281 deals on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Brokers said that with bank interest rates hovering in the range of 21 to 26 percent, investors found the money market a more lucrative attraction than the equities market.</p>
<p>&quot;It would appear that putting the money in banks brings higher reward in a totally risk-free environment. If you can still make your money at no risk, that would be the option to take; that is the option quite a few investors are taking,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>National carrier Kenya Airways was the main player, touching the 11 shilling mark, then dipping to 10.80 before settling at 10.90 from 10.85 on 54,722 shares.</p>
<p>Brooke Bond rose a shilling to 177 on 526 shares while Rea Vipingo Plantations lost up to 20 cents to 11 on 27,880 shares. George Williamson gained 50 cents to 66.50 on 720 shares.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank lost up to 7.0 to 105 on 1,319 shares, Standard Chartered Bank lost 75 cents to 45.25 on 4,300 shares while National Bank of Kenya closed unchanged at 39.25 on 41,205 shares.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
