<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31562" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius bourse index eases in mixed market.</title>
<headline>Mauritius bourse index eases in mixed market.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritius bourse share index, Semdex, eased 0.08 points to 321.71 on Wednesday reflecting a mixed trading session with price levels moving in tight ranges, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Volume rose to 3.41 million rupees on 154,912 shares from 1.64 million rupees on 67,352 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>The Mauritius bourse official market trades on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.</p>
<p>Share dealers said stocks were mixed in a trendless market that lacked liquidity owing to an absence of investor interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Against this background small volumes can make the shares move in either direction with losses in certain stocks being offset by gains in others and the Semdex hardly changing,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;Again the two banks' stocks captured the majority of volume while small deals were noted in the rest of the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank was unchanged at 73 rupees on 19,271 shares and State Bank of Mauritius remained at 8.40 rupees on 72,824 shares.</p>
<p>Investment-based Policy added 10 cents to 3.50 rupees on 1,850 shares and Fincorp gained 50 cents to 73.50 rupees on 996 shares.</p>
<p>Liberty Investment Trust (LIT) was 20 cents higher to 11 rupees on 300 shares. Sugar based Mon Tresor Mon Desert rose 20 cents to 32.70 rupees on 1,713 shares.</p>
<p>Conglomerates Rogers slipped 1.50 rupees to 93 on 1,700 shares while Ireland Blyth lost 10 cents to 13 rupees on 5,838 shares. Happy World Foods shed 20 cents to 14 rupees on 700 shares.</p>
<p>Grand Baie Hotel added 20 cents to 33.30 rupees on 3,500 shares while national carrier Air Mauritius was stable at 51 rupees on 2,267 shares.</p>
<p>--Mike Chung, Port Louis ++230 212-6870</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
