<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31578" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LESOTHO: FEATURE - Lesotho's sheep, traffic give way to African leaders.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Lesotho's sheep, traffic give way to African leaders.</headline>
<byline>Marius Bosch</byline>
<dateline>MASERU 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Travelling along Lesotho's winding mountain roads is hazardous most of the time.</p>
<p>But with hundreds of African delegates, stray sheep, polite policemen and confused diplomats all competing for space on the roads of the hilly capital Maseru, travel can be almost impossible.</p>
<p>Traffic came to a halt in August when the mountain kingdom hosted a showcase meeting of southern African leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;This is bad, especially in a town that has never been planned at all,&quot; said a prominent Lesotho journalist as he contemplated a line of cars snaking up a hill on a long detour to the sleepy capital's thoroughfare, Kingsway.</p>
<p>Only 200 metres (yards) away, the main street was blocked by Lesotho police wearing blue dress uniforms who ordered motorists to join the queue on the tortuous detour.</p>
<p>With 12 southern African leaders in town for the annual Southern African Development Community (SADC) summit, space and roads were at a premium.</p>
<p>Lesotho's first ever summit took three months to organise and many delegates said it was the best yet in SADC's 16-year history, inside the conference halls at least.</p>
<p>At intermittent intervals during the meeting, Maseru's main road was opened, closed and reopened to allow visiting VIP's access to the venue, the Maseru Sun hotel.</p>
<p>While politicians were offloaded with military precision at the hotel, ordinary Lesotho citizens and confused visitors made their way along back streets trying to dodge pot-holes, shepherds and their flocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Where to now?,&quot; one diplomat asked a policeman, who politely instructed him to turn his car around and head back the way he came along a pot-holed road.</p>
<p>&quot;You will learn the backroads of Maseru this weekend,&quot; said one Lesotho government official.</p>
<p>Locals and visitors from South Africa -- which prides itself on its smooth, well-kept highways -- know that that spells misery in a poor country with infamously bad roads.</p>
<p>Luckily things have improved in recent years -- mainly due to the massive Lesotho Highlands Development construction project that will see Lesotho's water dammed and transported to the parched neighbour, South Africa, which surrounds it.</p>
<p>In 1991, out of the country's 5,500 km (3,437 miles) of roads, only 764 km (477 miles) were tarred.</p>
<p>Lesotho authorities blame the poor roads for regular traffic accidents in the kingdom that is the size of Belgium but with just under two million people.</p>
<p>The geography does not help. Lesotho's lowest point is about 1,000 metres (yards) above sea-level and its highest 3,482 metres (yards). Large parts of the country are only reached by four-wheel drive vehicles or mountain ponies.</p>
<p>And in winter, heavy snowfalls closes many of the mountain roads. Recently, the South African Air Force was called in to help search for motorists and hikers marooned in the mountains after the heaviest snowfalls in years.</p>
<p>In January, Lesotho's King Moshoeshoe II was killed in a car accident on his way to visiting a remote cattle outpost.</p>
<p>A team of detectives from Britain's Scotland Yard found that the king was killed when his drunken royal chauffeur fell asleep at the wheel on a lonely moutain road. The car plunged into a ravine.</p>
<p>His son and successor, King Letsie, told delegates to the SADC summit that the nation was only now coming out of mourning. alm</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LESOT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MASERU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LESOTHO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
