<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31579" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish ruling coalition rows as minister sacked.</title>
<headline>Polish ruling coalition rows as minister sacked.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's president sacked foreign trade minister Jacek Buchacz on Wednesday, prompting a sudden crisis in the tense relations between the two parties in the ruling leftist coalition.</p>
<p>A government statement said Buchacz, 48, was fired on a motion by Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz after official probes revealed an improper blurring of public and private interests in the granting of export guarantees.</p>
<p>&quot;The motion of the head of cabinet in this matter is linked with a need to guarantee better care over the interests of the state treasury,&quot; the government statement said.</p>
<p>Heads of Buchacz's Polish Peasant Party (PSL) and the larger ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) of Cimoszewicz held a crisis meeting in Warsaw but the Peasants broke off the talks in anger at not being informed of the dismissal in advance.</p>
<p>&quot;The (SLD's) manner of dismissing Minister Buchacz, without informing its coalition partner, we view as an example of our partner's arrogant attitude,&quot; the PSL said in a statement.</p>
<p>PSL leader Waldemar Pawlak told PAP news agency the party's chiefs would meet on Friday to decide whether to resume talks with the SLD.</p>
<p>Buchacz himself, at a hastily convened news conference, said: &quot;I regard my dismissal...as a clear breaking of the coalition agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>PSL deputy Stanislaw Bartoszek went further by suggesting the sacking was an SLD move to break up the coalition and cause early parliamentary polls, otherwise not due until September 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a confrontational move, designed to put the blame on the PSL for the dissolution of the coalition and early elections,&quot; Bartoszek told Reuters.</p>
<p>The government statement said the sacking of Buchacz was closely related to inspections by the official Supreme Auditing Chamber (NIK) and the Cabinet Supervision Office.</p>
<p>It said the probes concerned &quot;the involvement of the treasury in ventures concerning export guarantees, in which state and private property is connected in a way that lacks sufficient clarity.&quot;</p>
<p>Buchacz did not directly answer these allegations.</p>
<p>But the PSL statement said his dismissal was the SLD's response to his warnings that Poland's official foreign trade deficit was likely to balloon to $10 billion by the end of 1996 from $1.8 billion last year.</p>
<p>The PSL and SLD have most recently clashed over the distribution of cabinet posts during a reorganisation of central government due this year, but had appeared to settle their differences with a so-far undisclosed compromise.</p>
<p>The coalition has linked the two parties rooted in the pre-1989 communist era, through two cabinet reshuffles, since they defeated parties stemming from Solidarity in 1993 polls.</p>
<p>Buchacz has been foreign trade minister since early 1995. He was appointed by the previous Prime Minister Jozef Oleksy and inherited the portfolio in the current cabinet.</p>
<p>Several weeks ago the government rejected plans by Buchacz to set up a new export guarantee system. His dismissal was formally signed by President Aleksander Kwasniewski.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
