<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31573" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa signs maize accord of intent with Taiwan.</title>
<headline>S.Africa signs maize accord of intent with Taiwan.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's Maize Board signed a long-term sales agreement of intent this week to sell maize to Taiwan until 1999, the Board's international marketing manager Giep Steenkamp said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement was reached on Monday for the period May 1 1996 to April 30, 1999,&quot; Steenkamp told Reuters, adding that no quantities or prices had been set.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an agreement of intent to do business,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Steenkamp said in the past three years, the board exported around 50,000 tonnes of maize in total to Taiwan.</p>
<p>In the current season, the Maize Board had earmarked 1.5 million tonnes of maize for export to all destinations.</p>
<p>&quot;We received 1.5 million tonnes of maize and there are quite of lot of (export) negotiations taking place,&quot; Steenkamp said.</p>
<p>South Africa's maize crop this year is estimated at 9.48 million tonnes, more than double the 4.405 million tonnes in the previous season.</p>
<p>Steenkamp said the Maize Board had already exported seven shiploads of maize -- a total of 242,235 tonnes -- this year, mostly to Iran.</p>
<p>Some white maize had also been shipped to South Korea and Venezuela, he said.</p>
<p>He said South Africa could have exported much larger quantities but exporters were hampered by congested facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;We could have exported much more if we had the facilities but because we work with other exporters we had limited rail and harbour facilities,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>South Africa's maize marketing scheme was de-regulated this year. Under the new dispensation, the Maize Board was also responsible for issuing export permits to private traders.</p>
<p>Private exporters have been allocated 1.8 million tonnes of maize for exports in the current season.</p>
<p>Private traders have in total received permits to export 1.465 million tonnes of white and yellow maize.</p>
<p>Steenkamp said private traders had exported about 700,000 tonnes of maize so far this season.</p>
<p>-- Marius Bosch, Johannesburg newsroom, +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
