<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31575" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Burundi's ousted Hutu party backs rebel group.</title>
<headline>Burundi's ousted Hutu party backs rebel group.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi's largest political party, Frodebu, has thrown its support behind Hutu rebels fighting the country's Tutsi-dominated army, a party spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Joseph Ntakirutimana told Reuters in Nairobi the party of ousted president Sylvestre Ntibantunganya was now appealing to Hutus to rally behind rebels of the National Council for the Defence of Democracy (CNDD).</p>
<p>The army seized power on July 25. Frodebu's Hutu leaders either fled the country or took refuge with Western embassies. Ntibantunganya is still holed up at the residence of the U.S. ambassador in Bujumbura.</p>
<p>In Bujumbura, political analysts said the Frodebu stand, if confirmed, could be the most significant step in the Hutu struggle against the besieged Tutsi military.</p>
<p>Regional countries clamped economic and transport sanctions on Burundi after Major Pierre Buyoya's coup. The sanctions are biting while the CNDD's armed wing, the Forces for the Defence of Democracy (FDD), steps up its military campaign.</p>
<p>Tutsis make up about 15 percent of Burundi's six million population and Hutus about 85 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;From now on we are together with the CNDD. We are going to reinforce them because we have the same enemy -- the Tutsi army,&quot; Ntakirutimana said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are fighting a minority system in Burundi similar to what the blacks were fighting in South Africa and it is important that we stand united, we wage the resistance,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the Frodebu position was supported by 25 former members of parliament now in exile in Kenya and Tanzania.</p>
<p>In Nairobi, three Frodebu MPs issued a statement on Tuesday calling on Hutus to back CNDD which broke away from Frodebu to launch a guerrilla campaign after Tutsi soldiers murdered Burundi's first democratically president, Melchior Ndadaye, a Hutu, in October 1993.</p>
<p>Frodebu had won Burundi's first free elections earlier in 1993 and had an overwhelming parliamentary majority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
