<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31584" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>Czech republic: FOCUS - Czech plane maker mulls Taiwan venture.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Czech plane maker mulls Taiwan venture.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech aircraft producer, Aero Vodochoday a.s. said on Wednesday that talks with Taiwanese officials on Friday would focus on completing a deal to jointly develop the new AE-270 small commercial aircraft.</p>
<p>&quot;We are preparing for Friday talks which should push forward the offer for completing the development and certification of the AE-270,&quot; Vladimir Nyvlt, executive director, of Aero Vodochody, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The AE-270, currently on the drawing board, is planned as a five to nine-seat, single-engine commercial plane.</p>
<p>Asked if the Taiwanese would join with Aero in actually building the plane, Nyvlt said, &quot;Right now we are talking about development and certification, because we're talking about such a large financial amount that we are not able to cover alone.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to say when the plane might go into production.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday in Taipei, a senior Taiwanese aviation official said details in the talks such as the investment amount and the output were in the final stages.</p>
<p>Jack Tang, deputy director of the Taiwan Economics Ministry's Committee for Aviation and Space Industry told Reuters that if upcoming the talks with the Czechs went smoothly &quot;we should reach an agreement in the near term&quot;.</p>
<p>A 23-member team comprising Taiwan officials and executives from aviation companies planned to visit the Czech Republic after this weeks airshow in Farnborough, Britain, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Czechs hope to manufacture the jets in their country. If we do that, some parts will be produced in Taiwan,&quot; Tang said by telephone.</p>
<p>Taiwan has been seeking cooperation with foreign aerospace firms to produce regional passenger jets and boost its fledgling aerospace industry.</p>
<p>Aero, a unit of Aero Holding a.s. which is 62 percent owned by the Czech government, is looking for a way out of major financial difficulties.</p>
<p>The company has been actively seeking buyers for its upgraded L-159 &quot;Albratross&quot; light fighter aircraft, using advanced Rockwell avionics.</p>
<p>-- John Mastrini, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
