<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31588" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Sept 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- A document proposed by Sir Arthur Watts, special negotiator for succession issues in former Yugoslavia, needs fundamental changes, said the leader of Slovenia's succession negotiation group, Miran Mejak, after meeting Watts in Ljubljana on Tuesday .</p>
<p>- Slovenia's Foreign Minister Davorin Kracun visited his Italian counterpart Lamberto Dini on Tuesday and said Italy supported Slovenia's efforts to enter Euro-Atlantic organisations.</p>
<p>- President Milan Kucan concluded second round talks with leaders of political parties on Tuesday to agree on the exact date of upcoming general elections.</p>
<p>- Slovenian authorities said there were 26 political parties registered in Slovenia, adding the number was expected to increase soon.</p>
<p>- Coalmine Velenje, 70 km (43 miles) northeast of Ljubljana, said its lignite output in August was 307,500 metric tonnes, 42,500 metric tonnes less than expected.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- The 14th international congress of bio-meteorologists began in Ljubljana on Tuesday. More than 300 experts from 50 countries will attend the congress.</p>
<p>- Bakers threatened to go on strike unless the government raised bread prices by 19 percent before September 20.</p>
<p>- Slovenia's interior ministry on Tuesday refused a request by former Yugoslav army General Milan Aksentijevic to extend his stay in Slovenia. The general will have to leave by midnight on Wednesday.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Most Slovenian political parties said they would like general elections to be held as soon as possible. Opposition leader Social Democrats Janez Jansa did not attend Tuesday's talks with Kucan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
