<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31587" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania-Hungary to sign pact on September 16.</title>
<headline>Romania-Hungary to sign pact on September 16.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania and Hungary have agreed to sign a long-delayed friendship treaty on September 16 in the western Romanian city of Timisoara, the two countries said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn and his Romanian counterpart Nicolae Vacaroiou will sign the pact, which is key to the ambitions of both countries to join NATO and the European Union, in the presence of Romania's President Ion Iliescu.</p>
<p>Timisoara, cradle of Romania's anti-communist revolution in 1989, is a compromise location roughly equidistant between Bucharest and Budapest.</p>
<p>Neither side would agree to the ceremony taking place in the other's capital and Romania rejected the suggestion of a neutral venue such as Vienna.</p>
<p>&quot;Timisoara is a big city in Romania, with European status and a Hungarian and German minority living in perfect harmony with Romanians, close to the border. It is a good place for such things,&quot; a Romanian foreign ministry official said.</p>
<p>The announcement came after the Hungarian parliament overwhelmingly rejected an opposition demand that the treaty's terms be reviewed.</p>
<p>The governing parties of both countries are determined to push through the pact, with Romania's ruling Party of Social Democracy going to the extent of dumping its anti-Hungarian coalition partner for its opposition to the deal.</p>
<p>The treaty, four years in the making, should end disputes over the status of Romania's 1.6 million ethnic Hungarians and improve economic and military relations between the two central European neighbours.</p>
<p>Timisoara is particularly remembered for its role in the 1989 revolution that toppled Stalinist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu.</p>
<p>Protests in the town against the forced removal of a Hungarian church leader were brutally suppressed, sparking the uprising that ended communism in Romania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
