<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31582" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Europe and CIS port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ALBANIA, Sept 2 - Durres - Four vessels in port discharging, 3 bagged flour, 1 general cargo. 3 awaiting berth in roads, 1 to discharge steel, 1 bagged cement, 1 diesel.</p>
<p>BULGARIA, Aug 26-Sept 1 - Bourgas - 30 vessels operating of which 20 loading, 6 general, 6 fertiliser, 1 copper cathodes, 1 metal, 1 iron anodes, 3 steel, 1 clinker, 1 tanker. 8 discharging, 1 sugar, 1 iron ore, 1 fertiliser, 2 zinc, 1 chemicals, 2 crude. 2 discharging/loading containers. 12 in roads, 6 to load, 1 cars, 1 tanker, 1 steel, 1 metal, 1 metal cathodes, 1 chemicals. 1 to discharge chemicals, 1 coal. 5 empty. 17 due, 13 to load, 1 trucks, 1 pipes, 1 copper concentrates, 1 clinker, 1 metal, 1 barite concentrate, 5 steel, 1 copper cathodes, 1 timber. 3 to discharge, 2 coal, 1 iron ore. 1 to discharge/load containers.</p>
<p>Varna - 34 vessels operating of which 27 loading, 11 soda, 2 cement, 1 craft paper, 2 fertiliser, 1 SAS, 1 iron plates, 1 brandy, 1 trucks, 1 cellulose/marble, 1 kaoline, 1 scrap, 1 clinker, 1 cigarettes, 2 quartz sand. 3 discharging, 1 rice, 1 phosphorite, 1 coal. 1 discharging/loading containers/trucks. 3 discharging/loading containers. 6 waiting in roads of which 2 to load, 1 fertiliser, 1 clinker. 1 to discharge sugar, 1 to discharge/load containers, 2 cargoes not nominated.</p>
<p>Sept 2 - Varna East - 2 vessels loading at berth, 2 discharging, 1 waiting at anchorage to load, 1 to discharge. 3 vessels awaiting orders. West - 8 loading at berth, 1 discharging, 1 waiting at anchorage to load. Bourgas East - 11 due, 6 loading at berth, 3 discharging. 1 vessel waiting at anchorage to load, 4 to discharge, 13 under repair/drydock, 4 awaiting orders. West - 10 due, 1 loading at berth, 1 discharging. Tankers, 1 loading at berth, 1 discharging.</p>
<p>CROATIA - Sept 2 - Rijeka - Three vessels discharging at berth, 5 loading. 1 berthed. 8 under repair/drydock, 1 anchored, 6 due. Delays - Zadar - One discharging at berth. Ploce - Two discharging. Pula, Rasa, Sibenik, Split, Dubrovnik - No vessels.</p>
<p>ESTONIA, Sept 2 - Tallinn city port - 2 vessels loading at berth (1 plywood, 1 steel billets). 1 waiting to load. 4 due, no delays. Kopli - 1 fertiliser vessel loading at berth, 1 meat vessel discharging. 5 due, no delays. Muuga - 2 loading (1 oil, 2 fertiliser). 2 at anchorage to load. 2 ferries. 2 vessels due, no delays. Parnu - One timber vessel loading, 4 due, no delays.</p>
<p>ITALY, Sept 3 - Naples - One tanker in port expected to berth 3/9. Gaeta, Salerno - No vessels in roads. Genoa commercial port - None in roads. No delays. 34 berthed, 3 in drydock. Multedo oil harbour - Two in roads, 4 berthed. Savona, Vado Ligure, Gaeta, Naples, Salerno, Palermo, Ancona/Falconara - None in roads, no delays. La Spezia - None in roads. No delays. 4 berthed, 2 under repair. Leghorn - Two in roads. No delays. 29 berthed. Civitavecchia - Two in roads. Oil terminal inoperative due to strike. Augusta oil harbour - One in roads, 2 berthed. Syracuse oil harbour - Two in roads, 3 berthed. Sarroch, Trieste - No information. Taranto - One 180,000 dwt vessel in roads. Ravenna - Nine in roads. Venice - Four in roads. No delays.</p>
<p>LATVIA , Sept 3 - Riga - 15 vessels in port of which 13 operating, 6 timber loaders, 1 cotton loader, 2 metal loaders, 2 container loaders, 1 chicken discharger, 1 fish discharger. 2 vessels waiting, no delays. 18 due. Ventspils - three operating, 1 steel billets loader, 1 ferrous loader, 1 cotton loader, no delays. 6 due. Liepaja - Eight operating, no delays, none due.</p>
<p>LITHUANIA, Sept 2 - Klaipeda - Vessels loading - 3 metal 2 scrap, 3 fertiliser, 1 oil, 1 potash, 2 fish vessels discharging. 1 in roads, 30 vessels due.</p>
<p>POLAND, Sept 3 - Szczecin - 86 vessels due, delays expected. 51 loading at berth, 32 discharging, 1 waiting to load, 1 to discharge. 12 under repair/drydock, 1 awaiting orders. Gdynia - two loading at berth, 1 coal, 1 general cargo. 4 discharging, 1 ore, 1 bulk, 2 general cargo. 2 awaiting orders, 15 under repair/drydock, 35 due. Gdansk - Eight loading of which 2 coal, 3 bulk, 3 general. 5 under repair/drydock, 18 due.</p>
<p>PORTUGAL, Sept 2 - Leixoes - 15 vessels operating of which 8 general cargo, 5 containers, 2 passenger. No vessels waiting, vacant places, 5 piers with cranes. Setubal, Sept 3 - Five vessels loading at berth, 4 discharging, 4 under repair/drydock. Vessels due - 5 to discharge, 7 to load, 3 for repairs.</p>
<p>ROMANIA, Sept 3 - Constanta - 43 vessels operating of which 25 general, 7 bulkers, 7 bagged chemicals, 2 tankers, 1 bagged cement, 1 container discharger. 12 vessels waiting in roads of which 7 general, 3 bulkers, 1 bagged chemicals, 1 tanker. Constantza South (Agigea) - 10 general cargo in port (8 loading/2 discharging), 1 bulker discharging. Mangalia - No vessels in port. Midia - Two livestock carriers loading.  </p>
<p>RUSSIA, Sept 2 - Baltic ports - St.Petersburg - 27 vessels operating of which 11 discharging - 1 sugar, 2 malt, 1 frozen chicken, 2 general cargo, 3 containers, 2 zinc ore. Loading - 4 non-ferrous, 4 fertiliser, 3 general cargo, 2 containers, 3 pulp. 5 vessels waiting, 23 due. Kaliningrad - three operating of which 1 coal loader, 1 fertiliser, 1 fish discharger. No delays, 1 vessel due. Vyborg - no vessels in port.</p>
<p>FAR EAST PORTS, Sept 3 - Vladivostok - 18 vessels in port of which 2 passenger, 10 loading (6 metal, 1 timber, 1 aluminium, 1 cotton, 1 general cargo), 6 waiting. Nakhodka - 12 in port of which 5 loading (4 metal, 1 timber), 1 tubes discharging, 6 waiting. Vostochniy - seven in port of which 5 loading (3 coal, 1 container, 1 metal), 2 discharging (1 cars, 1 tubes). Posyet - no vessels. Khasan - one loading metal. No delay/congestion/ strikes.</p>
<p>WHITE SEA, Archangel - 11 vessels in port of which 1 loading oil products, 4 sawn timber vessels berthed, 2 discharging gravel, 1 loading coal, 1 loading craft liner. 1 waiting to discharge (containers/general cargo), 1 sawn timber awaiting berth. 2 due to load oil products, 2 timber, 3 to load/discharge containers.</p>
<p>BLACK SEA, Novorossiysk - 14 vessels operating of which 8 loading, 2 scrap, 1 cement, 1 cast iron, 3 steel, 1 fertiliser, 5 discharging, 3 various, 2 rice, 1 cargo not nominated. 5 in roads, 4 to load - 1 general cargo, 1 steel, 1 copper, 1 wheat, 1 to discharge rice. 21 due of which 13 to load - 1 scrap, 5 steel, 2 slabs, 2 copper, 1 zinc, 1 other, 1 asbestos, 8 to discharge, 3 sugar, 1 general cargo, 2 zinc concentrate, 1 bananas, 1 planes. Oil terminal, Sept 3 - 4 tankers berthed, 2 loading crude, 1 diesel, 1 fuel oil, 6 in roads, 5 to load crude, 1 diesel. 4 due to load crude.</p>
<p>NORTHERN BASIN, Murmansk - three vessels operating of which 1 alumina, 1 cabotage, 1 wheat meal. No vessels waiting, 8 due in week of which 4 loaders (1 apatite, 2 NPK, 1 non-ferrous metal) 4 dischargers (2 alumina, 1 general cargo, 1 cabotage).</p>
<p>SLOVENIA, Sept 2 - Koper - 10 vessels berthed of which 3 loading (1 general, 1 bulker, 1 ferry), 4 discharging (2 bulkers, 1 car, 1 tanker), 3 containers loading/discharging, 13 due over next 2 days of which 3 to load (1 bulker, 2 general cargo), 7 to discharge (3 bulk carriers, 2 car carriers, 2 tankers), 3 container vessels to load/discharge.</p>
<p>SPAIN, Sept 2 - Aviles - four vessels operating, 2 discharging (1 blend, 1 scrap), 2 loading steel, 10 due Sept 2/3, no delays expected. Gijon - seven operating, 2 discharging (1 coal, 1 wood), 5 loading (2 cement, 1 general, 2 steel) 6 due, no delays.</p>
<p>Sept 3 - Pasajes - 16 in port, 8 discharging scrap, 1 each discharging magnesite, general cargo, potash, woodpulp. 1 discharging/loading cars. No delays. Cadiz - 15 operating of which 4 ro/ro, 1 sand, 1 tourist, 2 wheat, 1 semolina, 1 shipbuilding material, 1 clinker. 4 under repairs. No delays.</p>
<p>UKRAINE Sept 2 - Mariupol - six vessels loading at berth (2 metal products, 3 fertiliser, 1 slag), 5 discharging (3 general cargo, 1 metal products, 1 fertiliser), 5 waiting at anchorage to load (3 fertiliser, 1 metal products, 1 sulphur), 1 general cargo waiting to discharge, 9 floating storehouses of which 2 sulphur, 7 fertiliser 1 under repairs/dry-docked 19 due by 25/9 of which 8 to load (3 metal products, 3 coal, 1 coke, 1 fertiliser), 5 to discharge (2 fertiliser, 2 general cargo, 1 metal products), 6 to discharge/load general cargo. Kerch - two vessels under repairs/dry-docked, 1 due 4/9 to load metal products. Berdyansk - five loading at berth (3 metal products, 1 mustard seed, 1 coal).</p>
<p>Sept 3, Odessa - steel cargo loading, 5 vessels alongside 2 anchored 2 due. Grain loading, 4 vessels alongside, 1 anchored 1 due. Sugar discharging, no vessels alongside, 1 anchored. Tanker loading, 1 vessel alongside anchored. Tanker discharging, 1 alongside. General cargo, 1 vessel alongside. Ilyichevsk - steel cargo loading, 8 vessels alongside, 2 anchored.</p>
<p>YUGOSLAVIA, Sept 3 - Bar - eight vessels berthed of which 1 discharging granite, 1 discharging gasoline, 1 discharging gas oil, 1 discharging bananas, 2 loading steel coils, 2 loading alumina, no delays. Zelenika/Bijela - two vessels berthed of which 1 discharging jet fuel, 1 discharging gasoil, 4 vessels under repairs, no delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
