<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31589" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovakia - Sept 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>SME - Slovak and Czech steel producers VSZ and Trinecke Zelezarny (TZ) signed an agreement on commercial cooperation aimed at strenghtening positions of both firms on markets in eastern Europe .</p>
<p>- VSZ spokesman Ladislav Jakubec said &quot;he had no information about any plans for VSZ's capital entry into TZ&quot;.</p>
<p>- The government dismissed four deputy ministers, of the interior, culture, economics and environment, but gave no reason for the move.</p>
<p>- Losses of Slovakia's primary agricultural production are expected to total between 1.5 and two billion crowns in the first half of this year, compared with losses of 2.8 billion crowns in the same period last year.</p>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - Druha obchodna a.s., the new owner of 45.9 percent in oil and gas storage firm Nafta, said it fully supported the current management of the company.</p>
<p>- Nafta plans to increase its storage capacity to more than 2.5 billion cubic metres of gas by 1998 from the current capacity of two billion cubic metres.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Magnesite materials producer Slovmag Lubenik said it was now exporting 90 percent of its overall annual production, totalling some 80,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>- Kovo Sipox Gelnica has signed a contract for production of maritime ship cargo containers with German firm Toben. The current production is 20 containers a month and Kovo Sipox said it could double this if it had more money.</p>
<p>- This year's potato harvest is expected to cover domestic consumption fully.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
