<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31583" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: German leader urges patience on Czech accord.</title>
<headline>German leader urges patience on Czech accord.</headline>
<dateline>POLICKA, Czech Republic 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German President Roman Herzog on Wednesday called on young Czechs and Germans to be patient in waiting for a joint declaration by their countries aimed at formally closing the book on World War Two.</p>
<p>In a newspaper interview in Germany meanwhile, Czech President Vaclav Havel said Bonn was largely responsible for long delays in signing the declaration, intended to be issued by both countries' parliaments.</p>
<p>Bonn and Prague have been working for more than a year on the declaration which recognises Nazi atrocities as well as brutality during the mass expulsion of ethnic Germans from the former Czechoslovakia after the war.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that some of you hoped that we would already have the German-Czech declaration, on which our governments are working, on the table at this meeting,&quot; Herzog told a youth meeting in the Czech town of Policka which Havel also attended.</p>
<p>&quot;I am quite sure that it will come,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I believe, like Vaclav Havel, that there are immensely difficult problems -- above all psychological problems -- to deal with and therefore the greatest care is called for; this cannot be achieved in a few weeks,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In an interview with the Sueddeutsche Zeitung published on Wednesday, Havel indicated that only the question of political will remained and he laid the blame at Germany's door.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me that the hold-up is more on the German side than the Czech side,&quot; said Havel, who has campaigned to end mistrust between the two nations which persists more than half a century after the Nazi occupation.</p>
<p>Agreement has been held up by objections from leaders of the 2.5 million ethic &quot;Sudeten Germans&quot; expelled in the mid 1940s after they were collectively held responsible for betraying Czechoslovakia during the 1938-45 occupation.</p>
<p>Mainstream Czech political parties largely kept the issue out of campaigning for parliamentary elections in May.</p>
<p>But relations with the Czechs, the last major outstanding issue between Germany and the countries the Nazis invaded, have become entangled in domestic German politics.</p>
<p>Many Sudetens and their descendants live in Bavaria and the Bavarian-based Christian Social Union (CSU), a member of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's coalition, has backed their cause.</p>
<p>Czech politicians believe that CSU backing has given the Sudeten lobby influence in the federal German government out of proportion to its importance.</p>
<p>Speaking in Policka, Havel said an opportunity had been lost by not settling the issue in 1990. In that year Havel apologised for holding all Sudetens guilty of betraying their country to Nazi Germany, when some -- albeit a minority -- had remained loyal to the democratic Czechoslovak state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POLICKA, Czech Republic"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
