<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31597" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Two Poles stand trial for making child pornography.</title>
<headline>Two Poles stand trial for making child pornography.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two men went on trial in Poland on Wednesday on charges of using 12 and 13-year-old boys to make pornographic films, PAP news agency reported.</p>
<p>A shoemaker named only as Grzegorz D, and mineworker Miroslaw G, face up to 10 years in prison if found guilty.</p>
<p>To protect the children involved, the judge at the Rzeszow regional court in southeastern Poland ordered that the trial take place behind closed doors.</p>
<p>PAP reported the official charges as stating that the men picked up young teenagers outside railway stations, schools and children's care centres.</p>
<p>The two allegedly persuaded the boys to make the films, sometimes in bathhouses, hotels or the open air, in return for small sums of money or gifts of sweets and wine.</p>
<p>The main prosecution witness is a local Rzeszow journalist who, with his editors' approval, posed as a dealer in such films and agreed to cooperate with the two men.</p>
<p>&quot;On the road to Warsaw, where the first transaction was to take place, they were arrested by police,&quot; PAP said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
