<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31590" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Sept 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - President Vaclav Havel and Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus met officially yesterday for the first time since the forming of the new cabinet. They agreed upon a commission to look into the recent banking crisis as well as a closer coordination regarding foreign politics.</p>
<p>- Direct foreign investment in the Czech Republic reached 458 million dollars (12.5 billion crowns) in the first half of 1996. This marks an increase of 17.1 percent over the year before.</p>
<p>- Revenues and expenditures in the 1997 state budget should be approximately equal. Last week the government agreed on allowing expenditures of 549.1 billion crowns. Two variants on the level of revenues allow for 556 billion crowns and 549.9 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- In the course of the first seven months of 1996, the balance sheet total of Foresbank a.s. reached 16 billion crowns. The value of the bank's accounts exceeded 10 billion crowns for the first time ever.</p>
<p>- Shareholders in Ceska Pojistovna are to meet tomorrow to decide, among other things, upon the issue of 1.137 billion crowns worth of stock, effectively increasing their basic capital to 3.412 billion crowns.</p>
<p>- Investicni a Postovni Banka has yet to decide upon increasing its basic capital through the issue of global depositary receipts. The volume and issue date of which will be decided upon within 14 days.</p>
<p>- Agrobanka, the largest Czech monetary institute without state participation, posted a profit of 206 million crowns in the first seven months of this year. Half a billion crowns of profit is expected by year end.</p>
<p>- The exact delay in the construction of the Temelin nuclear power plant will be known in the middle of November when CEZ, the project's investor, and the main distributors will sign an updated contract. The delay is expected to result in construction to be completed six or seven months after the originally expected September, 1997 date.</p>
<p>- Benzina a.s.'s recent price cuts at many of their pumps have caused many of their competitors to follow suit.</p>
<p>- The Ministry of the Defence is preparing reductions in its plans to modernise the army due to a long-term lack of funds. As a result the Army has resorted to investments as well as budget cuts.</p>
<p>PRAVO - Yearly contruction output in July increased by 17 percent, the second best economic yearly increase since October of last year when it increased by 20 percent.</p>
<p>- The board of directors of Chemopetrol a.s. decided to increase the company's basic capital to 10.846 billion crowns. Chemopetrol is also planning to fuse with Unipetrol by the end of March, 1997.</p>
<p>- Approximately 600 employees of Zbrojovka Vsetin received three months notice last week. The reorganization of the company was given as the reason for the layoffs.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsdesk, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
