<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31593" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish ruling parties row over minister's sacking.</title>
<headline>Polish ruling parties row over minister's sacking.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's tense ruling coalition appeared near breakdown on Thursday after the prime minister from the dominant ex-communist grouping sacked the foreign trade minister from the smaller Peasant party.</p>
<p>The government announced on Wednesday that Jacek Buchacz had been dismissed by the president, on a motion from Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz, after official probes had revealed a blurring of public and private interests.</p>
<p>A government statement said the investigation revolved around the issue of export guarantees.</p>
<p>Buchacz and fellow Polish Peasant Party (PSL) leaders angrily charged that the prime minister's Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) had not even told them in advance of the move.</p>
<p>&quot;The (SLD's) manner of dismissing Minister Buchacz, without informing its coalition partner, we view as an example of our partner's arrogant attitude,&quot; the PSL said in a statement.</p>
<p>Buchacz himself told a news conference: &quot;I regard my dismissal...as a clear breaking of the coalition agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>He accused the SLD of behaving like the ruling party did before the 1989 fall of communism and added ominously: &quot;l would like to believe that the SLD-PSL coalition still exists.&quot;</p>
<p>PSL chiefs entered hasty talks with the SLD leadership on Wednesday but soon broke them off, saying they would call a meeting of their own party on Friday to decide whether to resume the discussions.</p>
<p>PSL deputy Stanislaw Bartoszek suggested the sacking was an SLD move to break up the coalition and cause early parliamentary polls, otherwise not due until September 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a confrontational move, designed to put the blame on the PSL for the dissolution of the coalition and early elections,&quot; Bartoszek told Reuters.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz denied he had taken the Peasants by surprise, saying he had told one of their leaders in advance that he had asked President Aleksander Kwasniewski to sack Buchacz. Other SLD leaders said the coalition should not be in danger.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz did not reveal details of the issue that prompted the sacking, except that it had emerged in June but he had awaited reports from inspection bodies before acting.</p>
<p>The PSL said the removal of Buchacz was the SLD's response to his persistent warnings that Poland's official foreign trade deficit was likely to balloon to $10 billion by the end of 1996 from $1.8 billion last year.</p>
<p>The two parties have most recently clashed over the distribution of cabinet posts during a gradual reorganisation of central government ministries due this year.</p>
<p>The coalition has linked the two parties rooted in the old communist system, through two cabinet reshuffles and several major rows, since the 1993 polls in which they defeated parties stemming from the anti-communist Solidarity movement.</p>
<p>Buchacz, 48, had been foreign trade minister since early 1995. Several weeks ago the government rejected plans by Buchacz to set up a new export guarantee system.</p>
<p>His post will be temporarily filled by deputy foreign trade minister Janusz Kaczurba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
