<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31596" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FOCUS- AIB to take control of WBK.</title>
<headline>FOCUS- AIB to take control of WBK.</headline>
<byline>Steven Silber</byline>
<dateline>POZNAN, Poland 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Allied Irish Banks Plc (AIB) plans to take a majority state in Poland's Wielkopolski Bank Kredytowy SA (WBK) -- a regional bank that does similar business to its own, AIB's president said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, AIB said it aimed to raise its 36.3 percent stake of WBK to a majority within three years from February 1997 by buying up to 23.9 percent of WBK currently held by the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD).</p>
<p>&quot;Our intention would be to exercise the option (to acquire EBRD's stake),&quot; Tom Mulcahy told a news conference.</p>
<p>Mulcahy said the two banks were compatible because they both were based in essentially agricultural regions where light industry dominated.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite confident about regional banks...because we believe that is where our strength as a company lies,&quot; he said. &quot;We should not try to imitate other banks.&quot;</p>
<p>Mulcahy said AIB European Investment Ltd, a wholly-owned AIB subsidiary, which holds WBK's shares, had no immediate plans to buy other banks in the region.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, WBK and AIB also signed a letter of intent on setting up a trust fund corporation and an asset management company in Poland.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to begin a family of funds sometime next year, starting with a balanced fund,&quot; Justin Konieczny, adviser to WBK's president on investment banking, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The planned joint-venture, which will run the group of funds, will be fully owned by the asset management company, in turn equally owned by WBK and AIB.</p>
<p>WBK, based in the western Polish city of Poznan, is also interested in buying the central-bank-owned Polish Investment Bank SA (PBI) and Prosper Bank SA.</p>
<p>Jacek Ksen, president of WBK, told Reuters his bank was competing with four or five others to acquire both firms and WBK would make a detailed financial analysis of PBI and Prosper Bank in September.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't make any decisions before a deep examination,&quot; Ksen said.</p>
<p>WBK had a net profit of 93.4 million zlotys over the first seven months of this year versus 59.5 million zlotys in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POZNAN, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
