<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31592" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Pressure mounts on Bosnia's chief election monitor.</title>
<headline>Pressure mounts on Bosnia's chief election monitor.</headline>
<byline>Dan de Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western powers, anxious to ensure smooth post-war elections in Bosnia, are pushing to sideline the chief of a team of independent observers who may cast doubt on the validity of the poll, analysts say.</p>
<p>Ed Van Thijn, coordinator of international observers in Bosnia, has emerged as a key figure for major powers who see him as a potential obstacle to certifying Bosnian elections on September 14 as &quot;free and fair&quot;, said analysts from the International Crisis Group (ICG), a think-tank in Sarajevo.</p>
<p>Van Thijn, former interior minister in the Netherlands, is known as an independent-minded man who has already publicly pronounced the pre-election process as a &quot;fraud&quot;.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation (OSCE), which is overseeing the elections and nominally oversees the observer group, promptly disowned Van Thijn's comments in a lengthy statement last month.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a move afoot to rein in the loose cannon,&quot; John Fawcett, deputy director of the International Crisis Group (ICG), told Reuters. &quot;They're trying to find any way they can.&quot;</p>
<p>Under arrangements anchored in the Dayton peace agreement which ended fighting in former Yugoslavia last November, Van Thijn has the authority to declare within 24 hours after the elections whether the electoral process was &quot;free and fair&quot;.</p>
<p>Van Thijn's conclusions are then sent to the chairman of the OSCE in Vienna, Flavio Cotti.</p>
<p>The Dayton treaty specifically states the elections, which are supposed to reunify the ethnically divided country, should be &quot;free and fair&quot;.</p>
<p>Human rights workers say conditions for free and fair elections do nost exist at all in Bosnia. They say the registration process was plagued by abuses and nationalist authorities have stifled free speech and free movement.</p>
<p>Whatever Cotti decides, a damning report from Van Thijn would be extremely embarassing for the United States and its European allies which have devoted tremendous resources to portraying the elections as legitimate.</p>
<p>Diplomats from the so-called &quot;Contact Group&quot;, the United States, Britain, France, Germany and Russia, are conferring in European capitals this week about Van Thijn's role and the thorny issue of certifying the elections.</p>
<p>The matter may come to a head on Monday, when Van Thijn is expected to travel to Switzerland to meet Cotti and the American envoy heading up the OSCE mission in Bosnia, Robert Frowick, diplomatic sources said.</p>
<p>Frowick was already forced to postpone municipal elections due to irregularities with voter registration. He has said that short of renewed warfare, the national elections will take place as scheduled on September 14.</p>
<p>Senior officials on Van Thijn's team say he has hinted he might step down rather than abide by a watered-down mandate.</p>
<p>If Western governments remove his power to report on the integrity of the elections, Van Thijn says he would become a &quot;short-term observer&quot;, the officials quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Referring to diplomatic meetings in Brussels and Frankfurt this week, the officials said his mandate would probably be decided &quot;in the next few days&quot;.</p>
<p>Van Thijn, who coordinates some 600 to 800 monitors, has planned to conduct a extensive survey of voters on election day to assess voting conditions.</p>
<p>If the elections are declared invalid or called into question, the international community, particularly the United States, could be drawn into a deeper military and diplomatic commitment which it wants to avoid, analysts say.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton has already promised to bring some 20,000 American troops home after they finish their one- year mission in December as part of the NATO-led peace force.</p>
<p>An inconclusive election result would place pressure on Washington to commit to a bigger military presence than envisaged and upset an ambitious timetable for the peace process set out by the Dayton accord.</p>
<p>Within 10 days of the certification, the High Representative to Bosnia, has the authority to recommend that the U.N. Security Council permanently lift economic sanctions against Belgrade. The sanctions were suspended in November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
