<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31606" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: Slovakia preparing new bankruptcy law - PM.</title>
<headline>Slovakia preparing new bankruptcy law - PM.</headline>
<byline>Jan Krcmar</byline>
<dateline>PIESTANY, Slovakia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovakia is preparing new bankruptcy legislation aimed at speeding up and simplifying the process so that banks could restructure their loan portfolios, Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Around 20 percent of Slovak enterprises are ripe for bankruptcy, or receivership,&quot; Meciar told a news conference after the first session of a four-day meeting of the country's economic and financial experts.</p>
<p>&quot;We are planning to create mechanism for bankruptcy procedures and enable banks to move their assets into profitable capital investments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The meeting in this western Slovak spa town is billed as a no-holds-barred session that should map the country's economic plans to the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;All opinions are allowed, there is no pulling of rank at this meeting,&quot; Meciar said in his opening speech earlier on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said the government and the banking sector were also discussing ways to write off irretrievable loans.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment these loans are on the books as assets and the banks pay tax on them. We must find ways to restructure this state of affair,&quot; Meciar said.</p>
<p>Last year, the Slovak banking sector had classified loans of around 90 billion crowns, most of them held by the four largest financial institutions.</p>
<p>They are required to provision additional reserves of around 30 billion crowns to cover them.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeking an agreement on restructuring these reserves and enable them to be used for concrete investment,&quot; Meciar said.</p>
<p>He added several of Slovakia's smaller banks might be urged to merge to increase competition in the domestic financial market.</p>
<p>Slovakia was also planning to set up by the end of this year an export-import bank with two billion crowns in basic capital to support the country's foreign trade, Meciar said,</p>
<p>Slovakia's foreign trade balance has swung to a deficit of 31.9 billion crowns in the first seven months of the year, after a foreign trade surplus of 1.8 billion crowns posted for the entire 1995. -- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-210-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PIESTANY, Slovakia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
