<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31603" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish trade minister fired, brings coalition row.</title>
<headline>Polish trade minister fired, brings coalition row.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Barker</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's president sacked Foreign Trade Minister Jacek Buchacz on Wednesday, rekindling smouldering tensions between the two parties in the ruling leftist coalition.</p>
<p>A government statement said Buchacz, 48, was fired on a motion by Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz after official probes revealed an improper blurring of public and private interests in the granting of export guarantees.</p>
<p>&quot;The motion of the head of cabinet in this matter is linked with a need to guarantee better care over the interests of the state treasury,&quot; the government statement said.</p>
<p>Heads of Buchacz's Polish Peasant Party (PSL) and the larger ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) of Cimoszewicz held a crisis meeting in Warsaw after the announcement, but most of the Peasant delegation quickly left the gathering.</p>
<p>Peasant deputy Stanislaw Bartoszek said his party had not been consulted over the sacking and this was an SLD move towards breaking up the coalition and causing early parliamentary polls, otherwise not due until September 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a confrontational move, designed to put the blame on the PSL for the dissolution of the coalition and early elections,&quot; Bartoszek told Reuters.</p>
<p>The government statement said the sacking of Buchacz was closely related to inspections by the Supreme Auditing Chamber (NIK) and the Cabinet Supervision Office -- two powerful official oversight bodies.</p>
<p>It said the probes concerned &quot;the involvement of the treasury in ventures concerning export guarantees, in which state and private property is connected in a way that lacks sufficient clarity.&quot;</p>
<p>Buchacz was not immediately available for comment but was due to hold a news conference later in the evening.</p>
<p>The PSL and SLD have most recently clashed over the distribution of cabinet posts during a reorganisation of central government due this year, but had appeared to settle their differences with a so-far undisclosed compromise.</p>
<p>The coalition has been trying to stay together at least until parliamentary elections due in September next year.</p>
<p>Buchacz, 48, has been foreign trade minister since early 1995. He was appointed by the previous Prime Minister Jozef Oleksy and inherited the portfolio in the current cabinet.</p>
<p>Several weeks ago the government rejected plans submitted by Buchacz to set up a new export guarantee system. His dismissal was formally signed by President Aleksander Kwasniewski.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
