<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31602" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UZBEKISTAN: Western Mining, Uzbekistan set up gold venture.</title>
<headline>Western Mining, Uzbekistan set up gold venture.</headline>
<dateline>TASHKENT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Western Mining Corporation (WMC) will set up a joint venture with Uzbekistan to exploit its Zarmitan gold deposit, a WMC official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Jonathan Saunders, head of the WMC branch in Uzbekistan, told reporters the deposit, 90 km (56 miles) north-west of Samarkand, holds an estimated 24 million tonnes of auriferous ore containing 10 grams of gold per tonne.</p>
<p>Saunders said WMC, which won an investment tender in February this year, plans to build a gold processing plant with an upgraded purification system.</p>
<p>He did not provide data for the capital structure of the future joint venture and the expected production capacity of the plant, but said that WMC was planning to invest a total of roughly $100 million in the project.</p>
<p>The joint venture plans to produce an alloy containing 86 to 90 percent of gold with further purification at two Uzbek plants.</p>
<p>Further economic and technical studies will take another 18-24 months after necessary documents are signed, he said.</p>
<p>Uzbek President Islam Karimov has estimated his country's natural reserves of gold at 5,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UZBK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TASHKENT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UZBEKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
