<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31609" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: Skopje and Belgrade sign $1 billion trade pact.</title>
<headline>Skopje and Belgrade sign $1 billion trade pact.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The prime ministers of Macedonia and Yugoslavia signed trade agreements in the Macedonian capital on Wednesday, sealing a pact that the Yugoslav Prime Minister said would be worth $1 billion in its first 12 months.</p>
<p>Macedonian Prime Minister Branko Crvenkovski and his Yugoslav counterpart, Radoje Kontic, signed seven separate documents, including an agreement on customs cooperation and the regulation of rail and air traffic.</p>
<p>&quot;Together, the agreements envisage the exchange (of trade worth) $1 billion over the next year,&quot; Kontic told reporters.</p>
<p>The agreements cap a mutual recognition pact that normalised relations between the two neighbours last April, ending five years of animosity in the wake of the violent disintegration of the former Yugoslav federation.</p>
<p>Macedonia split away from the old Yugoslavia in 1991, along with the republics of Slovenia, Croatia and Bosnia.</p>
<p>While both Skopje and Belgrade welcomed the trade accords, diplomats say a border dispute could still be a source of friction. A joint commission is studying the problem.</p>
<p>If Kontic's forecast of $1 billion in official trade is realised, it would restore economic ties to the level that economists estimate existed during war-time sanctions.</p>
<p>In 1992 the United Nations imposed wide-ranging economic sanctions on rump Yugoslavia, consisting of Serbia and Montenegro, over its role in the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>But economists estimate that bilateral trade reached $1.1 billion at the height of sanctions in 1995, about half the pre-sanctions trade which totalled $2.5 billion in 1989.</p>
<p>Kontic said trade across the border added up to $201 in the first six months of this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
