<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31601" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: OSCE funds suspected war criminal's party.</title>
<headline>OSCE funds suspected war criminal's party.</headline>
<byline>Dan de Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>International organisers of Bosnia's post-war elections confirmed on Wednesday that a Serb political party led by a suspected war criminal has qualified for 300,000 marks ($202,100) in campaign funds.</p>
<p>The Party of Serb Unity, led by notorious paramilitary commander Zeljko Raznatovic &quot;Arkan&quot;, receives campaign funding under rules set by the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), which oversees the elections, officials said.</p>
<p>Some 7.5 million marks ($5 million) was given to the OSCE by big powers to help political parties with office and advertising expenses for the September 14 poll, OSCE officials said.</p>
<p>Election organisers defended the campaign funding for Arkan and other parties saying the OSCE could only disqualify candidates or parties based on indictments handed down by the International Criminal Tribunal for Former Yugoslavia (ICTY).</p>
<p>Arkan was named as a suspected war criminal by the U.S. State Department. He was not indicted by the Hague tribunal.</p>
<p>Human rights groups accuse Arkan and his paramilitary &quot;Tiger&quot; unit of orchestrating brutal &quot;ethnic cleansing&quot; of Moslems and Croats in eastern Bosnia early in the war.</p>
<p>U.N. officials also allege Arkan's forces killed prisoners of war last year in northwest Bosnia, near Sanski Most.</p>
<p>The paramilitary commander, wanted by Interpol for earlier bank robbery and other crimes, dismisses the charges and enjoys celebrity status in neighbouring Serbia where he lives in an elaborate mansion in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Arkan himself is not running for office in Bosnia but his smiling portrait appears on leaflets handed out in Bosnian Serb territory, where he has opened a branch of his party.</p>
<p>OSCE officials said they did disqualify two candidates from Arkan's party who have been indicted by the U.N. tribunal.</p>
<p>The OSCE has already given a portion of the 300,000 marks to Arkan's party which will then have to submit receipts for campaign expenses, officials said.</p>
<p>In campaign literature paid for by the OSCE, Arkan's candidates oppose reunification of Bosnia as required by the Dayton treaty and advocate unifying with neighbouring Serbia.</p>
<p>Jean Ouellet, an OSCE official supervising political parties, said his office could not &quot;censor&quot; political statements unless candidates made open appeals to violence.</p>
<p>&quot;The political campaign funding is basically for all political parties to get their message across. We may not like some of them, we may not agree with some of them but we cannot censor them,&quot; Ouellet told reporters.</p>
<p>An opposition party headed by former prime minister Haris Silajdzic said it was &quot;&quot;outraged&quot; that Arkan's party received financial support from the international community.</p>
<p>The OSCE said 40 parties and 27 independent candidates were awarded funds based on their level of participation in the election, ranging from 22,500 marks for parties to a ceiling of 600,000 for coalitions. OSCE spokesmen could not explain the criteria for the amount of money set aside for Arkan's party. ($1=1.4846 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
