<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31612" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: IMF urges Bulgaria to stabilise banks, up revenue.</title>
<headline>IMF urges Bulgaria to stabilise banks, up revenue.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) urged Bulgaria on Wednesday to take action to build public confidence in local troubled banks and to boost tax collection.</p>
<p>The IMF postponed an urgently needed, second, $115 million tranch of its funding programme for Bulgaria sealed in July, due to Sofia's delay in meeting structural reform targets and closing down lossmaking enterprises.</p>
<p>&quot;We have recommended to the government to complete as quickly as possible its bank stabilisation programme,&quot; said IMF mission leader Anne McGuirk after a two-week mission to Sofia.</p>
<p>She was speaking at a meeting with foreign investors organised by the Bulgarian International Business Association.</p>
<p>Last month the central bank hiked capital requirements for banks for licences, to take effect March 31 next year.</p>
<p>Bankers have said a second wave of bank closures was possible early in 1997 if undercapitalised banks fail to stablise or merge into larger institutions.</p>
<p>Four months ago the central bank sought to have five major banks declared bankrupt in a bid to offset a bank crisis, though the courts will not rule on this until mid-Septmeber.</p>
<p>&quot;It does not make sense to wait, insolvent banks do not have prospects for rehabilitation and it only increases the ultimate cost of cleaning up the whole banking system,&quot; said McGuirk.</p>
<p>There was plenty of money in Bulgaria, but it was not in the central bank or commercial banking system, said McGuirk.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to see resources return into the commercial banking system which is shrinking now,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>McGuirk also urged the government to improve its tax collection in line with international recommendations.</p>
<p>&quot;It is counter-productive to keep increasing existing rates. The problem is collecting the taxes,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>One of the problems in Bulgaria was how to integrate the informal economy. The formal private economy was overtaxed because the government had not determined how to deal with the grey economy.</p>
<p>The Socialist government introduced a complicated taxation system under which taxes for private businesses amount to two-thirds of their revenue.</p>
<p>More business are forced to operate in the so-called informal or grey economy to keep afloat, local economists said. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
