<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31618" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: De Beers says Russia talks positive, no deal yet.</title>
<headline>De Beers says Russia talks positive, no deal yet.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia and De Beers have yet to reach a final agreement in their latest round of talks on a new three-year diamond deal but a De Beers official said that negotiations had been positive.</p>
<p>Raymond Clarke, head of De Beers' Moscow representation, declined to say when an agreement might be reached with Almazy Rossii-Sakha (ARS, or Diamonds of Russia-Sakha), which is Russia's largest diamond producer and sole authorised exporter.</p>
<p>&quot;I really can't speculate on when an agreement will be signed,&quot; Clarke said, after a day of talks.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether talks would continue on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are proceeding along the lines of the memorandum of understanding,&quot; Clarke said. &quot;I can tell you that we've had a very useful, positive couple of days.&quot;</p>
<p>De Beers Consolidated Mines Ltd signed a memorandum with the Russian government in February under which it will take half of Russia's rough diamond output.</p>
<p>But a formal agreement between the South African group and ARS has yet to be reached.</p>
<p>Clarke did not comment on an Itar-Tass news agency report that Russia's new industry ministry had named a former diamond official to head its department for precious metals and stones.</p>
<p>Tass quoted sources in the recently-formed ministry as saying Vladimir Piskunov, formerly a vice-president of ARS, had been appointed department chief.</p>
<p>Under its previous agreement with De Beers, Russia had to sell 75 percent of its stones through De Beers's Central Selling Organisation.</p>
<p>-- Lynnley Browning, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
