<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31627" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Baltics welcome Holbrooke but oppose regional group.</title>
<headline>Baltics welcome Holbrooke but oppose regional group.</headline>
<byline>Ed Stoddard</byline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Baltic states on Wednesday welcomed the appointment of U.S. troubleshooter Richard Holbrooke to a Baltic Sea Council but opposed a proposal to set up a Nordic/Baltic military grouping.</p>
<p>Holbrooke, the former U.S. assistant Secretary of State who brokered the Bosnia peace deal last year, took his place on a Swedish-sponsored advisory board on Baltic Sea cooperation in Stockholm on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>The 10-member body will examine Baltic issues with security topping the agenda.</p>
<p>All three Baltic states are seeking a place in the new European security order after breaking free from the former Soviet Union in 1991, and are hoping to join the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organisation (NATO).</p>
<p>&quot;We're pleased to see a statesman of his (Holbrooke's) stature participating in this process and welcome his appointment,&quot; a senior Lithuanian foreign ministry official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope Holbrooke will use his influence to support our desire to join NATO, which is our central foreign policy goal.&quot;</p>
<p>Bids for the first round of new EU members have to be ready by mid-1997 and NATO will decide next year with which countries it will hold discussions over membership.</p>
<p>Nordic and Western countries do not wish to see the three Baltics, Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania, drawn back into Russia's political sphere -- and the Baltics want to stay out.</p>
<p>But a proposal for a regional military network, put forward on Tuesday by Carl Bildt, former Swedish prime minister and current leader of the conservative party, was not well received.</p>
<p>Bildt proposed forming a North European partnership for peace (NPFP) to unite the Baltic states with the four Nordic states -- Sweden, Norway, Denmark and Finland -- in a military grouping.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not consider such regional arrangements as an option at this stage,&quot; the Lithuanian official said.</p>
<p>A Western diplomat based in Vilnius said as far as the Baltics were concerned, there was no alternatives to NATO.</p>
<p>Swedish Prime Minister Goran Persson told reporters after the meeting in Stockholm that he opposed any kind of regional grouping that could be seen as a NATO alternative.</p>
<p>&quot;It is wrong to now hop in with a different proposal,&quot; Persson said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BALTST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
