<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31628" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania poll hopeful starts countrywide campaign.</title>
<headline>Romania poll hopeful starts countrywide campaign.</headline>
<byline>Radu Sigheti</byline>
<dateline>RUGINOASA, Romania 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emil Constantinescu, main rival to President Ion Iliescu in Romania's November polls, struck deep into his opponent's heartlands on Wednesday to launch his campaign with a plea for the peasant vote.</p>
<p>On the first day of official campaigning in the country's third post-communist elections Constantinescu travelled to where his support is weakest, in the poor northern hill lands 400 km (250 miles) north-east of Bucharest.</p>
<p>Constantinescu, candidate of the Democratic Convention bloc (CDR) and losing presidential challenger in 1992, draws most of his support from Romania's big towns and cities.</p>
<p>Without the blanket state television coverage that sustains Iliescu's popularity in Romania's remote and undeveloped regions Constantinescu has begun what he calls a missionary voyage to spread his message of reform.</p>
<p>&quot;How can we be part of Europe with our muddy roads, with gas lamps and water carried from the village fountains, with villages without doctors and crumbling and empty schools,&quot; said Constantinescu, a 56-year-old academic.</p>
<p>Some 800 farmers and shepherds, some in traditional costume, gathered to hear a message of centre-right reform tailored for his village audience, with pledges to complete land hand-backs, ease credit for farm work and lessen taxes.</p>
<p>After his speech Constantinescu joined, along with his family, in a traditional peasant dance, in a populist touch that critics have said was lacking in his previous campaign. He has also been criticised for gaffes and political naivety.</p>
<p>He is still smarting from recent attacks by the ruling leftist Party of Social Democracy (PDSR), which charged he would betray the country by bringing back the exiled king if he was elected president on November 3.</p>
<p>To counter that accusation he struck a patriotic note by appearing in Ruginoasa, the summer residence of the 19th century founder of modern Romania, Alexandru Ioan Cuza.</p>
<p>&quot;Cuza is a symbol of reconciliation, reconstruction and a return to those who truly represent Romania's people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Constantinescu trails Iliescu in the opinion polls, although the CDR is more popular than the president's PDSR.</p>
<p>Iliescu, an ex-communist who ousted Stalinist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu in 1989 with the help of a popular revolt and has held power ever since, is a reluctant democrat who has failed to modernise Romania, says the opposition.</p>
<p>They charge that six years of lukewarm free-market reforms under Iliescu have enriched the PDSR and their friends through corruption while doing little to cure the country's real woes.</p>
<p>Constantinescu's manifesto promises a less aloof, more open style of government with a fierce attack on corruption and abuse of privilege.</p>
<p>&quot;The future government must be less preoccupied with staying in power and more with running the country,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Constantinescu claims he can defeat Iliescu's well-funded and professionally run campaign if he can get his message across in the countryside.</p>
<p>In Ruginoasa his reception was enthusiastic, although he was not greeted by the recently elected mayor, a PDSR member.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll vote for Emil and the Convention because they are not Bolsheviks,&quot; said Cosma Chiriac, 69, a weather-beaten peasant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RUGINOASA, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
