<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31625" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FOCUS-Polish PBR to place $50-$75 mln eurobond.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Polish PBR to place $50-$75 mln eurobond.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polski Bank Rozwoju SA (PBR) will issue a three-year Eurobond of $50 million to $75 million, placing it privately by mid-November, the Polish Development Bank's President Mieczyslaw Groszek said.</p>
<p>The issue will be led by Credit Suisse First Boston of the United States, Groszek told a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our shareholders and board have agreed that the issue be placed by mid-November this year,&quot; Groszek said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have finished the process of choosing an agent and advisor for the issue, which will be CS First Boston&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He said the Eurobond would help shift financing of state-controlled PBR's foreign currency credits to the longer-term and boost credit action, adding that there was a favourable climate on capital markets for Polish debt paper.</p>
<p>PBR's issue will be the third Eurobond placement by a Polish bank after the country returned to international financial markets last year with an official $250 million issue.</p>
<p>Poland's rating by Moody's Investor Service is now Baa3, while that of Standard and Poor's is BB.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect our Eurobonds to have similar yields to Bank Handlowy paper -- a couple of (basis) points higher or lower,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bank Handlowy's $100 million of three-year paper issued in April this year carried annual interest of seven percent.</p>
<p>PBR's planned issue has not received a rating yet, while Handlowy's public issue got a Baa3 from Moody's, but PBR's Eurobond will be directed to selected investors.</p>
<p>Groszek said the final size and yield of the Eurobond would be settled a week before the issue.</p>
<p>PBR aimed to use 45 to 65 percent of the funds raised to increase credit action, he added.</p>
<p>Groszek said PBR was considering further bond issues.</p>
<p>&quot;We will resort to bonds more often -- we are considering further issues, initially one denominated in zlotys,&quot; he said without giving details.</p>
<p>Groszek said that PBR planned by the end of the year to set up an investment fund called ATUT, along with Kleinwort Benson.</p>
<p>&quot;In the second half of the year our new investment fund will start up, but I cannot give details until it is registered,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank will also create a distinct corporate finance department, Groszek said.</p>
<p>He said that in the first half of 1996 PBR's net profits totalled 16 million zlotys, 66.6 percent more than in the same period of 1995, and most came from financial operations.</p>
<p>PBR is Poland's 14th largest bank measured by owned funds.</p>
<p>Poland's first corporate Eurobond was launched in April by Bank Rozwoju Eksportu SA (BRE), a three-year $50 million bond at 100 bp above LIBOR.</p>
<p>BRE on Wednesday said it had scrapped earlier plans to announce an issue this year of a further $100 million Eurobond.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not hold any more issues in 1996, but we will issue more dollar-denominated eurobonds in 1997,&quot; BRE President Krzysztof Szwarc told Reuters on Wednesday. -- Jacek Ramotowski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
