<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31637" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: New currency debut going calmly - Ukraine officials.</title>
<headline>New currency debut going calmly - Ukraine officials.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian government and central bank officials said introduction of the new hryvnya currency, launched on Monday, was going smoothly.</p>
<p>&quot;The worst is over. We were very worried in the days leading up to September 2 and now that day is behind us,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Viktor Pynzenyk said in a television address on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The hryvnya remained unchanged at 1.76 to the dollar on the Ukraine Interbank Currency Exchange on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have maintained stability on the currency exchange and we have maintained stability in the area of consumer prices,&quot; National Bank of Ukraine Chairman Viktor Yushchenko said.</p>
<p>Government and central bank officials have made frequent media appearances in the last few days to reassure Ukrainians they will not lose money during the currency reform programme.</p>
<p>The hryvnya replaces the temporary karbovanets currency introduced after independence in 1991, which will be withdrawn from circulation by September 16.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no overhanging threat that will devalue the hryvnya. We predict the measures that we are taking will strengthen the national currency,&quot; Yushchenko said.</p>
<p>The hyrvnya is worth 100,000 karbovanets, wiping five zeroes off Ukrainian prices. But Pynzenyk said the change is not simply a redenomination.</p>
<p>&quot;Monetary reform in Ukraine is not a straight denominational change. It will get people to put money into banks and will renew the investment climate,&quot; Pynzenyk said.</p>
<p>The central bank has said it has not intervened on the currency exchange to uphold the hryvnya, although some bankers have said the opposite is true and that the real level of the hryvnya will reveal itself once the karbovanets is withdrawn.</p>
<p>The karbovanets held the same level, at 176,000 to the dollar, for several months before the hryvnya's debut.</p>
<p>Yushchenko said the state savings bank Oshchadbank, Ukraine's largest with branches all over the country, had exchanged 17 trillion karbovanets ($10 million) during the first two days of this week.</p>
<p>Officials feared the public would begin panic buying of dollars because of fears the hryvnya would devalue.</p>
<p>The government also announced a month-long price freeze which started the day the hryvnya was introduced to stop businesses taking advantage of the change to push up prices.</p>
<p>Yushchenko also said the government had to close 180 exchange points which broke the law by selling the karbovanets at a rate 10 percent higher than the official rate.</p>
<p>--Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
