<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31638" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia steps up efforts to join NATO.</title>
<headline>Slovenia steps up efforts to join NATO.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian Defence Minister Jelko Kacin said on Wednesday his country had greatly increased international diplomatic and military activities in its bid to become a full member of NATO as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Recently Slovenia received senior military and government officials from the Netherlands, the United States and Norway. In the next two weeks the government is expecting officials from Germany and Belgium. A Slovenian delegation is to visit Rome within the same period to prepare a common army exercise.</p>
<p>&quot;All officials we talked to stressed that Slovenia is among the most serious candidates to become a member of NATO in its first stage of expansion, and acknowledged Slovenia had already fulfilled all NATO standards,&quot; Kacin told a news conference.</p>
<p>The 16-member North Atlantic Treaty Organisation is expected to decide when and how to enlarge the alliance by the end of this year and to start negotiations with the most promising candidates in 1997.</p>
<p>Kacin said Slovenia was glad to have an opportunity to host a three-day Regional Airspace Management Conference opening in the northwestern city of Bled on September 10.</p>
<p>&quot;The conference will show that Slovenia is several steps ahead of other central and eastern European states in terms of air-traffic control technology and its compatibility with NATO's technology,&quot; Kacin said.</p>
<p>If Slovenia is accepted into NATO, it would be the first ex-Yugoslav republic to be admitted.</p>
<p>Slovenia is already the first of the republics to sign an association agreement with the European Union and has formally applied to join the 15-member bloc. It is also a full member of the Council of Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
