<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31642" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Kohl sees calm NATO talks once elections over.</title>
<headline>Kohl sees calm NATO talks once elections over.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl, visiting Ukraine before a one-day trip to Moscow at the weekend, said calm talks on NATO expansion would be possible once the election season was over in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;Election time is not good for such talks,&quot; Kohl told a news conference, referring to Russia's July presidential election and the U.S. presidential poll in November.</p>
<p>He promised &quot;calm talks&quot; on expanding the Western alliance and said non-aligned Ukraine should not be left in an uncomfortable position between an enlarged NATO and Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia is our main partner (in the Commonwealth of Independent States) but it would be a very big mistake to think that the federal goverment and I, personally, look in only one direction -- to Moscow,&quot; Kohl told a news conference in Kiev.</p>
<p>&quot;The existence of a sovereign and independent Ukraine holds the greatest importance for us,&quot; he said at the end of a two-day visit to Ukraine.</p>
<p>He asked German investors to back Ukraine.</p>
<p>Ukraine, unlike Russia, is not directly opposed to the expansion of the NATO alliance, but Kiev wants the interests of all countries involved to be taken into account. It says nuclear arms should not be deployed in new member states.</p>
<p>&quot;Ukraine once had the world's third largest nuclear arsenal,&quot; Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma told the news conference. &quot;No one would deem us clever were we to support deployment of nuclear arms on new territories.&quot;</p>
<p>Poland, the Czech republic and Hungary are the favoured candidates for NATO membership.</p>
<p>Kohl said that no country had the right to veto another's membership in the North-Atlantic alliance -- a clear reference to the Kremlin's stance.</p>
<p>Kohl, a key advocate in the West of closer ties with Moscow, will visit President Boris Yeltsin at his holiday home near Moscow on Saturday, the first foreign leader to visit Yeltsin since before the Russian presidential election.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has been on holiday outside Moscow, and aides have denied a string of rumours that he is ill.</p>
<p>Ukrainian Prime Minister Pavlo Lazarenko said on Tuesday pressure should be put on Russia to reschedule Ukraine's $1 billion debt to Russia and the issue should be linked to rescheduling Moscow's multi-billion dollar debt to the West.</p>
<p>Germany, the Ukraine's largest European donor of financial and humanitarian aid, has granted Kiev three billion marks ($2 billion) in recent years.</p>
<p>Kohl promised that aid would continue and he called on German investors to get into the Ukrainian market.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not an appeal. But German businesses and investors should go to Ukraine. Here they can make good money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kohl left Kiev in the afternoon for a brief stopover in the Ukrainian Black Sea port of Odessa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
