<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31640" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Budapest bourse ends mixed, index closes lower.</title>
<headline>Budapest bourse ends mixed, index closes lower.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed mixed on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Wednesday, traders said, adding that while closing prices showed modest changes over yesterday the intraday changes were sharp.</p>
<p>The BUX index ended at 3,493.49 points, down 20.29. BUX index futures ended higher for the three closest maturities, firmed a half point for June 1997, and remained unchanged for the two farest terms.</p>
<p>Spot share turnover totalled 1.17 billion forints, BUX index futures deals generated 233.6 million forints.</p>
<p>As reflected by the index the market went through some correction, traders said, adding that while the short-term outlook was trendless, the long-term tendency is seen bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;The market just can't decide which direction to go to,&quot; Attila Gazdik of New York Broker Budapest said.</p>
<p>Many investors may emerge with the intention of profit-taking, traders said, adding that at the same time, with a positive long-term outlook, many may decide to start to open new long positions.</p>
<p>&quot;Many may regard current share prices quite attractive and the main question of the coming day will be how many decide to take profit,&quot; Gazdik said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless, I don't fear the rising trend would break.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said changes in expectations for a rate hike in the U.S. will remain one of the key influencing factors.</p>
<p>On Wednesday OTP Bank was a heavy gainer as it rose to peak at 2,615 forints, although later came down to end at 2,600, up 100.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
