<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31656" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: World Bank approves $24.3 million loan to Bulgaria.</title>
<headline>World Bank approves $24.3 million loan to Bulgaria.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Bank on Wednesday approved $24.3 million loan to Bulgaria to help finance a social insurance administration project, the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The project will support administrative reforms within the government's current social insurance programme by helping to restore the financial strength of its Social Security Fund (SSF),&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The project is aimed at assisting the government's reform goals by increasing the operational effciency of the newly formed national Social Security Institute (NSSI) and helping it develop a relationship with the private sector.</p>
<p>It is expected to replace the outdated pension payment system inherited from the communist regime which was completely subsidised by the state.</p>
<p>The dollar equivalent of the highest monthly pension in Bulgaria has melted down to a meagre $25 as a result of inflation and local currency depreciation.</p>
<p>The project due to be implemented over the next four years has a total cost of $32.2 million. Co-financing for the remaining cost will be sought from the European Union Phare programme, USAID, the UK know-How Fund and the NSSI.</p>
<p>The loan will be repayable over 20 years including five years grace.</p>
<p>World Bank commitments to Bulgaria total $893.3 million for tweleve projects since 1990, however less than half has been disbursed because of Bulgaria's delayed implementation of the various project stages.</p>
<p>-- Elisaveta Konstantinova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
