<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31651" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks rise, bullish trend seen lasting. [CORRECTED 14:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks rise, bullish trend seen lasting. [CORRECTED 14:00 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks rose with blue chips forging ahead on Wednesday, and market players predicted that the bullish trend would last for some time.</p>
<p>&quot;The current stable trend with mild growth in all share prices will continue,&quot; said one trader with a large market share, but noted a shortfall in volume for the most attractive, fully-listed issues. &quot;Volume could be limited because neither (drugs firm) Pliva nor Zagrebacka Banka share supply is overabundant.&quot;</p>
<p>* Five (Corrects from Six) of ten traded issues rose, one fell and three were unchanged. One firm made a debut on the bourse.</p>
<p>* Most active food processor Podravka, selling 3,245 shares, added five kuna to 235.</p>
<p>* The only loser, Varazdinska Banka second issue stock, traded on volume of 25 units, fell to 110 from 125 kuna in August.</p>
<p>* Pliva gained 100 kuna to 12,100 with 48 shares sold.</p>
<p>* Zagrebacka ordinary shares took a 15-kuna leap to 725 kuna on volume of 1,724.</p>
<p>* Confectioner Kras rose 20 kuna to 295 with 175 traded units.</p>
<p>* Istrian seaside hoteliers flat: Jadranturist at 160 kuna on volume of 179 shares, Arenaturist and Riviera at 100 kuna with 51 and 25 shares sold respectively.</p>
<p>* Shipper Atlantska Plovidba traded 53 shares at 90 kuna each in a first deal.</p>
<p>* Volume slightly lower at 5,637 shares, turnover 2.8 million kuna.</p>
<p>* Central bank's exchange rate: 5.2919 kuna = $ 1.</p>
<p>-- Kolumbina Bencevic, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
