<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31661" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish depo market squeezed, zloty just firmer.</title>
<headline>Polish depo market squeezed, zloty just firmer.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish one-day deposit market was squeezed for cash on Wedesday and rates rose as banks borrowed money to pay for T-bills bought at Monday's auction.</p>
<p>Dealers said bank accounts were also shortened by Tuesday's central bank drainage operations, which cleared 823 million zlotys from the market through a reverse repo and bill sale.</p>
<p>&quot;The wind was knocked out of the market by T-bill payments and recent drainage operations,&quot; said Malgorzata Sikora from ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Overnight rates closed at 18.80/19.30 percent, up from opening at 18.80/19.20 and Tuesday's close at 18.70/19.10.  </p>
<p>Tomorrow/next rates closed at 19.20/19.70 percent, up from 19.20/19.45 percent at opening and Tuesday's 18.80/19.20.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rise in T/N rates might signal that the market's tightness would carry over to Thursday, despite the early stage of Septbember's required reserve period.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to bid so high during the first few days of the new reserve period,&quot; ING's Sikora said.</p>
<p>Turnover on the secondary market was small, with trade focusing on 273-day NBP-bills, quoted at 19.90/19.70 percent, roughly half a point above the yield of a comparable 39-week T-bill in secondary trade.  </p>
<p>Dealers said regular NBP-bill auctions kept the market flooded with high-yielding 273-day bills, last sold at an average yield of 19.83 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The NBP wants the commercial banks to buy its higher yielding paper instead of T-bills as a part of its monetary policy,&quot; said Pawel Sadalski from ABN AMRO Bank (Polska) SA.</p>
<p>The zloty firmed a fraction against the currency basket, and after a live session with many sellers and buyers.</p>
<p>It closed at 1.75/1.70 percent from the trading band centre, just stronger Tuesday's close at 1.71/1.67 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;There were many transactions today but no clear trend formed,&quot; said Jaroslaw Mikolajczyk, forex dealer at Bank Amerykanski w Polsce SA.</p>
<p>It was at 2.7480/90 to the dollar, up from 2.7495/05 on Tuesday and at 1.8496/07 to the mark, just down from 1.8492/02.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
