<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31676" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: FORECAST -Ukraine Sept inflation seen at 1.5-2 pct.</title>
<headline>FORECAST -Ukraine Sept inflation seen at 1.5-2 pct.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's monthly inflation rate in September will fall back to 1.5-2.0 percent after jumping in August to 6.0-8.0 percent because of electricity price hikes, a senior official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The August and September inflation levels will be higher than in previous months but because of our policies to stabilise the economy, there will be no more shake-ups in inflation,&quot; deputy Economy Minister Viktor Kalnyk told national television late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ukraine achieved record low inflation rates of 0.1 percent in July and June, and the government expected annual inflation to fall to 40 percent from 182 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Ukrainian officials have said a rise in public utilities prices, encouraged by the International Monetary Fund which wants the government to eliminate consumer subsidies, caused inflation to spike up in August.</p>
<p>Though the government has not yet released official August inflation data, Interfax Ukraine news agency quoted Economy Ministry sources as saying it stood at 5.7 percent. Official data are expected to be released within the next several days.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Viktor Pynzenyk said small, seasonal price increases on the consumer market in autumn and minor, panic dollar buying due to the introduction of the new hryvnya currency on Monday, might have added to September inflation.</p>
<p>The hryvnya was unchanged at 1.760 to the dollar on the Ukraine Interbank Currency Exchange on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government ordered a month-long price freeze the day the hryvnya was introduced to prevent businesses from raising prices in the confusion and fuelling inflation, but many stores had raised prices before the hryvnya's debut. --Yuri Kulikov, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
