<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31675" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Kremlin breaks silence to praise Lebed rival.</title>
<headline>Kremlin breaks silence to praise Lebed rival.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin, keeping eerily quiet on Alexander Lebed's Chechnya peace deal, put his ambitious envoy firmly in his place on Wednesday by heaping praise on the man Lebed has said he cannot work with.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov got an award and a warm congratulatory letter for his 50th birthday on Wednesday, written in the flowery style of communist times.</p>
<p>&quot;I view your professional and personal qualities with great respect,&quot; said the letter, which followed the award of a medal, &quot;for services to the fatherland&quot;, on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lebed, who declared triumphantly that he had ended the 21-month-old Chechen conflict on Saturday, called on Yeltsin last month to choose between him and Kulikov, who he blamed for the fact the conflict had dragged on for so long.</p>
<p>Yeltsin said nothing at the time but the latest message from the Kremlin makes clear that call was out of line.</p>
<p>It also underlines the power play at the top of Russian politics surrounding the Chechnya deal, which has halted the fighting that cost tens of thousands of lives but has yet to be turned into a lasting peace.</p>
<p>Lebed's high-profile peace mission not only involves a humiliating withdrawal of troops from Chechnya, where the rebels are already showing signs of taking over, but also presents a danger that he will overshadow other top Russian politicians.</p>
<p>Even Yeltsin, whose decision to send troops to Chechnya in December 1994 started the conflict, could feel threatened by his outspoken envoy, who has presented himself as the peacemaker.</p>
<p>The president, who raised eyebrows by dropping out of the public eye in June, shortly before the final round of the election in which he won a second term, has greeted Lebed's peace deal with a deafening silence.</p>
<p>In the meantime Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin has acted as go-between, briefing the president at his residence outside Moscow and then expressing reservations on the deal, indicating it gave too much away to Chechnya's rebels.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Chernomyrdin at last gave it a cautious thumbs up. &quot;The agreements signed by Lebed cause some concern but on the whole we consider them right,&quot; he told a meeting of top North Caucasus officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We should act within the framework of these agreements and keep to their thrust.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts have speculated that Chernomyrdin, who would automatically step in if Yeltsin became seriously incapaciated and Lebed, who has not hidden his presidential ambitions, are jockeying for position in Yeltsin's absence.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Yeltsin's chief of staff Anatoly Chubais stepped into the ring.</p>
<p>&quot;One cannot say entirely that Lebed destroyed Russia and signed a capitulation, but one also cannot say that he deserves the Nobel prize,&quot; Interfax news agency quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's aides have been at pains to stress that the president's low profile is not a sign of failing health or a lack of control over policy.</p>
<p>But Yeltsin's office said once again on Wednesday that he was resting and unlikely to meet or talk to anyone by phone.</p>
<p>In the absence of his direct intervention, analysts said Kulikov, whose troops are still in Chechnya and getting increasingly restive at the free hand the rebels have been given over the deal, might still have a role in the power game.</p>
<p>&quot;Kulikov is not a big politician, he's a general. He wants to follow the orders of a politician,&quot; Sergei Markov of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace think-tank said. &quot;Chubais and Chernomyrdin might try to use Kulikov.&quot;</p>
<p>Lebed, not known for his diplomacy, has found it hard to contain his irritation at his boss's apparent lack of interest in his peace mission.</p>
<p>Asked if the plan could succeed without Yeltsin's direct approval, Lebed said on Tuesday, with typical dryness: &quot;I can do anything, but the president's direct support wouldn't hurt.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
