<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31687" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Economic issues fuel Russian fury at Iraq strikes.</title>
<headline>Economic issues fuel Russian fury at Iraq strikes.</headline>
<byline>Elaine Monaghan</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's tough stance against U.S. missile strikes on Iraq was fuelled by fears they could hurt its chances of recouping Baghdad's massive debt to the former Soviet Union, newspapers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The papers, analysing a complex Moscow position which appears to distance it from the West and bring it closer to Baghdad, said Russia had hoped to benefit from a United Nations agreement to let sanction-squeezed Iraq sell $2 billion of oil.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia's hopes of making money from Iraqi oil crashed with the explosion of the first missile,&quot; the Izvestia daily wrote.</p>
<p>The deal, aimed at bringing relief to the Iraqi people after six years of sanctions imposed after the Gulf War, foresees sales of oil in return for food, medicine and other goods.</p>
<p>But Britain's U.N. envoy Stephen Gomersall said the situation would have to revert to the status quo before oil sales could begin. After the deal was drawn up, Iraqi troops attacked the Kurdish north of the country, provoking two barrages of U.S. cruise missiles on southern Iraq.</p>
<p>The Russian government, the foreign ministry and President Boris Yeltsin's administration have reacted strongly to the U.S. attacks, launched on Tuesday and Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Russian government demanded a halt to all military action against Iraq and Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov said the bombings could lead to &quot;catastrophic consequences&quot; and &quot;anarchy&quot; on the world scene.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's chief-of-staff Anatoly Chubais said the president saw serious complications from the attacks.</p>
<p>But newspapers, aware that the row brought back memories of Cold War rivalries, also played up the economic angle.</p>
<p>&quot;Baghdad's debt to Moscow is about $7 billion and Iraq could return a significant part of that with free oil sales on the world market,&quot; the liberal opposition daily Nezavisimaya Gazeta wrote on its front page.</p>
<p>&quot;The Russian government was holding talks with Iraqi firms about joint...restoration of objects built with the help of the Soviet Union and destroyed during the 1991 war.&quot;</p>
<p>Russia has generally taken a softer line on Iraq than the United States since the end of the Gulf conflict, and has been pushing Washington and its Western European allies to lift crippling post-war sanctions against Baghdad.</p>
<p>Its position on the latest tension between President Saddam Hussein and the West was further complicated by the fact that Deputy Foreign Minister Viktor Posuvalyuk left Baghdad just a few hours before the first U.S. attack, Izvestia said.</p>
<p>Newspapers, echoing Primakov, suggested the air strikes were launched to help President Bill Clinton win the November presidential elections.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's closest rival in a June election and arch-enemy, Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov, backed the government line, accusing Washington of appointing itself a &quot;world policeman&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an unprecedented event which is making the whole planet nervous and these actions remind me of state terrorism. I fully back the Russian foreign ministry position,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Russian oil producers seemed content with the U.S. action. Interfax news agency quoted experts as saying producers and exporters stood to make an extra $7 on every tonne sold to the West in early September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
