<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31683" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugoslavia needs aid to reach pre-war GDP-official.</title>
<headline>Yugoslavia needs aid to reach pre-war GDP-official.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia warned on Wednesday it was unlikely to reach its pre-civil war GDP level by the year 2005 without financial help from abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;Yugoslavia's goal is to reach the pre-war level by the year 2005 with an average annual growth of seven percent,&quot; an official from the government's centre for development and economics said.</p>
<p>&quot;The projected growth, mostly based on a rise in imports, will be very difficult to reach without financial help from the International Monetary Fund and other financial organisations,&quot; said the official who declined to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;Without fresh funds either domestically or from abroad, the country will not be able to develop or to service its debt,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The violent disintegration of the former Yugoslav federation and international sanctions have been blamed for slashing Yugoslavia's GDP which fell to half its pre-war level in 1995.</p>
<p>In that year, GDP reached $15.9 billion, down by 44.7 percent against pre-war 1990. Income per capita last year stood at $1,500.</p>
<p>The official said existing differences between Yugoslavia, now comprising Serbia and Montenegro, and medium developed countries would widen further if the country could not reach its targeted GDP growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The development gap will increase drastically,&quot; the official said. &quot;And at that stage, no one will be interested in Yugoslavia as a country any more.&quot;</p>
<p>A Yugoslav delegation was due to begin talks with the IMF in Washington on Wednesday, hoping to bring down a so-called &quot;outer wall&quot; of economic sanctions which block the country's access to international money markets and finance. -- Gordana Kukic, Belgrade Newsroom 381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
