<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31684" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian lending rate rises to 8.7 from 7.8 pct.</title>
<headline>Croatian lending rate rises to 8.7 from 7.8 pct.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The average Croatian lending rate rose to 8.7 percent on Wednesday from 7.8 percent, boosted by a higher price of 15-30 day kuna loans despite weaker demand.</p>
<p>This coincided with higher rates paid by the central bank for its five- and 13-week liquidity paper at a weekly auction, reversing a downward trend over the past three months.</p>
<p>A total of 20 million kuna were settled on Zagreb's money market, of which dealers put fresh borrowing at 14 million.</p>
<p>They said thinning commercial banks' accounts caused interbank supply to shrink to 189 million, still largely overshooting demand.</p>
<p>The 15-30 day rate climbed to 12 from 11 percent.</p>
<p>Interbank loans were granted at a steady eight percent and insurers' funds at seven percent.</p>
<p>Tuesday's overnight trade doubled to 117.9 million after one bank bought 80 million for mandatory reserves, and the rest went for the covering of shortfalls at two other banks.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Croatia was again not active on the foreign exchange market. It calculated the kuna midrates for Thursday firmer at 5.2729 versus 5.2919 to the dollar and 3.5539 from 3.5590 against the German mark. -- Kolumbina Bencevic, Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
