<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31692" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Belgrade wants new draft plan for succession talks.</title>
<headline>Belgrade wants new draft plan for succession talks.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia has produced its own draft memorandum on carving up the old Yugoslavia's property, in response to an international document which the state-run Tanjug news agency described as unfair and inappropriate.</p>
<p>According to Tanjug, the negotiating team for the rump Yugoslavia, comprising Serbia and Montenegro, will present its version to talks with its former partners and international mediator Sir Arthur Watts in Brussels on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Since equal respect for the proposals and positions of all sides is essential for negotiations and since the number and nature of Yugoslavia's objections calls for more than partial amendments to the (Watts) memorandum, Yugoslavia has drawn up a memorandum of its own and submitted it to Watts,&quot; Tanjug said.</p>
<p>Watts is mediating negotiations between all the former republics to settle disputes over how the assets, debts and legal obligations of the old federation should be divided amongst the newly-independent states.</p>
<p>Tanjug criticised the Watts memorandum for &quot;prejudging the final settlement of all essential questions&quot;, and establishing a formula that favours the new states.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of insisting on the principle that joint investments must be distributed among all...the memorandum advocates a partial and physical distribution of the property of the (former) Yugoslavia,&quot; Tanjug said.</p>
<p>Belgrade's criticism of the Watts proposals followed a day of talks between officials from Slovenia, Bosnia, Croatia and Macedonia in the Slovenian capital Ljubljana on succession.</p>
<p>The new states said the negotiations made little progress, and insisted the Watts document would have to be altered significantly before talks could be concluded.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Miran Mejak of the Slovenian commission told a news conference that the most important issues related to Yugoslavia's assets held abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;For example we cannot agree that the new Yugoslavia simply retains embassies that used to belong to the former Yugoslavia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But in a television debate broadcast on Tuesday night, Belgrade's delegation insisted the key issues related to infrastructure built in the new states before they declared independence, but financed from the Yugoslav capital.</p>
<p>&quot;There are more than 9,000 facilities in question and we know exactly where they are,&quot; said delegation member Oskar Kovac. &quot;We feel those who hold these facilities owe the state since they were jointly financed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;(The Watts document) is not a memorandum of understanding but a memorandum of misunderstanding,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Belgrade's four-member team, led by accademic Kosta Mihajlovic, left the capital for Brussels on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
