<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31701" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia's Salus H1 profit down on lower margins.</title>
<headline>Slovenia's Salus H1 profit down on lower margins.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian drugs wholesaler Salus on Wednesday reported a drop in first-half net profit to 243.1 million tolars ($1.83 million) from 353.1 million tolars in the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason for the fall in profit was the government's reduction of trade margins for pharmaceutical trading companies,&quot; chief executive Igor Jenko said.</p>
<p>Salus' turnover for the six months to June 30 rose to 4.9 billion tolars ($ 37.3 million) from 4.8 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The company said the half-year dividend would remain unchanged at 500 tolars ($3.8) per share.</p>
<p>Salus' shares have risen 14.6 percent since August 27 when the Ljubljana district court found Salus not guilty of a faulty privatisation process. The shares closed at 14,625 tolars on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In February Salus appealed against a decision by the Slovenian Payment Agency requiring it to give the state an 80-percent stake in the company.</p>
<p>The agency said formerly state-owned Salus incorrectly transferred state capital to its newly established subsidiary Finsa in 1991.</p>
<p>The state does not currently own any part of Salus. -- Novica Mihajlovic, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
