<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31718" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Sept 4.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Wednesday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- The Pristina-Belgrade agreement for Kosovo Albanians, which was reached without Albanian President Sali Berisha, is seen as reducing his role as spokesman for Albanians in local and world affairs.</p>
<p>- Interior Minister Halit Shamata has reorganised Tirana's police to step up the fight against crime.</p>
<p>- Investigations into a Briton charged with sexually abusing minors have ended and his trial is to be held soon.</p>
<p>- Berisha and 14 parties are to meet in the afternoon on Wednesday to discuss election laws and upcoming local polls.</p>
<p>- The OSCE has sent a delegation to Tirana to discuss the October 20 local elections.</p>
<p>- After the Pristina-Belgrade agreement it is unlikely ethnic Albanians in Kosovo will boycott Serbia's November 3 elections, as threatened some time ago.</p>
<p>- Albanians have taken up nude bathing on some beaches.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- President Berisha is to propose a major simplification of voting procedures, and will discuss the &quot;genocide law&quot; and changes to political parties at a meeting this afternoon.</p>
<p>- European groups have voiced concern about a possible boycott of the local elections by the opposition Socialists.</p>
<p>- Police in the north have been ordered to take care of sheep smuggling in order to prevent foot-and-mouth disease.</p>
<p>- The probability of higher inflation seems to have pushed banks to increase their interest rates for savings accounts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
