<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31715" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechens pledge to avoid civil war.</title>
<headline>Chechens pledge to avoid civil war.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Lannin</byline>
<dateline>URUS-MARTAN, Russia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>When people say darkly that the withdrawal of Russian troops from Chechnya will plunge the breakaway region into civil war, Urus-Martan is one of the places mentioned as a potential powder keg.</p>
<p>But both separatists and supporters of the Russian-backed Chechen government in this town, 25 km (16 miles) southwest of the Chechen capital Grozny, said they saw little chance of civil strife if a peace deal between Moscow and the rebels is carried out.</p>
<p>&quot;The main thing is that we do not shoot each other,&quot; said Wakhid Mokhchayev, one of at least three local administration chiefs from Grozny who moved here after the separatists took over the capital on August 6.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not kill each other any more...we will not take up arms again,&quot; added Mokhchayev, referring to the truce agreed last month as part of a plan to withdraw Russian troops.</p>
<p>A separatist lieutenant said civil war was unlikely, if only because the rebels were stronger.</p>
<p>Urus-Martan has always been a centre of support for the pro-Russian Chechen government, set up by Moscow to oppose the independence-seeking separatists who have fought a bitter war against Russian troops for almost 21 months.</p>
<p>The rebels signed an accord with Russian peacemaker Alexander Lebed on Saturday and the word has gone out that there are thousands of armed men in Urus-Martan ready to fight any attempt by the separatists to use the deal to take power.</p>
<p>But there was no evidence of those men on the streets of the town during a visit this week.</p>
<p>Mokhchayev refused to discuss rumours spread by the man he officially reports to, pro-Russian leader Doku Zavgayev, that his supporters were gathering arms to fight the rebels.</p>
<p>He insisted that there would be no &quot;Afghan scenario&quot; in Chechnya, referring to the bloody civil war which broke out in Afghanistan after Soviet troops withdrew in 1989.</p>
<p>The shape of any new administration in Chechnya is not clear, but another Zavgayev loyalist said he wanted a &quot;third way&quot;, between pro-independence Chechens and pro-Moscow forces.</p>
<p>&quot;This town has always been a centre of compromise,&quot; said Sultan Gadayev, who worked as the head of the cultural section in Mokhchayev's district administration.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a neutral person,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Chechen separatists were also convinced that civil war should be avoided in their shattered region, although they said their opponents they would be crushed if they were not prepared to compromise.</p>
<p>Said-Magamet Amzayev, a separatist lieutenant, said the only reason any Chechens had sided with the Russians was because they were afraid of them and their huge firepower.</p>
<p>He said pro-Zavgayev forces were gathering, mentioning areas in northern Chechnya traditionally opposed to the separatists.</p>
<p>But he said the separatists had beaten Russia and they could also beat any Chechen who chose to take up arms. &quot;If there is opposition it should be on paper, but if it takes up arms it becomes an enemy and an enemy must be crushed.&quot;</p>
<p>Amzayev said what he really wanted to do was to put down his gun, allow the people to vote on Chechnya's future and go back to his job as a fireman.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="URUS-MARTAN, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
