<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31711" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania-Hungary pact signing on Sept 16th.</title>
<headline>Romania-Hungary pact signing on Sept 16th.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania and Hungary have agreed to sign a long-delayed friendship treaty on September 16th in the western Romanian city of Timisoara, a Romanian foreign ministry spokesman said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hungarian Prime Minister Gyula Horn and his Romanian counterpart Nicolae Vacaroiou will sign the pact, which is key to both countries ambitions to join NATO and the EU. Timisoara was the cradle of Romania's anti-communist revolution in 1989.  </p>
<p>The announcement in Bucharest was confirmed by a government spokesman in the Hungarian capital of Budapest.</p>
<p>It came after the Hungarian parliament overwhelmingly rejected an opposition bid for a review of the treaty's terms.</p>
<p>The governing parties of both countries are determined to push through the pact, with Romania's ruling Party of Social Democracy going to the extent of dumping its anti-Hungarian coalition partner because of its opposition to the deal.</p>
<p>The treaty, four years in the making, should end disputes over the status of Romania's 1.6 million ethnic Hungarians and improve economic and military relations between the two central European neighbours.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
