<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31710" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania to put Briton on trial for sex abuse.</title>
<headline>Albania to put Briton on trial for sex abuse.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British man charged with sexually abusing two young boys will go on trial soon, Tirana state prosecutor Adnan Xhelili said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The investigations are over and the file has been sent to the court,&quot; Xhelili told Reuters. &quot;The charges relate to various immoral acts, including sexual abuse.&quot;</p>
<p>Paul Thompson, 36, was arrested on August 25 in a hotel in the Adriatic resort of Durres, about 45 km (30 miles) west of Tirana. He has denied all the charges, but acknowledges befriending the two boys, aged 12 and 13.</p>
<p>Thompson, who lives in London, could face up to five years in jail if convicted.</p>
<p>Thompson's Albanian lawyer Delo Isufi said the Tirana court would decide on the trial date, which he said could be within the next two weeks.</p>
<p>Isufi said Thompson, who is divorced, befriended the boys because they reminded him of his own children who live with his former wife in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the evidence and on the truth that has come out, I am sure Mr Thompson will be cleared of the charges. But, of course, that's up to the court,&quot; Isufi told Reuters.</p>
<p>The legal age of consent for heterosexual and homosexual relations in Albania is 14.</p>
<p>Isufi said a fax obtained from the British embassy in Tirana showed that Thompson had donated one of his kidneys to his sister and needed to have tests every year.</p>
<p>Isufi said he would submit medical documents from Hammersmith Hospital in London to the court to verify his condition and the need for regular examinations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
