<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31721" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo must use its funds before tapping IMF.</title>
<headline>Yugo must use its funds before tapping IMF.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysts believe Yugoslavia will quickly be readmitted to the IMF but do not expect large capital influx by the end of next year until all Belgrade's reserves abroad have been used up to kickstart the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;I am an optimist regarding the date of our return to the IMF,&quot; a senior government official close to the negotiating team told Reuters on Wednesday, although he refused to specify a date.</p>
<p>The membership is of crucial importance for Belgrade's attempts to secure fresh funds to revive country's crippling economy devastated by 3-1/2 years of U.N. sanctions.</p>
<p>Yugoslav Finance Minister Tomica Raicevic is due to hold talks with senior IMF officials in Washington on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately we cannot expect fresh funds before the end of the next year,&quot; said a government analyst who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF and all the other financial institutions know exactly how much money we have abroad,&quot; he said. &quot;And they expect us to use that first.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats believe Yugoslav authorities have managed to spirit large amounts of hard currency abroad in the early 90's despite a trade and financial cordon around the country.</p>
<p>Despite the end of most U.N. sanctions last November, the international community left a so-called &quot;outer-wall&quot; of sanctions in place, blocking Yugoslavia's access to world financial markets and urgently needed fresh capital.</p>
<p>The Yugoslav parliament last week announced the government had accepted all the conditions required by the IMF to restore Belgrade's membership.</p>
<p>But local analysts doubt the new capital would come immediately after Yugoslavia's reacceptance into the fund.</p>
<p>The analysts believe the first so called golden tranche from the IMF will not take so long to get, but other installments would depend on the speed and degree of structural reforms the IMF is likely to insist on.</p>
<p>&quot;As the first tranche depends entirely on the IMF, we can get it very soon,&quot; Mihajlo Nikolic of the central bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the IMF would require a serious economic programme with high performance criteria for other installments,&quot; said Nikolic, once chief advisor to former central bank governor Dragoslav Avramovic.</p>
<p>&quot;This depends entirely on us and I am very sceptical the government is ready for such radical cuts.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgrade analysts believe the entire next year will pass in making the deals and clearing up details with the fund. &quot;If the IMF accepts postponment of our debt payments that will be a success,&quot; the government analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistically speaking, Yugoslavia could expect first significant financial injection at the beginning of 1998.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
