<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31728" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Sept 4.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>-  Tractorul UTB tractor maker in Brasov to raise tractor prices by an average 25 percent.</p>
<p>- Romania's farming sector affected by diesel oil shortage.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Price of sunflower oil to rise by 25 percent.</p>
<p>- Senate approved law on banks' privatisation.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Prices for petrol and diesel oil to remain unchanged till December.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>-  RWE Entsorgung of Germany eyes joint venture with Bucharest city-hall in new garbage damp project.</p>
<p>- Turnover at Bucharest bourse on the slide.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Italian and german companies to cooperate with Bucharest city-hall in major project to clean the city.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Present form of Romanian-Hungarian friendship treaty will be a constant source for tensions between the two states, capable of leading to huge inter-ethnic clashes in Romania, said Ioan Gavra, vice-president of National Unity Party (PUNR).</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes remarks by politicians from almost whole political spectrum on split of governing coalition after ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) canceled a protocol with PUNR.</p>
<p>- Health ministry says 17 people died and 303 were hospitalised so far in Romania's worst meningitis epidemic over the past 10 years.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Newspaper presents new agriculture, justice and communications ministers appointed after former PUNR members were sacked.</p>
<p>- Government sacked five local prefects and four deputy prefects, all PUNR members, following the brake of the PDSR-PUNR governing protocol.</p>
<p>- Government adopted decision to finance political parties from the state budget with 4.5 billion lei, the equivalent of 0.04 percent of the GDP.</p>
<p>- Independent senator resigned saying he was displeased with the low wage and pension he got as an MP.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- From December 1991 (when constitution was adopted) to October 1992 (when President Iliescu was elected) is not a &quot;presidential mandate but a period of transition&quot; said ruling PDSR in response to allegations that Iliescu's candidacy for November 3 presidential polls would be a third and therefore an unconstitutional mandate.</p>
<p>- Romania has only 9,000 purebreed horses.</p>
<p>- Miners' trade union confederation will back opposition Social Democratic Union (USD) and its presidential candidate former reformist premier Petre Roman in the November 3 polls.</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes programme of Adrian Paunescu, presidential candidate of Socialist Labour Party (PSM) in the November 3 presidential elections.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- President Iliescu said he would promote a center, Western kind electoral platform for the November 3 polls.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Declaration of dignitaries' assets could turn into benefit for the theves, said MPs debating the bill asking for the declaration to be confidential.</p>
<p>COTIDIANUL</p>
<p>- What was before (the constitution) does not count, the constitution is the starting point, says President Iliescu about his new candidacy for the November 3 polls, but former Justice minister Teofil Pop says Iliescu had already two constitutional mandates, a new one being in breach of the law.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- Opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) prepares a huge electoral fraud as it seems to have done in the local elections too, said PDSR president Oliviu Gherman.</p>
<p>DIMINEATA</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes report by governmental control bodies and justice ministry on measures taken to fight economic and financial crimes in the first half of 1996 and measures to stop corruption. ($=3,164 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
