<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31726" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - September 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - September 4.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Wednesday. Prepared for Reuters by the Co-operation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- President Guntis Ulmanis and Prime Minister Andris Skele signed an order reinstating Colonel Janis Dalbins as commander of Latvia's armed forces. Dalbins was exonerated by a special commission investigating a spate of murders and suicides in the country's army.</p>
<p>DIENNA</p>
<p>- Richard Holbrooke joins a Baltic Sea council established to examine security issues in the region.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Skele's foreign affairs advisor says the Prime Minister's visit to Moscow will still take place but will probably be postponed to a later date.</p>
<p>- A court hearing the case of alleged mafia boss Ivan Kharitonov listened to videotape testimony by the late Vladimirs Dukats, who was killed in an explosion in 1994.</p>
<p>- DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- The Latvian Foreign Minster criticises a story in Britain's Daily Telegraph that asserted Latvian forests and wildlife were being decimated by uncontrolled logging.</p>
<p>-- Riga newsroom +3717- 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
