<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31724" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Sept 4.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Wednesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Are we in for an Autumn government reshuffle?</p>
<p>- EBRD (European Bank for Reconstruction and Development) planning to invest 229.97 million Ecu in Croatia.</p>
<p>- The shipper Jadrolinija reports improvement by 76 percent compared to last years tourist season in the number of passenger on international passenger lines.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- A new World Bank loan: $107 million allocated for reconstruction.</p>
<p>- We are edging towards a total of $2 billion made from this years tourism, says in an interview tourism minister Niko Bulic.</p>
<p>- The kuna rate not to depreciate, topping 3.7 kuna against the German mark even with the weaker inflow of foreign currency this autumn.</p>
<p>- Compensating mutual debts of the Croatian companies seems like an attractive solution but it would not resolve causes for their insolvency, says central bank analyst Velimir Sonje.</p>
<p>- Zagrebacka, Privredna, Slavonska, Pozeska and Ilirija Banka cut interest rates in September.</p>
<p>- Money market: Supply stable, demand very modest.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- 2 million German marks to be used to burn old medical supplies sent by foreign donations.</p>
<p>- Economic commentary: Proposed increase of civil servants' salaries, while plans for next year's budget are being mulled, clashes with announced reduction of fiscal burden.</p>
<p>- Split's loss making plastic factory Diokom with facilities on Dalmatian islands to be rehabilitated by spliting it into 11 profit centres and liquidating the rest. Some 1,500 employees face lay-offs. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
