<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31736" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Farrakhan slams U.S. policy on Iraq, Cuba.</title>
<headline>Farrakhan slams U.S. policy on Iraq, Cuba.</headline>
<byline>Pascal Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. militant black Moslem leader Louis Farrakhan on Wednesday condemned Washington's hostile policies against Iraq, Cuba, Iran and Libya as heartless and inhuman and said he feared for the future of the United States.</p>
<p>Speaking in Cuba where he held talks with Cuban President Fidel Castro, the Nation of Islam leader urged President Bill Clinton to &quot;leave the Cuban people alone&quot; and lift the longstanding U.S. embargo against the communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>Farrakhan said he was in Cuba as part of a tour of states that were &quot;under (U.S.-imposed) sanctions and embargoes&quot;.</p>
<p>Before Cuba, he had visited Iran, Iraq, Libya and Sudan. All these states are listed by Washington as alleged sponsors of international &quot;terrorism&quot;. &quot;We hope soon to visit North Korea,&quot; he told a news conference before leaving Havana.</p>
<p>Condemning Washington's &quot;unjust policies&quot; against these countries, he said: &quot;It appears that the heart of the American leadership is not a heart of compassion for human suffering.&quot;</p>
<p>In an apparent direct appeal to Clinton, he went on: &quot;It appears you don't have the heart of a human being anymore.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If our government continues on the path it is going, I fear for the future of America. I believe America ... if it continues on this path, may go the way of ancient Rome, Egypt, Babylon and Sodom and Gomorrah,&quot; Farrakhan said, invoking cases of ancient civilisations that either declined or collapsed.</p>
<p>Referring to the U.S. missile attacks against Iraq, he said it was sad to see that in an election year President Clinton was using &quot;the enormous military power of the U.S. to add more pain and suffering to the Iraqi people.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The bombing of Iraq is causing many nations to wonder what is happening to the government of the U.S.,&quot; Farrakhan added.</p>
<p>He criticised Washington for trying to force Cuba to adopt western-style, multi-party democracy. &quot;Let the Cuban people decide what form of government they want. Leave the Cuban people alone and maybe God will be merciful to you,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Farrakhan said he had &quot;a very wonderful conversation&quot; with Castro, in which the main subject was &quot;ethics and morals&quot;.</p>
<p>Asked why the Cuban government had received Farrakhan, a senior Cuban Communist party official, Jose Arbezu, said the Nation of Islam leader had asked to visit the island. &quot;He's a prestigious figure, and so he's welcome here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Farrakhan said he was not worried about calls from some U.S. politicians urging that his U.S. passport be revoked, along with those of his companions on the trip.</p>
<p>&quot;The passports belong to the U.S. government. They can take them, that is their property. But I don't think it would be wise to do so,&quot; he said. He added: &quot;We are not criminals. We are religious people who have the right to travel to see the sufferings of others&quot;.</p>
<p>Farrakhan said he visited a Moslem mosque while in Havana and added his organisation would donate 100 copies of the Koram, the sacred book of Islam, to the mosque and also some money for its upkeep.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
