<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31737" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>EL SALVADOR: North and Central America port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>North and Central America port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>EL SALVADOR, Acajutla, Aug 30 - Two vessels discharging at berth of which bulk soymeal, 1 butane. No vessels waiting at anchorage, 12 due by 3/10 of which 10 to discharge (1 vehicles/spare parts, 1 petroleum products, 2 full containers, 1 soya meal/wheat, 1 cottonseed oil, 1 vehicles, 1 general cargo, 1 steel products, 1 containers), 1 to discharge/load containers. Delays depending on weather. Rainy season May-October.</p>
<p>HONDURAS, Sept 2 - Puerto Cortes - Four vessels berthed of which 2 discharging/loading containers, 1 discharging asphalt, 1 discharging grain. 1 vessel anchored to load bananas. 13 vessels due of which 8 to discharge/load containers, 5 to load bananas.</p>
<p>PANAMA, Sept 2 - Balboa - Two vessels of which 1 general cargo, 1 container carrier. Cristobal - Five vessels of which 4 container carriers, 1 passenger/ro/ro. Panama Canal - Miraflores locks lane outage still scheduled to be completed by 5/9. Twenty-three vessels due, 55 in queue awaiting turn at 01.00 hrs Sept 2. This is expected to increase to 65 vessels by Sept 4 due to reduced canal capacity, of these 11 are booked, 28 scheduled. As of Sept 3 average delays as follows - Category A, 3 days for vessels with 91 ft. beam and over and/or restricted due cargo/draft. Category b, 36 hours for vessels less than 91 ft. beam and not restricted.</p>
<p>Projected arrivals of category A vessels continue to be heavy and it may be at least Sept 14 before delays are at normal levels. Projected arrivals of category B are fairly light and it is hoped delays will be at normal level by Sept 9.  </p>
<p>UNITED STATES, Sept 2 - Baltimore, MD - no congestion expected at Dundalk terminal this week. High winds expected due to Hurricane Eduoard approaching east coast south Atlantic. Elevators and coal operations operating normally, with no delays. Average waiting time consol coal 7 days. Liquid bulk facilities operating normally, no berthing congestion. Anchorage clear at Baltimore and Annapolis.</p>
<p>Charleston, SC - Coast guard expects to close the port to incoming traffic at 0900 hours and all vessels to vacate by 2100 hours. Container terminals experiencing heavy traffic, with short delays. Hurricane threats will cause a bottleneck for the next week. Oil facilities are running without delays at a moderate rate. Dredging in the harbour has been completed in all major channels and alongside the container terminals. The grain terminal is not scheduled for discharge this week.</p>
<p>Jacksonville, FL - no heavy berth congestion or delays at the port or Fernandina Beach, FL. The Jacksonville bar pilots association has increased the operating draft in the St. Johns river from the entrance up river to buoy 75 to 38 ft FW from its previous 37 ft FW. The new draft refers to the operation of vessels in the main channel only. Vessels may be limited by the depth of water at their berth.</p>
<p>New york, NY - no congestion at anchorages, container, tanker terminals. Congestion continues in Brooklyn sugar terminal. No congestion at Yonkers sugar terminal.</p>
<p>Norfolk, VA - eleven vessels due at norfolk southern coal pier this week, 2 vessels presently anchored waiting to load. Nine vessels due at dominion terminal, 2 anchored waiting to load. Three vessels due at Pier IX coal terminal. Norfolk southern pier will not be loading any vessels from 2300 hours 1/9 until 0700 hours 3/9 due to Labour Day. Due to threat of Hurricane Eduoard Dominion is planning to stop vessel loadings from 1800 hours 30/8 until further notice. Situation will be reviewed every 12 hours, so loading may resume at any time depending on the track of the storm. No vessels due at Cargill this week. Vessels calling at the general cargo and container terminals are not expecting any delays in berthing and working. All shipping channels in the Hampton Roads area are open. The CMI heavy lift crane at Newport News marine terminal is back in service. Draft restrictions imposed by the Virginia Pilot Association along the James River are now rescinded. Maximum draft to and from Richmond is 22 ft. Inbound vessels drawing more than 21 ft 6 in must transit the river on a favourable tide. Outbound vessels drawing more than 21 ft 6 in will sail 2 hours before high water at Richmond. Navigation restrictions remain with respect to daylight navigation of the upper portion of the river above Hopewell.  </p>
<p>Philadelphia, PA - the US coast guard is notifying waterfront facilities that current projections indicate the potential for Hurricane Eduoard to pass near the New Jersey and Delaware shorelines. All waterfront facilities with the Philadelphia zone are advised to inspect their facilities, particularly docks and/or piers.</p>
<p>Savannah, GA - no congestion expected at the Georgia Ports Authorities Garden City terminal and Ocean terminals this week. All liquid bulk facilities are operating normally, no berth congestion expected. Colonial marine terminals (bulk clay) expects a 1-2 days wait  anchorage. All navigation remains normal, but may change due to approach of the hurricanes.</p>
<p>Gulf Coast - Houston, TX - no congestion at city docks, public grain elevator and Cargill grain elevator, but some congestion at private terminals for breakbulk cargo. Congestion at Farmland grain elevator in Galveston reduced to approx. 3 days.</p>
<p>New Orleans, LA - rain causes delays in grain loading. River stage at 3-8 ft., Normal transit times can be expected. Present max. Permissible DRT at SW Pass is 47 ft FW for vessels under 100,000 dwt, 46 ft FE for vessels over 100,000 dwt.</p>
<p>West Coast - Columbia River - grain activity in the Columbia River on the increase due to new western white harvest being placed into position. Sixteen vessels due for grain, 6 loading, 10 waiting at various anchorage locations. Average waiting time 3-6 days.</p>
<p>Coos Bay - no delays in vessel traffic. Some berth congestion will occur at ocean terminals with 3 vessels due. Channel deepening project progressing normally, with no delays in vessel traffic.</p>
<p>San Francisco, CA - petcoke cargo starting to move, all anchorages are open and waiting time is minimal.</p>
<p>Baltimore, MD - vessels in port - 5 bulkers, 3 container vessels, 2 ro/ro, 2 auto vessels, 1 tanker, 3 general cargo, 2 cable vessels on standby, 5 vessels in repair yard, 7 bulkers awaiting berth.</p>
<p>Hampton Roads, VA - nine general cargo/container vessels in pier operating, 3 vessels in pier loading coal, 4 anchored waiting to load, 1 bulker loading fertiliser, 1 anchored waiting to load, 1 parcel tanker discharging caustic soda, 2 vessels in pier under repairs.</p>
<p>Port Newark, NJ - two vessels in port.</p>
<p>Port Elizabeth, NJ - four vessels in port.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ELSAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EL SALVADOR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
