<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31739" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Nation of Islam's Farrakhan meets Castro.</title>
<headline>Nation of Islam's Farrakhan meets Castro.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Louis Farrakhan, leader of the U.S.-based Nation of Islam who recently travelled to Libya for a prize, met with Cuban President Fidel Castro, state media said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The black American leader and Castro discussed world affairs, the situation in Cuba and the U.S. African American community. The meeting took place a few hours after the Nation of Islam leader arrived in Cuba on Tuesday, accompanied by members of his family and other members of the organisation.</p>
<p>Farrakhan told Cuban reporters he was interested in obtaining a close view of the impact of recently tightened U.S. economic sanctions against Cuba. He was due to leave the communist-ruled island later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Farrakhan was recently awarded a $250,000 human rights prize in Libya, which is on the U.S. list of states that it says sponsor international terrorism. The U.S. Treasury Department denied his application to receive the $250,000 award or a $1 billion gift Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi had pledged to the Nation of Islam after they met last January.</p>
<p>Farrakhan organised last October's Million Man March that brought thousands of black men to Washington for a peaceful rally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
