<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31738" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: South American port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>South American port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ARGENTINA, Sept 3 - Santa Fe - No vessels berthed/in roads/due. Max draft 20 ft 1 in at access channel. Diamante - max draft 21 ft. 9 in at passage km 520. San Lorenzo - four vessels berthed of which 3 loading sbmp, 1 loading naphtha. 3 in roads. 18 due at 9 terminals during week. Max. draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. Rosario - 11 vessels berthed of which 1 awaiting orders, 6 discharging fertiliser, 1 loading vegetable oil, 1 loading fruit, 1 loading maize, 1 loading sorghum. 4 vessels in roads. 7 due during the week. Draft guided by Emilio Mitre channel. Villa Constitucion - two vessels berthed of which 1 discharging iron ore, 1 awaiting orders. None in roads. 2 vessels due. Max draft 19 ft 6 in FW. Acindar/Puerto Acevedo (iron ore/steel products) - guided by Emilio Mitre channel. San Nicolas - four berthed of which 1 loading steel products, 1 loading coils, 1 discharging fertiliser, 1 loading pig iron. No vessels in roads. 5 due. Max draft guided by EM channel. San Pedro - no vessels. Draft guided by EM channel. Max draft for Mitre channel at high tide 28 ft 6 in FW</p>
<p>Buenos Aires - 25 vessels in port. Max draft 31 ft. FW guided by entrance channel/high tide. Necochea - four vessels berthed of which 2 discharging dap, 1 loading sbmp, 1 loading wheat. 4 in roads. 9 due during week. Max draft 40 ft. Bahia Blanca - six berthed, 3 awaiting orders, 1 discharging urea, 1 loading wheat, 1 loading fish. 2 in roads. 11 due in week.</p>
<p>BRAZIL, Sept 3 - Vitoria - Vessels berthed - 1 granite/cellulose loader, 1 pig iron loader, 1 wheat discharger, 1 malt discharger, 1 sugar loader, 1 coffee loader, 1 pellets loader. Tubarao - 3 iron ore loaders, 1 petroleum. Praia Mole - 3 steel plates loaders, 2 coal dischargers. Ubu - 1 iron ore loader. 18 vessels waiting in roads. Santos - vessels berthed - 7 full containers, 1 bulk cement discharger, 11 sugar loaders, 3 general cargo, 1 propane discharger, 2 chemical products loaders, 1 chemical discharger, 3 wheat dischargers, 1 auto parts dischargers, 2 salt dischargers, 1 diesel oil loader, 4 fertiliser dischargers, 1 garlic discharger, 2 bulk pellets loaders. 35 vessels waiting in roads. 105 due during next 7 days. Private terminals - Cosipa - 1 bulk coal discharger, 2 steel products loaders, 1 iron ore discharger. Ultrafertil - 1 fertiliser discharger. Itajai - vessels berthed - 1 general cargo, 2 reefers, 1 full container. 7 vessels waiting in rods. 8 due during next 7 days. Rio Grande - vessels berthed - 3 bulk fertiliser discharger, 2 full containers, 1 soy loader, 1 soybean loader, 1 wheat transhipment. 2 waiting in roads. 29 due during next 10 days. Sao Sebastiao - Tebar - 3 vessels berthed. 5 waiting in roads. 10 due during next 7 days. Rio de Janeiro - vessels berthed - 1 steel products discharger, 1 steel products loader, 2 general cargo/container loaders, 3 general cargo/ container dischargers, 1 paper discharger, 2 wheat dischargers, 2 sugar loaders. Tecon - 5 vessels. 20 due during next 7 days. Paranagua - vessels berthed - 4 pellets loaders, 2 sugar loaders, 1 full container loader/discharger, 1 soybean loader, 2 general cargo loade/dischargers, 1 fertiliser discharger, 1 naphtha loader. 50 waiting in roads of which for loading - 13 sugar, 11 agribulk, 8 pellets, 1 diesel oil. For discharging - 11 fertiliser, 1 wheat. 5 containers loading/discharging. Salvador - port paralysed since 1900 Sept 999 due to casual labour (stevedores, tallyclerks) dispute with OGMO. Salvador Port Operators taking judicial action to remedy the situation.</p>
<p>CHILE, Sept 2 - Arica - Two vessels operating, 4 berths vacant. No vessels waiting in roads. No swell. 13 vessels due during week. Iquique - No vessels operating in port. 4 berths vacant. 2 out of service due to maintenance until 2/10. No vessels waiting in roads, 11 due during week. Antofagasta - three vessels berthed, 4 berths available. 6 vessels due during week for loading and discharging concentrates, copper bars, containers and general cargo. 1 vessel in roads awaiting cargo. Valparaiso - Three vessels berthed working normally. 6 berths vacant, 1 out of service. 1 vessel in roads awaiting cargo, 18 due during the week. San Antonio - Five vessels operating. 4 berths vacant. 13 vessels due during week, none in roads. 1 berth out of service due to repairs. Conception Bay - Talcahuano - one vessel berthed. No berths available. 3 vessels due this week, none in roads. San Vicente - one vessel berthed working normally. 2 berths available. No vessels in roads, 3 due during the week. Steel Pier - 2 vessels in port. No berths available. No vessels due, in roads. Oil terminal - 1 vessel operating. 1 berth available. No vessels due. Navy pier (Molo 500) - No vessels operating. 2 berths available. 2 due during the week, none in roads. Lirquen - Four operating. 2 berths available. No vessels in roads, 2 due in week. Puerto Montt - One in port. 1 berth available. No vessels in roads, 3 due in week. Punta Arenas - Nine vessels and coasters berthed. No berths available. 3 vessels and coasters due in week. None in roads.</p>
<p>PERU, Sept 2 - Callao - Seven vessels in bay, 5 in pier (general cargo/container vessels), no berthing delays. Paita - one fishmeal vessel in bay, no delays. Bayovar, Pisco - No vessels in ports. Talara - Two oil vessels in pier, no berthing delays. Chimbo - Two fishmeal vessels in bay, no berthing delays. Ilo - One copper vessel in pier, no berthing delays.</p>
<p>VENEZUELA, Sept 2 - Puerto Cabello - six vessels anchored, 10 berthed of which 6 grain, 4 general cargo. Piers 1 and 2 closed. Guanta - five vessels anchored, 4 general cargo vessels berthed. Sept 3 - Orinoco river draft 38 ft. Puerto Ordaz - two vessels loading iron ore, 2 due. Palua - one loading briquettes. Boca Grande - one vessel loading iron ore, 1 due. Mile 178 - six vessels waiting at anchorage to load/discharge. Matanzas - six vessels operating of which 1 discharging scrap, 5 loading steel products, 5 waiting at anchorage to load, 2 due. Venalum - three vessels loading aluminium. Alcasa, Interalumina - one vessel due at each. Puerto Cabello - 15 vessels operating of which 11 loading/discharging generals, 3 discharging grain, 1 discharging rice, 13 due. Maracaibo - one loading/discharging generals. Puerto Miranda - two vessels loading crude oil. Buoy b71 - one vessel loading coal. Palmarejo Sur - two loading crude. La Salina - one vessel loading crude. Bajo Grande - one loading crude. Guanta - three operating, 1 discharging salt, 1 barley, 1 loading steel billets, 8 due. All ports working normally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
