<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31734" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Sept 4.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn remained adamant that he will sign the Hungarian-Romanian basic treaty, in yesterday's heated special parliamentary debate.</p>
<p>- A lax 1997 budget could compel the economic cabinet to take harsh decisions later on, perhaps even amounting to a new Bokros package, Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy told a session of the Socialist Party's parliamentary faction, referring to the austerity measures associated with his predecessor.</p>
<p>- Addressing his regular monthly press conference, Prime Minister Gyula Horn confirmed yesterday that an economic strategic working group attached to the cabinet can take up work later this year.</p>
<p>- Firemen will take to the streets next Tuesday to press home their wage demands.</p>
<p>- Although the trading volume continued to be high, at nearly HUF 1.2 billion, most major share prices fell and the BUX index dropped by 61 points on the Budapest Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>- The Constitutional Court Tuesday struck down a three-year-old law regarding crimes committed against humanity while suppressing the 1956 uprising, particularly firing on crowds, in a ruling that deputy court chairman Tamas Labady said will allow authorities to prosecute a wider group of people.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn will head the Hungarian delegation at the Central European Free Trade Agreement meeting in Demanovska Dolina, Slovakia on September 13.</p>
<p>- King Juan Carlos of Spain and his wife Sofia will pay an official visit to Hungary September 10-13.</p>
<p>- The Ministry of Culture intends to link all secondary schools to the Internet by the end of the 1997-1998 school year, announced Culture Minister Balint Magyar.</p>
<p>- The nation's foreign trade balance continued to improve notably in July, the Ministry of Industry and Trade reported Tuesday, as exports through July came to $7.3 billion, a 5.2 percent year-on-year increase, while imports rose only 0.1 percent from the same time last year, to $9 billion.</p>
<p>- Market players say Creditanstalt and ABN-Amro banks are the favourites in the bidding for Magyar Hitel Bank Rt.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- Theo Waigel, Germany's finance minister, will hold talks with Prime Minister Gyula Horn and Finance Minister Peter Medgyessy this Friday, before addressing a Hungarian-German Economic Forum in Budapest.</p>
<p>- President Arpad Goncz will pay an official visit to NATO headquarters in Brussels on September 16 and meet Javier Solana, Secretary General of the Alliance.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Karoly Lotz, minister for telecoms, transport and water, met his Bulgarian counterpart for talks on the prospects of laying an optical fibre cable between Budapest and Sofia.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The steel industry giant Dunaferr Dunai Vasmu signed a $25 million contract Tuesday with Samsung, under which the South Korean company will install a spool system into a hot rolling mill in Dunaujvaros.</p>
<p>- The nation's largest construction firm, Strabag Hungaria Epito Rt., a subsidiary of Strabag Osterreich AG, reports that a continuing recession in its sector made for poor first half results.</p>
<p>			    -- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
