<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31746" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's Fox backs Zedillo's tough stand on rebels.</title>
<headline>Mexico's Fox backs Zedillo's tough stand on rebels.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition state governor Vicente Fox on Wednesday praised President Ernesto Zedillo's tough approach to a new guerrilla group, but warned the government is not acting to solve the conflict's causes.</p>
<p>Fox, considered a rising star in Mexico's opposition National Action Party (PAN), told a gathering of U.S. businessmen that he backed Zedillo's military response to rebels of the self-syled Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR).  </p>
<p>&quot;It's being handled with an appropriate strategy. Clearly, in this case we are talking about terrorists...they have to be confronted,&quot; Fox told the American Chamber of Commerce in Mexico City.</p>
<p>But he said the EPR rose from the ashes of misery and neglect produced by 67 years of Institutional Revolutionary Party rule -- conditions most Mexicans understand.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to go further than just confronting them with the army...we need political stability, we need real democracy, we need immediate results on the economy...otherwise, there will not be enough armies to hold what could come,&quot; Fox said.  </p>
<p>The EPR appeared about two months ago in the western state of Guerrero and has since launched military attacks in at least three other central and southern states.</p>
<p>Fox criticized some hardline elements of the ruling PRI for taking advantage of the guerrilla group to create a climate of repression in Mexico and pointing to opposition politicians and the church as possible rebel sympathizers.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems a lot of people want to use this as an excuse to militarize the country, to have an excuse for repression and further violence,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The 55-year-old politician, considered a likely presidential candidate in 2000, said he was sure the opposition would win next year's mid-term elections and the presidential race in 2000.</p>
<p>He said the ruling PRI was incapable of change and had lost the hearts of Mexicans. He added he did not rule out the idea of an opposition coalition to beat the PRI in the 2000 race.</p>
<p>Fox and former Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev plan to host a November 21-23 conference of the non-profit State of the World Forum in Guanajuato that will discuss Latin America and the challenges of the next millenium.</p>
<p>-- David Luhnow, Mexico City newsroom 525 7289565</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
