<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31741" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian Congress asked to approve war bonds.</title>
<headline>Colombian Congress asked to approve war bonds.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The embattled Colombian government asked Congress on Tuesday to approve a law requiring rich Colombians to buy war bonds to help finance the country's long-running battle against leftist guerrillas.</p>
<p>The proposed legislation was presented to the lower house of Congress by Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo, who said the government hoped to raise $420 million through the sale of the bonds.</p>
<p>In a message to lawmakers explaining the need for additional military financing, Ocampo said &quot;the current circumstances of insecurity and deterioration in law and order&quot; more than justify the government's call on wealthy taxpayers to dig deeper into their pockets.</p>
<p>&quot;Colombia is perhaps the only country in the world that faces a simultaneous threat from guerrillas, drug traffickers, armed groups taking justice into their own hands and other criminals,&quot; the message said.</p>
<p>&quot;The current administration considers the adoption of financial tools to permit a greater and more effective control of security throughout the country something that cannot be postponed,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The bond sale would take the place of a proposed war tax, which the government determined was not permitted under the constitution.</p>
<p>Under the plan, any individuals or businesses with a net worth of more $85,000 would be required to buy the five-year bonds, which would be issued in denominations of 500,000 pesos ($480) and carry an annual interest rate of 6 percent.</p>
<p>The bonds, which could eventually be bought and sold on the secondary market, would be worth 20 percent more than their face value if used to purchase assets, including real estate, confiscated from Colombian drug lords.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Samper said in a national radio and television address on Monday night that money raised through the bond sales would be used to provide the military with new weapons, transportation and intelligence equipment.</p>
<p>He did not elaborate, but the Colombian Army faces what Western military experts describe as serious limits in its ability to transport combat troops.</p>
<p>Armed forces chief Adm. Holdan Delgado conceded in a recent interview that the military has fewer than three dozen working helicopters -- the number the U.S. Army uses to support a single brigade.</p>
<p>Guerrillas launched a nationwide offensive last Friday, killing at least 60 security force members in two days of fighting that put a virtual stranglehold on the country of 37 million people.</p>
<p>The offensive included an attack by hundreds of Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) rebels on a military base in southwest Putumayo province in which at least 27 soldiers were killed and 60 taken prisoner.</p>
<p>The FARC, Colombia's largest and oldest guerrilla group, has grown rich through banditry, kidnappings and the protection of rural drug operations. Western experts say it poses more of a threat today than at any time since its founding as a pro-Soviet Marxist group in 1964.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
