<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31744" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Central America seeks diverse S. Korea investments.</title>
<headline>Central America seeks diverse S. Korea investments.</headline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The economy ministers of Central America met with their South Korean counterpart Wednesday and asked him to promote more diverse investments in the region, a government official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to study the diversification of Korean investment in the region, especially towards areas other than (textile assembly) and towards activities that will leave more profit in the region,&quot; Guatemala's Economy Minister Juan Mauricio Wurmser told a news conference.  </p>
<p>South Korea's Economy Minister Jaeyoon Park was in Guatemala as part of the delegation of President Kim Young-sam, the first South Korean head of state to visit the region.</p>
<p>Most Asian businesses in impoverished Central America are so-called maquiladoras, or assembly plants that take advantage of cheap labor to produce apparel and other goods easily made by hand.</p>
<p>The Korean delegation leaves Guatemala Thursday to visit Argentina, Brasil, Chile and Peru.  </p>
<p>Park and the ministers of Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador discussed trade deficits, Korean investments and Central American exports.</p>
<p>Park said no South Korean investors, especially from large industrial conglomerates such as Samsung, Daewoo and Hyundai, had come to Central America with the delegation.</p>
<p>&quot;I am supposed to relate information to them at my return,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wurmser said the ministers spoke of establishing commercial missions across the Pacific to stimulate the interest of mid- and large-sized Korean investors.</p>
<p>&quot;If only Hyundai would come here to invest,&quot; Wurmser told reporters.</p>
<p>According to Wurmser, Central America's trade deficit with Korea was $110 million in 1995, with Central American countries exporting only $17 million worth of goods to Korea.</p>
<p>-- Fiona Ortiz, Guatemala bureau +502 251-5718</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
