<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31755" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chilean shares backtrack, close almost even.</title>
<headline>Chilean shares backtrack, close almost even.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chilean shares pared early gains and closed virtually unchanged as investors took stock of rumors of a shakeup in the electrical industry and the Central Bank's 1997 economic projections.</p>
<p>Reports that Enersis would sell its 20 percent stake in power generator Endesa to a big-name foreign buyer, possibly Endesa of Spain, continued to drive up electrical shares despite denials from Enersis.</p>
<p>The blue-chip IPSA ended 0.01 percent higher to 96.04 points. The all-share IGPA rose 0.07 percent to 5293.37 points on heavy volume 25 billion pesos.  </p>
<p>The market was still studying the 1997 projections issued by interim Central Bank President Jorge Marshall. Most, but not all, brokers said the targets pointed to continued restrictive interest rate policies known as the adjustment.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is still digesting this, but I think it indicates that the adjustment will continue,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>The Central Bank set a target of 5.5 percent inflation next year plus 5.5 to six percent growth, and a $950 million trade deficit due mainly to slumping copper prices.  </p>
<p>But others said most of the numbers were within market expectations and Marshall's speech would not have a major effect in the coming days.</p>
<p>The possibility of a deal between Enersis and a foreign company concentrated most attention. One analyst said the excitement the reports were generating showed a lack of local fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;This market is hurting from a lack of interest and persistently high interest rates. I see the market looking abroad for guidance,&quot; said Lance Eckel of brokers Sud Americano.  </p>
<p>The Enersis reports were &quot;spinning the market around,&quot; he said. Enersis itself closed unchanged at 252 pesos.</p>
<p>Investment societies related to Enersis were among the biggest gainers. Chispa Uno and Chispa Dos A series were both up 2.45 percent to 167 pesos, while Luz y Fuerza A series rose three percent to 167 pesos.</p>
<p>Embotelladora Andina rose 0.9 percent to 2250 pesos after announcing a purchase deal in Argentina, and Masisa, which also has investments in Argentina, rose two percent to 199 pesos.  </p>
<p>Decliners included Telex-Chile, off 2.4 percent to 1200 pesos, and Zofri, down 2.6 percent to 164.5 pesos.</p>
<p>--Roger Atwood, Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
