<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31756" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: So.Korean, Cen. American presidents talk trade.</title>
<headline>So.Korean, Cen. American presidents talk trade.</headline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade and investment dominated the agenda at a summit meeting Wednesday between four Central American presidents, Nicaragua's Vice President and South Korean president Kim Young-sam, host officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;This exercise...will contribute to the introduction of investment, trade, technological interchange and cooperation between the Republic of Korea and the Central American nations,&quot; Guatemalan President Alvaro Arzu said at a briefing.</p>
<p>The Central American nations and South Korea signed a declaration establishing an ongoing dialogue to define specific cooperation measures.</p>
<p>At the summit El Salvador's President Armando Calderon Sol spoke of Central America's interest in improving trade with Korea, opening the Korean market for exports from the isthmus and diversifying Korean investment in Central America.</p>
<p>Korea runs a big trade surplus with Central America. According to Guatemala's Central Bank, Guatemala's $33.3 million trade deficit with Korea is the largest in Central America.</p>
<p>Last year Guatemala exports to Korea totaled $1.5 million and imports were $34.8 million, mostly raw materials for the textile assembly (maquila) industry which is dominated by Korean-owned factories here.</p>
<p>Vice President Luis Flores Asturias told reporters that Guatemala aimed to guarantee Korean investment and to sign a cooperation agreement to promote economic, technological and social development.</p>
<p>Guatemala is also negotiating a $100 million loan from Korea for social and land programs, and will ask for economic support for programs the government commited to in peace agreements signed this year with leftist rebels.</p>
<p>President Kim is the first South Korean head of state to visit Central America. On Thursday he will travel to South America where he will visit Chile, Argentina, Brasil and Peru.</p>
<p>Accompanied by government ministers and businessmen, he is blazing the path for Korean industry which follows the government lead. In Central America Koreans are seeking investment opportunities and cheap production bases.</p>
<p>Critics of Korea's investment pattern in Central America say Korean-owned textile assembly plants (maquilas) throughout the region exploit cheap labor and take advantage of generous investment incentives without benefiting the region.</p>
<p>According to the Korean embassy in Guatemala, 180 Korean- owned maquilas assemble clothes under contract to U.S. companies and generate $120 million a year in exports, totaling five percent of Guatemala's total exports.</p>
<p>Flores said complaints about labor law violations in maquilas were exaggerated and could scare away investment and potential jobs for Guatemalans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
