<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31751" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: COCOA - Handful of companies dominate Bahia market.</title>
<headline>COCOA - Handful of companies dominate Bahia market.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The cocoa trade in Bahia, which once supported numerous exporting and grinding companies, is becoming increasingly concentrated in the hands of small number of major companies, farmers and traders said.</p>
<p>The trend is worrying farmers, who say the process is likely to continue and fear the lack of choice of buyers will lead to lower prices.</p>
<p>&quot;They are pushing the prices below the international level. They have been paying 15 Real when the international market has been paying 17,&quot; said farmer Ronaldo Monteiro.  </p>
<p>&quot;They are punishing the producers,&quot; Monteiro said. &quot;They are killing the hen that lays the golden egg.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazilian production, 90 percent of which comes from Bahia, has slumped in the last five years because of witch's broom disease and low world prices.</p>
<p>The 1995/6 crop is expected to produce only 2.5 million 60-kg bags, compared to the roughly 6.0 million bag crop that was traditional before the rot set in.</p>
<p>As a result, the production has been barely enough to meet the needs of local grinders who have snapped up nearly all the cocoa as it comes off the trees, leaving little for export.  </p>
<p>This, in turn, has forced many exporters out of the market and dealers predicted that the few that are left could go the same way within the next few months.</p>
<p>One exporting company, for example, said this week they were closing some buying stations and using their infrastructure to distribute fertilisers under a new deal with a local company.</p>
<p>Dealers said that within a few months, the market could be dominated almost exclusively by three grinding companies.</p>
<p>Paradoxically, given the smaller production, this could cause a surplus of cocoa.  </p>
<p>Dealers estimated that between them, the three companies would have a combined grinding capacity of 2.1 million bags, around half a million bags below current production. However, with no exporters left and no way to export cocoa themselves, farmers would have nowhere to sell the excess.</p>
<p>&quot;The big losers in a very short time are going to be the farmers,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;There will be an excess of cocoa but the shippers will not be there any more. The internal price will bear no relation to the external market.&quot;</p>
<p>Brazilian chocolate manufacturers who buy from exporters could also be affected.  </p>
<p>&quot;The manufacturers like to be able to just ring up and order their cocoa. They don't want to have to open up buying stations, where they will have farmers yelling at them,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Monteiro said the concentration of the trade and what he said was a lack of interest on the government's part in the region's problems were bigger problems than witch's broom.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible to live with witch's broom disease and the low prices,&quot; he said. &quot;But we can't survive with the complete lack of interest of the government and the industries playing against us. That we can't live with.&quot;  </p>
<p>Monteiro said the two month-long dry spell in the cocoa region had continued this week, with only one decent day of rain in the last week.</p>
<p>Producers said the general situation remained unchanged with the main crop, harvested from October to April, expected to total 1.0 million bags and the current midcrop expected to produce 1.5 million bags.</p>
<p>Although the drought has last longer than the last dry spell, 18 months ago, it has been less severe as it has come in winter when the sun is not as strong.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
