<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31760" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil govt knows nothing of Trieste coffee ruling.</title>
<headline>Brazil govt knows nothing of Trieste coffee ruling.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Brazilian commodities official Wednesday said the Ministry of Industry and Commerce knew nothing about market talk that an Italian court had ruled against Brazil over the so-called Operation London Terminal.</p>
<p>Traders reported talk that a court in Italy has ruled Brazil had to compensate exporters for losses made in the 1986 operation, more commonly known as Operation Patricia.</p>
<p>&quot;I know nothing about this,&quot; said Mauricio Assis, head of the primary commodities department at the Ministry of Industry and Commerce.  </p>
<p>Operation Patricia involved 338,739 60-kg bags of coffee, currently stored in a warehouse in Trieste.</p>
<p>Operation Patricia was authorized by the Brazilian government in 1986 when a group of trading houses bought futures contracts on the London coffee futures market in order to boost world prices, according to coffee sources.</p>
<p>The idea was to maximize Brazil's revenue from exports which were sharply down that year because of a drought.  </p>
<p>In theory, the trade houses were to be paid back either in coffee or in cash by the government.</p>
<p>But the government only paid firms some $15 million at the beginning of 1987, supposedly only one-tenth of what they were owed, as well as giving as a guarantee the coffee stored in Trieste, market sources said.</p>
<p>In April, Assis' predecessor at the ministry, Luiz Milton Veloso Costa, said he believed a solution was near.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
