<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31762" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOLIVIA: Latin leaders cement partnership, blast U.S..</title>
<headline>Latin leaders cement partnership, blast U.S..</headline>
<byline>David Haskel</byline>
<dateline>COCHABAMBA, Bolivia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latin American leaders closed a two-day summit on Wednesday, consolidating their trade and political integration and lashing out at U.S. legislation tightening the trade embargo on Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;We reaffirm ... our energetic rejection of the so-called Helms-Burton law,&quot; the 14-nation Rio Group said in a declaration at the end of its 10th presidential summit.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton Act, passed earlier this year, tightens sanctions against foreign firms doing business in Cuba. Latin leaders say they consider the law a U.S. attempt to infringe other countries' sovereignty.</p>
<p>The group, set up in 1986, advanced its integration plans. Peru and Ecuador said they would try to resolve their border dispute and the area's two main trading blocs announced they would negotiate a free-trade deal.</p>
<p>At a short meeting on Tuesday, President Abdala Bucaram of Ecuador and his Peruvian counterpart Alberto Fujimori said they were ready for friendship and prepared to seek a negotiated solution to the dispute, which erupted in border clashes last year that killed 100 troops.</p>
<p>&quot;I will visit Peru in January to strengthen our friendship,&quot; Bucaram said. Fujimori said they were on a first-name basis.</p>
<p>The four-nation Mercosur customs union and the five-member Andean Group said they would negotiate a pact allowing for the free flow of goods through the two blocs.</p>
<p>The Andean Group, comprising Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Bolivia, also said it would seek free trade with Panama. Mercosur members are Brazil, Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay.</p>
<p>In their final declaration, the leaders also expressed their will to work toward the creation of a Latin American Community with executive, legislative and judicial powers.</p>
<p>Although the Rio Group criticised the White House for its Cuba policy and several members rejected Washington's decision to cancel the U.S. travel visa of Colombian President Ernesto Samper, the two sides said they trusted U.S.-Latin ties would not suffer.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not marking a cooling of relations,&quot; Bolivian President Gonzalo Sanchez de Lozada told a news conference closing the two-day summit. &quot;This is showing the need for frank and clear discussions with the United States.&quot;</p>
<p>He proposed that U.S. and Latin American government ministers should meet within the United Nations framework to iron out their differences.</p>
<p>Over the past few years, the two sides came closer than ever as virtually every country in Latin America returned to democratic rule and its leaders embraced the free market.</p>
<p>The U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, Madeleine Albright, in Cochabamba for talks with Latin leaders, said she trusted the renewed friendship would withstand differences.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly there are disagreements ... but we have so many other issues that we deal with and that we have a common purpose on that I do not think there will be an anti-American feeling&quot; in Latin America, she said late on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COCHABAMBA, Bolivia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOLIVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
