<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31772" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks end firm, Banco de Colombia leads.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks end firm, Banco de Colombia leads.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks closed higher in active trade that saw Banco de Colombia post gains for the sixth consecutive day.</p>
<p>Medellin's IBOMED general price index closed up 0.21 percent, at 13,275.35 on a volume of 2.3 billion pesos.</p>
<p>Bogota's IBB index ended up 0.31 percent at 848.54 in above-average trading volume of 2.6 billion pesos.</p>
<p>Banco de Colombia extended its winning streak for the sixth consecutive session by closing up 1.12 percent at 450 pesos a share in Bogota and 2.24 percent to 455 pesos in Medellin.  </p>
<p>&quot;Demand for Banco de Colombia continues to be strong because of the call for a 20 percent increase in its bi-annual dividend at the next shareholders meeting,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>The rise in the Bogota index was fueled at least in part by 1.24 percent gain in Banco de Bogota, which was heavily traded and closed at 5,700 pesos per share. Brewer Bavaria SA, also among most actives, ended up 0.26 percent at 3,760 pesos.</p>
<p>Losers in Bogota included financial group Corfivalle, whose preferential shares fell 10 percent to close at 3,600 pesos and Banco Ganadero, whose preferential shares dropped 5.91 percent to end at 205.10 pesos.  </p>
<p>In Medellin, movers included Bavaria, which closed up 0.53 percent at 3,770 pesos per share. Banco de Bogota also closed higher in Medellin, ending up 1.24 percent at 5,700 pesos a share.</p>
<p>Large cross-trades in companies belonging to the powerful Sindicato Antioqueno industrial group contributed to the heavy trading volume in Medellin, but had no impact on prices, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
