<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31771" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil shrs end fractionally higher in weak trade.</title>
<headline>Brazil shrs end fractionally higher in weak trade.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian stocks ended slightly higher, tracking the Dow Jones' mild rise, but trading was at a near standstill due to a lack of local or foreign market-moving news, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was very weak,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;We have no relevant economic or political news.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sao Paulo bourse's Bovespa index of 49 most traded shares edged up 69 points to close at 62,769 points, up 0.11 percent.</p>
<p>Turnover was an anemic 165 million reais, one of the lowest volumes of the year.  </p>
<p>Brokers said trade was moribund due to a lack of news, local or foreign. &quot;There's nothing going on,&quot; brokers said.</p>
<p>Brazilian stocks dipped at the open, but remained mostly stable through the day, shadowing the Dow Jones and keeping a watchful eye on developments in Iraq, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is going very, very sideways these days,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;Iraq hurt on the first day, but not today, and otherwise the market is closely following the Dow.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bovespa's rise was led by Banco do Brasil common BBp.SA, up 5.1 percent to end at 10.50 reais. Steelmaker CSN common led losers, falling 3.4 percent to 22.60 reais.  </p>
<p>Among blue chips, benchmark Telebras preferred dipped 0.26 percent to close at 75.40 reais, while its common rose 0.80 percent to end at 61.88 reais.</p>
<p>Telebras shares and options comprised 40 percent of the day's total trade, brokers said.</p>
<p>Other blue chips were mixed.</p>
<p>Brazil's state oil monopoly Petrobras preferred ended the day up 0.83 percent at 121.00 reais and state mining giant Vale do Rio Doce preferred climbed 1.02 percent to 19.85 reais.  </p>
<p>But blue chip power firm Eletrobras dipped 0.36 percent to end at 280.00 reais despite a 0.78 percent rise in the bolsa's Electrical Energy Index of nine most-liquid power shares to 1,591 points.</p>
<p>-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
