<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31777" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine Catamarca mine tender seen as benchmark.</title>
<headline>Argentine Catamarca mine tender seen as benchmark.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Results of an Argentine mine exploration tender due Friday may help set a benchmark for Catamarca province's mining negotiations, the provincial mining secretary said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm awaiting the tender with interest, as it may serve for terms of reference in agreeing future deals,&quot; Raul Galarza told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Argentine firm Yacimientos Mineros Aguas de Dionisio (YMAD) said earlier Wednesday that it would soon announce the winner of the tender, which has already drawn three bids of about $20 million.  </p>
<p>Galarza said that the three bidders had each offered about $2 million cash to YMAD as part of their proposals.</p>
<p>Catamarca province has already agreed on terms for exploration rights with Canada's Northern Orion Explorations Ltd for the Antofalla Este gold, copper and silver prospect.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that in 30 days we will have issued the final decree for Antofalla Este so that they can begin work at the site this summer,&quot; Galarza said.  </p>
<p>Catamarca is also negotiating with Northern Orion over the La Hoyada and Diablillos prospects, and with Australia's BHP Ltd over the Filo Colorado prospect.</p>
<p>Galarza said he expected talks over Filo Colorado to be concluded first, followed by La Hoyada and then Diablillos.</p>
<p>Bidders to explore YMAD's 230-square km site in the northwestern province of Catamarca were MRN Explorations SA, Le Source Development Argentina IATE and Eastcan Mining Ltd. Each proposed spending about $20 million in exploration.</p>
<p>MRN is a joint-venture between MIM Holdings Ltd, Australia's North Ltd and Rio Algom Ltd of Canada. These three companies are already partners in the billion-dollar Bajo de la Alumbrera copper and gold project, adjacent to the property now being tendered.</p>
<p>Le Source is made up by Australia's Normandy Mining and French company BRGM. Eastcan is from Canada.</p>
<p>-- Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
