<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31773" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela to use oil windfall to pay off debt.</title>
<headline>Venezuela to use oil windfall to pay off debt.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuelan ministers cautiously welcomed windfall oil revenues produced by renewed tension in the Middle East and insisted that the extra cash would go to pay off foreign debt.</p>
<p>&quot;For every extra dollar in the oil price (per barrel), 100 billion bolivars ($210 million) goes to the Treasury and will be used to pay this heavy burden of debt,&quot; Energy and Mines Minister Erwin Arrieta told reporters.</p>
<p>The Venezuelan government recently established a special account to place revenues from oil exceeding $14.70 per barrel. The account is to be used to pay off outstanding debt.  </p>
<p>Arrieta announced that Venezuela's basket of crude and products had risen to $20.12 per barrel on Wednesday, up from $19.05 on Friday. The average for the year so far is $17.19 per barrel, he said.</p>
<p>Planning Minister Teodoro Petkoff, meanwhile, warned that &quot;downpour of dollars&quot; caused by rising oil prices could tempt the government to forget its austere economic reform program.</p>
<p>&quot;We are being careful to not forget the necessity of this adjustment,&quot; Petkoff said in an interview with Radio Caracas.</p>
<p>Venezuela launched an economic reform program in April aimed at reducing the fiscal deficit and cutting inflation.</p>
<p>-- Caracas newsroom, 582 834405</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
