<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31776" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine bonds slip on light profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Argentine bonds slip on light profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine bonds finished lower Wednesday on some light profit-taking sparked by lower U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was very calm with a downturn in Treasuries sufficient to provoke some profit-taking after the gains in recent days.</p>
<p>The 5.5 percent dollar-denominated Bocon Previsional 2 due 2001 fell $0.15 to 115.95. The market was firmer in the morning but slipped during the afternoon.</p>
<p>A trader at a local bank said the market was waiting for Thursday's meeting of the ruling Peronist Party at which President Carlos Menem is expected to attempt to whip up support for the government's economic policies among party members.</p>
<p>In addition, the rise in U.S. bond yields has traders once again looking to the U.S., particularly with the important September jobless report due for release on Friday which could provide more clues on whether the Federal Reserve is likely to raise rates any time soon.</p>
<p>Still, sentiment in the Argentine market remained fairly upbeat. The issue of another mark bond this session and confirmation from the Economy Ministry that it is considering launching a 30-year bond helped maintain a positive tone.</p>
<p>&quot;I am bullish for the medium term,&quot; said Roberto Costa Bourdieu, senior fixed income analyst at Banco Rio de la Plata.</p>
<p>In the money markets, one day call money rates fell to 8.15 percent from 8.45 percent.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
