<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31779" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico same-day Cetes rates reverse gains at close.</title>
<headline>Mexico same-day Cetes rates reverse gains at close.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican same-day Cetes rates reversed early gains to close 45 basis points down on Wednesday at 23 percent due to greater liquidity in late trading.</p>
<p>The same-day rates reached a high of 24.30 percent mid-morning in what was considered an adjustment in line with primary rates assigned at Tuesday night's auction.  </p>
<p>Traders said that higher primary rates calmed the market and reduced speculation. The benchmark 28-day primary Cetes rose to 25.75 percent in Tuesday's auction.</p>
<p>&quot;The market opened higher and the (primary rate) hikes calmed things down a little, but we are still watching out for U.S. economic data,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Other traders said that volume was moderate as dealers await forthcoming U.S. unemployment figures, which are due out on Friday, and their impact on long-bond yields.  </p>
<p>Term rates closely followed the move in same-day paper, with 28-day and 91-day Cetes also closing about 50 basis points down at 25.58 and 28.83 percent respectively. Overnight bank paper was unchanged, however, at 25.50 percent.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico earlier injected 3.942 billion pesos of liquidity by auctioning credits at between 25.85 percent and 26.69 percent.</p>
<p>Liquidity shortfalls on Thursday may arise from 2.29 billion pesos of loans falling due and an estimated 300 million pesos to be injected by the central bank on Wednesday afternoon to help banks tidy up their checking accounts.</p>
<p>There was also an oversupply of 435 million pesos carried over from Tuesday's primary auction.</p>
<p>-- Patricia Lezama, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
