<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31785" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Invermexico to finalize Latinvest sale.</title>
<headline>Invermexico to finalize Latinvest sale.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican financial group Grupo Financiero Invermexico may finalize the sale of its 66 percent stake in the New York-based brokerage house Latinvest to Banco Bilbao Vizcaya this week, a group spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;At the end of this week, or next week at the latest, the final sales contract will be signed between the four parties involved,&quot; said Inaki de Abiega, from the international area at Invermexico.  </p>
<p>&quot;The sales formula will be determined by (Latinvest's) share capital on September 30, when the deal is to be settled. The amount will vary between 100 and 105 million pesos,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At the beginning of August, the owners of Latinvest -- Invermexico, Brazilian bank Banco Bozano Simonsen and the board of Latinvest -- signed a letter of intent to sell 100 percent of the shares in the brokerage to Spanish bank Banco Bilbao Vizcaya.</p>
<p>&quot;The effects of the transaction (on Invermexico) will be on accounts only. The 66 percent stake (held by Invermexico's brokerage) is equivalent to 97 million pesos,&quot; de Abiega added.</p>
<p>Although the amount involved in the transaction is not considered substantial, it constitutes part of Invermexico's effort to capitalize its main subsidiary, Banco Mexicano.</p>
<p>At the end of June, Banco Mexicano's capitalization index stood at 9.12 percent, or slightly above the required minimum of eight percent.</p>
<p>-- Maria Luisa Aguilar, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9553</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
