<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31788" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's ICA says highway debts to be restructured.</title>
<headline>Mexico's ICA says highway debts to be restructured.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican government has indicated that it will soon restructure financing for loss-making highway construction concessions granted to private firms, said a major construction company head on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are holding talks over financial restructuring for the highway concessions ... the process should be concluded soon as the government has given positive signs,&quot; Bernardo Quintana, CEO of Empresas ICA, told a news conference. During the 1988-1994 presidency of Carlos Salinas, some 4,000 km (2,500 miles) of toll roads were built by Mexico's main construction firms, many with huge loans from private banks.  </p>
<p>But because the concession holders were forced to charge prohibitively high tolls because of the short terms of the concession, the highways have mostly made huge losses.</p>
<p>Refinancing debts held by private highway concessions will grant commercial banks some relief, Quintana said.</p>
<p>&quot;The program will help free highway concession projects from debt and rid the commercial banks of loans which have not been profitable for them,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Appendices to President Zedillo's second state of the nation speech, delivered on Sunday, show that the estimated cost of this program will be 14 billion pesos.</p>
<p>The main objective of the program, Quintana said, will be to grant relief for the financing of each concession and set up suitable repayment periods so that capital investors may recoup outlay.</p>
<p>Quintana also felt that it would be convenient for the government to be a shareholder in toll highways.</p>
<p>&quot;I think so, it would be convenient, and I think that in the future there will be projects that may not go ahead with strictly private capital, and there will have to be joint investment by the government,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Claudia Villegas, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9549</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
