<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31782" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima shares end firm as foreigners step up buying.</title>
<headline>Lima shares end firm as foreigners step up buying.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on the Lima stock exchange closed firmer on Wednesday as an increase in foreign investment flows enlivened trade, brokers said.</p>
<p>After largely apathetic activity throughout August, foreign players are increasingly visible this month, they said. As a result, the upward trend is expected to continue Thursday, they added.</p>
<p>Wednesday the General Index rose 0.75 percent to 1,429.97 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index climbed 1.29 percent to 1,973.43 points, according to preliminary stock figures.  </p>
<p>The government announcement earlier that the country's gross domestic product expanded 2.0 percent in the first seven months of the year demonstrated the healthy prospects for the country's economy in the medium-term, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear the economy is going to continue performing well, which means companies will achieve better results,&quot; said Manuel Torres of local brokerage Finvest.</p>
<p>These prospects have made investors upbeat about positioning themselves in Peruvian equities, brokers said.  </p>
<p>Among leaders Wednesday, benchmark Telefnica del Per, accounting for 16.5 percent of the day's volume of 41.4 million soles ($16.8 million), rose 0.52 percent to 5.78 soles.</p>
<p>Edegel, which accounted for 10 percent of the session's volume, remained attractive as investors sought buy the stock before the end of Wednesday -- the record date for a cash dividend of 0.1326 sol per share, brokers said.</p>
<p>The electricity generating utility's share price rose 0.16 percent to 6.22 soles.  </p>
<p>In high volume of 1.1 million shares, chocolate producer D'Onofrio soared 10.18 percent to 1.18 soles on rumors of a takeover bid by a foreign company. D'Onofrio strongly denied the rumors.</p>
<p>In a total of 2,245 trades, 27 stocks rose, 27 fell and 32 were stable.</p>
<p>-- Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
