<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31793" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Sandinistas may change anthem to smooth image.</title>
<headline>Sandinistas may change anthem to smooth image.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua's left-wing Sandinista Front may change the words to its controversial anthem to improve relations with the United States, a top party official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Yankee is the enemy of humanity&quot; says a line in the anthem. The Sandinistas governed Nicaragua from 1979 to 1990, maintaining close ties with the Soviet Union and Cuba, while fighting an eight-year war against U.S.-backed Contra rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we're thinking of changing those words. They don't do a lot to help our relations with the United States,&quot; Sandinista vice presidential candidate Juan Manuel Caldera told Reuters.</p>
<p>As they campaigned for the Oct. 20 presidential elections, the Sandinistas were trying to improve relations with the United States to reassure voters that a victory for them would not mean a return to civil war. Sandinista presidential candidate Daniel Ortega has repeatedly said his party's relations with the United States are different from what they were in the 1980s and that the two could work together.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a Sandinista Front that has evolved, placing itself within the new national and international reality,&quot; said Bayardo Arce, a member of the Sandinista ruling council.</p>
<p>Caldera, a non-Sandinista rancher who was named as Ortega's running mate in an effort to broaden the party's appeal, was set to leave on Sept. 6 for a five-day visit to the United States to drum up support for the party.</p>
<p>Ortega currently trails Arnoldo Aleman of the right-wing Liberal Alliance 40 percent to 30 percent at the polls in the race to be Nicaragua's next president.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
