<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31790" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico spot peso closes weaker on long bond.</title>
<headline>Mexico spot peso closes weaker on long bond.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican peso reversed its early gains on the 48-hour contract on Wednesday to close slightly weaker as the U.S. 30-year Treasury bond yield climbed back above 7.10 percent and the stock market flagged, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The long bond (yield) revived a little after midday and that made some investors begin to acquire positions in dollars, which squeezed the market a bit,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour or spot peso closed 0.25 of a centavo weaker to 7.5750/7.5800, while 24-hour peso closed unchanged at 7.5700/7.5750.</p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday, the same-day peso closed two centavos stronger at 7.5510/7.5540.  </p>
<p>U.S. 30-year Treasury bond yields peaked at 7.12 percent, compared to 7.08 percent in early trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors usually move ahead of economic data which they feel may be unfavorable, which could be why the long bond yield is increasing,&quot; one peso trader said.</p>
<p>U.S. employment figures are due out on Friday, which traders said may lead to upside pressure on long-bond rates.</p>
<p>The Mexican stock market's leading index dipped from an early high of 3,309.96 points to around 3,298.05 as the currency market was closing. But stock prices have since inched higher.</p>
<p>--Alexis Quinones, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9555</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
