<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31798" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine business backs proposed income tax hike.</title>
<headline>Argentine business backs proposed income tax hike.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's powerful Group of Eight federation of the country's biggest business lobbies said Wednesday it backed proposals to replace a rise in wealth tax with a rise in income tax.</p>
<p>Group official Alberto Alvarez Gaiani, also vice-president of the Argentine Industrial Union, said businessmen opposed to proposals by Peronist deputies to double personal wealth tax to 1.0 percent had proposed the income tax alternative.  </p>
<p>&quot;The badly-termed 'wealth tax' is a tax on all assets and could have caused more problems for industry, and especially to small and medium-sized firms, so as an alternative we sought an increase in income tax,&quot; he told local radio.</p>
<p>Leaders of the ruling Peronist Party's Congress majority agreed with Economy Minister Roque Fernandez Tuesday to seek a 10 percent hike in income tax rather than an increase in wealth tax.  </p>
<p>Fernandez, President Carlos Menem and business groups were all opposed to a hike in wealth tax. But Peronist deputies had proposed it as a way of boosting fiscal revenue after they defied the minister by insisting he share with the provinces any revenue from new fuel taxes in his fiscal austerity bill.</p>
<p>Oscar Lamberto, Peronist head of the Budget Committee of the Chamber of Deputies, said Wednesday that each alternative would raise $600 million towards Fernandez's attempts to head off a 1996 budget deficit he says could reach $6.6 billion.  </p>
<p>Fernandez had hoped his package would boost the budget by $1.6 billion this year, but it has already been delayed and watered down by parliament.</p>
<p>The lower house of Congress is due to debate the package next Wednesday, but Menem wants to reach party consensus on it and on his proposals for more flexible labor laws in a key meeting of party leaders scheduled for Thursday.</p>
<p>Alvarez Gaiani said business leaders would have preferred &quot;no new taxes affecting the productivity of the country, but we face a fiscal deficit and we are all in the same boat so within the choices we had, this was the lesser evil.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the Group of Eight had also proposed replacing Fernandez's planned new 10 percent tax on new diesel cars with a one percent tax on all cars made between 1986-1996. This would avoid &quot;recession and sackings in the sector,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Stephen Brown, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0695</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
