<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31794" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Embraer commuter jet sale to cut '96 loss.</title>
<headline>Embraer commuter jet sale to cut '96 loss.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The recent sale of 25 regional jets to Continental Airlines Inc affiliate Continental Express Inc for $375 million will help Brazilian airplane maker Embraer SA cut a projected 1996 loss and post a profit next year, a company official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The sale was fundamental to meeting our goals,&quot; said Embraer corporate affairs director Claudio Moreira. &quot;It confirms our (financial) numbers and projections for production,&quot; Moreira added.  </p>
<p>Empresa Brasileira de Aeronautica, or Embraer, posted a $300-million loss last year due to one-time restructuring costs.</p>
<p>Banking on its new EMB-145 twin-jet to reverse its fortunes, the firm projects a net loss of between $40 million and $60 million this year and a modest profit in 1997.</p>
<p>Moreira said the sale of the 50-seat jets to Houston-based Continental Express, a commuter carrier unit of Continental Airlines, was included in company plans and earnings forecasts for the next several years.  </p>
<p>&quot;It does not change our plans at all,&quot; he said. &quot;But if the sale had not taken place, that would have affected us very seriously.&quot;  The sale, Embraer's largest contract to date, was announced Tuesday in Houston and at an international aviation show in Farnborough, England.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the company published a notice to stockholders about the hefty deal in Brazilian newspapers.</p>
<p>The purchase agreement calls for the aircraft to be delivered over the next two years, starting in December, and includes an option for 175 more aircraft over the next 12 years, officials said.  </p>
<p>The news prompted a surge in shares of the recently privatized firm.</p>
<p>Embraer preferred, which opened at 5.50 reais, jumped to 6.00 reais by 1535 local/1835 GMT Wednesday on the Sao Paulo stock exchange.  The stock was up 85 centavos from Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>A group of Brazilian and U.S. banks and pension funds that bought formerly state-owned Embraer in December 1994 has pumped $180 million into the firm to complete development of the EMB-145.  The aircraft is seen as a replacement for its 30-seater turboprop EMB-130 Brasilia model launched 11 years ago.</p>
<p>-- Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
