<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31807" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Rights group urges safe return of Colombian troops.</title>
<headline>Rights group urges safe return of Colombian troops.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA, Colombia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Human Rights Watch/Americas group urged leftist rebels on Wednesday to arrange the safe and speedy release about 60 soldiers seized as &quot;prisoners of war&quot; during an attack on a military base in Colombia's southwestern jungle.</p>
<p>The Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia (FARC) said in a statement on Monday that between 60 and 67 soldiers had been taken prisoner after its forces overran the remote Las Delicias military base in southwest Putumayo province last Friday.</p>
<p>At least 27 soldiers were killed in the attack, 11 of them reportedly sentries hacked to death with machetes before guerrillas overran the compound.</p>
<p>The Washington-based human rights group urged the FARC in a statement issued by its executive director, Jose Miguel Vivanco, to &quot;ensure that the soldiers captured as prisoners of war receive humane treatment.&quot;</p>
<p>Pierre Gassmann, chief delegate in Colombia of the International Committee of the Red Cross, told reporters on Tuesday that he had been assured by FARC spokesmen the soliders were all in good health and would eventually be released to a committee of government representatives and members of the ICRC.</p>
<p>&quot;The FARC is obligated to protect the life and well-being of each prisoner and take advantage of the most expedient and safe way to turn them over to the proper authorities, in this case the International Committee of the Red Cross,&quot; Vivanco said.</p>
<p>The FARC, Colombia's largest and oldest guerrilla group, grew out of peasant militias formed in 1948. It was officially founded as a Marxist pro-Soviet group in 1964.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA, Colombia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
