<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31809" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SURINAM: Surinam set for tight presidential vote.</title>
<headline>Surinam set for tight presidential vote.</headline>
<byline>Dennis Samson</byline>
<dateline>PARAMARIBO, Surinam 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Surinam's government and main opposition parties rallied members on Wednesday on the eve of the closest presidential run-off since independence from the Netherlands two decades ago.</p>
<p>The 869-member United Peoples Assembly (VVV), which includes national, regional and district representatives, will vote on Thursday to decide whether a former school teacher or a leading member of Surinam's former military government should run the South American country.</p>
<p>President Ronald Venetiaan, 60, had appeared to be in the driver's seat after his New Front coalition beat former military strongman Desi Bouterse's National Democratic Party in elections in May. But his margin of victory was not wide enough to take control after two voting rounds in the National Assembly and recent defections by New Front members have left him neck-and-neck with NDP candidate Jules Wijdenbosch.</p>
<p>A simple majority of votes at the VVV meeting will be enough to take the presidency and form a government.</p>
<p>&quot;It's so close that nobody wants to bet even a bottle of whisky on the outcome,&quot; one Western diplomat said.</p>
<p>While party activists sought to secure every vote, leaders from both sides said victory was assured. &quot;Everything shows that people are behind us, that they are tired of the old parties,&quot; Wijdenbosch told a news conference on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Parties that have joined the NDP-led coalition have done so on condition that Bouterse, 50, will hold no public office. He is held responsible by many for ordering the torture and murder of 15 opposition leaders in 1982.</p>
<p>His stern regime provoked an armed uprising by colourful rebel leader Ronny Brunswijk. The six-year conflict, which started in 1986, cost more than 500 lives and saw about 15,000 seek exile in neighbouring French Guiana.</p>
<p>Many fear that despite Bouterse's assurances, victory for Wijdenbosch, his right-hand man in the 1980s, effectively would place the former leader in power. &quot;Wijdenbosch will be no more than Bouterse's puppet,&quot; the diplomat said.</p>
<p>Ties with the Netherlands, which were virtually broken off during Bouterse's regime, were re-established after Venetiaan's victory in a VVV vote in 1991.</p>
<p>Surinam, with a population of 400,000, is one of the world's biggest bauxite producers. But the effects of civil war and a tough economic programme launched in 1993 have seen its gross domestic product per capita fall from more than $3,000 to $1,200 in the last 15 years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SURM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARAMARIBO, Surinam"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SURINAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
