<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31812" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOLIVIA: Andean ministers to meet in Lima on free trade.</title>
<headline>Andean ministers to meet in Lima on free trade.</headline>
<dateline>COCHABAMBA, Bolivia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign ministers from the five Andean nations will meet within the next 15 days in Lima to discuss their plans to seek free trade with the Mercosur bloc, a senior Bolivian official said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The ministers will discuss whether the five Andean Pact members Bolivia, Colombia, Ecuador, Peru and Venezuela will negotiate with the Mercosur customs union as a group or whether Bolivia and Peru would do it separately, Bolivia's Deputy Foreign Minister Victor Rico told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;That has not been decided yet,&quot; he said after the five Andean Pact presidents met in this central Bolivian city on the fringes of the 10th Rio Group of Latin American nations summit winding up later Wednesday.</p>
<p>Colombia said Tuesday that Andean Pact trade ministers will meet in Caracas next week to discuss their upcoming negotiations with Mercosur, which comprises Brazil, Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay.</p>
<p>Panama, a country with close ties to the Andean Pact, has also requested free trade with the five-nation group, Rico said. The Andean leaders instructed their ministers to start talks with Panama as soon as possible, he said.</p>
<p>Virtually all Latin American countries have now cast aside protectionistic and isolationistic practices of the past, adopting regional economic integration as their watchword.</p>
<p>Chile has negotiated a free-trade deal with Mercosur and other countries, including Mexico have expressed interest in a pact as well.</p>
<p>-- David Haskel, Cochabamba Press Center +591 411-7173</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COCHABAMBA, Bolivia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOLIVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
