<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31816" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico agrees to buy up unsold sorghum stocks.</title>
<headline>Mexico agrees to buy up unsold sorghum stocks.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Controversial unsold stocks of sorghum will be bought by the Mexican government from farmers in the northeast state of Tamaulipas, the head of the Association of Matamoros Farmers said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We calculate that there are around 400,000 tonnes of sorghum unsold from this crop that the government has agreed to liquidate at 1,200 pesos per tonne,&quot; Alvaro Rivera told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Rivera said the government had promised to pay for the stocks, mainly unsold because of the federal grain import policies, by September 12.  </p>
<p>Rivera said government grain import policies this spring, allowing tariff-free imports from nations such as the United States and Argentina, has caused local markets to be saturated because they discounted national production.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no buyers for our sorghum and prices came down,&quot; he said, saying that farmers in the region were hurt because they need to sell to pay debts and prepare for upcoming planting cycles.  </p>
<p>Rivera added the government decision to buy the sorghum, via the state-owned warehousing and trading arm Almancenes Nacionales de Deposito SA, or Ansa, is recognition that government policies caused the problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is now acting in consequence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The farm leader said an exact figure could not really be placed on how much sorghum would be snapped up by the government through Ansa, the most respected state vehicle for commodities intervention.  </p>
<p>He explained the problem was one of 550,000 tonnes when it emerged 10 weeks ago and now he calculated around 400,000, because local producers had recently transported, at their own costs, around 80,000 tonnes of stored sorghum to consumer states such as Puebla, Michoacan and the central Bajio region.</p>
<p>Monterrey-based daily El Norte reported Wednesday that the amount of sorghum to be bought by the government would be 356,000 tonnes, citing the state Agricultural Minister Eduardo Garza Gonzalez.</p>
<p>But Rivera said he thought the final amount would easily surpass that total, considering that Tamaulipas this cycle produced around 1 to 1.2 million tonnes of sorghum, down from average output figures between 2 and 2.5 million tonnes largely because of the drought.</p>
<p>Rivera said what urked Tamaulipas farmers most about the controversy was not only the time it took the government to react but also the fact that imports were still entering the country when it was well known what levels of sorghum could be expected from February plantings (harvests starting in June).</p>
<p>-- Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
