<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31823" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile sees $950 mln trade gap next year - Marshall.</title>
<headline>Chile sees $950 mln trade gap next year - Marshall.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile can expect a $950 million trade deficit next year, much higher than this year's deficit and due mainly to lower copper prices, interim Central Bank President Jorge Marshall said.</p>
<p>In a speech to Congress giving the bank's preliminary 1997 economic projections, Marshall said the gross volume of Chilean exports will rise markedly next year -- up 11 percent for all exports and 14 percent for copper.</p>
<p>By value, total exports should rise about 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>But average copper prices next year will slump to about 95 cents a pound, accounting for much of the trade gap, he said.  </p>
<p>The forecasts gave an overall picture of a &quot;reasonable balance in external accounts,&quot; said Marshall.</p>
<p>The trade deficit will end this year at about $400 million, while copper prices are expected to end with a 1995 average of around 105 cents, according to most private forecasts.</p>
<p>Next year's slump in copper exports by value &quot;will be partially compensated by the significant, 14 percent increase of sales by volume,&quot; said Marshall.  </p>
<p>But no major price increases were expected on Chile's other main exports either, he said. After copper, Chile's top exports are paper pulp, fresh fruit and fishmeal.</p>
<p>Overall, Marshall's message was one of weaker growth, fiscal prudence and adverse conditions for export prices.</p>
<p>The government's current accounts deficit will widen to about $2.85 billion next year, or about four percent of GDP, he said. He attributed that deficit to this year's trade gap -- which he projected to be about $350 million -- and for higher service payments of about $300 million.  </p>
<p>The balance of payments will post an overall surplus of $800 million next year, with a surplus in capital accounts more than making up for the current accounts deficit, said Marshall.</p>
<p>All told, Chile can expect a net capital inflow next year of $3.65 billion, about $3.1 billion of which are medium and long-term investments, he said.</p>
<p>New foreign investment should total next year about $1.7 billion, while new credit disbursements should total about $3.2 billion and amortizations about $1.8 billion, said Marshall.</p>
<p>-- Roger Atwood, Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
