<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31837" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine Congress to raise income, not wealth tax.</title>
<headline>Argentine Congress to raise income, not wealth tax.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The president of the Budget and Finance Committee of Argentina's lower house of Congress said Wednesday that the proposed hike in the wealth tax would be replaced by a rise in income tax.</p>
<p>&quot;Personally I like much more the income tax because of its progressive scale and because it places a tax on revenues not on capital,&quot; said Oscar Lamberto of the ruling Peronist Party.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have to collect the same amount in income as from the wealth tax,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The proposed doubling of the wealth tax to 1.0 percent, opposed by President Carlos Menem and the business community, would reap the same revenue as a 10 percent rise in income tax, Lamberto said.</p>
<p>A 10 percent increment in the income tax is estimated to raise revenue by $600 million per year, as total proceeds from that levy now amount to $6.0 billion.</p>
<p>It was unclear whether the increase in income tax would be applied across the board or only to higher-income earners.  </p>
<p>Economy Minister Roque Fernandez and Peronist legislators tried Tuesday to iron out differences over Fernandez's fiscal austerity package, submitted to Congress a week ago.</p>
<p>Fernandez hopes to narrow a fiscal deficit which he warns could hit $6.6 billion this year without the measures.  He had hoped to boost the budget by $1.6 billion, but the package is being delayed and the bill to be debated first by the deputies has been watered down by the budget committee.</p>
<p>Fernandez and Menem opposed the proposed doubling of the wealth tax to 1.0 percent which was a concession won by lawmakers to compensate the provinces for lost revenues from other changes in the tax structure.</p>
<p>Menem pledged this week he would not allow any measures that scare off capital.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Helft, Buenos Aires Newsroom + 541 318 0663</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
