<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31839" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Telebras 1996 net seen over 2.2 bln reais.</title>
<headline>Telebras 1996 net seen over 2.2 bln reais.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian telecoms giant Telebras will post a 1996 consolidated net profit of at least 2.2 billion reais as both line traffic and profits from last year's rate hike continue climbing, analysts said.</p>
<p>Strong seven-month results reported by Telebras last week were in line with market expectations, leaving most projections for year-end earnings unchanged, analysts polled by Reuters said.</p>
<p>&quot;The company's outlook is excellent,&quot; said one local analyst who asked not to be named.  </p>
<p>Known formally as Telecomunicacoes Brasileiras S.A., the Telebras system, with 28 subsidiaries, is one of Latin America's fastest growing telecoms. Its preferred stock is the benchmark on Brazil's stock exchanges and traded as an ADS on U.S. markets.</p>
<p>Consolidated 1996 earnings estimates range between 2.2 billion reais and 2.92 billion reais, versus some $800 million last year. Projections for profits for Telebras' holding reach 3.26 billion reais this year.</p>
<p>Analysts said Telebras preferred is likely to end the year between 95 and 100 reais. It closed Tuesday at 75.80 reais.  </p>
<p>In the January-July period, Telebras posted a consolidated net profit of 1.573 billion reais, up 230 million reais from a first-half consolidated net of 1.343 billion reais.</p>
<p>Unaudited July earnings were up from prior months due mostly to heavier-than-normal telecoms traffic stemming from the Atlanta Olympics.</p>
<p>Some analysts expect monthly earnings to continue climbing as traffic grows, partly because of increased use of the Internet, and further cost-cutting to prepare for privatization starting in early 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe the company's results are accelerating toward the end of the year,&quot; an analyst at the local branch of a major foreign bank said.</p>
<p>Others said those rising profits may be tempered slightly by inflationary losses in tariffs. Brazil's 1996 inflation rate is projected to be about 15 percent.</p>
<p>As good as 1996 looks, 1997 may be even better for the telecoms giant, the analysts said.  </p>
<p>A second round of tariff adjustments slated for November is not expected to significantly affect 1996 earnings. But it jack up profits sharply in 1997, with analysts' projections ranging up to 4.7 billion reais.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is now looking to 1997 and it looks very, very strong,&quot; said Eduardo Munemori, telecoms analyst for local Banco Pactual.</p>
<p>The basic residential subscription rate is likely to rise at least 100 percent while long-distance tariffs will be cut as the government eliminates subsidies of basic service.</p>
<p>Still, Telebras' medium- and long-term outlook depends on some as yet unclear factors, such as how the government will write new regulations for Brazil's telecoms sector and how it plans to privatize the firm.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally think it will be broken up into five or six 'baby brases,' like they did with AT&amp;T,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
