<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31846" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: FEATURE-Macarena dancing queen lives in Caracas.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Macarena dancing queen lives in Caracas.</headline>
<byline>Paul Hughes</byline>
<dateline>CARACAS, Venezuela 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The next time you find yourself humming &quot;Hey Macarena!&quot; blame Diana Patricia.</p>
<p>A Venezuelan flamenco instructor and professional dancer whose full name is Diana Patricia Cubillan, the 25-year-old beauty is responsible for the unlikely summer hit and the biggest dance craze to sweep the globe since the lambada.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't believe what I have done, that all this has happened,&quot; Cubillan told Reuters at her Caracas home. &quot;I am the Macarena, I am the inspiration for the song.&quot;</p>
<p>Few parts of the world have escaped the mayhem she unleashed. The catchy tune by Spanish crooners Antonio Romero and Rafael Ruiz has topped charts from Tokyo to Toronto.</p>
<p>Cubillan, glowing and confident in a flowing pink traditional flamenco dress, remembers the fateful moment vividly. It happened nearly four years ago when she briefly teamed up with Romero and Ruiz, the flamenco duo known as &quot;Los del Rio,&quot; at a show in Caracas.</p>
<p>&quot;They invited me to come on stage and when I began to dance Antonio sang that famous phrase.&quot; The phrase &quot;Dale a tu cuerpo alegria,&quot; or &quot;move your body,&quot; leads the song into a series of saucy lines and the tale of a macho Spaniard and his advances on the beautiful Macarena.</p>
<p>In Seville, hometown of Los del Rio, the Virgin de la Esperanza Macarena is the patron saint of bullfighters. As if to prove divine intervention works in mysterious ways, Cubillan sat in her modest apartment below a portrait of the Macarena Virgin, which has been in her family for more than 50 years. &quot;It was meant to be,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>After early success at home the song appeared to have died out until early this summer when, in one of those quirks of fashion, it suddenly caught on and broke record sales across Europe, the United States and Asia. Today there are dozens of versions including recordings in Portuguese, Italian and Japanese.</p>
<p>&quot;I love the song, it has very fresh lyrics with double meaning,&quot; said Cubillan, who lives with her mother in the upper-middle-class Caracas suburb of Santa Paula.</p>
<p>La Macarena is accompanied by a deceptively simple 10-step dance that harks back to the days of disco and John Travolta's hit movie &quot;Saturday Night Fever&quot; in the late 1970s. Almost daily events are organised in search of the world record for the biggest simultaneous Macarena dance. The current record stands at more than 40,000.</p>
<p>In Manila, capital of the Philippines, traffic police were told to cheer up gridlocked motorists by jigging along to the infectious chart-topper.</p>
<p>Cubillan started dancing when she was six. Despite having no traceable ancestry from Spain -- seven generations of her family hail from Venezuela's Andean region -- she quickly became expert in flamenco. By the age of 14 she was performing in night clubs and bars as a professional dancer.</p>
<p>&quot;I had to get her a special permission from the Labour Ministry,&quot; her mother, Amanda Herrera, recalled.</p>
<p>Now that her secret identity is out in the open she has incorporated a flamenco version of La Macarena into her routine. &quot;I do it at the end of the show. The crowd love it.&quot;</p>
<p>It seems fitting that the inspiration for the sexiest dance craze on the planet hails from Venezuela, a country famous for its beautiful women, which boasts the reigning Miss Universe and Miss World and has claimed more international beauty crowns than any other nation.</p>
<p>Cubillan, who studied flamenco at the famous Amor de Dios academy in Madrid, recently met up with Romero and Ruiz in Spain. The three plan to team up again when the group's tour reaches Latin America at the end of the year.</p>
<p>Heaven help us if they come up with another trend-setting collaboration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS, Venezuela"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
