<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31844" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOLIVIA: Latin leaders blast U.S on Cuba, U.S. nonchalant.</title>
<headline>Latin leaders blast U.S on Cuba, U.S. nonchalant.</headline>
<byline>David Haskel</byline>
<dateline>COCHABAMBA, Bolivia 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>As Latin leaders prepared on Tuesday to blast U.S. legislation tightening the trade embargo on Cuba, the United States played down the issue as a minor disagreement among friends.</p>
<p>Leaders of 14 Latin American and Caribbean nations holding a regional summit in Cochabamba were preparing a final declaration in which they planned to include a strong rejection of the U.S. Helms-Burton law, delegates said.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton Act, passed earlier this year, tightens sanctions against foreign firms doing business in Cuba. Latin leaders say they consider the law a U.S. attempt to infringe on other countries' sovereignty.</p>
<p>But the U.S. ambassador to the United Nations, Madeleine Albright, who held a series of talks with Latin leaders and ministers on Monday and Tuesday, minimised the issue, saying all agreed on the need for Cuba to return to the democratic path.</p>
<p>&quot;I am well aware of the difference of opinion on the Helms-Burton legislation within the hemisphere,&quot; she told reporters before boarding a plane back to New York, where the United Nations was discussing the Iraqi crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;But I was also struck in my conversations with a variety of Latin American leaders about our common desire to have democratization take place in Cuba,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Albright acknowledged that some Latin leaders were not pleased with Washington's decision in July to revoke the U.S. travel visa of Colombian President Ernesto Samper, whom the Clinton administration accuses of having links with drug cartels.</p>
<p>But she said U.S.-Latin American ties have dramatically consolidated over the past few years, mostly because of a common approach to democracy and free markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly there are disagreements on the Helms-Burton law and some questions about the Samper visa, but we have so many other issues that we deal with and that we have a common purpose on that I do not think there will be an anti-American feeling,&quot; Albright said.</p>
<p>Albright also discussed U.S. plans to try to unseat U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali in a December vote, but she did not say whether she was able to garner any support. Her purpose was to make clear the U.S. stance was &quot;irrevocable,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COCHABAMBA, Bolivia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOLIVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
