<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31855" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a landmark decision which may force the Government to rewrite parts of its industrial relations reform legislation, the High Court yesterday struck down provisions of the Federal Industrial Relations Act which allowed workers to gain compensation or renstatement if the dismissal was found to be otherwise &quot;harsh, unjust and unreasonable&quot;. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Speaking during a visit to Taiwan by Federal Primary Industries Minister John Anderson, Taiwanese President Lee Teng-hui said he would like to visit Australia to show his gratitude for the nation's support during the recent China missile crisis. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Environment Minister Robert Hill said yesterday the Howard Government is likely to be able to meet the concerns of Tasmanian Independent Brian Harradine about the proportion of money from the Telstra sale to be spent on the Tasmanian environment, but he added that Harradine's concerns could mean changing the makeup of the board administering the Natural Heritage Trust, or giving him an estimate of what Tasmania could expect to receive. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Environment Minister Robert Hill told The Australian Financial Review yesterday the Queensland Government is likely to end its opposition to the Cape York land use agreement after the High Court brings down its decision on the Wik case - expected later ths year - allowing the agreement to go ahead. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Industrial Relations Minister Peter Reith said last night he had no doubt the Government's Workplace Relations Bill was constitutionally valid, and he said any constitutional doubts about the widespread changes in industrial relations had been erased by aHigh Court decision yesterday to uphold its wide powers to make law in the area. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Opening Australia's first national conference on homelessness - called Homelessness in the Lucky Country - the Governor-General, Sir William Deane, made an outspoken plea for the nation's disadvantaged yesterday, saying their collective plight constituted a problem across Australia of overwhelming dimensions. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Speaking before a second round of Tomahawk cruise missiles was launched by the United States yesterday, Prime Minister John Howard said the US missile attacks on Iraq were the &quot;proper response&quot; but ruled out any Australian involvement in the conflict at tis stage, saying &quot;no suggestion&quot; had been made of any direct military role for Australia. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Immigration Minister Philip Ruddock yesterday moved to limit changes which will require all sponsors of migrants to be Australian citizens by announcing the immediate families of humanitarian program entrants and protection visa holders would be eligible o come to Australia under the preferential category - a move which will mean refugees will be able to sponsor immediate family members more easily. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>According to the Report on Women's Ministry in the Diocese of Sydney by the Archdeacon for Women's Ministry, Dianne Nicholios, four out of five Anglican clergy are in favour of women preaching and leading church services - a result which adds to the prospct of women priests being ordained in Sydney. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The ABC's radio news, sport and current affairs executives decided to end their popular rugby league radio broadcasts when they met last week to find savings and determine policy for next year, claiming Australian Rules has emerged as the national game. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Consolidated Press found the very suggestion of sex too hot yesterday when the publisher axed a new television commercial, which had already been cleared by the Federation of Australian Commercial Television Stations, for its women's magazine Csmopolitan hours before it was to air. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Pregnant non-smoker Marie Deanshaw, who worked for tobacco company Rothmans of Pall Mall as a marketing representative and was sacked for swapping her staff-issued cigarettes for model cars, has launched an unfair dismissal claim against the group. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Although a A$70 million investment in Victoria by German-based Robert Bosch Group to establish at its Clayton plant a facility for worldwide production of car body electronics was announced this week, the move was jeopardised by the Howard Government's deision to cut the 150 per cent tax deduction for research and development to 125 per cent. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Widow Theone Cheong told the Melbourne Coroner's Court yesterday that her husband would still be alive if a mobile intensive care ambulance (MICA) sent from the Alfred Hospital had arrived earlier. General practitioner Dr Steven Ehrenreich supported her view, claiming that her husband's chances of surviving the heart attack would have been enhanced if he had received paramedic assistance sooner. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government will look to win the support of the Senate's two independents after yesterday receiving confirmation from Democrats Leader Cheryl Kernot that her party would oppose Budget proposals to increase prescription charges and change the Higher Education Contribution Scheme. Page A3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under the latest management proposal to meet Australian Broadcasting Corporation budget cuts, State bulletins would cease after 7pm on weekdays and not start until midday on weekends and 30 journalists' positions would be cut nationwide. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
