<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31857" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>RTRS-TIMELINES-Today in History - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>**BIRTHDAYS**</p>
<p>The colonial administrator and explorer EDWARD JOHN EYRE, who discovered Lake Eyre, was born in 1815.</p>
<p>American film director JOHN HUSTON, whose films included &quot;The Maltese Falcon&quot; and &quot;The African Queen&quot;, was born in 1906.</p>
<p>Australian Prime Minister HAROLD HOLT, who sent Australian troops to Vietnam, was born in 1908. He was prime minister briefly from 1966 to 1967 before he went missing, presumed drowned off Victoria's Cheviot Beach.</p>
<p>American actor ROBERT TAYLOR (SPANGLER ARLINGTON BROUGH) was born in 1911. He was the screen idol for millions of women. It wasn't revealed until after his death that he was homosexual.</p>
<p>American astronaut and the first man on the moon, NEIL ARMSTRONG, was born in 1930.</p>
<p>Australian actor JOHN JARRATT was born in Wollongong in 1952. He played 'NED KELLY' in the television series &quot;The Last Outlaw&quot;. His career has included stage, television and film work.</p>
<p>				**EVENTS**</p>
<p>    1729 :    The man who invented the first automatic steam</p>
<p>engine, THOMAS NEWCOMEN, died.</p>
<p>    1861 :    National income tax was introduced in the United</p>
<p>States. It was imposed to fund the Civil War, but when the war ended, the tax continued.</p>
<p>    1881 :    Construction began on the Innisfail Sugar Mill</p>
<p>just south of Cairns. It was built under the auspices of the Catholic Bishop of Brisbane, DR JAMES QUINN. Crushing began in January 1882.</p>
<p>    1913 :    Suffragettes upgraded their campaign to secure the</p>
<p>vote for women. In London they bombed several MP's country homes. Three weeks later they attacked the prime minister while he was playing golf.</p>
<p>    1914 :    The first electric traffic lights were installed</p>
<p>in Cleveland, Ohio.</p>
<p>    1926 :    A Sydney milkman became the first claimant under</p>
<p>the Workers' Compensation Act, saying he had contracted bronchitis in a fog.</p>
<p>    1936 :    HITLER turned his back on American athlete, JESSE</p>
<p>OWENS, as he won his third gold medal at the 11th Olympics in Berlin. The 23 year old black American was a living example of opposition to HITLER's theory of Aryan superiority. After OWEN won the 200 metres, the disgruntled Fuhrer privately congratulated the silver medalist from Germany but ignored OWEN and left the stadium.</p>
<p>    1944 :    There was an attempted mass breakout of 1,000</p>
<p>Japanese prisoners of war at the Cowra POW camp in southern New South Wales.</p>
<p>    1958 :    The nuclear-powered submarine &quot;Nautilus&quot; under</p>
<p>Commander WILLIAM R. ANDERSON, completed an historic underwater journey passing directly under the North Pole. The 3,200 kilometre journey took five days.</p>
<p>    1962 :    The woman called &quot;the ultimate sex symbol&quot;,</p>
<p>MARILYN MONROE, was found dead in her Hollywood home. She was lying naked clutching a telephone receiver, with an empty bottle of sleeping pills on her bedside table. MARILYN was born NORMA JEAN MORTENSEN and spent her childhood with foster parents. Her first of three marriages was when she was 16. She became a photographer's model and started her movie career with bit parts. MARILYN made 23 films. Her friendship with the US President JOHN F. KENNEDY and her death were the subject of conspiracy theories. The official cause of death was an accute barbiturate overdose.</p>
<p>    1963 :    Australia and Japan signed an historic trade</p>
<p>agreement, paving the way for a greater exchange of goods between the two countries.</p>
<p>    1968 :    Governor of California, RONALD REAGAN, said he</p>
<p>would run for the presidency.</p>
<p>    1971 :    The three editors of the &quot;Oz&quot; magazine were</p>
<p>convicted of obscenity charges for an edition aimed at schoolchildren. Hundreds of young protestors demonstrated outside the Old Bailey, burning an effigy of the judge and blocking traffic for two hours. The three editors, JAMES ANDERSON, FELIX DENNIS and Australian RICHARD NEVILLE were jailed for between 9 and 15 months. NEVILLE was also recommended for deportation.  The &quot;Oz&quot; magazine had as its stated content &quot;dope, sex, cheap thrills, porn and rock'n'roll.&quot; The case caused division within the community with many claiming the sentences were too harsh.</p>
<p>    1972 :    During the Olympic games, Arab terrorists of the</p>
<p>Black September movement attacked an Israeli dormitory in the Olympic village at Munich, killing two members of the Israeli Olympic team. Nine Israelis, five terrorists and a West German policeman later died in a shoot-out at Munich Airport.</p>
<p>    1984 :    Welsh-born actor RICHARD BURTON died at his home</p>
<p>in Switzerland. Twice married to actress ELIZABETH TAYLOR, BURTON appeared along side his wife in 1962 in &quot;Cleopatra&quot; and in &quot;Who's Afraid Of Virginia Wolf&quot; in 1966. He won acclaim for his many Shakespearian and contemporary performances on stage and screen.</p>
<p>    1990 :    United States President GEORGE BUSH sent troops</p>
<p>into Liberia, the capital of Monrovia, to evacuate American nationals and protect the US embassy.</p>
<p>    1990 :    Iraq claimed it was withdrawing troops from</p>
<p>Kuwait. The invasion of the oil-rich country led to the Gulf War, which effectively destroyed the 500,000 strong Iraqi army.</p>
<p>    1991 :    After seven decades of certainty, the Soviet Union</p>
<p>destroyed its old power structures and virtually abolished the constitution. President GORBACHEV created a transitional regime robbing him of much of his power and delivering it to the republics.</p>
<p>    1995 :    France conducted an underground nuclear test on</p>
<p>Mururoa Atoll, causing worldwide condemnation. Anti-nuclear and independence protesters rioted in Tahiti for two days.</p>
<p>(Compiled from ABC ARCHIVES, ABC RADIO NATIONAL, &quot;On This Day&quot; published by REED INTERNATIONAL BOOKS LIMITED, &quot;The Chronicle Of The 20th Century&quot; published by PENGUIN BOOKS and &quot;Rock And Pop (Day By Day)&quot; published by BLANDFORD BOOKS)</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
