<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31859" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australian bonds rally, outlook checkered.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australian bonds rally, outlook checkered.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------(Snapshot at 4.35 P.M./0635 GMT)------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES					  CASH YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS  (DEC) 93.16  (+ 0.08)    6.94    (- 0.01)</p>
<p>3-YR T-BONDS  (SEP) 92.54  (+ 0.08)    7.32    (- 0.08)</p>
<p>10-YR T-BONDS (SEP) 91.830 (+0.105)    8.19    (- 0.11)</p>
<p>AUD/USD  0.7920 (PREV 0.7913) US 30-YR  7.06   (7.06 NY)</p>
<p>---------------------(Sept 4)-------------------------------</p>
<p>*Australian bonds rallied sharply after Tuesday's aggressive futures-led sell-off as the market regrouped on current positive economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>*However, tone still cautious on U.S. market, Iraq crisis.  </p>
<p>By Colin Brinsden</p>
<p>Australian bonds rallied sharply after Tuesday's aggressive sell-off as the market regrouped on current positive economic fundamentals, and generally shrugged off the absence of any Reserve Bank rates announcement.</p>
<p>However, the market is keeping a wary eye on developments in the U.S./Iraq conflict, although it showed no reaction to a second U.S. cruise missile attack on Iraq today.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides have played their pawns, and the question is what piece does Saddam Hussein move next?&quot; said Stephen Roberts, chief economist at UBS Australia.  </p>
<p>The inflationary implications of higher oil prices eminating from the Iraq crisis appeared to be brushed aside for now as the immediate focus concentrates on Friday's U.S. non-farm payrolls.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries rebounded on Tuesday on a more subdued than feared NAPM index and a soft Redbook retail sales report, but fears of a tightening by the Federal Reserve remain close at hand, traders said.</p>
<p>The local market went into near free fall yesterday amid the combination of the Iraq crisis, newspaper reports that the Fed is leaning towards a 50 basis point tightening and a sharp jump in local retail sales.  </p>
<p>The Reserve Bank left monetary policy unchanged after Tuesday's board meeting, making no announcement at its money market operations time today.</p>
<p>This came as little surprise after yesterday's 2.4 percent leap in retail sales and given that the central bank had eased policy by 50 basis points only in July.</p>
<p>However, bill futures remained fairly jumpy in the run-up to the Bank's dealing time, but quickly eased back when no policy statement was made.</p>
<p>The active December bill futures contract ended at 93.16 after a day's high of 93.19. It had touched 93.35 on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>-----------------------(SPREADS)----------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 84 (+ 01)   130 (- 04) * FUTURES   71   (- 02)</p>
<p> CAD	132 (- 07)    77 (- 09) * CASH	85   (- 05)</p>
<p> NZD	-91 (- 10)   -27 (- 15) *</p>
<p>------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The Australian/U.S. 10-year bond yield spread narrowed slightly after Tuesday's blow-out. This spread had got down to around 115 basis points on Monday when a firm local short end, on tentative rate cut hopes, had supported long bonds and briefly decoupled from a shaky U.S. market.  </p>
<p>--------------------(TECHNICALS)-----------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*DAY'S HILO  *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (SEP)*91.85-91.78 *91.77-91.83 *50 PCT *91.93 *91.94</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (SEP)*92.58-92.52 *92.50-92.59 *50 PCT *92.66 *92.69</p>
<p>90-DAY  (DEC)*93.19-93.13 *93.10-93.20 *52 PCT *93.26 *93.29</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The 10-year bond futures contract rotated around 91.830 for most of the session after bouncing from 91.665 in after hours trade and having sustained a break back over 91.770. Immediate range seen between 91.700 to 91.900</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
