<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31856" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>After more than 540,000 of National Mutual Holdings' 1.2 million policy holders selected shares instead of cash ahead of its stock exchange listing, Australia's second-largest life office has increased the asking price for its remaining shares to a range of A$1.35 to A$1.55. The unexpectedly large take-up of shares will see NatMut having the largest share register in the country. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an effort to cut costs and offer lower electricity prices as the sector moves towards full deregulation, Australia's second-largest power distributor, Integral Energy Ltd, has signed a five-year A$100 million outsourcing deal with giant information tecnology firm EDS. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A vision statement about what Australia's car industry could achieve by the year 2010, which will be used to evaluate the recommendations of the Productivity Commission, is being prepared by the Department of Industry, Science and Tourism at the request of the Minister, John Moore. Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although TNT Ltd yesterday announced its worst bottom line for four years, a 75.4 per cent fall to A$9.84 million, managing director David Mortimer said the result was the fault of major &quot;black spots&quot; Ansett Holdings Ltd  AIRa.NZ and wholly owned transport operations in Australia and Brazil, which are now sold, or soon to be offloaded. Page 15.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After announcing a 50 per cent rise in net profit to A$225.4 million in the year to June, boosted by a strong performance by the Nine Network and a big abnormal gain from non-core asset sales, Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd managing director James Packer said a weakening advertising market for TV and magazines made the outlook difficult to assess. Page 16.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although Woodside Petroleum Ltd's profit rose strongly to A$84.38 million after tax, the result - about A$10 million below market expectations - was eroded by technical problems on Woodside's Cossack Pioneer floating oil and gas production vessel. Page 17</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The battle for domination in the Coles Myer Ltd boardroom has intensified, with New Zealand corporate raider Brierley Investments Ltd, which announced last month it had increased its shareholding in Coles to 6.8 per cent, renewing its push for board repreentation. In recent talks with Coles chairman Nobby Clark, BIL is understood to have pitched for a board seat. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Telstra Corp Ltd chief executive Frank Blount yesterday defended the group's controversial A$4 billion Foxtel cable sellout, saying a decision to avoid the move would have slashed 20 per cent off the national telecommunications carrier's shareholder value within a decade. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Announcing the second stage of life insurance giant National Mutual Holdings' A$1 billion plus listing, NMH managing director Geoff Tomlinson revealed the group will boast Australia's biggest share register when it lists on the stock market next month aftr approximately half the eligible shareholders chose to take up their share entitlement in preference to a cash payment. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>At a time when media profits across the industry are flat, the Nine Network has unexpectedly boosted the Packer family's listed vehicle, Publishing &amp; Broadcasting Ltd, to a 15.3 per cent rise in annual net profit to A$172.6 million, with PBL shares closing 15 cents higher at a two-and-a-half year high of A$6.05. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After TNT Ltd yesterday reported a 57 per cent drop in its 1995-96 pre-abnormals net profit to A$25.8 million, the group's managing director David Mortimer predicted a profit recovery for TNT now that it is free of the &quot;huge distraction&quot; of its 50 per cent ownership of struggling Ansett Airlines AIRa.NZ. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Woodside Petroleum Ltd yesterday announced earnings of A$89.3 million - A$84.4 million after an abnormal loss of A$4.9 million for the relocation of its head office from Melbourne to Perth - which was a lower than expected profit increase for the half year.  However, its shares made further gains due to a strong rise in the oil price because of the conflict in the Middle East. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>National Mutual Holdings managing director Geoff Tomlinson has described as &quot;gratifying&quot; the decision by more than 540,000 policyholders to take up their entitlement to shares in the A$2.5 billion sharemarket listing next month - a result which will see the group having Australia's largest share register. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Transport group TNT managing director David Mortimer yesterday predicted profit would improve in 1997 despite the group suffering a 75 per cent fall in net profit to A$9.8 million due to a plunge in Ansett Australia's profit contribution and significant anormal losses from the restructure of its struggling domestic general freight operations. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Kerry Packer's Nine Network has secured a negotiation of the option agreement which allows him to buy up to 20 per cent of Optus Vision - a deal which has angered Seven Network chairman Kerry Stokes as it could result in a cheaper entry into the pay-TV market for Packer. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The proposed A$115 million sharemarket listing of Colly Farms Cotton is set to go ahead after Argentinian-based agricultural specialist John Kahlbetzer, flush from the sale of his 30 per cent stake in Australian Agriculture last year, agreed to become the core shareholder with a 25 per cent stake through his private group Twynam Investments. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Speaking after a speech to the Securities Institute luncheon, Telstra chief executive Frank Blount down played the importance of selling 100 per cent of Telstra, saying the planned one-third float of the national carrier would deliver between &quot;80 to 90 per cent&quot; of the benefits associated with privatisation. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting has posted a 50.3 per cent rise in net profit to A$225.39 million for 1995-96, up from A$149.94 in the previous year, defying a weak advertising market and an increase in paper costs and setting the scene for strng growth over the next two years. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>More than 540,000 National Mutual Holdings policy holders have accepted their share entitlement, taking up 55 per cent of the shares available in the offer. The result will give National Mutual Australia's biggest share register when it lists on 8 October.  Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd has signed an exclusive five-year contract with Dreamworks SKG to buy Australian rights to the Hollywood production company's movies and television series. Dreamworks was created in 1994 by producer Steven Sielberg, former Walt Disney Studios chairman Jeffrey Katzenberg and music industry mogul David Geffen. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Japanese Post and Telecommunications Ministry has stopped Rupert Murdoch from appointing a non-executive, Australian director to the board of Asahi Broadcasting because radio laws do not permit foreigners to serve on the boards of Japanese broadcasting companies. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Heavy abnormal writedowns stemming from TNT's Spanish freight operations and a significantly lower contribution from the group's 50 per cent stake in Ansett Australia have been blamed for the transport services group's 75 per cent drop in net profit for the year to June 30, from A$40 million to A$9.84 million. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>With earnings from building and construction business slumping from A$14.38 million to just A$6.71 million, National Consolidated reported a 42 per cent fall in June year net profit to A$14.41 million. Business linked to the car industry was also down, returning only A$16.32 million, compared with A$21.09 million a year ago. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although the Melbourne-based Spotless group reported a 49.3 per cent increase in full-year net profit to A$18.1 million, chairman Brian Blythe said little growth could be expected from the core business services sector, which produced a small fall in sales in the 1996 financial year. Page B3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
