<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31860" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian stocks follow bonds to higher end.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian stocks follow bonds to higher end.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian share market finished on a strong note on Wednesday, closing at its day's highs as the bond market climbed off the floor after Tuesday's solid selloff.</p>
<p>At 4.30 p.m. (0630 GMT), the All Ordinaries index was 13.9 points higher at 2258.5 while September share price index futures were up 26 points at 2,263 and at a 4.5 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said the Dow's rebound off its day's lows, after the U.S. bond market was rescued by weaker than expected economic data, had proved sufficient incentive for local players.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have taken a guide from New York,&quot; said dealer Peter Struk of brokerage Reynolds and Co, noting that reasonable buying had underpinned the day's strength.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been good buying and we have held our ground.&quot;</p>
<p>Other traders made similar sentiments, saying the Dow's recuperative powers had allowed the local market to gain ground.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a pleasing showing,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;With the Dow showing some resilience, bonds have given us the impetus to go ahead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Caution was evident from both traders, though, as they pointed to continuing concerns over U.S. interest rates.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is still very much wait and see. People are still jittery about the U.S.,&quot; Struk noted.</p>
<p>Banks stole the limelight, the big banks rebounding as bond markets recovered.</p>
<p>The banking index outperformed the rest of the market, adding 1.67 percent on the day compared to the benchmark All Ordinaries' gain of just 0.62 percent.</p>
<p>Other strong performances came from Kerry Packer-controlled television and magazine group, Publishing and Broadcasting, which scored highly with investors after a 50 percent higher full year net profit of A$225.4 milion.  </p>
<p>Among others, Qantas Airways shares ended off a couple of cents as oil prices jumped in response to the Iraqi crisis.</p>
<p>Other results came from transport and logistics group TNT which saw its shares end firmer, despite a sharply lower A$9.84 million full year net profit.</p>
<p>Caterers and providores Spotless Services and Spotless Group both saw their shares close firmer after reporting higher year net profits of A$20.27 million and A$18.05 million respectively.</p>
<p>Insurance group HIH Winterthur ended only just firmer despite a sharp increase in full year net profit to A$26.1 million.  </p>
<p>Kitchen and bathroom fittings manufacturer GWA International closed higher despite posting a flat full year net profit of A$30.12 million.</p>
<p>Oil and gas major Woodside saw its shares close stronger after nearly doubling its first half net profit to A$84.38 million, while coal miner QCT Resources also ended higher after more than doubling its full year net profit to A$71.47 million.</p>
<p>Dairy group QUF's full year net profit of A$11.51 million was down as were its shares by the close.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about nine to seven, while about 32 percent of stocks traded remained steady.  </p>
<p>In other local markets, bonds rallied sharply after Tuesday's aggressive sell-off as the market regrouped and shrugged off the absence of any Reserve Bank rates announcement.</p>
<p>By 4.35 p.m. (0635 GMT), 10 year T-bonds were yielding 8.19, down 0.11 on Tuesday's levels.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar inched ahead Wednesday after the Reserve Bank held official rates steady in the wake of Tuesday's policy meeting.</p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the dollar had made hard work of a modest gain to be quoted at US$0.7922/27 from an early US$0.7914/19 and US$0.7913/18 here late on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>FUTURES/OPTIONS - Futures trading saw moderate activity as did options markets although both were slowed from Tuesday's strong levels.</p>
<p>Total options traded 44,477 (58,477)</p>
<p>Turnover in September SPI contracts totalled 6,605 (11,217)</p>
<p>-----------------------(TECHNICALS)-------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2240/2270     2240	2270	54.59   2270   2255</p>
<p>SPI    2250/2280     2240	2280	53.43   2272   2260</p>
<p>---------------------(KEY ACTIVES)--------------------------</p>
<p>*NAB A$12.28 (+.22 ) 12.09/12.20 Vol: 1,556,550</p>
<p>*Comm Bank A$10.77 (+.17) 10.63/10/78 Vol: 678,162</p>
<p>*Comm Bank Rec A$6.70 (+.15) 6.58/6.72 Vol: 471,635</p>
<p>*Westpac A$6.17 (+.15) 6.05/6.19 Vol: 3,642,315</p>
<p>Banks impresss as bond market bounces back.</p>
<p>*Pub Broad A$6.05 (+.15) 5.86/6.05 Vol: 84,393</p>
<p>Media shares surge with strong profit result.</p>
<p>*Spotless Services A$2.17 (+.07) 2.14/2.17 Vol: 3,000</p>
<p>*Spotless Group A$2.02 (+.07) 1.98/2.02 Vol: 54,500</p>
<p>Caterers/providores shares edge up after full year profits.</p>
<p>*TNT A$1.47 (+.03) 1.44/1.47 Vol: 834,073</p>
<p>Transport group reported lower year net profit of A$9.84 million.</p>
<p>*HIH Winterthur A$2.60 (+.01) 2.53/2.60 Vol: 51,390</p>
<p>Insurance group reported half year net profit of A$26.1 million.</p>
<p>*QCT Res A$1.75 (+.04) 1.718/1.75 Vol: 351,955</p>
<p>Coal producer's year net profit rose 142 pct to A$71.47 million</p>
<p>*BHP A$17.23 (+.11) 17.18/17.28 Vol: 2,422,028</p>
<p>*WMC A$8.67 (+.02) 8.66/8.75 Vol: 876,074</p>
<p>*CRA A$19.10 (+.02) 19.04/19.25 Vol: 1,055,628</p>
<p>Resources leaders close firmer as Dow, bonds bounce.</p>
<p>-- Walter Watson 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
