<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31863" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RBA says no case for mega industry regulator.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RBA says no case for mega industry regulator.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) deputy governor Graeme Thompson said on Thursday he did not see a compelling case for the Wallis Inquiry into the nation's financial system to support the formation of a &quot;mega-regulator&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The objective should be a supervisory system which achieves its prime objectives while being as flexible and &quot;market-friendly&quot; as possible,&quot; Thompson, who is responsible for prudential supervision at the central bank, said in a speech to the Economic Society of Australia.  </p>
<p>&quot;The idea that a monolithic supervisory bureaucracy is more likely to deliver this than a small number of specialist agencies working co-operatively on issues of common concern seems rather fanciful,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under the current system, the RBA oversees banks, the Australian Financial Institutions Commission (AFIC) oversees building societies and credit unions, and the Insurance and Superannuation Commission (ISC) is responsible for superannuation funds.  </p>
<p>The industry inquiry, to be chaired by former Amcor Ltd managing director Stan Wallis, was announced by the conservative government earlier this year to consider further deregulation and any other necessary changes.</p>
<p>A key issue for the inquiry, which is due to hand its report to the government in March 1997 will be whether or not the four major banks should be allowed to merge with each other, or with the two largest superannuation funds. Thompson did not address this topic in his speech.  </p>
<p>He said financial institutions were generally not faced with onerous costs as they did not have to meet the demands of more than one regulator.</p>
<p>&quot;Overlaps would be more serious if an individual institution was answerable to more than one prudential supervisor,&quot; Thompson said.</p>
<p>&quot;By and large, this is not the case in Australia - each supervised institution is clearly the responsibility of only one of the main supervisory agencies - the RBA, ISC, or AFIC.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said Australian banks did not face problems with the current regulatory system and their high profitability was at odds with the view that prudential constraints had a heavy bearing on their operations.</p>
<p>&quot;While recent high levels of profitability are now being challenged, this is primarily the result of new competitors with much lower operating costs than the banks have,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our overall assessment is that the supervisory burden on Australian banks is not excessive - and much less than in countries such as the United States and Japan which engage in extensive on-site examinations,&quot; Thompson said.  </p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
