<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31865" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Boral sees housing-led improvement.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Boral sees housing-led improvement.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building products and energy group Boral Ltd said on Thursday that an expected upturn in the housing sector early in 1997 should produce a significant improvement in second half earnings.</p>
<p>It also said performance enhancement programmes would deliver annualised savings of over A$50 million in 1996/97.  </p>
<p>Boral said that even though housing starts appeared to have bottomed, the lag in construction meant the current half would remain challenging.</p>
<p>But it said profits in July and August were well ahead of the monthly rate earned in the first half of 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing of the upturn in housing is not clear, but most forecasters expect an upturn in the new year which should result in a significant improvement in second half earnings over the comparable period,&quot; Boral Managing Director Tony Berg said in a statement with the 1995/96 results.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Boral reported a 30 percent fall in net profit to A$205.69 million in the year to June 30, 1996 and posted a 7.5 cents per share final dividend, down from 10.5 cents in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Profits before abnormals fell 45 percent to A$171 million, at the lower end of analysts' expectations of between A$165 million and A$185 million.</p>
<p>Boral said the major cause of the profit fall was the housing downturn in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to volumes, intense price competition caused margins to shrink,&quot; Boral said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Additionally PEP (Performance Enhancement Programmes) will deliver annualised savings of over A$50 million in 1996/97,&quot; Berg said.</p>
<p>Boral's shares closed unchanged at A$3.01 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
