<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31861" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FOCUS-BIL profit down on '95 and forecast.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-BIL profit down on '95 and forecast.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's Brierley Investments Ltd on Thursday posted an annual net profit in the June 1996 year that was down on 1995 and on analysts' forecasts.</p>
<p>The profit of NZ$310.3 million compared with $431.7 million last year and market expectations of around $320 million.</p>
<p>BIL chairman Bob Matthew told a news briefing the year had seen a great many achievements and few disappointments.</p>
<p>&quot;While the reported profit is not another record outcome, on the key measures for underlying value enhancement and investment returns for shareholders, this has been a very good year.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said that while some New Zealand businesses were experiencing difficult trading times due to an economic slowdown and the strong currency, the present expectation was earnings from operations in the current year would be &quot;satisfactory&quot;.</p>
<p>There had been significant increases in the book value of BIL's investments, particularly Sky City, up $230 million, and the soon-to-be-floated British Thistle Hotels group.  </p>
<p>Contributions from trading activities increased to $300 million from $290 million, while investment contributions fell to $195 million from $316 million -- the main reason for the overall profit decrease.</p>
<p>BIL had major contributions from Thistle, Air New Zealand and the Weeks Bass Strait Royalty.</p>
<p>One investment blow was Australian retailer, Vox, which lost A$17 million and BIL now expected to take until 2000 to turn it around against the plan of completing it next year.  </p>
<p>BIL revealed it had increased its stake in Australian retailer Coles Myer to 6.8 percent from 5.0 percent but chief executive Paul Collins did not reveal's BIL's intentions.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an evolving strategy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BIL also confirmed it had four percent of Fletcher Challenge Energy  FCLTE.NZ, seven percent of Macraes Mining, and increased its stake in James Hardie Industries to 26 percent from 20 and in British brickmaker Ibstock  IBSK.L to 21 percent from 13 percent.  </p>
<p>Collins said quality management of assets and seizing new opportunities for investment -- with a focus on New Zealand, Australia, Britain and Asia -- were the key to BIL's future.</p>
<p>He said BIL had over $2 billion in cash and uncommitted lines and the company could comfortably invest $1.0-1.5 billion in the next 12-18 months without damaging its financials.</p>
<p>As a large scale investment company, BIL had seen many Australasian rivals disappear and now had the field largely to itself, Collins said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are uniquely positioned to take advantage.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the investment by an Asia consortium, Delham Investments, in 20 percent of BIL in March was because the investors saw, and still did, substantial value in BIL.</p>
<p>BIL expected to work with Delham, whose investment was last month put into Malex Industries Bhd, with opportunities being sought particularly in Australia.</p>
<p>BIL's assets in Australia rose in the year to $1.27 billion from $856 million a year ago and were likely to rise further.</p>
<p>Collins said the recent Air NZ buy-in to Australia's Ansett would give the airline a growth spurt in the late 1990s.  </p>
<p>Ibstock was seen as &quot;quite an important company for us going forward in terms of its position in its own marketplace&quot; while James Hardie had unrecognised potential in the United States and would be &quot;part of the group (BIL) for some time, with exciting prospects&quot;.</p>
<p>After the result, BIL's share price fell one cent to $1.42, close to the $1.40 &quot;intrinsic value&quot; BIL put on the share price.</p>
<p>&quot;From our perspective, we never look at the profit figure anyway...it's more the asset backing and the growth in assets that we look at,&quot; said ANZ Securities Managing Director Tim Preston. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
