<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31870" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Goodman sees stronger second half.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Goodman sees stronger second half.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australasian food group Goodman Fielder Ltd expects the second half of 1996/97 to be stronger than the first half, chief executive David Hearn said.</p>
<p>Hearn said wheat prices were likely to be cheaper in the second half of 1996/97, contributing to the better outlook for the second half. The company earlier reported a net profit of A$28.3 million for the year to June 30 compared with a loss of A$52.8 million a year earlier.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the wheat purchases this year, however, given that we're already in the first half, it's fair to say that wheat will almost certainly be cheaper in the second half than it is in the first half,&quot; Hearn told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;And that, because of the very large effect wheat purchases have on our business, suggests we will have a stronger second half than we will a first half this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hearn repeated comments made in an earlier statement however that it was too early to forecast how much profits would be improved for the 1996/97 year overall.  </p>
<p>&quot;The only other part of the forecast that I'm prepared to commit to is we'll have a tougher first half this year, F97, than in the second, based if nothing else on wheat prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hearn said Goodman had to absorb over A$50 million worth of grain cost increases in the 1995/96 year because of the rise in the wheat price to a 30 year high three months ago. He said, however, the price had fallen since then.</p>
<p>Goodman's pre-abnormals net profit rose 3.5 percent of A$100.7 million. This compared with analysts expectations of around A$100 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;Fiscal 97 will see the start of the business making further gains from what we see as a strong stabilised position this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hearn said trading conditions in the early part of the currrent financial year had been mixed, although there were some signs that some sectors could accept price rises.</p>
<p>&quot;There is increasing evidence that the retail trade in particular are beginning to realise they need some price inflation as much as anybody else does in order to see their margins widen,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They've begun to look for price inflation, not in a cavalier manner, but where it's appropriately supported by activity in the market-place and where its defendable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is slightly more room for pricing in the retail sector and I think that the very strong rise in wheat prices is giving room in some sectors for pricing to go through,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hearn said overall there were probably more positive signs for pricing increases in terms of numbers of sectors.  </p>
<p>&quot;For us we're very dependent on flour and bread pricing, and I would say in flour ironically, while wheat pricing has been an issue, the industry dynamics are suggesting that flour and bread pricing are still going to be quite tight.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm cautious about predicting what pricing will do until I'm sure what's going to happen for flour and bread.&quot;</p>
<p>Hearn said the improvement evident in the poultry division in the final quarter of 1995/96, where earnings were double the annual rate in 1995/96, had continued into the early months of 1996/97. Goodmans' shares closed one cent lower at A$1.30 on Wednesday.  -- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
