<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31874" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Goodman Fielder sees improvement after &quot;solid&quot; yr.</title>
<headline>Goodman Fielder sees improvement after &quot;solid&quot; yr.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian food group Goodman Fielder Ltd called its annual result &quot;a solid performance in a very difficult environment&quot; and said it expected an improvement in the current year.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are still in a process of rebuilding Goodman Fielder, the company is in a much stronger position and we are confident that we will deliver an improved performance in the coming year,&quot; Chief Executive David Hearn said.  </p>
<p>Goodman Fielder said the performance of most of its businesses improved towards the end of the financial year as sales prices started to move, synergies across the group began to be realised and the drive to a more value-added margin mix started to take effect.</p>
<p>&quot;We are anticipating that this momentum will continue into the current year,&quot; it said. However, fluctuating world wheat prices meant it was too early to predict current year earnings.  </p>
<p>The company said the food industry worldwide had faced record input prices in some key areas and continued pressure on selling prices. The increase in wheat prices added more than A$44 million to its costs over the year.</p>
<p>The main components of its $72.2 million abnormal accounting charge were writedowns of $25 million in poultry assets, $14.6 million for rationalisation of Asian operations and $13.6 million for capital and commissioning costs in relation to its new Beaudesert gelatin plant.  </p>
<p>The other factors were recognition of $7.7 million in retrenchment costs within the European operations, and a $11.3 million downward revaluation of investments in associated companies. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
