<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31889" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia stands firm on U.N. nuclear treaty move.</title>
<headline>Australia stands firm on U.N. nuclear treaty move.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Wednesday stood firm on plans to push for United Nations approval of a Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty (CTBT), but said its differences with India over the issue would not undermine bilateral relations.</p>
<p>&quot;We and India have different positions on the CTBT. I think what Australia is doing is absolutely right,&quot; Foreign Minister Alexander Downer told reporters after launching an Australian trade promotion campaign aimed at India.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to see a successful CTBT concluded and we are doing everything we can to do that in taking the (treaty) resolution to the United Nations General Assembly,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The CTBT is not an issue that I will allow to undermine the strengthening of our bilateral relationship,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The treaty is designed to ban all nuclear explosions used to test or refine atomic weapons.</p>
<p>New Delhi, which exploded a nuclear device in 1974 but has denied possessing atomic weapons, said the treaty was flawed.</p>
<p>After nearly three years of negotiations for a CTBT, India in August vetoed the draft treaty because it allows the five declared nuclear powers to refine their nuclear arsenals through laboratory tests. It also failed to commit them to a timetable for total disarmament.</p>
<p>India also said it opposed a clause that would require its signature to ratify the pact. New Delhi said the measure impinged on its sovereignty.</p>
<p>The five nuclear states are Britain, the United States, Russia, China and France, with India, Pakistan and Israel known as the three threshold states.</p>
<p>Australia has called a meeting of the U.N. General Assembly for September 9 to have it adopt a draft treaty and open it for signature by individual states.</p>
<p>India has said it would demand a two-thirds vote in the United Nations on the treaty, which it opposes, but would not move to prevent the 185-member body from debating the issue.</p>
<p>Asked by an Indian reporter whether a CTBT would result in &quot;nuclear apartheid&quot; and not disarmament, Downer said he preferred not to use such emotive terms.</p>
<p>The minister said it was best to stop the proliferation of nuclear weapons before seeking disarmament by the five powers.</p>
<p>&quot;The first step is to stop the process of proliferation. We believe a CTBT will make a valuable contribution to that process,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>&quot;If nuclear weapons proliferate, I think we will move into a new era of a deeply dangerous world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Diplomats say Australia is well-placed to put the draft text before the U.N. Canberra firmly established its anti-nuclear credentials in its fierce campaign against recent French nuclear tests in the South Pacific in a stauch effort that won it worldwide recognition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
