<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31894" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - AT&amp;T says no plans for Australia local calls.</title>
<headline>RTRS - AT&amp;T says no plans for Australia local calls.</headline>
<dateline>GOLD COAST, Australia 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. telephone giant AT&amp;T Corp has no plans to enter Australia's local telephone call market when the market is fully deregulated next July 1, AT&amp;T president Asia Pacific John Legere said.</p>
<p>Legere, who is attending a APEC telecommunications ministers meeting here, said AT&amp;T has an alliance with Telstra Corp for the provision of the state-owned group's long distance calls, and that it would monitor the deregulation process in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;As the market liberalises, we will look at the opportunities,&quot; Legere told Reuters in an interview after he gave a speech to the APEC conference on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will look at the impact on our relationships and just watch the evolving situation and see if it provides opportunities for us,&quot; Legere said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is planned at this time. Australia is a very important market for us to serve our global customers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Australian telecommunications minister Richard Alston said at the conference the government would be releasing its 1997 telecommunications deregulation plan in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>State-owned Telstra Corp had a monopoly on Australia's local call market until pay tv and telecommunications group Optus Communications started its local telephone services in June.  </p>
<p>The government plans to sell one-third of Telstra as part of the liberalisation of Australia's telecommunications market.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOLD COAST, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
