<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31897" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>Hong kong: Hong Kong provides rich pickings for classic car fans.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong provides rich pickings for classic car fans.</headline>
<byline>John Newland</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fancy a limo in leathered luxury, a late 1970s Rolls-Royce Silver Shadow I?</p>
<p>Take a trip to Hong Kong and drive away that bargain for a mere $6,460 to $12,920, depending on condition, as wealthy residents leave the British colony in droves before it reverts to Chinese rule next year. Even with shipping costs of about $3,000 to the United States, it's a steal considering a new Rolls-Royce could set you back $388,000.</p>
<p>While most of the 10 million visitors to Hong Kong each year leave with souvenirs packed in a suitcase, a growing number are sending home fully laden shipping containers.</p>
<p>The containers are full of cars -- second-hand prestige vehicles tracked down in Asia's capital of consumerism by astute overseas businessmen, particularly from Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>&quot;There's several million dollars' worth of second-hand cars being exported every month,&quot; said Paul Gross, managing director of Hong Kong's European Motors, which deals in used cars for local and overseas sale.</p>
<p>&quot;And they're making a pretty penny,&quot; he said of the dealers with overseas links.</p>
<p>These are not exports usually associated with the Pearl of the Orient, which earns billions from trade in clothing and textiles, jewelry and myriad other manufactured items.</p>
<p>But the often-jammed roads carrying 500,000 licensed vehicles through the bustling British colony of 6.2 million people offer rich pickings for those with an eye for a bargain.</p>
<p>Well-heeled locals aspire to the latest gleaming model, whether it's a Rolls-Royce, Mercedes, Porsche, BMW or Jaguar, providing an abundant supply of older cars rejected by a throwaway society focused on the latest and greatest.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the cars on the market can be attributed to expats and Chinese moving away from Hong Kong in the run-up to the 1997 handover (to China),&quot; Gross said.</p>
<p>&quot;Then there are a lot who own more than one car who are reducing their ownership exposure for reasons, either real or imagined, in an uncertain period,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While new cars were expensive in Hong Kong, there is no set market value for cars more than a few years old, unlike in the United States, Britain and Australia where dealers have a recorded base price to work from.</p>
<p>&quot;This means you can pick up a bargain,&quot; said a Hong Kong dealer who did not wish to be named. He said he had contacts in Australia's major cities to whom he sold several cars a month.</p>
<p>Pick up the epitome of sports touring, a late 1970s Porsche 911 for HK$60,000 ($7,762), or a Mercedes 350SL convertible for $50,000 ($6,443).</p>
<p>The disparity in prices for older cars between Hong Kong and Australia and New Zealand, where prestige motoring is prized but prohibitively expensive for most due to steep import duties, makes the 9,300 miles round trip from Sydney well worth an entrepreneur's effort.</p>
<p>To ship a limo to New York, expect to pay about $2,000 for the trip, about $250 each for customs clearance, the duty bond and monitoring fee, and a $100 terminal fee. Insurance, which is optional, costs 1.75 percent of the value of the vehicle, according to Overseas Movers in Great Neck, N.Y.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a perception of rich pickings on the streets of Hong Kong,&quot; Gross said. &quot;The disparity of values makes the trade a profitable proposition.</p>
<p>&quot;There was one guy up here recently from Sydney specialising in Mercedes who picked up a dozen in one hit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gross says he has regular buyers from both the North and South islands of New Zealand.</p>
<p>In Australia, where old European cars are rare and sought as classics, prices fetch up to five times Hong Kong levels.</p>
<p>Early models such as a 1972 Mercedes 280 are almost worthless on the local market, says Tom Wilson, of Auto Dynamics on Hong Kong Island. His mechanical repair business also handles pre-sale assessments for prospective car buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;You'd be lucky to get HK$8,000 ($1,031) for an old 280... if you could sell it,&quot; Wilson said.</p>
<p>Not in Australia, where a three-pointed star on the bonnet still rates, irrespective of age.</p>
<p>&quot;Here, you basically have to give an old car away but if it's in good condition these guys from Australia can cash in,&quot; Wilson said. &quot;People here want new cars.&quot;</p>
<p>A stronger Australian and New Zealand dollar combined with a lowering of import duties in Australia for older cars has propelled the trade in the past year.</p>
<p>The visiting buyers target vehicles 15 years or older which attract duties of only around 50 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Business is brisk,&quot; Gross said between frequent phonecalls from clients in search of a bargain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
