<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31898" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Taiwan foreign minister holds talks in Indonesia.</title>
<headline>Taiwan foreign minister holds talks in Indonesia.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwanese Foreign Minister John Chang held talks with his Indonesian counterpart, Ali Alatas, on Wednesday and played hide-and-seek with journalists during a private, one-day visit to Jakarta, Indonesian government sources said.</p>
<p>The venue of Chang's meeting with Alatas was switched from the Foreign Ministry headquarters at the last minute to avoid reporters, but ministry sources and police later confirmed the two had met in a posh, central Jakarta hotel.</p>
<p>Chang also held talks with Research and Technology Minister Jusuf Habibie before a convoy of cars carrying Taiwanese officials headed for President Suharto's residence, the sources said.</p>
<p>No details of the talks were available.</p>
<p>The sources said Chang arrived late on Tuesday and was scheduled to leave on Wednesday. The visit was not announced officially and Chang's office in Taipei refused to comment on his whereabouts.</p>
<p>The visit was likely to anger Beijing, which views Taiwan as a renegade province and routinely attacks the island's attempts to raise its international profile. A civil war separated China and Taiwan in 1949.</p>
<p>Indonesia and Taiwan do not have diplomatic relations, but have strong business ties.</p>
<p>Taipei's mass-circulation United Daily News newspaper said Chang would discuss economic and trade ties between Indonesia and Taiwan in his talks with Alatas.</p>
<p>It said also he would attend the wedding of Alatas' daughter, but the ceremony was scheduled for this weekend.</p>
<p>Chang's unannounced trip to Indonesia followed Vice President Lien Chan's secret visit to the Ukraine in late August.</p>
<p>Beijing bitterly protested that trip and cancelled a visit by a high-level Chinese delegation to Kiev after Lien, who doubles as premier, went there to promote unofficial ties.</p>
<p>Beijing accused the former Soviet republic of violating the &quot;one China&quot; commitment that it made in establishing ties with Beijing.</p>
<p>Only 30 countries, mostly in Africa and central America, recognise Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government.</p>
<p>Taiwan, maintaining that its 21 million people have a right to a voice in the United Nations and other forums, has pushed to win new foreign friends and raise its international profile.</p>
<p>Taiwanese President Lee Teng-hui made an unofficial visit to Jakarta in February 1994. China, which has diplomatic relations with Indonesia, was enraged by the visit and lodged an official protest with Jakarta.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
