<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31895" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Sept 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Sept 5.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Thursday's Malaysian newspapers.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>- The government will consider extending the Intensification of Research in Priority Areas (IRPA) to the private sector, Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said today. He said the IRPA scheme was aimed at meeting the cost of research and development undertaken by universities and government institutions.</p>
<p>- The Employees' Provident Fund has expressed interest in playing a leading role in meeting the country's housing needs, including in the setting up of a housing board.</p>
<p>STAR</p>
<p>- The Social Security Organisation has increased its minimum benefits for temporary and permanent disablement, invalidity pension, survivors' pension and other categories.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>- The Federation of Malaysian Manufacturers has expressed concern over the recent amendments to Section 121 and 338 of the Companies Act 1965 which it says have caused problems, confusion and serious business implications to the private sector. The amendments require every company to have the company's number inscribed on its common seal and on all documents.</p>
<p>- The Malaysian International Chamber of Commerce and Industry warned against drawing conclusions on Malaysia's export activities from a small survey of organisations. The group was commenting on the Bank Negara Survey of Selected Services 1995, which said Malaysia's services sector has not developed its export potential fully.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
