<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31902" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan steelmakers cut first-half profit forecasts.</title>
<headline>Japan steelmakers cut first-half profit forecasts.</headline>
<byline>Mitsuo Suzuki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese steelmakers on Wednesday lowered their profit forecasts for the six months to September 30, 1996, largely due to a delay in inventory adjustments.</p>
<p>Among the top five makers, all except NKK Corp lowered their half-year profit forecasts.</p>
<p>Industry leader Nippon Steel Corp, for example, lowered its outlook for six-month parent current profit to 25 billion yen ($229 million) from its May forecast of 35 billion yen ($321 million).</p>
<p>&quot;We expect steel sheet market prices to recover in the second half (of 1996/97) as we have been cutting output of steel sheets. However, we are not sure whether real demand will increase or whether the demand will be anticipatory demand,&quot; Nippon Steel managing director Takeshi Yoshii told a news conference.</p>
<p>Nippon Steel's actual half-year parent current profit in 1995/96 was 29.38 billion yen ($269 million). Current profit is a pre-tax profit which includes gains and losses made on securities investments and other non-operating activities.</p>
<p>&quot;Supply and demand balance in the steel industry is showing signs of recovery. But Japan's crude steel output in the first half of this business year is expected to remain as low as that of the second half of last year due to a drastic cut in output for inventory adjustment,&quot; Nippon Steel said in a statement.</p>
<p>Steel stocks have piled up due to oversupply, industry analysts said. Steelmakers said they had expected larger demand for steel construction materials due to reconstruction following the massive earthquake in Kobe in January last year and the recovery in Japan's overall economy.</p>
<p>Steelmakers have said since late last year that they were cutting output to reduce inventories and bolster market prices, but analysts say the level of inventories remains high.</p>
<p>Sumitomo Metal Industries Ltd said a fall in steel exports and higher costs for materials were other reasons for the lowered profit forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not confirmed yet whether steel market prices hit bottom in the first half. We should confirm it in the second half,&quot; Sumitomo vice president Kazuaki Tsuda said.</p>
<p>NKK maintained its previous forecast for half-year current profit of 10 billion yen ($91.7 million), helped by its efforts at cost-cutting in both in its steel and engineering divisions and a drop in interest payments as it has been making efforts to cut down on its debts, an NKK spokesman said.</p>
<p>But it lowered its forecast for parent current profit in 1996/97 to 40 billion yen ($366 million) from a May forecast of 45 billion yen ($412 million), mainly due to continued weakness in steel export prices.</p>
<p>Sumitomo Metal and Kobe Steel Ltd lowered their forecasts for full-year parent current profit, while Nippon Steel maintained its earlier outlook for profits for the full year.</p>
<p>The steelmakers estimated Japan's overall crude steel output in 1996/97 at around 98 million tonnes, little changed from their May forecast. This would be the first year-on-year decline in three years and the first time in three years that the figure is expected to fall below 100 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We will post year-on-year declines in both sales and profit this year as we cannot expect a rapid recovery in the domestic economy in the second half due to concerns that the effects of the government's public spending will run out,&quot; Kobe vice president Koshi Mizukoshi told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will make utmost efforts to achieve 90 billion yen in parent current profit for the full year. Steel demand from manufacturing industries will increase in the second half,&quot; Nippon Steel's Yoshii said. ($1=109 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
