<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31906" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei ends barely changed after early falls.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei ends barely changed after early falls.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Nikkei stock index futures ended barely changed on Wednesday after falling initially on news of the second U.S. missile attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>The benchmark September index recovered from the day's low of 20,080 to finish at 20,195. An estimated 20,500 contracts changed hands.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pretty featureless day,&quot; said one dealer with a Japanese futures house. &quot;After the news of the U.S. attack the September contract recovered and resumed its trading range,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the sideways movement of the Nikkei contract would allow it to recover from its current technically oversold position and open the way for the contract to fall further on soft market sentiment.</p>
<p>They said the next downward support for the September contract is at 19,600. &quot;But it's not a very strong support and it should break through this quite, quite easily before testing 19,300 eventually,&quot; said one dealer.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the gloomy business sentiment, as reflected in the Bank Of Japan's Tankan survey, continued to weigh on Nikkei sentiment and expectations for the poor performance of Japanese corporates this year.</p>
<p>They said news of the U.S. attack had a limited impact on Nikkei futures as oil prices and currencies were relatively stable. -- Valerie Lee (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
