<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31901" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia palm oil ends up on good fundamentals.</title>
<headline>Malaysia palm oil ends up on good fundamentals.</headline>
<text>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES     PALM OIL PHYSICAL</p>
<p>Nov (3rd pos)  1,248 rgt/tonne	Sep (south) 1,265*</p>
<p>Open/Hi/low    1,246/1,254/1,241    Prev close 1,26O</p>
<p>Prev settlement 1,244		    * sellers prices</p>
<p>PALM OIL FUTURES - Supportive fundamanetals helped prices to finish higher after the market had drifted in narrow range. Lack of fresh tenders also kept most players at sidelines. Talk of Pakistan in the market but there was no confirmation. Nov futures seen trading between 1,240 and 1,265.</p>
<p>PALM OIL PHYSICAL - The market was also thinly traded with interest among crude palm oil and RBD palm olein.  </p>
<p>Traders estimated end-August stocks at around 750,000 to 755,000 tonnes, against end-July's 754,634 tonnes.</p>
<p>A slower production growth for August also helped market sentiment. Traders estimated a rise of four to five percent over July's 721,893 tonnes, against private forecaster Ivan Wong's August output forecast of a seven percent increase.</p>
<p>Trading was cautious with players awaiting fresh tenders from traditional buyers. There was talk that Pakistan was in the market but traders were unable to confirm it.</p>
<p>Trading volume on the futures market was 1,881 lots against 1,879 on Tuesday.  </p>
<p>But some traders were cautious at the higher and refused to take up large positions for fear that the market may pull back.</p>
<p>At the close, November futures closed five ringgit up at 1,248 ringgit ($499.80) a tonne after trading between 1,241 and 1,254. Traders expect the contract to trade in the 1,230-1,265 ringgit range in the near term.</p>
<p>Physicals saw interest among nearby crude palm oil with Sep (south) crude palm oil quoting sellers at 1,265 ringgit a tonne after trading at 1,260. Bids were at 1,260 ringgit.  </p>
<p>Sep (central) was offered at 1,250 with bids at 1,240. Sep (north) saw offers at 1,240 and bids at 1,230.</p>
<p>Oct/Nov/Dec (south) crude palm oil was offered at 1,275 ringgit with bids at 1,265. Oct (central) saw offers at 1,255 and bids at 1,245 and Nov (central) at 1,265 with bids at 1,255.</p>
<p>In refined products, Sep RBD palmoil was offered at $540 a tonne FOB Malaysia, and Oct/Nov/Dec at $535.</p>
<p>Sep palm olein saw offers at $582.50, Oct at $572.50 and Nov/Dec at $562.50. Dec was traded at $560.  </p>
<p>Sep RBD pam stearin was offered at $422.50 and Oct at $427.50. Sep/Oct palm fatty acid distillate saw sellers at $342.50.</p>
<p>--  Tan Lee Lee (603-2308911) ($1=2.4970 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
