<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31917" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong people to remove lighthouse on islands.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong people to remove lighthouse on islands.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 20 Hong Kong people on Wednesday announced plans to remove a lighthouse erected by right-wing Japanese on one of a group of disputed islands in the East China Sea, a Hong Kong television station reported.</p>
<p>Spokesman Tsang Kin-shing, a pro-democracy legislator, told a news conference the group would sail to the Diaoyu Islands at the beginning of next month, Cable TV reported.</p>
<p>He said they hoped to raise HK$500,000-HK$1 million (US$640,000-US$128,000) to finance the trip, including hiring boats. The islands lie some 1,100 km (680 miles) north-northeast of Hongkong and 400 km (250 miles) east of Fuzhou, on the east coast of China.</p>
<p>The group would would inform the Chinese and Taiwanese governments before their departure, Cable TV said.</p>
<p>Another TV station, Asia Television, quoted Tsang as saying the activists had decided to take matters into their own hands because neither China nor Taiwan had done enough to reclaim the islands.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts from British rule to Chinese sovereignty in mid-1997.</p>
<p>The islands, known as the Senkakus in Japan, are claimed by Japan, Taiwan and China.</p>
<p>A row broke out between China and Japan in July when the Japanese built a lighthouse on one of the islands.</p>
<p>The activists said they had decided to remove the structure after unsuccessful attempts to hand a petition to Japanese Foreign Minister Yukihiko Ikeda during his visit to Hong Kong last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
