<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31925" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Cold Storage swaps asset with Dairy Farm.</title>
<headline>Cold Storage swaps asset with Dairy Farm.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's Cold Storage (M) Bhd said on Wednesday it has entered agreements with Dairy Farm International Holdings Ltd to swap stakes in their retail pharmacy businesses.</p>
<p>The asset swap meant that the two companies under the Jardine Strategic Holdings Ltd stable will work closely together in the future, Cold Storage said in a statement.</p>
<p>Jardine Strategic is a substantial shareholder in Cold Storage and is the holding company of Dairy Farm.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Cold Storage will sell its 30 percent stake in wholly-owned Cold Storage Retail Sdn Bhd to Dairy Farm for 30.40 million ringgit in cash.</p>
<p>In exchange, it will buy a 30 percent stake in Dairy Farm's Guardian SEA Pte Ltd for S$13.80 million in cash.</p>
<p>Cold Storage Retail operates one of the largest retail pharmacy chains in Malaysia under the Guardian name which has 47 Guardian outlets.</p>
<p>Guardian SEA has 54 Guardian retail operations in Singapore and owns the franchise for Guardian operations in Indonesia and Brunei. It also runs a Singapore pharmacy wholesaling business.</p>
<p>Cold Storage will also buy a 70 percent stake in a new wholesaling business being established in Malaysia under Dairy Farm's AMS Health Care Products Sdn Bhd for S$3.29 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
