<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31931" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - HK, China deals get done.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - HK, China deals get done.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets offered a few new Hong Kong and China transactions on Wednesday as well as some chatter on deals done and to come.</p>
<p>Guangzhou Investment Finance Cayman Islands, a special purpose vehicle of Hong Kong-listed Guangzhou Investment Co, launched a 60 million Swiss franc floating rate note issue.</p>
<p>Lenders have the option of swapping the issue into dollars.</p>
<p>The two-year FRN pays a margin of 125 basis points over the six-month Swiss franc London Interbank Offered Rate. With fees, the all-in return is 210 basis points to the top tier.</p>
<p>The deal pays US$ LIBOR plus 175 basis points if done in dollars, but skimpier fees mean the all-in totals 207.5 basis points.</p>
<p>Guangzhou Investment is a property and investment company. Its major shareholder Yue Xiu is an investment company wholly owned by China's Guangzhou municipality.</p>
<p>Arrangers are AB Capital Markets (HK) and UBS.</p>
<p>Details also were out on Fujian Enterprises US$40 million transferable loan certificates deal, which is being arranged by Standard Chartered Investment Banking, AB Capital Markets (HK), KMBC Asia and KEXIM Asia.</p>
<p>Bankers now say that South Korea's Cho Hung Bank may be looking for one-year, rather than three-year, paper.</p>
<p>A number of Korean banks have brought one-year deals lately. For the issuer, the one-year tenor allows it to refinance at a presumably better rate next year, assuming South Korea is accepted into the OECD.</p>
<p>For the lender, the less-than-one-year tenor means that the paper qualifies for a 20 percent risk weighting.</p>
<p>KEB Hong Kong's recently closed HK$500 million 364-day floating rate certificate of deposit issue reportedly is trading well in the secondary market.</p>
<p>Bankers said Moody's downgrading of Bangkok Bank's short-term ratings in tandem with its cutting of Thailand's ratings could be bad news for the bank's US$150 million FRCD that currently is in syndication.</p>
<p>Moody's on Tuesday cut to Prime 2 from Prime 1 the short-term deposit ratings of Bangkok Bank, Siam Commercial Bank and Thai Farmers Bank along with the sovereign.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bangkok Bank deal already was too tightly priced so this certainly is negative for it,&quot; remarked one banker. The five-year deal (seven-year final, five-year put) pays an all-in return of 24 basis points.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
