<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31933" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Gas to remain Malaysia dominant source of power.</title>
<headline>Gas to remain Malaysia dominant source of power.</headline>
<byline>Ramthan Hussain</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia plans to reduce the role of natural gas in its power generation, but it will remain the country's dominant energy source for electricity, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Malaysia's state-owned utility, Tenaga Nasional Bhd, said last month that it planned to reduce its reliance on natural gas turbine power stations after a 12-to-15-hour peninsula-wide blackout on August 3.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not had any policy changes as such and the situation will remain as it is until the (post-blackout) study shows otherwise,&quot; Francis Xavier Jacob, principal assistant director of the Department of Electricity and Gas Supply, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jacob said he did not think British consulting firm National Grid Plc, due to finish a report on Tenaga's operations in a month, would recommend reducing the dominance of gas in Malaysia's power generation.</p>
<p>&quot;What Tenaga said was that we must be careful with the use of gas in terms of its proportion,&quot; Jacob said.</p>
<p>&quot;Reducing always means in proportion, but may not be in absolute terms. The system must be such that if we make use of more gas, we need other kinds of generation to compensate in case these kinds of things happen,&quot; Jacob said in Singapore where he spoke at an energy infrastructure conference.</p>
<p>Tenaga said the blackout was triggered by a faulty component in a 275kv circuit breaker at its Paka power plant in Terengganu state, which tripped several gas turbines and led to an automatic cut-off to the national transmission grid.</p>
<p>Power generation to the grid before the blackout was 5,760 megawatts, of which 62.9 percent was generated by gas turbines, 30.7 percent at thermal plants and 6.4 percent at hydro power plants.</p>
<p>Tenaga said there were concerns about the reliablity of the power supply system because of the high proportion of of gas turbines, which it said have &quot;unpredictable performance characteristics&quot; during system failures.</p>
<p>Jacob said gas turbine power stations have a problem restarting when a trip occurs because the spinning reserve will drop off altogether when it hits a maximum temperature.</p>
<p>Spinning reserve is the additional generation capacity available immediately after the loss of a power plant or an increase in power usage.</p>
<p>Jacob said Tenaga had reviewed all the spinning reserves and put them under thermal plants rather than gas plants.</p>
<p>Analysts say Tenaga seemed to blame the gas and not the equipment for the blackout.</p>
<p>Jacob agreed that Middle Eastern countries have a much bigger proportion of power turbines using gas and have not faced such problems.</p>
<p>He said Malaysian policy was to make gas the main source of energy for the power, industrial and commercial sectors, which will be supplied by the Peninsular Gas Utilisation project.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a lot of gas and we are trying to utilise it. That is one goal. But we must not go to the extent that it makes the whole system vulnerable, so we must study the effects of that as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But technically, it may be possible to marry the two together, that is, increase the use of gas and at the same time make the power system reliable.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
