<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31936" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: China market seen tough for foreign oil firms.</title>
<headline>China market seen tough for foreign oil firms.</headline>
<byline>Ang Bee Lin</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign firms looking for a slice of the potentially massive Chinese oil market could be disappointed due to reluctance in Beijing to let them sell onto the local market, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The sources added that China has its own plans to boost domestic refining.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no more new refineries planned before the year 2000 and attention will be focused on de-bottlenecking, revamping and upgrading existing refineries,&quot; a source at Chinese state refiner SINOPEC told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Various refineries along coastal China have already started on the expansion plans,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>There are plans to add new catalytic crackers that refine heavier oils into products like kerosene (jet fuel) and diesel, said another industry source.</p>
<p>And China plans to integrate refining with the petrochemicals sector, he added.</p>
<p>China's total refining capacity was just over 200 million tonnes last year, and SINOPEC was responsible for 80 percent of it. The expansion plans were expected to add at least 20 million tonnes of capacity by 2000, the source said.</p>
<p>Industry sources said China had also been slow to approve new refinery ventures, and several joint venture projects with foreign partners were still awaiting approval from the State Planning Commission.</p>
<p>Among them were a 200,000 barrels per day (bpd) refinery that state trader SINOCHEM wants to build with Saudi Aramco at Qingdao, a proposal for a 160,000 bpd refiner by China National Offshore Oil Corp and Shell, along with Yukong's plan for a 100,000 bpd export refinery. Feasibilty studies for the three ventures were submitted more than a year ago, the sources said.</p>
<p>They said SINOPEC was hoping that foreign companies keen to build refineries in China would put their money into upgrading existing ones instead.</p>
<p>Five foreign companies -- Arco, Caltex, Amoco, Exxon and Saudi Aramco -- were involved in plans to upgrade China's coastal refineries at Jingling, Fujian, Guangzhou and Moaming respectively, the sources said.</p>
<p>But they said progress had been slow because they could not agree on terms for the upgrades with Chinese refiners.</p>
<p>Foreign investors were keen to help China build new refineries and expand old ones if they could gain access to China's domestic market, a source at SINOCHEM told Reuters.</p>
<p>But legislation that took effect in 1994 requires at least 70 percent of the output from joint venture refineries to be exported, the source said.</p>
<p>SINOPEC'S priorities still were expanding existing refineries and keeping a tight hold on its own retail rights, he said.</p>
<p>He said China has too many refineries. The problem was that they were not running efficiently. &quot;It will make more economic sense to expand old ones,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>So far the only joint venture to materialise is the 100,000 bpd refinery at Dalian built by Total of France and SINOCHEM. It now is undergoing tests.</p>
<p>But downstream, opportunities for foreign investors remained for smaller and less capital-intensive projects in China's booming Liquefied Petroleum Gas, lube oil related business and petrochemcial projects, a Chinese industry source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
