<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31934" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Flood damage to Thai crops seen limited this year.</title>
<headline>Flood damage to Thai crops seen limited this year.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flood damage this year to Thai crops will be limited compared with 1995, when more than a million hectares of crop land was devastated by heavy rains, officials and industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>However, Meteorological Department officials warned farmers not to be complacent. They said farmers should be prepared for more rainstorms during September and October, when the monsoon season peaks.</p>
<p>Seven people had died since May, the start of the rainy season, officials at the Interior Ministry said.</p>
<p>So far, only 12,550 hectares of farmland had been damaged by flash floods between May and September 2, officials said.</p>
<p>The agriculture ministry did not plan to sharply revise the national forecast for rice, maize, soybeans or sugar cane output to take the flooding into account, Boontham Pholyiam, of the Meteorological Department's forecast division, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Revised crop output forecasts would be released later this month, he said.</p>
<p>According to official July projections, rice output for the first crop of 1996/97 (April-March) season was put at 18.11 million tonnes and maize (July-June) output at 4.36 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The forecast for sugar cane output for 1996/97 (November-October) was put at 62.4 million tonnes, and soybean (April-March) at 411,916 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;For the rice, if there is any downward revision at all, it would be because of drought rather than flood,&quot; said Boontham.</p>
<p>He said some provinces in the northeast, one of Thailand's major rice-growing areas, reported a lack of much-needed rain between July and August.</p>
<p>This could adversely affect the rice crop, he said, adding that damage to the sugar cane crop was minimal so far.</p>
<p>Siriboon Pliphol, head of the forecast division, said more rain-bearing low-pressure cells were expected to hit Thailand from now until next month.</p>
<p>Thailand's northeastern region would be affected most during September and the northern region in October.</p>
<p>&quot;Water is already swelling in some rivers. But the good news is, the sea level during that period will not be as high as that of last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And it seems that after the massive damage last year many government agencies are prepared to deal with the problem,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
