<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31943" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Inter-Continental Hotels accelerates China push.</title>
<headline>Inter-Continental Hotels accelerates China push.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Inter-Continental Hotels and Resorts, one of the world's biggest privately owned luxury-hotel chains, said on Wednesday it has formed a joint venture with the Hong Kong-based Dynasty Group to accelerate expansion in China.</p>
<p>The joint venture would add hotels in Beijing, Chengdu, Qingdao and Xian to Inter-Continental's network, bringing its portfolio in China to six properties.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement moves us one step closer to our goal of having 25 hotels in China by the year 2010,&quot; Marcello Pigozzo, Inter-Continental's President, Asia Pacific, told a news conference in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Dynasty is involved in the development, financing and management of hotels in China, where it currently has four.</p>
<p>He refused to disclose the level of investment the company plans in its push into China, saying only that in the past decade it had invested more than US$100 million in the region.</p>
<p>The hotel group began a rapid expansion programme in the Asia-Pacific region last year, with China and India earmarked as key development targets.</p>
<p>Chairman Yuji Tsutsumi said the Asia Pacific region had not only become a rapidly growing focus for international tourism, but that Asians would soon make up the greater proportion of global travellers.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that by the year 2005 Asians will comprise more than 50 percent of global travellers on airlines alone,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Inter-Continental had planned a stock market flotation next year, but last month announced it was postponing its listing until early 1998.</p>
<p>Tsutsumi said on Wednesday that the company was still reviewing its stock flotation plans after the death of former chief executive Sueaki Takaoka in March.</p>
<p>&quot;Inter-Continental should not be owned by one company and one nationality,&quot; Dynasty Group Chairman Andrew Chan told the news conference. &quot;Going public would be a great advantage.&quot;</p>
<p>Inter-Continental, a U.S.-based chain and part of Japan's Saison Corporation, owns more than 100 luxury hotels under its own name and at least 23 through the Forum Hotels chain. It runs a number of other hotels, some under different names, through joint ventures.</p>
<p>The chain hopes to increase the number of hotels it owns or manages by at least 50 from around 180 by the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6352</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
