<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31941" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil product market discounts Gulf conflict.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil product market discounts Gulf conflict.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil product prices on Wednesday fell, retracing some of the gains made earlier this week as the market discounted U.S./Iraq tensions blowing up to a full conflict.</p>
<p>But refinery sources said since the turmoil in the Gulf started early this week, simple margins have doubled to $1.00 a barrel while complex margins have jumped by 60 cents to $2.80. Naphtha was thinly talked although September paper fell to $20.35/$20.40, down from Tuesday's $21.20 bid. A 92-octane unleaded gasoline cargo was traded at $23.00 a barrel for September 22-26 lifting, up 25 cents from Tuesday's bid.  </p>
<p>Taiwan awarded its gasoline tender which closed on Tuesday, and bought two cargoes of unleaded 95-octane reformate despite higher prices, close to $24.00 a barrel cost-and-freight Taiwan for October 16-30 delivery. &quot;The price was not so good .. we are used to $22,&quot; an official said. &quot;The tender just closed at a wrong time.&quot;</p>
<p>Gas oil fell with October swaps traded down through the day with deals done from at $27.50 to $27.10. Physical traders were cautious and bids were much lower than swap values, at $26.60, about $1.00 below Tuesday's trades. Jet fuel was buoyed by expectations of increased buying from North Asia for the winter.  </p>
<p>Fuel oil prices ended softer with traders saying the market is unmoved by the second round of missile attacks by the U.S. on Wednesday. A bid for 180-centistoke cargo was seen for September 19-23 loading cargo from Singapore at $112.50 per tonne against an offer seen at $116. Levels were lower from Tuesday's $113-$116 per tonne. Traders said the market has jumped too high on Tuesday on news that U.S had launched its first round of missile attacks on Iraq. September paper was bid/asked at $110.50/$111.50 down from Tuesday's $113/$114.5.Fundamentals remained unchanged with demand still seen from India and China while more Mideast supplies are to arrive in late September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
