<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31944" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Glorious Sun sees mass retail expansion.</title>
<headline>HK's Glorious Sun sees mass retail expansion.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Casual wear maker Glorious Sun Enterprises Ltd said it planned to expand its retail outlets in China, Australia and New Zealand to 510 shops by April 1998, from the current 349 shops.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan to expand our network to over 500 by April 1998 and to over 1,000 shops after the year 2000, fulfilling our concept of hundred cities, thousands shops,&quot; said the company's chairman Charles Yeung in a flotation briefing on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Glorious Sun currently has 203 shops in China mainly in province outside Guangdong, 146 shops in Australia and New Zealand, and the number will be increased to 330 shops in China by April 1998 and 180 in the latter areas.</p>
<p>The company forecast its profit attributable to shareholders to jump to HK$168 million for the year ended March 31, 1997, from HK$91 million in 1996.</p>
<p>Yeung said a sharp rise in profit for 1997 was mainly led by expected contribution from its retail operation.</p>
<p>Jackson Pau, deputy genreal manager of the company, said the company's retail business is expected to contribute 51 percent of its total sales for fiscal year ending in 1997, and export at 41 percent. Sales from China is seen contributing to 25 percent of its 1996/97 total sales while Australia and New Zealand are at 26 percent, Pau added.</p>
<p>Glorious Sun said in its flotation prospectus that retail sales from China and Australia shared 47 percent of its turnover for the fiscal year ended March 31, 1996, and export sales is at 43 percent.</p>
<p>The company Jeanswest brandname retail network forms the largest foreign-invested casual wear chain in China and the second largest retailer of jeans and casual wear in Australia.</p>
<p>In export, its major clients include GAP, JC Penney, Phillip Van Heusen, Structure and Haggar.</p>
<p>The company has production facilities in China, the Philippines, Indonesia, Bangladesh, Hong Kong and Cambodia.</p>
<p>Glorious Sun planned to issue 250 million new shares, or 25 percent of its expanded share capital, at HK$1.60 per share to raise a total HK$400 million to expand its retail network in China, Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>Its director Herman Hui said the company  aimed to raise its reputation, arouse awareness and increase the company's transparency through seeking a listing on the Hong Kong exchange.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
