<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31945" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX interest rate futures discount Iraqi news.</title>
<headline>SIMEX interest rate futures discount Iraqi news.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen interest rate futures ended steady on Wednesday after a session of featureless trade enlivened only by news the United States had launched a second missile attack on Iraq.</p>
<p>The news sparked a brief spurt of early activity which fizzled out later in the trading day.</p>
<p>&quot;There was really nothing going on after that,&quot; said one dealer with a European futures house. &quot;The market was staying on the sidelines and waiting for fresh leads,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Eurodollar dealers are awaiting the release of key jobless data this Friday, players said.  </p>
<p>The overnight release of the National Association of Purchasing Management (NAPM) report has shifted market forecasts to a 25-basis-point hike in the Federal Reserve's rate against fears of a 50-basis-point hike triggered by a newspaper report on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market is likely to stay rangebound until the release of the August job report due out on Friday at 1230 GMT. A Reuter survey puts payrolls up by 244,000 against an increase of 193,000 in July.</p>
<p>December Eurodollars ended at 93.92 against their previous IMM close at 93.91. An estimated 10,000 contracts changed hands.  </p>
<p>Euroyen trade saw a rollover from the September contract as December became the benchmark trading month.</p>
<p>Dealers said the contract gained from strength in the Japanese government bond futures market but otherwise there were few factors to stimulate trade. December ended unchanged against its previous 99.27 close in Chicago.</p>
<p>Japanese government bond futures, meanwhile, ended slightly easier with September at 122.38 against its opening at 122.40.</p>
<p>-- Valerie Lee (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
