<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31955" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China's Zhenhai dismisses doomsday talk.</title>
<headline>China's Zhenhai dismisses doomsday talk.</headline>
<byline>Tan Ee Lyn</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Zhenhai Refining &amp; Chemical Co Ltd, whose stock price has been lashed by the U.S. missile attacks on Iraq, said investors had over-reacted and assured it was able to overcome present difficulties.</p>
<p>&quot;I would call the reaction in (the stock market in) Hong Kong merely psychological...there is minimal real impact, and if crude prices are high now we just would not buy,&quot; said a senior manager in Ningbo, eastern Zhejiang province, by telephone.</p>
<p>The Chinese oil refiner's share price in Hong Kong crashed almost 10 percent to HK$2.05 intraday on Tuesday before closing at HK$2.075, down 20 cents on investor fears that the refinery would be hit badly by the sharp hike in crude oil prices.</p>
<p>It regained only partway on Wednesday to close at HK$2.175.</p>
<p>After the first U.S. missile attack on Tuesday, oil prices hit their highest level since Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990, and investors feared Zhenhai - which runs predominantly on imported crudes and sells most of its output into China's domestic markets where product prices are strictly fixed - would be hit.  </p>
<p>But the eight-million tonne per year refiner, which had stopped buying crude oil cargoes since the start of the Iraqi crisis on Monday, said its crude stock-pile would help tide over high prices, at least in the short term.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very hard to say how prices will go, but for now, we have our two months worth of crude stock-pile,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The refiner, China's third largest, imports up to 55 percent of its crude needs from overseas, and covers 25 percent from China's offshore production.</p>
<p>Twenty percent is supplied from China's highly subsidised domestic onshore production, the manager said.</p>
<p>While 30 percent of Zhenhai's output is sold into international markets, the volume would be increased should high crude oil prices persist, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no limit on how much we can export, so we can push it up to cover our higher costs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG NEWSROOM (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
