<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31952" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China's Henan Binxiong wins OK to offer A shares.</title>
<headline>China's Henan Binxiong wins OK to offer A shares.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Henan Binxionng Co Ltd has won approval from the China Securities Regulatory Commission to offer 18 million class A shares in Shanghai, the China Securities Bulletin reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The offer, priced at 5.18 yuan per share, would be launched via the Shanghai bourse's automated quotation system on September 16, the bulletin quoted a company spokesman as saying.</p>
<p>China Southern Securities was the chief underwriter.</p>
<p>Binxiong, which produces refrigerators and refrigerated containers, has also received approval to simultaneously issue two million staff shares, the Bulletin said.</p>
<p>The staff shares would not be floated until six months after the listing of the A shares for domestic investors, tentatively set for September 30.</p>
<p>Binxiong has total share capital of 60 million state shares and would use proceeds to expand its core business and upgrade production facilities.</p>
<p>Based in the city of Shangqiu in central China's Henan province, Binxiong has forecast after-tax profits of 27.00 million yuan for 1996 against 21.65 million yuan posted last year and 15.82 million yuan in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
