<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31959" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: RESEARCH ALERT - Nat Fertilizer rated &quot;buy&quot;.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Nat Fertilizer rated &quot;buy&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seamico Securities Plc on Wednesday rated National Fertilizer Corp a &quot;buy&quot; at 8.50 baht, saying Thailand's sole fertilizer producer has strong long-term fundamentals.</p>
<p>Seamico said National Fertilizer has potential to expand its one-million-tonne capacity plant at a relatively low cost after its delayed production start-up until October 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock should offer attractive returns in the longer term and it certainly deserves to be better rated,&quot; Seamico said.</p>
<p>Seamico said National Fertilizer became one of the worst performing new Thai stocks this year when it debuted on August 26. It closed its first trading day at 9.90 baht ($0.40) against a 16.00 baht initial public offering.</p>
<p>National Fertilizer finished on Wednesday at 7.90 baht.</p>
<p>Seamico said National Fertilizer will need to invest about three billion baht to expand its annual output capacity to two million tonnes from one million.</p>
<p>Its start-up plant, costing over six billion baht, will run at 80 percent of capacity in 1998, rising to 90 percent in 1999 and 100 percent in the year 2000.</p>
<p>National Fertilizer is expected to post a net operating loss in 1997, the first year of its domestic production, against a projected 50 million baht profit this year from sales of imported fertilizer.</p>
<p>($1.00=25 baht)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-2529950-3</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
