<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31957" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai govt instability brings quick military deal.</title>
<headline>Thai govt instability brings quick military deal.</headline>
<byline>Sutin Wannabovorn</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The upcoming no-confidence debate against Thai Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa has forced the government to make a quick deal on the sensitive annual military reshuffle, military sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The annual promotion of armed forces personnel is a delicate matter in Thailand, which has had 17 coups or attempted coups since it changed from absolute monarchy to the parliamentary system in 1932.</p>
<p>But this year's promotion list has been settled quickly, sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The promotion list is completed and General Chetta (Tanajaro) is nominated to be the new army chief, and I am definitely sure there will be no further change in the area of armed forces chief,&quot; one army source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Last year, wrangling between Defence Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh and top military leaders over the promotions caused several weeks' delay in the announcement.</p>
<p>But due to the political uncertainty, no delay is expected this year, officials said.</p>
<p>Chavalit favors Chetta as the new army commander, the most powerful military post in Thailand. The 58-year-old moderate has said he wants to distance the army from politics.</p>
<p>One army general said the list was expected to be released next week because no one wants to risk major upsets or delays before the no-confidence debate due later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect there will be major changes after the no-confidence debate, so the armed forces need to know for sure before that who will be their new bosses,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Opposition parties have tabled a no-confidence motion against Banharn, and debate on it will begin on September 18. Some political analysts doubt the coalition will survive the vote even though it has 203 of the 391 seats in the lower house.</p>
<p>The uncertainty has forced Banharn and General Viroj Saengsanit, the outgoing supreme commander who is known to be close to Banharn, to ease their objections to the military promotion list to please Chavalit before the vote, sources said.</p>
<p>Viroj earlier had threatened to change the nominees of the chiefs of the military branches if he did not approve of them.</p>
<p>Chavalit also heads the New Aspiraton Party, the second largest member of Banharn's six-party coalition. He was said to disagree with Banharn over who will be the new army commander.</p>
<p>The current army boss, General Pramon Phalasin, is close to Chavalit and is due to retire at the end of September. Pramon got the job last year after Chavalit lobbied for him rather than another general who had been nominated by the military.</p>
<p>Banharn favoured General Mongkol Amphornpisit, head of the joint chiefs of staff, for the top army job. But he likely will be given the more ceremonial post of supreme commander since Banharn does not want to upset Chavalit, military sources said.</p>
<p>Air Chief Marshal Amorn Naewmalee was expected to be named air force chief, and Admiral Vijit Chamnankarn the navy commander, they said.</p>
<p>Banharn has said he has received the list, which will be reviewed and forwarded to the king for endorsement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
