<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31953" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia urges improved ASEAN customs procedures.</title>
<headline>Indonesia urges improved ASEAN customs procedures.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Finance Minister Mar'ie Muhammad on Wednesday urged customs officials in Southeast Asian countries to improve their administrations and smooth the flow of trade.</p>
<p>Directors-general of customs of the seven-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) opened a two-day meeting in the Indonesian capital to review the progress in improving the handling of cross-border trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Ensuring that customs administration supports legitimate economic activities and ensures a smooth flow of goods across our national boundaries is crucial to our efforts to create a stronger ASEAN,&quot; Mar'ie said in an address delivered on his behalf.</p>
<p>He said customs continued to have a crucial role in effectively and fairly applying existing tariffs and enforcing rules against smuggling and illegal trade.</p>
<p>They also had to improve their work &quot;to ensure that customs administration is not seen as a bottleneck to investment and production&quot;.</p>
<p>ASEAN Secretary-General Ajit Singh said progress had already been made in such areas as harmonising tariff nomenclature, valuation and procedures.</p>
<p>Other enhancements under way include a common customs form, the green lane system to speed up the clearance of goods, and the drafting of an ASEAN agreement on customs.</p>
<p>Singh noted that ASEAN was the world's fourth-biggest trading entity, with imports and exports of more than $500 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;Efficient customs administrations with simplified, transparent and predictable customs procedures will certainly reduce costs and enable the private sector to function more smoothly and effectively,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ASEAN comprises Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, Thailand, Vietnam, Brunei and the Philippines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
