<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31968" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore refiners see profits on Gulf turmoil.</title>
<headline>Singapore refiners see profits on Gulf turmoil.</headline>
<byline>Marguerita Choy</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore refiners, having cut production in June to stem losses, are considering going back to maximum output now that U.S.-Iraq tensions have helped them make money, refinery sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Most products, especially clean fuels such as naphtha, gasoline, diesel and jet fuel or kerosene, have hit record prices since Monday, after Iraqi President Saddam Hussein sent troops into Kurdish areas of the country's north.</p>
<p>On Tuesday and Wednesday, U.S. cruise missiles were launched against Iraqi air defences in retaliation. Oil prices jumped.</p>
<p>&quot;Although margins have improved recently, the problems in the Gulf have given margins a good push,&quot; said a refining manager.</p>
<p>He said margins, the difference between feedstock and production costs, had risen mainly because product prices had gone up faster than crude prices.</p>
<p>&quot;It will depend on the refinery's configuration,&quot; he said. &quot;Those with more upgrading units will have better margins.&quot;</p>
<p>Upgrading units convert heavier products, like fuel oil, into higher priced products such as diesel and jet fuel.</p>
<p>Naphtha, used as a feedstock in petrochemical and gasoline production, hit a post-Gulf war high of $21.50 a barrel on Tuesday, while jet fuel prices soared to $30 a barrel, the highest since the peak of winter buying in January.</p>
<p>In comparison, crude reached only a four-month high with benchmark Brent crude's October closing at $22.21 a barrel on Tuesday on London's IPE.</p>
<p>Singapore refiners were already starting to see some profit returning at the end of August, with the onset of winter demand for jet fuel, or kerosene, widely used for heating in north Asia.</p>
<p>Stronger markets in the West have also supported Asian product prices by keeping arbitrage cargoes out of the region and enabling Singapore refiners to find outlets for their own surplus supplies.</p>
<p>But only the country's largest refiner, Shell Singapore, moved on Monday to return its production back to maximum capacity of 435,000 barrels-per-day (bpd).</p>
<p>Shell had cut runs at its 200,000 bpd crude unit by 80 percent in early August.</p>
<p>In June, Mobil cut output at a 280,000 bpd refinery by 10,000 bpd. At around the same time, Esso Singapore Private Limited, an affiliate of U.S. Exxon Corp, cut output by 15 percent at its 230,000 bpd plant.</p>
<p>Mobil and Esso sources said their companies were hopeful, but still hesitant, of returning to full production.</p>
<p>Profits from upgrading units have jumped more than 60 cents since the beginning of the week -- up to $2.80 a barrel, refinery sources said.</p>
<p>Profits from basic refining of crude have doubled to around $1.00 a barrel, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would think these sorts of margins should encourage going back to full capacity. But it is too early to tell...it has only been one day and it could just be a blip. The crude programme is planned months ahead and you cannot react that fast,&quot; said one refinery source.</p>
<p>&quot;We need things to stabilise, and won't act on a knee-jerk reaction,&quot; said another.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
