<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31977" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Wharf interim profits as expected, better H2 seen.</title>
<headline>Wharf interim profits as expected, better H2 seen.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wharf Holdings Ltd's interim earnings announced on Wednesday came in within the range of expectations and analysts expected to see an improvement in second-half figures compared to the first half.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong conglomerate reported first-half profit of HK$1.30 billion (US$168 million), down from HK$3.00 billion in the first half of last year when the figures were boosted by a HK$1.95 billion  exceptional gain.</p>
<p>Operating profit in the first half 1996 rose 37 percent to HK$1.33 billion from HK$970.2 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they (the results) are really close,&quot; said Philip Tulk, analyst at DBS Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said first-half growth in rental income and property sales had been disappointing but they expected an improvement in the second half.</p>
<p>&quot;Investment rental income was up about seven percent. I had expected more growth,&quot; said one analyst at a Japanese brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;Gains on the sale of property were lower than what I was going for,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The analyst said he had expected interim profit of HK$1.4 billion but said &quot;most people are probably comfortable with the general results&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the second half will definitely be better. They sold some property but it will not be booked until the second half,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Wharf said property sales activities had been revived &quot;but only a small portion of the profits arising was booked in the first half of 1996&quot;. It said four floors of Telford House had been sold recently and more sales were envisaged.</p>
<p>Franklin Lam, director of research at HG Asia, said the results also fell short of his forecast of HK$1.46 billion profit due to bigger-than-anticipated losses at cable television arm Wharf Cable and losses linked to the New T&amp;T telephone unit.</p>
<p>But he said he was maintaining Wharf as a &quot;top tier buy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I think all the core rentals, MTL (container terminal operator Modern Terminals Ltd) and all other operations including property sales and so on are all in line,&quot; he said. &quot;The company is improving. We have touched a bottom.&quot;</p>
<p>Lam said Wharf posted a loss of HK$300 million for cable television in the first half which was higher than his estimate.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year they made HK$600 million in losses on cable TV. We were expecting HK$450 million for the full year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wharf said its financial performance was also hurt in the first half by &quot;budgeted start-up deficits at New T&amp;T.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We were expecting them to continue to capitalise on losses but they declared a loss and allowed it to flow through to the bottom line,&quot; said Lam.</p>
<p>&quot;The second half will be an improvement on the first half in all aspects,&quot; he said. &quot;I think the bulk of the reversions on the rentals will come through in the second half.&quot;</p>
<p>Tulk, who had forecast profit of HK$1.2 billion, said Wharf had booked a larger gain than he had anticipated from the sale of its Omni Hotels interest and certain investment properties.</p>
<p>Wharf reported an exceptional gain of HK$102.7 million in the period.</p>
<p>He said cable losses were also lower than his HK$350 million forecast. &quot;Reduction of losses at cable help forward growth,&quot; said Tulk, adding that he may lift his full year estimate to HK$3.0 billion from HK$2.9 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good set of figures. The bar was set quite low and they jumped over it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>(US$1=HK$7.73)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
