<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31979" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares ignore Iraq news, end sharply up.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares ignore Iraq news, end sharply up.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed sharply up on Wednesday on foreign buying of selected big-capitalised stocks and active local buying of small stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index rose 5.46 points, or 1.01 percent to 546.00 points. Gainers led losers by 70 to 26, with 43 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market appeared to shrug off news of the second U.S missile attack on Iraq with more foreign buyers entering the market in late trade.  </p>
<p>&quot;It seems the U.S and Iraq news had only a mild impact on the region and improved market sentiment in regional markets gave a little confidence to foreigners here,&quot; said Budianto Wijaya of PT DBS Securities Indonesia.</p>
<p>But another broker said overall sentiment is volatile as global markets remain directionless.</p>
<p>&quot;Many operators are waiting for upcoming U.S economic data for clues whether the U.S Federal Reserve would hike interest rates or leave it unchanged,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Telecommunications heavyweight Telkom, cement producer Semen Gresik and cigarette maker Gudang Garam were among the stocks targeted by foreigners.</p>
<p>Semen Gresik rose 175 rupiah to 6,325 on a volume of 759,000 shares. Brokers said the rise was due to reports saying cement prices had risen in some parts of Indonesia following tight supply.</p>
<p>Medium-sized stocks, including Bakrie Brothers and Citatah, were also actively traded. Brokers said some investors were shifting their portfolios and both stocks were favoured.  </p>
<p>Plantation and telecommunications company Bakrie Brothers rose 19.35 percent, or 450 rupiah, to 2,775 on a turnover of 7.7 million shares. Brokers said the rise was due to strong first-half results.</p>
<p>Lippo Securities and Lippo Life, both owned by the Lippo Group conglomerate, were also actively traded on plans by both for rights issues, brokers said.</p>
<p>Lippo Securities topped the active list with 9.3 million shares, rising 100 rupiah to 1,425 rupiah.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
