<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31976" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan first-half platinum sales up - jewellery body.</title>
<headline>Japan first-half platinum sales up - jewellery body.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's retail sales of platinum jewellery in the first half of calendar 1996 rose eight percent from a year earlier in terms of the number of items sold, the Platinum Guild International (PGI) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Back by the recent popularity of white jewellery among younger people, platinum jewellery enjoyed good sales,&quot; an official of the industry body told reporters at the Japan Jewellery Fair now being held in Yokohama, neighbouring Tokyo.</p>
<p>The value of platinum jewellery sales in the first half of this year was up three percent from the same period last year, it said. The actual value of the sales was not disclosed.</p>
<p>Japan is the world's largest platinum consumer.</p>
<p>In platinum jewellery, the number of pairs of pierced earrings sold grew by 62 percent and that of bracelets by 27 percent from the same period a year earlier.</p>
<p>Precious metal industry sources said, however, that despite an increase in sales volume, total platinum demand from the jewellery sector is likely to be flat this year.</p>
<p>Jewellery accounted for about 65 percent of Japan's overall platinum demand. Imports in the first seven months of 1996 amounted to 41.97 tonnes, against 42.41 tonnes in the same period last year, Finance Ministry data showed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
