<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31980" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan chip makers cut investment, face profit drop.</title>
<headline>Japan chip makers cut investment, face profit drop.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese semiconductor makers, worried by a sharp downturn in memory chip prices, said on Wednesday that they would cut back investments in microchips in the second half of this business year.</p>
<p>The companies, which only last year had reaped record profits thanks to their high-flying microchip business, said the impact of the crash in chip prices would be limited due to surging profits in their information equipment divisions and smaller deficits in consumer electronics.</p>
<p>But analysts say a plunge in parent company profits is inevitable this year due to the companies' heavy reliance on 16-megabit dynamic random access memories (DRAMs), prices of which have nosedived more than 70 percent in the past nine months.</p>
<p>Toshiba Corp said it planned to cut group capital investment for microchips by 10 billion yen ($92.5 million) to 170 billion yen ($1.57 billion) for the year ending March 1997.</p>
<p>Toshiba expects its microchip production for the year to be 10 percent below its original forecast, a company spokesman said. Its forecast for chip sales for the year is now 950 billion yen ($8.79 billion).</p>
<p>NEC Corp, Mitsubishi Electric Corp, Hitachi Ltd and Fujitsu Ltd all said they were reviewing their investment programmes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite natural for some investments to be carried over into the next year, depending on the market situation,&quot; a Hitachi spokesman said.</p>
<p>Prices of 16-megabit DRAMs -- currently the mainstay computer memory chip -- for volume users are being quoted at around 1,200 yen ($11) each, down from around 5,000 yen ($46) at the beginning of this year. Spot prices have been below 1,000 yen ($9) and are still heading downward.</p>
<p>Amid a big supply glut following a worldwide slowdown in personal computer sales, some makers have begun selling 16-megabit DRAMs at between $8.50 and $9, raising concerns about possible dumping suits, an industry source said.</p>
<p>Akira Minamikawa, an analyst at research firm IDC Corp, estimates production costs for a 16-megabit DRAM for small makers at around $12, and for some big South Korean and Japanese makers $8. &quot;The break-even point is approaching for some makers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Minamikawa said stability in the 16-megabit DRAM market would not come until the October-December quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Nomura Research Institute expects all microchip makers to make sharp downward revisions in their earnings forecast for the current business year.</p>
<p>It estimates Toshiba's 1996/97 parent current profit at 50 billion yen ($462 million) against the company's own forecast, unveiled on Wednesday, of 121.5 billion yen ($1.12 billion).</p>
<p>NEC's profit is estimated at 85 billion yen ($787 million), Hitachi's at 85 billion yen ($787 million) and Fujitsu's at 65 billion yen ($601 million).</p>
<p>Daiwa Institute of Research expects Toshiba to post parent current profit of 105 billion yen ($972 million) and NEC 90 billion yen ($833 million).</p>
<p>&quot;All the firms will be hit hard by lower chip prices. But results will differ depending on how well their other divisions fare,&quot; said Daiwa analyst Mami Indo. ($1=109 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
