<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31987" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end down on Moody's downgrade, Iraq.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end down on Moody's downgrade, Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks dropped in thin trade and ended 1.38 percent down on Wednesday on investors' worries over a recent Moody's downgrade of Thailand's short-term rating and tensions in the Gulf, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index ended 14.71 points down at 1,049.74 on 3.2 billion baht trade. Decliners led gainers 262 to 77 while 102 issues were unchanged. The SET-50 index lost 1.21 points to finish at 79.72.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors sold key stocks as they became more worried over Moody's downgrading of Thailand's short-term rating,&quot; said Thanawat Patchimkul of Seamico Securities.  </p>
<p>Moody's said on Tuesday it had downgraded Thailand's short-term sovereign ceiling ratings for bank deposits and other short-term obligations to Prime 2 from Prime 1.</p>
<p>Brokers said the report had a negative psychological impact on the market, which has dropped for five days in a row.</p>
<p>Reacting to the downgrade, the Bank of Thailand on Wednesday said new measures were being considered to control rising short-term foreign debt to solve the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;News on the U.S. attacking Iraq also affected the market but to a lesser degree,&quot; said Thanawat.  </p>
<p>&quot;The U.S.-Iraq conflict will affect the market in the short-term while the report by Moody's on Thailand's short-term rating is likely to affect the market in long-term,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Bangkok Bank topped the active list, closing unchanged at 212 baht. Finance One slipped three to 101 while Shinawatra Computer and Communications dropped six to 376 and Electricity Generating declined 1.50 to finish at 72.</p>
<p>-- Suthep Chawla (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
