<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31984" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan aluminium alloy makers welcome MITI tax move.</title>
<headline>Japan aluminium alloy makers welcome MITI tax move.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's aluminium alloy producers welcomed on Wednesday the Ministry of International Trade and Industry's (MITI) decision not to extend tax breaks to alloy imports.</p>
<p>&quot;We're a bit relieved,&quot; said Shoji Fujimoto, managing director of the Japan Aluminium Alloy Refiners' Association.</p>
<p>A MITI official said on Wednesday that the ministry had decided to exclude alloy from an import promotion scheme that gives tax breaks to companies that boost purchases of imported goods.  </p>
<p>Alloy imports became eligible for the tax break after tariffs on them were abolished in April 1995. The ministry had been scheduled to decide by the end of August whether or not to apply the tax break to alloy from next April.</p>
<p>Under the import promotion scheme, in effect since 1990, a company that increases its purchases of an eligible import in a given year can claim a tax deduction on the amount of the increase, up to a maximum of 10 percent, or 15 percent for small businesses.  </p>
<p>MITI determined, however, that aluminium alloy falls into the category of internationally traded commodities, which are not eligible for the tax break.</p>
<p>Fujimoto said Japan's alloy producers had been hit hard in recent years as automakers, which consume over 70 percent of domestic alloy output, shifted manufacturing overseas.</p>
<p>Federation data shows that Japanese aluminium alloy production fell more than 10 percent to 922,398 tonnes in 1995 from a peak of 1,030,323 tonnes in 1990.</p>
<p>Imports have risen recently, however, increasing 15.5 percent last year to 756,359 tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Commodities Desk (81-3 3432 6179)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
