<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31982" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Hundreds detained in Saigon &quot;social evils&quot; sweep.</title>
<headline>Hundreds detained in Saigon &quot;social evils&quot; sweep.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of prostitutes, drug addicts, beggars and petty criminals were detained in an overnight blitz on &quot;social evils&quot; in Ho Chi Minh City last week, an official in the southern Vietnamese city said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Every year we have such a campaign to resolve social problems,&quot; the official at the government's anti-social evils department told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Over 1,900 were rounded up this time. This is the biggest campaign in more than 20 years, with the largest number,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The official, who declined to be identified, said those detained in the August 28 sweep in old Saigon included homeless children and old people and migrants from other parts of the country, many of whom were beggars and pickpockets.</p>
<p>He said homes would be found for the homeless, drug addicts would be sent to rehabilitation centres and prostitutes would go to education centres.</p>
<p>Vietnam's communist leadership launched a nationwide clampdown on prostitution, pornography, drug abuse and gambling earlier this year as part of a drive to safeguard national culture and values.</p>
<p>For weeks, police swept through towns and cities, raiding massage parlours and karaoke bars. Local officials destroyed blue movie videos and erotic posters in ritual public ceremonies.</p>
<p>In an unexpected twist to the campaign against what many believe are &quot;poisonous&quot; cultural influences and products from abroad, advertisements and signs in foreign language were pulled down or covered over.</p>
<p>At the time, Western analysts saw the blitz as an attempt by the Communist Party to assert its influence ahead of a key party congress in June.</p>
<p>But there has been no let-up in the campaign since then.</p>
<p>Many in Hanoi remain suspicious of the increasingly freewheeling society of Ho Chi Minh City, the country's economic hub.</p>
<p>The official Saigon Giai Phong daily said that in the first six months of this year the city's anti-social evils department had closed 109 brothels, arrested 700 people involved in the sex trade and arrested 168 people for drug-related offences.</p>
<p>&quot;Social evils have decreased by 50-70 percent since the government issued the anti-social vices decision,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
