<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31997" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HSBC HK bond index rose 0.98 pct to 116.65 in Aug.</title>
<headline>HSBC HK bond index rose 0.98 pct to 116.65 in Aug.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>HSBC Markets said its Hong Kong bond index rose to 116.65 in August, a 0.98 percent increase over July. The sub-index for Hong Kong government paper increased by 0.83 percent, while the sub-index for non-Hong Kong government paper rose by 1.07 percent.</p>
<p>Compared with levels at end-August 1995, the overall index increased by 8.1 percent, the sub-index for Hong Kong government paper rose by 6.1 percent and the sub-index for non-Hong Kong government paper increased by 9.3 percent.</p>
<p>Expectations that softer U.S. economic data would discourage the Federal Reserve from raising rates at its August 20 meeting supported Hong Kong debt issues early in the month, HSBC said.</p>
<p>But yields edged higher toward the end of August on renewed concern over a Fed tightening.</p>
<p>HSBC said Hong Kong dollar debt yields widened versus U.S. paper during early August, but the gap narrowed as investors took advantage of the spread to buy Hong Kong dollar bonds.</p>
<p>There also was significant interest in the swap market, contributing to the narrowing of spreads between Hong Kong and U.S. interest rates, HSBC Markets said. It said that narrowing was particularly prominent in the short-end of the market because of increased liquidity. -- HK Newsroom (852) 2843-6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
