<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="31994" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Gold crackdown slashes South Korea's bullion trade.</title>
<headline>Gold crackdown slashes South Korea's bullion trade.</headline>
<byline>Jae Hur</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's crackdown on speculative gold traders has cut by half the country's exports of the metal and put many bullion houses out of business, traders and officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gold imports in July plunged 49.6 percent to $335 million from $665 million a month ago and $255 million a year earlier, trade ministry figures showed.</p>
<p>Exports tumbled 50.9 percent to $318 million in July from $648 million in June and $234 in July last year.</p>
<p>The crackdown on the booming gold transshipment business began on July 1.</p>
<p>Bullion houses were importing huge amounts of gold on 90-day deferred payment, immediately exporting the metal and parking the proceeds in high interest-bearing domestic money market instruments.</p>
<p>They reaped huge profits from arbitrage between local interest rates of more than 11 percent and London Interbank Offered Rate of around five percent.  </p>
<p>On July 1, the government shortened the deferred payment period to a maximum 30 days. That, plus a depreciation of the Korean won against the dollar, made gold trading unprofitable for all but the biggest houses dealing in huge quantities.</p>
<p>&quot;For 30 days deferred payment, nobody wants to do business,&quot; said a trader with Ssangyong Corp, who declined to be named. He said the company had stopped taking new contracts.</p>
<p>The Ssangyong trader said gold trade figures would show further monthly declines after contracts in the pipeline before the crackdown had been fulfilled.</p>
<p>Hyundai Corp is no longer in the bullion business, a Hyundai trader said. It had wound up all its operations before July 1.</p>
<p>Kay Lee, Seoul-based manager of the World Gold Council, said the remaining active bullion trading houses were Daewoo Corp, Samsung Corp and LG International Corp.</p>
<p>Oh Tae-Hwan, general manager of the precious metals division of Daewoo, said that in the first half of this year Daewoo had exported 16 tonnes of bullion each month to Hong Kong and Singapore. It was now exporting half that.  </p>
<p>&quot;The current local market is not profitable because of the government measures and the depreciation of the won,&quot; Oh said. &quot;But we keep going because we are not making losses.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We deal in huge amounts of gold so we can get good terms and conditions compared with other houses that deal only small amounts,&quot; he said. &quot;We have a good reputation and record of performance with our clients.&quot;</p>
<p>Oh said that in the first four months of this year Daewoo accounted for about 50 percent of South Korean exports, but its share had now dropped to about 33 percent.</p>
<p>In 1995, Daewoo supplied 38 percent of Singapore's total imports, Oh said.</p>
<p>Oh said South Korean gold export premiums to Hong Kong were now being quoted at 50 cents over LOCO London market price, and at 60 to 65 cents over the London spot price for Singapore.</p>
<p>Lee said he expected bullion imports would pick up in the fourth quarter because of seasonal demand before Christmas and the Korean Thanksgiving holiday at the end of September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
