<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32001" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Profits at China-listed firms seen picking up.</title>
<headline>Profits at China-listed firms seen picking up.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's listed firms have put in a lacklustre interim earnings performance, but their fortunes should pick up in the second half in line with the expected improvement in the national economy, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>All 433 firms listed in Shanghai and Shenzhen published their half-year results by the end of August in keeping with exchange rules.</p>
<p>Exchange statistics showed average earnings by Shanghai firms of 0.1427 yuan ($0.0172) per share in the first half of 1996 and of 0.1458 yuan in Shenzhen, about the same as in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>In Shanghai, 11 companies reported net losses in the first half, against six which posted losses for the full 1995 year, and 15 firms recorded losses in Shenzhen, up from 11 for the full 1995 year.</p>
<p>&quot;The overall performance of listed firms was about the same level this year as last year,&quot; said one stock analyst with Shenyin &amp; Wanguo Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;But some listed firms which were formerly state-run enterprises continued to report bad results, mainly due to poor management which made them unable to cope with Beijing's austerity measures in the past three years,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>But analysts believe that with China's inflation falling sharply and the People's Bank of China having cut bank interest rates twice this year, listed companies will fare better in the second half of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect them (listed firms) to perform much better in the rest of this year, with the national economy improving,&quot; said Zhang Jun, a stock analyst with China Guotai Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate cuts will help the recovery of companies closely related to the macro-economy such as those in real estate and construction materials,&quot; said Zhou Hua, a Shenzhen-based analyst with China's Southern Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite worse-than-expected results in the past two years, listed firms are still an elite among Chinese companies and will feel the effects of a national economic recovery first,&quot; said an economist with China Finance Trust and Investment Co.</p>
<p>China's inflation was a year-on-year 7.1 percent in the first half of 1996, compared with a year-on-year rate of 14.8 percent in the full 1995 year, with GDP growing at 9.8 percent in the first half.</p>
<p>The People's Bank of China cut interest rates for bank deposits and loans respectively by an average 1.5 and 1.2 percentage points on August 23 after an earlier cut on May 1.</p>
<p>But most loss-making companies are cautious about their near-term prospects.</p>
<p>Shanghai-listed Sichuan International Cooperation Co, a contractor for overseas construction projects that saw a 0.77 yuan per share net loss in the first half, was the biggest loser among China's listed firms.</p>
<p>A company official would only say they would do their utmost to cut losses in the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Huadian Co Ltd of Zhuhai, a power generation company listed in Shenzhen, posted interim net losses for the second straight year.</p>
<p>Company officials said power generated by the company was mainly used in Guangdong, but the supply was sufficient in the province and the company lacked additional power quota. Its performance for the rest of 1996 would depend on what quotas the firm can get. ($1=8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
