<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32004" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill repo rates end up, spots down.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill repo rates end up, spots down.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>-- Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai ended mostly up on Wednesday, with turnover falling to 11.61 million lots from 12.49 million.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the three-day contract rose to 24.50 percent from 21.75 percent on Tuesday and the most active seven-day contract to 14.00 percent from 13.50 percent.</p>
<p>One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.</p>
<p>Traders said rises of the early-maturing contracts in the past few trading days were mainly due to continued issues of domestic A shares in Shanghai this week. &quot;The stock market is active, attracting liquidity from the repo market,&quot; one said.  </p>
<p>Traders believe there will be a technical correction after sharp gains in the past few days.</p>
<p>Contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai ended mostly down on Wednesday, with liquidity flowing to the more active stock market, traders said. The most active 10-year bond that matures in June 2006 closed down at 121.87 yuan from 122.20.</p>
<p>Combined volume of the eight-contract market fell to 2.58 million lots from 3.38 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The T-bill spot market is unlikely to rally in the short term with the stock market absorbing a large amount of money,&quot; one trader said. -- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
