<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32003" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks rebound in cautious trade.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks rebound in cautious trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks rebounded on Wednesday, regaining most of Tuesday's losses on the U.S. missile attack on Iraq, as investors believed the conflict would not escalate and impact on corporate earnings, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index advanced 119.77 points, or 1.09 percent, to close at 11,076.95, gaining back about three-quarters of Tuesday's tumble. Turnover fell to HK$3.87 billion, compared with HK$4.16 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday's fall was entirely futures led,&quot; said James Osborn, sales director at ING Barings.</p>
<p>The big cap stocks were hit the hardest yesterday, suggesting that the fall was led by futures traders, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But long-term investors believe this (conflict) is a short, sharp incident that won't impact on earnings and they are buying at these levels,&quot; Osborn said.</p>
<p>While the finance sub-index led the blue chips with a gain of 1.36 percent, H shares made the biggest advance, with the Hang Seng China Enterprise Index rising 1.95 percent.</p>
<p>Brokers were upbeat about the outlook for the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The market should do better tomorrow,&quot; said Janet Dulunaqio, sales executive with OCBC Securities Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;There are better sounds coming out of the north, and it looks like Hong Kong and Beijing may stop quarreling for awhile,&quot; Dulunaqio said.</p>
<p>&quot;Economic fundamentals in southeast Asian markets look weak and there could be a regional reweighting more in favour of Hong Kong coming up, she added.</p>
<p>The H share rebound is finished, according to Osborn.</p>
<p>&quot;The P/E (price to earnings) valuations are too high. P stands for promise and E for eventually,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short-term they are too expensive,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Commercial and Industrial sub-index put on 1.19 percent on the back of buying in Wharf in advance of its earnings report, released Wednesday afternoon.</p>
<p>Wharf reported net profit of HK$1.30 billion for first half 1996, advanced HK$0.75 to HK$28.95 on heavy turnover of HK$95.8 million.</p>
<p>Property stocks lost some of their morning gains in the afternoon and the sector index finished up only 0.91 percent. Cheung Kong ended up HK$0.50 at HK$54.50.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
