<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32017" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>Israel: Netanyahu, Arafat begin summit with handshakes.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu, Arafat begin summit with handshakes.</headline>
<byline>Robert Mahoney</byline>
<dateline>EREZ, Gaza Strip 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat held their first summit on Wednesday, opening the way for the resumption of full-fledged Israel-PLO peace talks.</p>
<p>Netanyahu and Arafat started the meeting at the Israel-Gaza border with a handshake so brief that photographers had to ask them to repeat it, witnesses said.</p>
<p>On the second try, the right-wing Israeli leader, who had said he hoped never to meet the former guerrilla chief, rose from across the negotiating table and extended a hand to Arafat at an Israeli-Palestinian liaison complex.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a meeting for photos. It is not a meeting for (the sake of) a meeting. It is to produce -- to advance the peace process, to advance the negotiation...to do something for peace,&quot; Arafat aide Nabil Abu Rdainah said earlier.</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators, with the help of a Norwegian middleman who helped broker the original Oslo self-rule accord in 1993, had struggled over the past week to find a formula for a summit and full-scale peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The foundations were agreed here for conducting the negotiations on a framework of issues between us and the Palestinians,&quot; Israeli Cabinet Secretary Danny Naveh, told Israel's Channel Two television, referring to the results of the pre-summit contacts.</p>
<p>Palestinians had been pressing for the summit and resumed talks to tackle the issue of Israel's long-delayed troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>The sides had been tussling over the wording of a document that would commit Israel's current government to the groundbreaking interim peace deal which late Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin sealed with Arafat when they shook hands on the White House lawn in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;In this meeting we hope we can put the mechanism by which we will be able to proceed with all our negotiations in order for us to carry out the implementation of the interim agreement,&quot; Palestinian negotiator Saeb Erekat said.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope we can put the peace process back on track. Putting the peace process back on track means only the implementation of the interim agreement on the ground,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we need deeds and not words.&quot;</p>
<p>The meeting followed four days of round-the-clock talks to fix a summit seen as vital to reviving peace talks suspended since Islamic suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in February and March.</p>
<p>Palestine Liberation Organisation officials said Netanyahu had resisted making a commitment to implementing the 1993 self-rule deal.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has said the agreement on Hebron, where Israeli troops are to remain in parts of the city to ensure the safety of 400 Jewish settlers living in enclaves among more than 100,000 Arabs, must be re-examined due to security concerns.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's communications director David Bar-Illan said on Tuesday: &quot;The thrust of the meeting between the prime minister and Arafat is to confirm that an agreement has been reached on the agenda of the negotiations and to seal it with a handshake.&quot;</p>
<p>In the May election, Netanyahu ousted Israeli Prime Minister Shimon Peres who in November succeeded Rabin, assassinated by a Jew opposed to peace moves with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, elected in May on a vow to take a hard line in peace talks with the Palestinians, had said originally he preferred not to meet Arafat but softened his position in recent days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EREZ, Gaza Strip"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
