<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32018" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraqi Kurds try to resume normal life in Arbil.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurds try to resume normal life in Arbil.</headline>
<byline>Daren Butler</byline>
<dateline>ARBIL, Iraq 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Local residents struggled on Wednesday to resume daily life under new leaders in the city of Arbil, but there were reports of fresh Iraqi shelling further south.</p>
<p>Shop shutters remained down and people gathered at carts carrying barrels with the last water supplies, four days after Baghdad's forces and guerrillas of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) captured the city from a rival Kurdish faction.</p>
<p>Fadil Mirani, the KDP boss for Arbil, said between 150 and 180 people had been killed in the fighting but said civilians had been largely unharmed.</p>
<p>&quot;It is becoming increasingly unpleasant trying to cope. Electricity and water are life,&quot; said a local taxi driver. Arbil has neither.</p>
<p>KDP officials accused the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) of cutting off water from a dam outside Arbil, which it had held from December 1994 until Saturday's attack by Baghdad and the KDP.</p>
<p>The United States retaliated with missile attacks on Iraq but the PUK said Iraqi President Saddam Hussein's forces, apparently unbowed, resumed shelling in the Kurdish-controlled region early on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;From this morning at nine o'clock (0500 GMT)...the Iraqi government began to shell Chamchamal and Sulaimaniya,&quot; Shazad Saib, the PUK's Turkey representative, told Reuters. Saib said he did not know if the shelling continued.</p>
<p>Sulaimaniya, a PUK stronghold, is 120 km (80 miles) south of Arbil. Chamchamal is some 70 km (40 miles) north of Sulaimaniya.</p>
<p>In Arbil, the new rulers -- KDP peshmerga guerrillas -- patrolled streets in open-topped trucks mounted with machine guns.</p>
<p>People worried about the return of Iraqi troops, who have left Arbil. They said Iraqi forces had taken PUK members and other opposition figures and one driver said the Iraqi secret police were still in the city.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw Iraqi soldiers take people with my own eyes,&quot; a taxi driver said. &quot;People are miserable because the KDP came here with the Iraqi regime.&quot;</p>
<p>At Arbil's main hospital, people were being treated for injuries from the fighting. Hospital officials said two people had died because electricity had been cut off from the town.</p>
<p>&quot;I was walking down the street when Iraqi soldiers opened fire from a tank,&quot; said Abdul Hassan, 30, his bearded face pale and drawn. A medic treated wounds to his arm and shoulder.</p>
<p>But scars of the fighting in the northern Iraq city were scarce, A Western observer, entering for the first time since Saturday, said: &quot;This is not a city that has been fought over.&quot;</p>
<p>Damage was concentrated around the parliament building and the house of PUK leader Jalal Talabani.</p>
<p>The facade of the parliament building, on the southwestern edge of the town, was holed by tank shells. A bullet-riddled bus stood by the driveway. The building was empty, guarded by a handful of KDP guerrillas.</p>
<p>The scarred building symbolised the failure of the Kurdish attempt at democracy and self-rule. The Kurdish parliament met there in May 1992 after Iraqi Kurdistan's first democratic elections.</p>
<p>At the time Talabani and KDP chief Massoud Barzani agreed to share power, evenly dividing seats in parliament. But fighting ensued and the PUK captured Arbil.</p>
<p>Mirani, the KDP boss, told reporters his forces had allied with the Iraqi army to combat aggression by Iran and &quot;treachery&quot; by Talabani.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARBIL, Iraq"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
