<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32015" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</title>
<headline>Mideast and African port conditions - Lloyds.</headline>
<text>
<p>Port conditions from Lloyds Shipping Intelligence Service --</p>
<p>ISRAEL, Sept 3 - Haifa - Four vessels due, 1-2 days delay expected. Delays in loading/discharging at berth - general cargo up to 3 days, bulk 2-3 days, containers 3 days. Waiting at anchorage to load/discharge - general cargo up to 1 day, bulk 1-2 days, containers 1 day. 2 vessels bunkering, 6 under repair/drydock, 3 awaiting orders.</p>
<p>Ashdod - Delays of 1-2 days expected. Delays in loading/discharging at berth, general cargo up to 3 days, bulk 2-3 days, containers 2 days. Waiting at anchorage to load/discharge - general cargo up to 2 days, bulk 1-2 days, containers 2 days. 1 vessel under repair/drydock. Eilat - Three vessels due. No delays expected. Loading/discharging at berth - bulk and containers 1 day.</p>
<p>MAURITIUS, Sep 3 - Port Louis - Two container vessels alongside for discharging and unloading, 3 general cargo vessels alongside for discharging, 21 fishing vessels for transhipment of fish/discharging and bunkering purposes. No idle vessels, 1 vessel in drydock, 16 due by 10/9.</p>
<p>MOZAMBIQUE, Sept 2 - Nacala - Port working normally (first come, first served basis). No restriction on berthing and sailing during night time. Draft restriction of 9.5 metres plus height of tide at general cargo berths and 14 metres at container berths. One tugboat available. Beira - General cargo berths working normally (first come, first served basis). Container terminal/other terminals working normally. Pilotage restricted to daylight only. Two tugboats now fully operational. Night navation by special arrangement and restricted to LOA 130 metres. Maputo - Pilotage restricted to daylight only. Two tugboats available, one out of order. All berths working normally and expected to remain so (first come, first served basis). Draft restriction in the channel is 8.5 metres less 0.5 metre plus rise of tide.</p>
<p>NAMIBIA, Sept 2 - Walvis Bay - Working normally.</p>
<p>SIERRA LEONE, Freetown, Sept 3 - Vessels due - 2 container dischargers, 1 bulk wheat discharger, 1 oil discharger, 1 container/vehicles discharger. Vessels loading at berth - 5 rice dischargers, 1 container discharger. In the interest of security, vessels must endeavour to be in/out of port before 1900 hours.</p>
<p>SOUTH AFRICA, Sept 2 - Richards Bay - general cargo berths working normally. Bulk import berths congested, delays of 14-30 days. Bulk export berths working normally. Bulk coal berths working normally, vessels berthing on arrival. 5 vessels due 6/9, berthing delays approx 12 hours possible.</p>
<p>Durban - container terminal delays of up to 72 hours. Point/New Pier/Maydon wharf berths working normally. Maize terminal (Maydon wharf 8) - 5 maize loads for September. Bunker supplies delays in supplying bunkers expected due to bunching of vessels. Drydock and floating dock fully booked to mid-October. East London - general cargo/combi terminal berths busy, but no delays expected. Drydock fully booked until mid-October. Elevator 4 vessels awaiting berth, up to 5 days berthing delay. Gasoil pipeline under-utilised.</p>
<p>Port Elizabeth - eight vessels in port, no delays expected at general, tanker or fruit berths. Container berths no delays expected. Ore berth working normally, 1 vessel due 2/9. Cape Town - breakbulk berths vessels working on arrival. Container terminal delays due to shifting and relocating of gantry cranes. Bunker berths no delays expected. Drydock and repair quay fully occupied, booking essential. Saldanha Bay - working normally.  </p>
<p>TUNISIA, Aug 31 - Gabes - three vessels loading at berth (1 bulk fertiliser, 1 di-calcium phosphate, 1 gas), 1 discharging bulk aluminium hydroxide. No vessels waiting at anchor. Sfax - seven vessels in port operating of which 3 discharging (1 soy pellets, 1 general cargo, 1 gasoil), 4 loading (1 bulk salt, 1 bulk olive oil, 1 rock phosphate, 1 bulk tsp). Sousse - one berthed discharging crude oil, no vessels anchored/due, no delays expected. Tunis - two vessels in port of which 1 general cargo, 1 awaiting owner's instructions. 2 floating cranes vacant.</p>
<p>Rades - five vessels in port of which 3 ro/ros discharging cars/trailers, 1 cereal, 1 loading containers. La Goulette - north side 1 general cargo, 2 passenger. South Side - 1 discharging grain, 2 in roads awaiting berth priority. 2 mobile cranes vacant.</p>
<p>Sept 2 - Bizerta - three in port of which 1 loading cement, 1 discharging steel, 1 loading white products. No berthing delays or congestion. Zarzis - no vessels in port.</p>
<p>TURKEY, Sept 2 - Istanbul - Haydarpasa - ten vessels operating of which 6 dry cargo, 3 containers, 1 ro/ro. No berthing delays except for heavy lift cargoes. Galata - eight cargo/passenger vessels operating, port congested. Ambarl - 15 operating of which 14 dry cargo, 1 tanker, no berthing delays.</p>
<p>Sept 3 - Mersin - 16 vessels operating of which loading - 2 flour, 1 cement, 1 beer, 1 general cargo, 3 livestock, 1 bulk soda. Discharging - 1 rice, 1 vegetable oil. Loading and discharging - 2 vehicles, 2 containers, 1 container/general cargo, 12 awaiting orders. Free zone piers - 1 vessel loading beans, 2 loading chrome. Seka - no vessels in port. Iskenderun - two discharging of which 1 fuel oil, 1 fertiliser, 2 anchored. Sariseki - two discharging fertiliser. Yazilar - one discharging scrap iron.</p>
<p>Ekinciler - one discharging scrap iron, 1 loading steel billets, 2 anchored. Isdemir - one discharging coal, 1 loading steel billets. Toros - one discharging coal, 2 anchored. Mersin - 15 operating of which loading - 2 soda, 1 general cargo, 2 flour, 1 livestock, 1 cement, 1 chrome, 1 bean. Discharging - 1 rice, 1 pyroxylin, 1 vegetable oil, import/export 2 container vessels, 20 anchored.</p>
<p>YEMEN  Sept 2 - Hodeidah - four vessels berthed of which 2 bulk wheat, 1 sugar, 1 rice, 3 berths vacant. No vessels anchored. Berthing delays - containers - up to 1 day, general cargo - up to 2 days, bagged cargoes - up to 4 days, bulk cargoes - up to 6 days. Mokha - no vessels berthed, none anchored, no berthing delays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
