<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32021" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu, Arafat shake hands at last.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu, Arafat shake hands at last.</headline>
<byline>Robert Mahoney</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>With a reserved but nonetheless ice-breaking handshake Benjamin Netanyahu and Yasser Arafat have relaunched stalled talks on extending Palestinian self-rule in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>Israel's new right-wing prime minister took the hand of the PLO leader he used to brand a &quot;terrorist&quot; at a brief summit meeting on the Israeli-Gazan border on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The meeting marked Netanyahu's formal acceptance of Arafat as a negotiating partner three years after the Palestinian president sealed a peace deal with a historic handshake with Yitzhak Rabin on the White House lawn.</p>
<p>The two leaders did not solve major problems such as Netanyahu's delay in honouring his predecessor's commitment to redeploy Israeli soldiers in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Israeli Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai will meet Arafat on Sunday to tackle that issue and discuss Israel's six-month-old closure of the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>But the hour-long summit paved the way for a completion of the first phase of the Oslo accords and the resumption of second stage talks on a final settlement of the 50-year-old Israeli-Palestinian conflict.</p>
<p>Although short on substance the meeting and handshake were seen as vital symbols of both sides' commitment to the Oslo agreement signed by the Labour government that Netanyahu toppled in May.</p>
<p>Netanyahu had delayed meeting Arafat, citing security concerns on Hebron. But the Likud prime minister came under strong pressure from the United States, co-sponsor of Middle East peace efforts, to meet the PLO chairman.</p>
<p>Netanyahu visits Washington next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Both parties reiterate their commitment to the interim agreement and their determination to carry out its implementation,&quot; Netanyahu told a joint news conference with Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) we have to take into account the needs and requirements of both sides on the basis of reciprocity and the assurance of the security and well-being of both Israelis and Palestinians alike,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Arafat, who feared Netanyahu might try to rewrite Olso, pledged to work with the Likud leader.</p>
<p>&quot;The road is paved for the negotiations between us on all aspects and at every level, including the final-status talks, of course,&quot; Arafat said.</p>
<p>The final status talks cover the thorniest issues such as Jewish settlements, the status of Jerusalem, refugees, land and resources. Arafat hopes they will secure him a Palestinian state with Arab East Jerusalem as its capital.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, in a speech to Israeli journalists after the meeting, sketched out a different vision of the future.</p>
<p>&quot;What will be in the permanent settlement?&quot; Netanyahu asked. &quot;It is clear that we do not want to run the lives of the Palestinians...But there are certain areas, first among them security, and obviously other questions, like water, like ties with foreign elements, foreign countries, making treaties for instance, things of this sort that must stay under Israel's control,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;These will be tough negotiations,&quot; Netanyahu added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
