<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32027" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Bank gains push Moroccan bourse higher.</title>
<headline>Bank gains push Moroccan bourse higher.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca bourse closed higher on Wednesday due mainly to active trading in the banking sector, stockbrokers said.</p>
<p>The all-share index rose 0.65 percent to close at 409.12 points.</p>
<p>Banque Commerciale du Maroc, the market largest capitalisation, gained 15 dirhams to close at 660 dirhams.</p>
<p>&quot;Because there is a lack of the bank's shares on the market, BCM stock is rising,&quot; said Majid Benjelloun, a stockbroker at Maroc Inter Titres.  </p>
<p>Wafabank, one of the market's blue chips, rose eight dirhams to close at 440.</p>
<p>Benjelloun said: &quot;There has been a constant evolution of Wafa stock since June 24. It has the lowest price-earning ratio on the market.&quot;</p>
<p>ONA Group, Morocco's largest private conglomerate, remained unchanged at 410 dirhams despite the official announcement the group bought major stakes in four mining companies, producing silver, fluorite, cobalt and copper. The purchase, at the equivalent of $75 million, had long been known to stockbrokers.</p>
<p>One analyst expected the stock value to rise in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>SONASID, the country's giant steel plant operator, which was recently privatised, gained four dirhams to close at 339. The bourse total trading reached 5.9 million dirhams, compared to 44.7 million dirhams on Tuesday and 6.8 million dirhams on Monday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.6 dirhams)</p>
<p>-- Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
