<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32020" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Baghdad tense after blasts, us says goals achieved.</title>
<headline>Baghdad tense after blasts, us says goals achieved.</headline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq accused the United States of launching a rocket attack on Baghdad, hours after a series of explosions shook the city, triggering air raid sirens and the thunder of anti-aircraft fire.</p>
<p>The United States, which launched a total of 44 cruise missiles against military targets in southern Iraq early on Tuesday and on Wednesday morning, denied attacking Baghdad.</p>
<p>But state television showed pictures of a building it said was destroyed in an attack on Wednesday night and a crater in a road in a residential area. Government officials said they would take reporters in Baghdad to see the damage.</p>
<p>An Iraqi military statement said a number of people were killed in attacks on military and civilian targets but did not say how many.</p>
<p>The statement called U.S. President Bill Clinton a &quot;war criminal&quot;.</p>
<p>Clinton, however, said the United States had achieved the goals it set itself following Iraq's military incursion against areas of Kurdish-held northern Iraq at the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;Our mission has been achieved,&quot; Clinton told reporters called to the Oval Office in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a withdrawal of the (Iraqi) forces, a dispersal of the forces, but it's too soon to say that this is permanent or that further action will not be taken,&quot; Clinton said, referring to Iraq's incursion into areas of Kurdish-held northern Iraq at the weekend which prompted the U.S. response.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein met his air force commanders twice on Wednesday and was reported to have urged them to hit back at U.S., British and French planes policing the northern and now expanded southern no-fly zones over Iraq.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said Iraqi forces twice challenged the new enlarged no-fly zone after it took effect at noon Baghdad time -- sending two MiG fighters toward U.S. planes before turning off and tracking a U.S. F-16 fighter with radar until it retaliated with a missile.</p>
<p>Enforcement of the no-fly zone from Iraq's southern border to close to Baghdad came hours after the United States fired the second wave of cruise missiles in two days at targets in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Four ships fired 17 cruise missiles in a &quot;mop-up&quot; operation ordered by Clinton, U.S. officials said. The mission, which Iraq said killed one person and wounded seven, was to destroy Iraq's ability to attack aircraft enforcing the expanded no-fly zone.</p>
<p>The second wave was aimed at targets in southern Iraq not destroyed in an attack by 27 missiles on Tuesday which Baghdad said killed five people and wounded 19.</p>
<p>Iraq's official newspapers, including Babel which is run by Saddam's eldest son Uday, said on Wednesday that Baghdad would ignore restrictions on Iraqi flights.</p>
<p>&quot;Once again we say to the ungodly Americans in a loud voice ...from today there are no more imaginary parallel lines...from today there will be no (part) of Iraqi territory off limits to us whether in the north or the south,&quot; said Babel.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall defend our sovereignty with our nails and teeth.&quot;</p>
<p>However, the United States said Iraq had obeyed a warning to withdraw aircraft from the expanded no-fly zone or leave them on the ground. A Western military source said Iraq flew out some 30 planes, including Russian MiG and Sukhoi jets.</p>
<p>U.S. Air Force General Joseph Ralston, deputy chairman of the military Joint Chiefs of Staff, said U.S., British and French aircraft began patrolling the new no-fly zone.</p>
<p>But France denied that its combat aircraft had joined U.S. and British planes in patrolling up to the 33rd parallel.</p>
<p>The French foreign ministry said they stayed south of the 30th parallel, which embraces Kuwait and a narrow slice of Iraqi territory.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher said on his way to Britain he hoped to persuade France to join the United States and Britain in patrolling the expanded no-fly zone.</p>
<p>The Russian government demanded a halt to all military action against Iraq and Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov said the bombings could lead to &quot;catastrophic consequences&quot; and &quot;anarchy&quot; on the world scene.</p>
<p>Iraq's neighbour Turkey showed its readiness to protect its interests in the region. A foreign ministry spokesman said Ankara planned to create a security cordon inside northern Iraq to curb increasing Kurdish separatist activity along the porous border between the two countries.</p>
<p>Residents of the mainly Kurdish city of Arbil, which was captured on Saturday by combined Iraqi-Kurdish forces, were trying to return to normal life -- but with no water or electricity supplies and little food.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
