<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32029" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: A handshake so brief it had to be done again.</title>
<headline>A handshake so brief it had to be done again.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>EREZ, Gaza Strip 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first time Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat shook hands, the gesture was so brief that photographers had to ask them to do it again.</p>
<p>The scene on Wednesday was far less a spectacle than when the late Yitzhak Rabin became the first Israeli prime minister to shake Arafat's hand almost exactly three years ago.</p>
<p>That one took place before a crowd of thousands and a live international television audience on the White House lawn in Washington.</p>
<p>Only a few journalists and officials witnessed the historic moment on Wednesday -- in a crowded conference room at the heavily guarded Israeli-Gaza border. Cameras recorded the event for broadcast only later.</p>
<p>The latest handshake with Arafat was a personal and political milestone for the 46-year-old right-wing Israeli leader who built his career on branding Arafat's Palestine Liberation Organisation a terrorist group.</p>
<p>Israelis in the prime minister's entourage said he was extremely tense before the hour-long meeting. Asked hours later how he felt shaking Arafat's hand, Netanyahu said: &quot;I'm not dealing here in feelings. Feelings I leave to biographies.&quot;</p>
<p>The first Netanyahu-Arafat handshake went by so quickly that photographers were unable to record it. They insisted on a repeat performance.</p>
<p>The second handshake, the one recorded for posterity, lasted four seconds -- an unusually quick greeting for the ever-courteous Arafat, 67, known for his big bear hugs and stubble-faced kisses.</p>
<p>Netanyahu rose first, tentatively, as cameras rolled at the Israeli-Palestinian liaison office at the Erez crossing. Netanyahu was host of the meeting since it took place at a complex under Israeli army control.</p>
<p>The Israeli leader buttoned his suit before extending a hand to Arafat who, having risen in tandem with the prime minister, reached across the negotiating table to grasp it.</p>
<p>Arafat half-smiled while Netanyahu appeared to say something to him. Netanyahu, who took office on June 18 and had resisted meeting Arafat, maintained a serious demeanour.</p>
<p>The news conference that followed the meeting also had its moments. At the end of the news conference, the two walked away rather than agree to another handshake for the bulk of the journalists who had missed the earlier ones.</p>
<p>Palestinians, their pride hurt, objected when they realised before the news conference their leader's podium was much shorter than the one for Netanyahu and not bullet-proof. The Israelis brought in one the same size for Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Arafat, normally punctilious about giving people titles, at one point slipped up, referring to the Israeli leader as &quot;Mr Bibi&quot;. Netanyahu's nickname is &quot;Bibi&quot;. Arafat caught himself and then referred to Netanyahu as &quot;His Excellency&quot;.</p>
<p>Arafat looked extremely drawn and tired after almost a week of midnight sessions fretting over whether the meeting would take place.</p>
<p>Netanyahu addressed Arafat, the president of the Palestinian Authority, as chairman, a reference to his leadership of the PLO.</p>
<p>Some aides to Arafat felt the Palestinian leader had been snubbed because Netanyahu, who arrived first, did not come out to the car to greet him.</p>
<p>The meeting was called fewer than three hours before it took place and security was so disorganised that dozens of journalists were stuck at a security check unable to record the historic arrival of the two leaders.</p>
<p>Netanyahu was the third Israeli prime minister to shake hands with Arafat after Rabin and Shimon Peres, who took over after Rabin's assassination by an Israeli Jew opposed to peace moves. Peres was ousted by Netanyahu in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EREZ, Gaza Strip"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
