<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32026" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel court rejects bedouin petition.</title>
<headline>Israel court rejects bedouin petition.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's High Court on Wednesday rejected a petition by bedouin Arabs it block their eviction from lands adjacent to a West Bank Jewish settlement, a court spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Their petition was rejected,&quot; spokesman Moshe Gorali told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Jahalin bedouin tribe had protested against Israel's decision to move them from their encampments near Maaleh Adumim settlement east of Jerusalem to a new location designated by the government they said was unfit for habitation.</p>
<p>&quot;The court ruled the new location was fine,&quot; Gorali said.</p>
<p>The court decision clears the way for the eviction of the Jahalin tribe.</p>
<p>Human rights activists condemned the ruling.</p>
<p>&quot;We absolutely condemn this ruling which amounts to ethnic cleansing without genocide,&quot; said Boudewijn Wegerif, a champion of the bedouins' struggle.</p>
<p>Peter Lerner, spokesman for Israel's occupation authority in the West Bank, has said the bedouins were squatting on state-owned land and would be moved to a new area fitted with public services.</p>
<p>Wegerif told Reuters the proposed site for the tribe's relocation was adjacent to a garbage dump and had only one pipe to carry water to the 50 families of the Jahalin tribe.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a very real danger of infestation,&quot; he said. &quot;We are seeing a once-proud tribe being reduced to slum residents through Israeli actions.&quot;</p>
<p>Lerner said the current bedouin camp was on land earmarked for the expansion of the Jewish settlement of Maaleh Adumim.</p>
<p>&quot;The court decision is against peace,&quot; the Palestinian Center for the Study of Nonviolence said in a news release.</p>
<p>&quot;The settlements expansion is leading not to peace but to potential violence from an increasingly dissatisfied Palestinian people,&quot; the release said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
