<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32035" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: McDonnell may delay first F-15s to Israel.</title>
<headline>McDonnell may delay first F-15s to Israel.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonnell Douglas Corp may delay delivery of the first of the F-15 fighter planes to Israel because of a strike, Israeli defence sources and a company spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be a delay of several months because of the strike,&quot; a defence source said. The company also said a delay was possible.</p>
<p>Israel, which ordered 25 F-15s, was to begin taking delivery in 1997. Deliveries to the Israeli Air Force are to continue to the end of 1998.</p>
<p>The 6,700 workers of the International Association of Machinists District 837 went on strike at McDonnell Douglas' St. Louis plant on June 5, primarily over the issue of job security.</p>
<p>Tom Williams, McDonnell Douglas vice president for communications, said the company began hiring temporary workers immediately and there are now 5,200 people in the factory, compared with the 6,400 that normally work there.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been producing aircraft. We made our deliveries to the U.S. -- in June and July we delivered 10 aircraft and 22 missiles and for August we delivered three aircraft,&quot; Williams said. Among the aircraft delivered were F-15s.</p>
<p>&quot;We're behind in knockdown kits,&quot; he said. But Israel will receive fully assembled planes that will be delivered first to the U.S. government, which will send them to Israel.</p>
<p>Williams said it was possible there would be a delay of a few months in delivery of the first of the F-15s to Israel.</p>
<p>Negotiations with the striking workers broke off three weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if the strike continues we expect to catch up on any delays come the begining of next year,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we expect to be back at the bargaining table very soon and perhaps bring this to a conclusion.&quot;</p>
<p>- Tova Cohen, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
