<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32033" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: U.S. strike against Iraq boosts Kuwait shares.</title>
<headline>U.S. strike against Iraq boosts Kuwait shares.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait share index ended the week to Wednesday at a record high after U.S. attacks on Iraq and the expansion of a no-fly zone in the south of Kuwait's former occupier boosted confidence in security, dealers said.</p>
<p>The index rose 13.3 points or 0.8 percent reaching a record level of 1,636.7 points, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people believe that as long as the no-fly zone in Iraq has been expanded the Gulf would be safer,&quot; said Mohammad al-Duhaishi, a dealer.</p>
<p>Analysts said the expansion on Wednesday of a no-fly zone almost to Baghdad's suburbs will sharply curb Iraqi air power and hand Washington's Gulf allies valuable extra warning time of any potential trouble from Iraq.</p>
<p>U.S. air and naval forces have fired 44 cruise missiles against military targets in southern Iraq since early Tuesday.</p>
<p>Another reason for the increased trade and higher prices is that a September 6 deadline for bad debt payments by private debtors did not cause share dumping, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Worries about the debts deadline ended. Sales were expected to occur on the last day of the week and there was no sign of that,&quot; Duhaishi said.</p>
<p>Debtors involved in a plan to settle bad debts owed to the state have to pay an installment by September 6. The debt, with an original value of $20 billion, is owed by businessmen and private companies including listed firms.</p>
<p>Daily average volume rose 93.1 percent to 138.5 million shares, with a total volume of 692.7 million shares.</p>
<p>Traded value gained 74.3 percent on a daily average basis to 25.1 million dinars ($83.9 million), with a total value of 125.9 million. Deals rose 53.7 percent to an average of 1,461 a day.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will be more active next week,&quot; said Khaled al-Saleh, chairman of the Gulf Brokerage Company. &quot;Capital is flowing into the market and the results of (listed) companies are expected to be very good.&quot;</p>
<p>Gains led losses 27-13, with 15 stocks unchanged.</p>
<p>The most active stocks were Commercial Bank, Investment Projects, United Realty, Pearl of Kuwait Real Estate and Kuwait Real Estate.</p>
<p>Banks were the most active sector by value with 39.4 percent, followed by property shares with 30.7 percent and investment companies with 15.8 percent.</p>
<p>Properties were the most active by volume with 44.6 percent. Banks came second with 26.8 percent and investment firms were third with 17.8 percent.</p>
<p>($1 = 0.299 dinars)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
