<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32039" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordanian deputies condemn U.S. missile strikes.</title>
<headline>Jordanian deputies condemn U.S. missile strikes.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian parliamentarians on Wednesday condemned U.S. missile strikes on Iraq as an act of American arrogance violating international laws.</p>
<p>A statement issued by the 80-seat lower house of deputies said its members &quot;deeply reject the American aggression on brotherly Iraq and breaching its sovereignty and the unity of its people and territories.&quot;</p>
<p>It described the U.S. attacks as &quot;contrary to all international principles and morals.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This aggression is not justified by any international legitimacy nor any (United Nations) Security Council resolution,&quot; said the statement carried by Petra news agency. &quot;(It) is just American arrogance based purely on internal calculations.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States fired a second batch of missiles at targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday and extended a no-fly zone in the south of the country nearly up to Baghdad's outskirts.</p>
<p>Jordan's government has campaigned for change in Baghdad for over a year but the cabinet expressed concern on Tuesday after the first wave of missile strikes and called for restraint to avoid a further escalation of violence.</p>
<p>The deputies said in their statement that the U.S. attacks came just as the Arab world and international community &quot;were striving to help Iraq and its neighbours overcome the reasons and the effects of the (1991) Gulf War&quot;.</p>
<p>Iraq and the U.N. were about to implement a long-delayed $2 billion oil-for-food deal last week which would allow Baghdad to sell oil for the first time since sanctions were imposed to punish Saddam Hussein for his 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Washington says that deal is now on hold after Saddam sent his troops into the Kurdish city of Arbil.</p>
<p>The statement also warned neighbouring Turkey and Iran, both troubled by Kurdish minorities, against interfering in Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;While the American aggression came under the pretext of Iraq's military movements inside its own territory, the house calls on the international community and Iraq's neighbours to halt their barefaced interference and attacks on the sovereignty... of Iraq,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Jordan's King Hussein has pledged that his country would not be used as a base for any attacks on Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
