<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32045" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Evacuation of U.S. coastal areas accelerates.</title>
<headline>Evacuation of U.S. coastal areas accelerates.</headline>
<byline>Lorrie Grant</byline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, S.C. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roadways, food markets and hardware stores from Florida to North Carolina were jammed on Wednesday because of predictions powerful Hurricane Fran was likely to strike the U.S. Atlantic coast.</p>
<p>Tensions were highest in South Carolina, as the National Hurricane Center listed 300-year-old Charleston, a city pounded seven years ago by Hurricane Hugo, as Fran's most likely target.</p>
<p>But the storm was so large -- hurricane-force winds extended 145 miles (230 km) from its center and tropical storm force winds 290 miles (465 km) -- that coastal areas from northern Florida to North Carolina were put on alert.</p>
<p>At 5 p.m. EDT (2100 GMT), the National Hurricane Center issued a hurricane warning from north of Brunswick, Georgia, to Cape Lookout, North Carolina, and a hurricane watch from north of Cape Lookout to Currituck Beach Light, North Carolina. A tropical storm watch was posted from Flagler Beach, Florida, to Brunswick, Georgia.</p>
<p>Emergency management officials worried about the dangerous strength of Hurricane Fran began evacuating residents of Ocracoke Island, N.C., a low-lying resort island late Wednesday.</p>
<p>Peter Stone, emergency management manager for the tiny island that is part of North Carolina's famed Outer Banks, said the decision was based on the proximity of storm and the forecast for it to grow stronger.</p>
<p>&quot;It was time to get everybody the hell out of here,&quot; Stone said.</p>
<p>Ocracoke Island, a sliver of flood-prone land near Cape Hatteras, has about 800 permanent residents and an estimated 2,000 tourists. Three ferries and a two-lane highway are the only ways to get on and off the island.</p>
<p>&quot;Preparations in the hurricane warning area should be rushed to completion,&quot; said hurricane specialist Ed Rappaport. &quot;At this time, Hurricane Fran is about as large as Hurricane Hugo, and has the potential to become just as strong.&quot;</p>
<p>South Carolina Gov. David Beasley declared a statewide state of emergency, and issued a mandatory evacuation order affecting beachfront property and other low-lying areas in six counties several hours later as Fran approached.</p>
<p>&quot;This storm is incredibly dangerous and must be taken seriously as the life-threatening force that it is,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Georgia Gov. Zell Miller declared a state of emergency in 11 counties along the coast as Georgia officials urged voluntary evacuations.</p>
<p>At 5 p.m. EDT (2100 GMT) Fran was about 410 miles (660 km) southeast of Charleston, the National Hurricane Center said, at latitude 28.2 north and longitude 75.8 west with winds of 115 mph (185 kph) and moving northwest near 12 mph (19 kph).</p>
<p>Fran was a dangerous Category 3 hurricane and was expected to make U.S. landfall sometime on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people are leaving right now. We're urging people to leave,&quot; said Stacey Livingston, a clerk with the town of Kiawah Island, one of the barrier resorts to the south of Charleston.</p>
<p>Hurricane Hugo, ranked as the second costliest hurricane in U.S. history, was a Category 4 storm that slammed into Charleston on Sept. 21, 1989, with winds clocked at more than 140 mph (225 kph) and caused more than $7 billion in damage. Hugo was also blamed for 27 deaths and destroyed some 17,000 homes Charleston.</p>
<p>At Cape Canaveral, about halfway up the Florida coast, NASA rolled the space shuttle Atlantis back to its massive garage as a precaution against storm conditions, delaying its takeoff.</p>
<p>Atlantis, already six weeks late because of rocket problems, had been due to blast off on Sept. 14 on a mission to pick up U.S. astronaut Shannon Lucid from the Russian Mir space station and drop off her replacement, John Blaha.</p>
<p>A hurricane warning was also in effect for the northwestern Bahamas as Fran moved parallel to the islands.</p>
<p>The potential for flooding was a serious concern, as forecasters warned of tides of 12 to 16 feet (4 to 5.3 metres) above normal near and northeast of where Fran's center makes landfall. Five to 10 inches (12.5-25 cm) of rain also were expected along Fran's path.</p>
<p>Forecasters also began tracking a second Atlantic weather headache on Wednesday, as the eighth tropical depression of the Atlantic hurricane season formed east of the Caribbean Sea.</p>
<p>At 5 p.m. EDT (2100 GMT), the depression was about 865 miles (1,395 km) east of the Lesser Antilles and threatening to become Tropical Storm Hortense within 24 hours as it moved west. A previous storm, Gustav, dissipated in the Atlantic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
