<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32043" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Risks of natural birth after Cesarean mixed.</title>
<headline>Risks of natural birth after Cesarean mixed.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Women who needed a Cesarean section to give birth in the past face twice the risk of major complications if they have another baby vaginally, according to a study in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
<p>But the results were not expected to have a major impact on the national campaign to discourage Cesarean sections because the complication rate, although twice as high, still represents a low risk to individual mothers.</p>
<p>In addition, the number of minor complications is lower, and the likelihood of death is roughly the same, if a woman who has had a Cesarean delivers the next child naturally.</p>
<p>&quot;The good news from this study is that complications were rare in both groups and that there were no maternal deaths,&quot; said Dr. Richard Paul of the University of Southern California School of Medicine in an editorial in the Journal.</p>
<p>For many years women who had delivered a child by Cesarean section had been encouraged by doctors to have all subsequent babies the same way. &quot;Once a Cesarean, always a Cesarean&quot; was the watchword. But by 1980, the medical community had realised that the slogan was not necessarily true.</p>
<p>The new study, led by Dr. Michael McMahon of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, was designed to assess the risks in detail. The researchers evaluated records of 6,138 pregnant women who had delivered a child through Cesarean section. A total of 3,249 decided to try a vaginal delivery, while the rest elected to have another Cesarean.</p>
<p>The study found that the likelihood of a major complication was 1.6 percent for the women who tried natural labour and delivery, compared with 0.8 percent for the women who elected to have another Cesarean.</p>
<p>The uterus ruptured in 10 women who tried labour, compared with 1 who got a Cesarean. Forty-one women who went into labour were injured during surgery, usually because they needed a Cesarean section anyway, compared with 18 who elected to have a Cesarean.</p>
<p>But the risk of minor complications such as the need for a transfusion, a fever or an abdominal wound infection was 20 percent lower in the women who tried to deliver naturally. The likelihood that the baby would have problems was similar whether the woman opted for natural delivery or a Cesarean.</p>
<p>McMahon and his colleagues found that, compared to women who had never delivered a child vaginally, the women in their study who had given birth vaginally once before were three times more likely to have a successful vaginal delivery.</p>
<p>They also discovered that a woman who had hoped to deliver her baby naturally was more likely to end up with a Cesarean section if she had not attended prenatal classes, the baby weighed at least nine pounds (four kg), or she was trying to deliver in a regional or community hospital.</p>
<p>Larger hospitals seem to have a better track record for getting patients to deliver vaginally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
