<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32051" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. plant group attacks karnal bunt quarantine.</title>
<headline>U.S. plant group attacks karnal bunt quarantine.</headline>
<dateline>ST PAUL 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The American Phytopathological Society, a private group that studies plant diseases, said scientific evidence does not warrant use of a &quot;zero tolerance&quot; rule for marketing wheat detected with the karnal bunt fungus.</p>
<p>&quot;The APS position is that available scientific information does not support a 'zero tolerance' requirement for spores in seed lots as the standard for smut and bunt diseases in cereals, including for karnal bunt,&quot; said APS president Lawrence Madden, an Ohio State University plant pathologist.  </p>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department quarantined wheat in parts of four Western states this year when karnal bunt was found in wheat.</p>
<p>The USDA has imposed a 'zero tolerance' rule to prevent movement of wheat or seed from the quarantined areas and has proposed strict regulations for planting, cleaning and testing wheat, durum and triticale in affected areas this year.</p>
<p>U.S. House Agriculture Committee chairman Pat Roberts of Kansas on August 14 defended the zero tolerance rule as vital for the confidence of U.S. overseas grain customers and for the standards of the milling industry.  </p>
<p>He said USDA should continue researching control of the tilletia indica fungus which causes karnal bunt and no change in policy should come without scientific evidence.</p>
<p>&quot;The APS position is that these diseases can be managed through cultural practices and planting of resistant varieties. These management options are in addition to the use of clean, high-quality seed,&quot; Madden said.</p>
<p>APS said in a statement that karnal bunt was nontoxic to humans or livestock but flour made from more than three percent bunted wheat kernels render a fishy odor and taste and so were unacceptable for human consumption.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although quarantines may delay introduction of pathogens into new areas, they are unlikely to absolutely prevent such introductions and subsequent establishment,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the specific case of karnal bunt, experience from countries where this disease has occurred would suggest further that this is a minor disease and what little risk does occur can be effectively managed without the use of quarantines,&quot; the APS statement said.</p>
<p>The statement, which was released on the Group's World Wide Web home page, followed a two-month on-line roundtable the Society conducted this summer on karnal bunt, an APS spokeswoman said. The APS has 5,000 members in more than 70 countries and is funded by dues and publications, she said.</p>
<p>The USDA held four public forums last month to discuss its proposed rules on karnal bunt areas for the 1996-97 season.</p>
<p>Despite low world wheat stocks, overseas buyers remain concerned about certification of U.S. wheat quality.</p>
<p>The U.S. agricultural attache in Chile said in a report issued on August 14, that it was unlikely the United States would sell any more wheat to that country this year due to disagreement over certification following the karnal bunt outbreak.</p>
<p>(Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8720)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST PAUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
