<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32052" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue chips end slightly higher; focus on jobs numbers.</title>
<headline>Blue chips end slightly higher; focus on jobs numbers.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ended with small gains Wednesday as Wall Street reacted calmly to news of the second U.S. military strike against Iraqi targets and focused on Friday's jobs data for clues to the Federal Reserve's interest rate policy.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 8.51 points at 5,656.90. In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,370 to 927 on moderate volume of 351 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;At the present time both stocks and bonds are acting antsy about Friday's news,&quot; said Harry Laubscher, market analyst at Tucker Anthony. &quot;Investors are largely on the sidelines in advance of the jobs data.&quot;</p>
<p>The new round of missile attacks by the United States against Iraq early Wednesday continued to roil limited segments of the market, though oil stocks were only barely higher on the day.</p>
<p>Traders said the U.S. military intervention had largely faded as a market-moving factor, and most investors shifted to upcoming economic data, such as Friday's jobs report that is expected to help the Fed decide whether to raise or keep interest rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Analysts on average expect non-farm payrolls to rise by 224,000 in August compared with July's 193,000 increase, while the unemployment rate is seen edging lower to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond was off 16/32 and its yield, which moves in the opposite direction from the price, rose to 7.10 percent from 7.06 percent at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>The energy-hungry transportation sector was weak and the shares of airline companies were battered by the prospect that higher fuel prices will hurt their results.</p>
<p>United Airlines' parent, UAL Corp. lost 1/2 at 47 and American Airlines' parent AMR Corp. was down two at 80.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices ended 16 cents lower at $23.24 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange after soaring $1.15 Tuesday on the United Nations' decision to call off the sale by Iraq of 600,000 to 700,000 barrels per day of oil following Baghdad's military incursion into northern Iraqi Kurdistan.</p>
<p>Despite the pullback, oil prices have gained about $1 this week and are nearly $6 above year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Retail stocks got a boost from news that office product retailer Staples Inc. agreed to acquire competitor Office Depot Inc. in a deal that creates an industry giant with more than $10 billion in annual sales.</p>
<p>Office Depot jumped 4-5/8 to 20-1/2, while Staples, which will pay 1.14 shares for each Office Depot share, fell 3/4 to 18-3/4.</p>
<p>The deal sparked strong demand for retail stocks. J.C. Penney Co. gained 1-7/8 to 55-1/2, May Department Stores Co. rose 1-3/8 to 47-1/2 and Sears Roebuck &amp; Co. rose 1-1/8 to 44-3/4.</p>
<p>&quot;You've had concern in that sector about too many competitors and margin erosion,&quot; said Philip Orlando, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management. &quot;This deal suggests managements recognise the potential problem and are going to enact the strategic consolidation that is needed.&quot;</p>
<p>One stock that failed to participate in the retail rally was OfficeMax Inc., which slipped 5/8 to 13-1/8. The company, a direct competitor of Staples and Office Depot, said it may pursue acquisitions of its own in light of the merger.</p>
<p>Rubbermaid Inc. fell 3-5/8 to 22-7/8 after warning that its third quarter earnings would be hurt by rising raw materials prices. The company also said it agreed to buy Graco Children's Products Inc. for $320 million in cash.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 1.53 points to 1,143.82.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 0.89 to 655.61. The American Stock Exchange index dipped 0.45 to 557.34.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 1.61 to 352.37. The average share was up 6 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,454.798, up 10.114, or 0.16 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
