<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32063" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Staples buying Office Depot for $3.48 billion.</title>
<headline>Staples buying Office Depot for $3.48 billion.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Staples Inc. said Wednesday it agreed to acquire rival Office Depot Inc. for about $3.48 billion in stock in a deal that will create the largest office products superstore chain in the United States.</p>
<p>The combined company, to be known as Staples The Office Depot, will have more than 1,100 store locations and some $10 billion in revenues in the fast-growing office products market. The firms will also combine their mail order and contract printing businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;This company will have instant national scale and scope,&quot; Staples Chief Executive Thomas Stemberg told reporters during a conference call. &quot;We will cover 96 percent of the metropolitan areas in North America, and interestingly, we only overlap in 21 percent of those.&quot;</p>
<p>Boston-based Staples and Office Depot, based in South Florida, helped revolutionise the office products market by offering low prices and a wide assortment of office supplies under one roof.</p>
<p>Each company opened its first store 10 years ago and each was one of only six U.S. companies ever to reach $3 billion in sales in a decade, Stemberg said.</p>
<p>Under the proposed takeover, Office Depot stockholders will receive 1.14 share of Staples common stock for each share they own in a tax-free transaction.</p>
<p>Based on Staples closing price of $19.50 on Tuesday and Office Depot's 156.6 million outstanding shares, the deal would be worth about $22.23 for each of Office Depot's shares, or about $3.48 biillion.</p>
<p>Shares of Office Depot jumped $4.625 to $20.375 in late trading on the New York Stock Exchange. Staples fell 75 cents to $18.75 on the Nasdaq market.</p>
<p>The third major rival among office superstores, OfficeMax Inc., said it was reviewing the deal and considering its own acquisition plans.</p>
<p>Presumbably to ward off an unwanted acquistion, Office Depot and Staples agreed to buy 19.9 percent of each other's stock if certain conditions were triggered. Officials with Staples said they did not know the conditions.</p>
<p>David Fuente, currently chairman and chief executive of Office Depot, will be chairman of the new company. Stemberg, chairman and chief executive of Staples, will serve as CEO, and Martin Hanaka, president and chief operating officer of Staples, will retain those roles.</p>
<p>The corporate headquarters for Staples/Office Depot will be located in Framingham, Mass., where Staples now has its headquarters. However, the company also intends to maintain a significant presence in Delray Beach, Fla., where Office Depot is based.</p>
<p>Stemberg said around 70 stores may be closed as a result of the merger, but nonetheless, 50 new stores will open in 1997, and between 120 and 150 will open in 1998 and beyond.</p>
<p>The growth plans will allow Staples to cut overlapping stores without the layoffs associated with so many mergers currently, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't intend to lay off people here. That is not where this deal will get paid for,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new company will have growth of more than 20 percent in revenues and 40 percent in earnings per share in 1997, Stemberg said.</p>
<p>Hanaka said the company will take charges of $520 million to cover the costs of the takeover, including facility closings, remodelling, inventory integration, transaction expenses and other costs.</p>
<p>The transaction, which is subject to customary closing conditions, including the approval of the stockholders of both companies and required regulatory approvals, is expected to be completed in 18 months to two years.</p>
<p>Analysts said the two chains have surprisingly little geographical overlap and only a small portion of the overall office products market.</p>
<p>&quot;The overlap isn't that great and I think the possiblility of this going through is pretty high,&quot; said Thomas Kully, an analyst with William Blair &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Asked if Staples faced any regulatory problems, Stemberg replied, &quot;One would hope that when you look at a merger between two companies whose entire livelihood has been generated by cutting prices that they would see through any potential problems to see the tremendous consumer benefits this merger represents.&quot;</p>
<p>Staples operates 517 office products superstores in over 100 markets across the United States and in Canada. It is also a joint venture partner in start-up office supply store chains in Britain and Germany.</p>
<p>Office Depot operates 539 stores, including 532 office supply superstores in the United States. It also operates 32 superstores in Canada and has operations in Mexico, Israel, Poland, Thailand, France, Colombia and Japan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
