<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32096" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Three Sopranos to debut in Los Angeles.</title>
<headline>Three Sopranos to debut in Los Angeles.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Now that The Three Tenors have pushed opera to the top of music sales charts, the world is about to get a second helping -- courtesy of The Three Sopranos, who will make a recording in Los Angeles on Thursday.</p>
<p>Producer and impresario Tibor Rudas struck gold with the recording of the 1994 Three Tenors concert in Dodger Stadium, performed by Jose Carreras, Placido Domingo and Luciano Pavarotti, which sold about five million copies worldwide.</p>
<p>Rudas was also the man behind the scenes of a planned Three Sopranos concert recording in Los Angeles on Thursday.</p>
<p>Following the success of The Three Tenors, Rudas and Ahmet Ertegun, co-chairman and co-chief executive officer of Atlantic Records, are collaborating again to bring three fledgling divas, Kathleen Cassello, Kallen Esperian and Cynthia Lawrence, into the mainstream.</p>
<p>&quot;We are extremely pleased to have the opportunity to be a part of this special musical event,&quot; Ertegun said.</p>
<p>&quot;As with our Three Tenors recording two years ago, the appeal of the Three Sopranos is sure to extend far beyond the traditional classical music audience into the realm of popular culture,&quot; Ertegun said.</p>
<p>The debut appearance of The Three Sopranos will be televised nationwide on U.S. public television in December and the album is set for an Oct. 29 release, a spokeswoman for Atlantic Records said.</p>
<p>Rudas prefers not to compare the Three Sopranos concert to The Three Tenors, but considers it a stand-alone event.</p>
<p>&quot;The opera was built around the soprano. We're not giving an answer to The Three Tenors, but reviving a particular and historic trend,&quot; Rudas told Reuters. &quot;We are doing something practically brand new.&quot;</p>
<p>Tickets for Thursday night's performance of The Three Sopranos, who will perform on a specially-constructed stage next to the Century Plaza Hotel in Los Angeles in a space designed to seat about 3,000, were selling at $25 to $100.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
