<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32091" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans press for cuts in spending, not taxes.</title>
<headline>Republicans press for cuts in spending, not taxes.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>House and Senate Republican leaders said Wednesday they had decided not to push for passage of a tax cut before the November elections and would instead press ahead on domestic spending cuts.</p>
<p>House Speaker Newt Gingrich and Senate Majority Leader Trent Lott told reporters after meeting with top Republicans from both chambers that they agreed there was no point in passing a tax cut just to see it vetoed by President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Some Republicans had hoped passage of a tax cut by their party would boost their chances of retaining control of the House and Senate and would help Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole.</p>
<p>The cornerstone of Dole's campaign policy on economics is a deep income tax cut of 15 percent and a cut in the capital gains tax rate to a maximum of 14 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If we were to pass a real tax cut, Bill Clinton would veto it,&quot; Gingrich, R-Georgia, told reporters. &quot;That's right,&quot; Lott added.</p>
<p>The Republicans agreed their goal would be to pass and send to the president for signature as many of the 13 annual spending bills as can be done by the end of September.</p>
<p>Those federal programs for which spending has not been cleared by the Oct. 1 start of the fiscal year will be covered by funding included in a catch-all spending measure called a &quot;continuing resolution.&quot;</p>
<p>However, major disagreements remain over spending with Clinton seeking higher funds for many domestic programs and about $10 billion less than approved by Congress for the military.</p>
<p>Earlier Lott told reporters that September 27-28 was his target date for adjournment prior to the November 5 elections.</p>
<p>Lott said he was concerned that income tax legislation would be loaded up with numerous provisions that would not help the economy though he still hoped the Senate could act on a more limited tax cut in some form of a 4.3 cents a gallon cut in gasoline taxes.</p>
<p>Dole had proposed the gasoline tax cut when he was majority leader.</p>
<p>Lott, R-Mississippi, told reporters he favored various tax cut proposals but &quot;reality is I don't think we can get it done in September.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
