<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32107" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DoubleClick unveils Internet ad tracking product.</title>
<headline>DoubleClick unveils Internet ad tracking product.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>DoubleClick Inc, an Internet advertising network, on Wednesday said it was introducing proprietary software and a service to allow customers to track the performance of advertisements on the World Wide Web.</p>
<p>Jeff Dickey, vice president of business development at the New York-based company, said a new technology called Spotlight enables customers to monitor the number of pages &quot;clicked through&quot; by an individual user and to determine the point at which the user seeks more information or makes a purchase.  </p>
<p>Dickey and David Henderson, vice president of North American sales, said the technology would improve the ability of advertisers to target individual consumer tastes and produce qualified leads and purchases.</p>
<p>&quot;Our business is not just eyeballs,&quot; or the number of people who use their mouse to click on banner advertisements to view -- or eyeball -- an advertiser's site on the Internet's World Wide Web, Dickey said.</p>
<p>The two executives said the technology matches a shift in advertising on the Web from general branding to more specific targeting to produce responses.  </p>
<p>While the survey found that most Internet advertisers are still high-tech companies advertising on one another's sites, DoubleClick has detected a big increase in Web advertising plans by the consumer product companies -- among the biggest advertisers in national magazines and on television and radio.</p>
<p>&quot;The reality is that the Internet is the greatest empowerment tool in history,&quot; Dickey said of the allure of using the medium for advertising to individuals.</p>
<p>DoubleClick Network was launched less than six months ago. The company was formed in March after the merger of a division of Bozell Worldwide's Poppe Tyson advertising agency with the Atlanta-based Internet Advertising Network.</p>
<p>Last month, the company surpassed the 10 million-user mark, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
