<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32106" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y. Pataki says still reviewing welfare reforms.</title>
<headline>N.Y. Pataki says still reviewing welfare reforms.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York Governor George Pataki, who has estimated that the dramatic federal welfare reforms will cost the state &quot;several hundred million dollars,&quot; said on Wednesday that a bipartisan group still is studying the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;The task force is continuing its work, a line-by-line review of a 300-page bill,&quot; said Michael McKeon, a spokesman for the governor.</p>
<p>Pataki has not set a deadline for the group to finish its work, the spokesman said, explaining the governor wants it to be as thorough as possible.</p>
<p>And the governor has backed off on his earlier suggestion that a special legislative session might be needed to deal with the new federal reforms. &quot;That is not an issue that we've addressed at this point,&quot; his spokesman said.</p>
<p>The governor went to Utica, in Oneida County, on Wednesday to highlight the area's success in reducing the number of people who collect welfare.</p>
<p>In the past year, Oneida County has cut the number of welfare recipients by 2,700, McKeon said, adding that New York state as a whole reduced the program's rolls by 181,000 from January 1995 to May 1996.</p>
<p>The drop reflects Pataki's efforts to shift people from welfare to work, he said.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
