<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32108" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oil prices fall back as Iraqi troops withdraw.</title>
<headline>Oil prices fall back as Iraqi troops withdraw.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices closed lower Wednesday after Iraqi troops withdrew from some Kurdish areas in northern Iraq and President Clinton said immediate U.S. goals had been met after a second missile attack on Iraqi military targets.</p>
<p>At the New York Mercatile Exchange October crude oil futures closed 16 cents a barrel lower at $23.24 and October heating oil closed 0.86 cent a gallon lower at 64.21 cents.</p>
<p>Selling was restrained by continued uncertainty about the Iraqi situation and other factors such as Hurricane Fran, a massive storm threatening the mid-Atlantic seaboard.</p>
<p>October unleaded gasoline ended unchanged at 62.96 cents per gallon.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a combination of the uncertainty and the fundamentals. We are still not getting 700,000 barrels,&quot; said Rita Beale, an analyst with Fimat USA Futures, of the limited sell-off in futures on news of the Iraqi troop withdrawal.</p>
<p>&quot;The uptrend is still in place,&quot; Beale said.</p>
<p>Iraq was expected to start providing 700,000 barrels a day of crude to world markets later this month under a United Nations deal to sell oil to buy food and medicine.</p>
<p>That deal was frozen indefinitely over the weekend after Iraqi troops attacked Kurdish groups in a move that prompted U.S. cruise missile attacks on Iraqi radar and other installations.</p>
<p>Analysts also pointed to underlying heating oil demand and tight crude oil stocks as reasons to keep the oil market firm.</p>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute reported after the close of trading that U.S. crude oil stocks fell 5.68 million barrels in the week ended Aug. 30 to 313.15 million barrels.</p>
<p>Gasoline stocks fell 3.71 million barrels to 192.82 million from 196.53 million barrels but distillate or heating oil stocks rose 3.24 million barrels to 108.90 million.</p>
<p>At the Commodity Exchange, December copper closed 1.45 cents per pound lower at 94.40 cents per pound following a sharp sell-off on the London Metal Exchange. But analysts said a rebound could occur due to a possible mine strike.</p>
<p>Union officials negotiating for a new contract at Phelps Dodge Corp.'s Chino, N.M., mine said Wednesday that talks were at a stalemate. The contract for 670 workers at the 170,000-ton-per-year mine expired on June 30.</p>
<p>At the Chicago Board of Trade, improved sentiment about this year's corn and soybean crops pushed prices lower.</p>
<p>November soybeans closed 15-1/4 cents per bushel lower at $7.80-1/4, and December corn ended 8 cents per bushel lower at $3.33-1/2.</p>
<p>Iowa-based Farmers Commodities Corp. late Tuesday predicted the U.S. soybean crop would total 2.276 billion bushels, up slightly from its previous guess of 2.271 billion.</p>
<p>FCC also pegged the corn crop at 9.02 billion bushels, below its previous 9.081 billion but well above last month's forecast by the Agriculture Department at 8.695 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a reality check today for the market from FCC,&quot; said analyst Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>At the New York Cotton Exchange prices fell back as Hurricane Fran looked set to avoid any major damage to southern crops. December cotton closed down 1.63 cents at 75.62 cents a pound.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
