<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32114" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Venerable U.S. city braces for another hurricane.</title>
<headline>Venerable U.S. city braces for another hurricane.</headline>
<byline>Eric Frazier</byline>
<dateline>CHARLESTON, S.C. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fear rippled through this stately southern city on Wednesday as Hurricane Fran swirled toward its shores, whipping up memories of destruction and death wrought seven years ago by another killer hurricane.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a madhouse in here,&quot; said Van Herridge, a clerk at Hughes Lumber and Building Supply in downtown Charleston, noting that shoppers were lined up outside the store before it opened Wednesday morning, and some 1,000 sheets of plywood had been sold by lunchtime.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a truck coming in at 2 a.m. this morning to stock up for tomorrow. It'll be even worse tomorrow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The sleepy southern pace of life in this 300-year-old city began gathering pace Tuesday night as weather forecasters said Hurricane Fran, a dangerous Category 3 hurricane brewing in the Atlantic, could be heading for landfall nearby.</p>
<p>&quot;At this point, Hurricane Fran poses a very real threat to this community,&quot; Charleston County Council Chairman Barrett Lawrimore told a news conference. &quot;Please don't panic.&quot;</p>
<p>The skies over Charleston were a clear, deep blue Wednesday morning, but were overcast with a steady rain by mid-afternoon.</p>
<p>Grocery stores were jammed, as residents stocked up on bottled water, canned foods, batteries and other supplies. Homeowners climbed ladders to put up shutters and pieces of plywood. Low-lying areas were evacuated and emergency officials readied relief plans.</p>
<p>The Charleston metropolitan area is home to about 500,000 people, about 90,000 of them in the city itself. And many lived through Hurricane Hugo, the category 4 storm that slammed into South Carolina just north of Charleston seven years ago this month.</p>
<p>Hugo's visit on Sept. 21, 1989, left 29 dead and 50,000 people homeless. Insurance claims reached more than $4 billion and state officials estimated that the storm pushed as many as 184,000 residents below the poverty line as it damaged industries like tourism and fishing.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of residents lived without power for days, and while it took historic Charleston and resort communities only months to rebuild, rural areas north of the city hardest hit by the storm took years to recover.</p>
<p>Cynthia Reynolds, a resident of Awendaw, a village about 30 miles north of Charleston that saw wind gusts as high as 179 mph during Hugo, said Fran's approach reminded her too much of the earlier storm.</p>
<p>&quot;There's eerie similarities. Enough to make you uncomfortable,&quot; she said. &quot;People are trying to keep their anxieties in check. Many people are battening down the hatches, but some will not leave, just exactly like Hugo. There are so many similarities, it's kind of weird.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARLESTON, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
