<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32124" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Distant &quot;blobs&quot; may be building blocks of galaxies.</title>
<headline>Distant &quot;blobs&quot; may be building blocks of galaxies.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Astronomers said on Wednesday they had identified &quot;blobs&quot; in the distant sky that they believed were the basic building blocks of galaxies.</p>
<p>&quot;There are 18 little blobs, 11 billion light years from Earth,&quot; seen through the Hubble Space Telescope, astronomer Rogier Windhorst told a NASA news briefing in Washington.</p>
<p>The theory is that &quot;subgalactic clumps&quot; like these would eventually have merged and &quot;grown into the galaxies we see around us,&quot; added Windhorst, a professor at Arizona State University at Tempe and the co-author of an article about the findings in Thursday's edition of the journal Nature.</p>
<p>In a galaxy, such as the Milky Way, billions of stars are bound together by gravity. Galaxies are the largest assemblages of stars in the universe.</p>
<p>Astronomers had long sought galactic building blocks, but no land-based telescope had the power to detect them.</p>
<p>The Hubble was able to see them near the constellation Hercules, 11 billion light years away, in a glimpse of the era during which galaxies are commonly believed to have formed.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the first page of an otherwise blank book,&quot; Bruce Margon, an astronomer at the University of Washington at Seattle, told the National Aeronautics and Space Administration briefing.</p>
<p>Each blob has about a billion young stars.</p>
<p>Astronomers have already seen stars form. &quot;Stars form all the time. It's a continual process of birth, maturation, death,&quot; Margon said. &quot;Galaxies do not form all the time.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Windhorst said he believed his blobs would collide and merge into bigger galaxies, some astronomers hold rival theories.</p>
<p>Anne Kinney, an astronomer at the Space Telescope Science Institute, said there was still no proof whether galaxies &quot;form from small to big or big to small.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
