<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32129" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Powell supports U.S. action in Iraq.</title>
<headline>Powell supports U.S. action in Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Retired Army Gen. Colin Powell, a popular Republican who was the U.S. military's top officer during the 1991 Gulf War, on Wednesday praised this week's U.S. military action in Iraq and voiced disappointment with reaction from the coalition that won the war.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the president did exactly the right thing,&quot; Powell said in a CNN interview when asked about cruise missile strikes on Iraq ordered by President Bill Clinton, a Democrat.</p>
<p>&quot;I must say I am a little disappointed that we didn't get the level of support that I would have expected and that we have seen in the past,&quot; he added of criticism of the move by France and refusal by some other nations to join the action aimed at weakening Iraq President Saddam Hussein's military.</p>
<p>He said Saddam, whose's forces attacked Kurds in a protected zone in northern Iraq, was again pushing the limits of western patience.</p>
<p>&quot;What the president (Clinton) is trying to do as he and his associates have said is to deliver a tailored, targeted response to this provocation without trying to expand the response or to get deeply involved in the rather complicated Kurdish situation up north,&quot; Powell said.</p>
<p>He said he expected little or no military opposition from Iraq to an expanded no-fly zone declared by the United States in southern Iraq despite calls from Saddam for his forces to ignore the zone and to resist.</p>
<p>&quot;We should not underestimate the power that we have in the region and separate out his (Saddam's) rhetoric from the reality of the strategic situation,&quot; said Powell.</p>
<p>In an interview with MSNBC television, Powell also defended the decision by the U.S. military and President George Bush against trying to overthrow Saddam after the U.S.-led coalition soundly defeated Iraq's military and drove Iraqi troops from Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;We ejected the Iraqi army from Kuwait,&quot; said Powell, who was chairman of the U.S. military Joint Chiefs of Staff at the time and earlier this year turned down appeals from some Republicans to run for president against Clinton in November.</p>
<p>&quot;We kept intact a marvellous coalition that never had as its mission to go to Baghdad or to eliminate Saddam Hussein,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
