<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32127" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans accuse Clinton of losing war on drugs.</title>
<headline>Republicans accuse Clinton of losing war on drugs.</headline>
<byline>Sue Kirchhoff</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Congressional Republicans Wednesday accused President Clinton of surrendering in the war against illegal drugs, escalating tough election-year rhetoric over the issue.</p>
<p>Administration officials fought back, charging the Republican-led Congress had failed to fully fund Clinton's drug education and prevention programmes and calling for bipartisan cooperation to cut down drug use in America.</p>
<p>The sparring came during a Senate Judiciary Committee hearing examining a recent administration study that found drug use among 12- to 17-year-olds doubled from 5.3 percent to 10.9 percent from 1992-1996.</p>
<p>Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole has seized on the findings to hammer Clinton, attacking him for deep cuts in the White House drug czar's office and running political ads accusing the president of a lack of leadership.</p>
<p>Clinton's re-election campaign has begun airing its own advertisements defending his drug policies and pointing out that Dole originally opposed legislation to create the position of drug czar, the White House drug policy office.</p>
<p>&quot;A president is uniquely positioned to rally a nation over this issue ... many of us believe that President Clinton has not provided the leadership that is needed,&quot; said Senate Judiciary Committee Chairman Orrin Hatch.</p>
<p>Alabama Republican Sen. Richard Shelby said, &quot;It doesn't cost a dime for our national leaders to say drugs are wrong.... it's a value problem, it's a moral problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Aides said Republicans planned a series of hearings over the next several weeks to focus attention on the issue.</p>
<p>Clinton's drug czar, former four-star general Barry McCaffrey, defended the administration efforts and said the House had cut more than $300 million from Clinton's 1997 drug budget proposals. He called on lawmakers to increase funding, warning society would reap a harvest of crime and violence unless policymakers stepped up efforts to fight the drug war.</p>
<p>McCaffrey pointed to lack of public attention, studies showing youth were more accepting of drug use and glamorization of drugs in music and mass media as factors for the increase in drug use.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not allow this issue to become a political football. That could send the wrong message to kids -- and make them think drugs are just an issue for the politicans and not something they have to take personal responsiblity for,&quot; said Health Secretary Donna Shalala.</p>
<p>Democrats defended the president. But Delaware Democratic Sen. Joe Biden complained Clinton didn't talk enough about the issue during his first two years in office and called on Congress to pass a series of new anti-drug initiatives before the election, including increased funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
