<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32135" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Susan McDougal cited for contempt in Whitewater case.</title>
<headline>Susan McDougal cited for contempt in Whitewater case.</headline>
<byline>Steve Barnes</byline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Arkansas 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Susan McDougal, a former Whitewater business partner of President Bill Clinton, was cited for contempt of court on Wednesday for refusing to answer questions about Clinton's alleged role in fraudulent business deals from a decade ago.</p>
<p>McDougal said she was asked by prosecutors before a grand jury whether Clinton knew about an illegal $300,000 loan made to her in 1986, and whether the president lied during his testimony at a Whitewater trial in May, but she flatly refused to answer.</p>
<p>When prosecutors complained she was refusing to cooperate, U.S. District Judge Susan Wright gave McDougal, 41, until Monday to answer the questions or face jail.</p>
<p>&quot;Your right to remain silent does not extend to the grand jury. You are obligated to cooperate with a lawful inquiry,&quot; Wright told McDougal in a Little Rock court.</p>
<p>McDougal and her attorney, Bobby McDaniel, alleged that she was being victimised by prosecutors determined to dig up incriminating evidence against Clinton at whatever cost.</p>
<p>Lead prosecutor Ray Jahn said McDougal was a &quot;recalcitrant&quot; witness.</p>
<p>McDougal has previously said she has no information that would incriminate Clinton in any illegal deals, and insisted on Wednesday that she had a right to refuse testimony.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a matter of principle. I didn't think I should have to testify before this grand jury,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>McDougal, her former husband James McDougal and former Arkansas Governor Jim Guy Tucker were found guilty in May on a string of fraud and conspiracy charges surrounding real estate and business deals from the mid-1980s.</p>
<p>James McDougal, who was convicted on 18 of 19 charges in the trial, agreed to cooperate with prosecutors and his sentencing was postponed until November.</p>
<p>The McDougals and Clintons were business partners in the failed Whitewater venture. The Clintons lost money in the project and have come under heavy pressure as Whitewater investigators have probed the business dealings of their friends and allies in Arkansas.</p>
<p>But Susan McDougal has so far refused to cut a plea bargain deal and was last month sentenced to two years in prison for the convictions on four fraud charges.</p>
<p>McDaniel said independent counsel Kenneth Starr threatened to indict Susan McDougal on more charges if she refused to follow her former husband's lead and cooperate with investigators.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't understand the level of intimidation and coercion that goes on. If the American taxpayers knew, there would be an open revolt,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Arkansas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
