<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32130" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>SOYOIL SALE - Tunisia bought 33,000 tonnes of soyoil at prices between $577 and $580 per tonne C&amp;F at a tender on Wednesday. Delivery is for October 5-20 and November 5-20. The tender was launched for up to 12,000 tonnes of soy and/or rapeseed oils by Office National de l'Huile.</p>
<p>BARLEY SALE - The Cyprus Grain Commission said on Tuesday it had accepted a tender from Lecureur September 3 to supply 25,000 tonnes of feed barley, with shipment for Sept 25-Oct 10 from Europe or Sept 15-30 from North America.  </p>
<p>WHEAT SALE - U.S. exporters reported sales of 100,000 tonnes of optional origin wheat to Sri Lanka for the 1996/97 marketing year, USDA said Wednesday. The wheat was 50,000 tonnes hard red winter and 50,000 tonnes soft red winter.</p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - South Korea said it will tender Sept 5 for 20,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 1 soybean. Bids will be opened Sept 6. Shipment was set for Sept 26-Oct 15 if from the U.S. Gulf or for October 11-30 if from the Pacific Northwest.</p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - Tunisia will tender on September 5 to import 125,000 tonnes of optional-origin soft wheat for shipment in October, November and December.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - The CCC on Sept 10 seeks 19,860 tonnes of soft white wheat, of which 15,340 is for donation to Ethiopia and 4,520 for Pakistan. Shipment is for Sept 25-Oct 20.</p>
<p>- The CCC seeks a total of 23,500 tonnes of U.S. wheat under the export donation program to Honduras.</p>
<p>The deal includes 5,000 tonnes northern spring/dark northern spring wheat and 3,000 tonnes soft red winter wheat set for November 1-25 shipment. It also includes 9,500 NS/DNS wheat and 6,000 tonnes SRW wheat slated for December 10-30 shipment. Offers are due on September 11.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - South Korea's Dongah Flour Mills Co Ltd and Cheiljedang Corp have invited tenders for a total of 22,500 tonnes of U.S. wheat on Thursday, traders said. Shipment was set for December 10-January 10 to Pusan and Ulsan.</p>
<p>CORN TENDER - Taiwan's Members Feed Industry Group will tender on Friday for a 56,000-tonne shipment of U.S. No.2 corn for October delivery, traders said.</p>
<p>CORN AND SOYBEAN TENDER - State-owned Taiwan Sugar Corp will tender on Thursday for 20,000 tonnes of No.2 or better U.S. yellow corn and 10,000 tonnes of No.2 or better U.S. yellow soybeans, traders said.  </p>
<p>WHEAT AND BARLEY TENDER - The Japanese Food Agency will seek on Wednesday night a total of 80,000 tonnes U.S. wheat, 50,000 tonnes Canadian western spring wheat and 17,000 tonnes of Australian prime hard wheat.</p>
<p>Japan will also tender for 20,000 tonnes U.S. or Canadian optional origin feed barley, 20,000 tonnes Australian feed barley and 20,000 tonnes Australian two-row barley.</p>
<p>Shipment period for all commodities is slated for November 11-December 10 except for the Australian prime hard wheat, which is set for October 11-November 10.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - A total of about 150,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat tainted by a fungus known as TCK smut is sitting in ships off the Chinese ports of Shanghai and Fuzhou, an official of the U.S. Agricultural Trade Office said. The ships arrived in August and the U.S. has sent scientific experts to look into the problem, he said.</p>
<p>... Southeast Asian corn prices were steady to easier this week with high stocks, ample imports and pressure from domestic harvest supplies keeping a lid on the market, regional traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In Malaysia, both corn and wheat prices were quoted lower as feedmillers, farm owners and flour companies were comfortable with adequate stocks in their silos and waiting to pick up bargains, local traders said.</p>
<p>--Doris Frankel 312-983-7305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
