<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32132" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot resid prices steady on firm paper values.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot resid prices steady on firm paper values.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot residual fuel oil prices ended steady to higher Wednesday, supported by firmness in the paper market, brokers and traders said.</p>
<p>The forwards and physical resid values, which were at parity, held their gains from Tuesday despite weaker crude and natural prices, industry sources said.</p>
<p>NYMEX October crude futures finished down 16 cents at $23.24 a barrel after surging more than a dollar Tuesday due to escalating tension between U.S. and Iraq, which resulted a number of attacks on Iraqi military installation since this past weekend.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, NYMEX October Henry Hub natural gas futures settled down 5.7 cents at $1.764 per million British thermal units on softer cash prices.</p>
<p>In the New York harbor, September one percent sulphur paper prices closed at $17.40-$17.60 a barrel, compared with $17.25-$17.55 earlier today.</p>
<p>In the Gulf Coast paper market, October three percent values finished at $15.50-$15.75 with several confirmed trades reported at $15.50. compared with $15.40-$15.60 earlier today.</p>
<p>No physical trade was heard reported.</p>
<p>&quot;There's little interest from end-users,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>New York city gate September gas prices were assessed at $2.05 today, versus NYH one percent resid at a $2.77/mmBtu equivalent.</p>
<p>Separately, a number of resid players were absent from the market because of an industry event in Connecticut.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk 212-859-1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
