<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32150" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Southeast utilities brace for Hurricane Fran.</title>
<headline>Southeast utilities brace for Hurricane Fran.</headline>
<byline>James Jelter</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Utilities on the Southeast Atlantic coast said Wednesday they were scurrying to secure their power plants and position emergency crews as they prepare for Hurricane Fran.</p>
<p>South Carolina Electric &amp; Gas Co. is the utility most directly in the latest projected path of the storm.</p>
<p>&quot;Fran is headed for the coast north of Savannah and south of Charleston. That's pretty much the heart of our service territory,&quot; said company spokesman Roger Schrumm.</p>
<p>Meteorologists are predicting Fran, now a Category three hurricane with winds of 115 miles per hour, will smash into the South Carolina coast late Thursday or early Friday.</p>
<p>SCE&amp;G serves about 500,000 electricity and 250,000 natural gas customers, or about 2.3 million residents, in the southern and south-central parts of the state.</p>
<p>The company's overall generation capacity is about 4,300 megawatts, including its 960 MW Summer nuclear power plant in Parr, S.C., and six large coal-fired plants.</p>
<p>&quot;We only have one coal plant really exposed to the storm, the Williams station on Charleston Harbour,&quot; said Schrumm.</p>
<p>He said the 600 MW plant likely would be shut ahead of the storm if it continues to press on toward the Charleston area.</p>
<p>&quot;Our nuclear power plant is well inland, about 60 miles north of Columbia, and should be out of harm's way. Our main concern is the transmission lines. If they are lost, you're generating power without anywhere to send your load,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Several of SCE&amp;G's big coal-fired units were damaged, though none significantly, during Hurricane Hugo in September, 1989, the last major storm to clobber the state.</p>
<p>SCE&amp;G, a unit of SCANA Corp., sustained about $53 million in damages -- mostly to its transmission system -- when Hugo hit Charleston.</p>
<p>Hugo racked up $7 billion in overall damages, making it the second-costliest storm in U.S. history.</p>
<p>It also prompted the state's public service commission to grant SCE&amp;G's request for a storm damage fund, which allows the utility to raise rates to customers without further approval to cover storm damages exceeding $2.5 million a year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a rather unique arrangement among U.S. utilities, but it reflects the conditions in which we operate,&quot; said Schrumm.</p>
<p>Savannah Electric &amp; Power Co., based just across the border in neighbouring Georgia and at the southern reaches of Fran's anticipated landfall, said it, too, was taking all necessary hurricane precautions.</p>
<p>&quot;We've put our emergency response plan into place ... We're in the best possible shape we could be in,&quot; said company spokeswoman Swann Brannon. &quot;Of course, we'd like to see a different set of coordinates for the storm.&quot;</p>
<p>Savannah Electric, a subsidiary of the Southern Co., serves about 120,000 customers, or 250,000 residents, in the southeast corner of Georgia.</p>
<p>Brannon said they were expecting gale force winds and heavy rain to hit their area by Thursday mid-morning.</p>
<p>Citing experiences from Hugo, she said most of the utility's customers had power restored within two to three days, but added: &quot;If there's significant damage to peoples' homes, there's no point restoring their power.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
