<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32153" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kellogg Q3, full-year results to be down.</title>
<headline>Kellogg Q3, full-year results to be down.</headline>
<dateline>BATTLE CREEK, Mich. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kellogg Co said Wednesday that its decision to slash cereal prices will lower third quarter earnings by about 20 percent below the $1.05 a share it earned a year ago, not including the impact of non-recurring events.</p>
<p>Kellogg said it expects earnings will return to growth in the fourth quarter. But full-year earnings will be less than the $3.48 a share it posted for all of 1995.  </p>
<p>Kellogg said it remains committed to its strategy of reducing inefficient promotion spending in the U.S. ready-to-eat cereal business, which it has done while also cutting cereal prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to believe this is the best long-term strategy to deliver more value for consumers, promote category growth and achieve superior returns for Kellogg stockholders,&quot; Arnold Langbo, chairman and chief executive officer, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to direct our efforts away from deep price promotion; however, we are unwilling to see our leadership position compromised,&quot; Langbo said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our fourth quarter results will be influenced significantly by competitive conditions in the category at that time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts have been questioning whether the cereal giant could hit the $3.48 figure of a year ago. Kellogg said in late July that it expected 1996 earnings to be about the same as 1995, excluding charges.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BATTLE CREEK, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
