<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32151" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole campaigns in crucial Midwest states.</title>
<headline>Dole campaigns in crucial Midwest states.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>MADISON, Wisc. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole campaigned in the battlegrounds of U.S. politics on Wednesday, taking his tax-cutting pitch to four heartland states where elections often are won or lost.</p>
<p>On a whirlwind day on the stump, Dole took his standard sermon of slashing taxes and government bureaucracy to Iowa, Wisconsin, Michigan and Ohio. The Republican candidate, who lags President Bill Clinton by double digits in opinion polls, sought to increase his allure in both Iowa and Wisconsin by appearing with their popular Republican governors at his side.</p>
<p>He also pushed his proposal to cut tax rates by 15 percent in a new television spot, saying people &quot;shouldn't have to apologise&quot; for wanting to keep what they earn and criticising Clinton's 1993 tax increase as &quot;the largest&quot; in history.</p>
<p>In Wisconsin, Dole told a rally Clinton had not delivered on his 1992 campaign promise of a middle class tax cut. &quot;Everybody who got that middle class tax cut ought to vote for Bill Clinton,&quot; Dole told several hundred cheering supporters at an airport outside Madison. &quot;Nobody got it in Wisconsin.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole was to turn his attention later on Wednesday to Michigan, the bellwether of U.S. politics that has voted for the winner in the past three presidential elections, and then travel to Ohio. They are among the small group of &quot;swing&quot; states in the country that historically have tended to determine the outcome of presidential elections.</p>
<p>If Dole's decision to focus on this critical region was obvious, his tactics were not. On this three-and-a-half day campaign swing, he spent his first night in Utah, which has just five electoral college votes, and his second in Iowa, with just seven.</p>
<p>He was scheduled to spend only the final 24 hours in the three key states of  Wisconsin, Michigan and Ohio, which among them have 50 of the 538 electoral college votes that actually elect the president.</p>
<p>In contrast, Clinton spent parts of three days in Ohio on his train trip to the Democratic convention in Chicago last week and he visited Missouri, Illinois, Kentucky and Tennessee on his bus trip afterwards.</p>
<p>The president, a native of Arkansas, also departed from tradition and chose the Ohio delegation to cast the critical votes that formally gave him the Democratic nomination for president at the Chicago convention.</p>
<p>After a three-hour stop in Dearborn, Michigan, later on Wednesday to hold his second &quot;Listening to America&quot; roundtable of the day, Dole was scheduled to spent the night in Dayton, Ohio. He was expected to campaign in two Ohio cities on Thursday before returning to Washington in the afternoon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADISON, Wisc."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
