<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32155" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Iraq crisis boosts Clinton, overshadows Dole.</title>
<headline>Iraq crisis boosts Clinton, overshadows Dole.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>The Iraqi crisis on Wednesday again dominated the U.S. airwaves, boosting President Bill Clinton and obliterating the campaign efforts of Republican Bob Dole.</p>
<p>An ABC poll taken before Wednesday's second round of U.S. missile attacks on Iraqi targets showed that 79 percent of respondents approved Clinton's action, although 39 percent said it was too weak.</p>
<p>Another pollster conducting a survey since Monday said Clinton, who already leads Dole by a wide margin, had received an additional boost from the air attacks. Support for the president had picked up significantly since Tuesday, he said.</p>
<p>Pollsters call this the &quot;rally effect&quot; that typically gives presidents a short-term boost following military action. Clinton's challenge now is to bring the affair to a swift and satisfactory conclusion.</p>
<p>More seriously for Dole, the Iraqi standoff made it even harder for him to gain voters' attention as he campaigned in the Midwest on Wednesday. The Republican nominee, who initially attacked Clinton's &quot;weak leadership,&quot; was forced on Tuesday to fall into line with general support of U.S. military personnel.</p>
<p>Dole's vice presidential running mate Jack Kemp on Wednesday urged support for the military operation. &quot;All of us, irrespective of political party, should share in support of the goals of this mission with our prayers, our hearts and our minds,&quot; Kemp told about 1,000 workers at a uniform manufacturing plant in the Cincinnati suburbs.</p>
<p>Dole himself spent the day in the battleground states of Iowa, Wisconsin, Michigan and Ohio where he served up his standard message of slashing taxes and government bureaucracy.</p>
<p>In Wisconsin, he accused Clinton of breaking his 1992 campaign promise of a middle class tax cut. &quot;Everybody who got that middle class tax cut ought to vote for Bill Clinton,&quot; he told a cheering, lunchtime rally of several hundred supporters at an airport outside Madison. &quot;Nobody got it in Wisconsin.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole's campaign also unveiled a new television ad pushing his tax-cut plan, saying Americans &quot;shouldn't have to apologise&quot; for wanting to keep their money.</p>
<p>The spot, which will be broadcast in 17 states, said Clinton had approved the biggest tax hike in history. It opens with an announcer's voice criticising the Clinton administration: &quot;Stagnant wages. The largest tax increase in history. Two incomes needed to make ends meet. Americans deserve better.&quot;</p>
<p>Republicans, not seeming to want to criticise the nation's military, took subtle swipes at Clinton's leadership.</p>
<p>&quot;I of course support the president when he takes military action as all Americans do and should,&quot; said Arizona Sen. John McCain, a key Dole adviser on military affairs.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm curious what plan B might be if this does not have the desired effect ... It's unfortunate that they didn't take the time or effort to get the coalition together again, both our European allies as well as our friends in the region,&quot; McCain added.</p>
<p>Republican House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich said it was noticeable that many of the allies who supported the United States in the 1991 Gulf War against Iraq were not supporting Washington now.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Texas billionaire Ross Perot, running on the ticket of the Reform Party he created, said the United States had failed to complete its mission in Iraq in the Gulf War.</p>
<p>Perot, whose support has dropped to around five percent in some recent polls, told a convention of U.S. war veterans: &quot;If I am elected president we will never have to fight a war to satisfy a soundbite. If we start it we will finish it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
