<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32162" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: What did Ford give to be the UAW's target?</title>
<headline>What did Ford give to be the UAW's target?</headline>
<byline>Todd Nissen</byline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co.'s long-shot bid to sit down first with the United Auto Workers union paid off, but analysts wondered Wednesday what the automaker had to give up in exchange for being the Big Three's lead-off negotiator.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone wants to be first, and that's obviously a plus for Ford in that regard,&quot; said J.P. Morgan analyst David Bradley. &quot;The question is, 'What price did they have to pay to be first?'&quot;</p>
<p>The UAW told Ford executives Tuesday it had selected the company to be the first of Detroit's Big Three automakers to hammer out a new labour contract.</p>
<p>Union officials stopped short of referring to Ford as its traditional &quot;strike target.&quot; In the past, the UAW has selected one of the Big Three to start serious bargaining about two weeks before the contract expires.</p>
<p>Automakers prefer to be the target because they can dictate some of the contract terms, even though they run the risk of a strike. Ford, which was also the target in 1993, did just that. Expecting to hire thousands of new workers, it negotiated a &quot;grow-in&quot; provision allowing it to pay new hires at 70 percent of the full rate. Ford has brought on more than 20,000 new hourly workers in three years.</p>
<p>Since January, analysts and other auto industry observers believed Chrysler Corp. would be the target because it outsources more work than its domestic competitiors and might be willing to cut back. Outsourcing -- the practice of contracting parts work to outside suppliers -- is a key job security issue for the UAW this year.</p>
<p>Both union and Ford officials declined to comment on the UAW's decision to go with Ford.</p>
<p>Despite the coup of beating out General Motors Corp. and Chrysler, the company issued a mild statement saying it is &quot;encouraged&quot; by the tone of the talks.</p>
<p>In picking Ford, which employs about 104,000 UAW members, the union starts with a company that is recognised as having the best labour relations among Detroit's Big Three. The UAW last struck a Ford plant in 1986.</p>
<p>Analysts said Ford's relative labour peace has given it better work rules and allows it more flexibility to use overtime to increase production. It also has spared the company costly strikes such as those that have hit GM and Chrysler.</p>
<p>The downside, according to Wall Street analysts, is that Ford has not been as aggressive on farming out work to less-expensive outside suppliers.</p>
<p>Although no one knows what company and union officials hashed out in private, analysts speculated Ford may have expressed some willingness to spur union organising efforts among its suppliers. That would address job security issues that are crucial as the UAW faces a shrinking membership base.</p>
<p>In return, the union may have agreed to consider a contract that spans more than the traditional three years.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (Ford) would love to have a five- or six-year agreement,&quot; said Michael Ward, an analyst at PaineWebber Inc. &quot;It strengthens Ford's position with the UAW.&quot;</p>
<p>A big unknown is how far Ford was willing to be flexible on limiting the number of components it buys from outside suppliers, which often have non-union work forces.</p>
<p>James Harbour, president of Troy, Mich.-based industry consultant Harbour and Associates Inc., said Ford does not have the breadth of engineering talent to bring large numbers of parts in-house.</p>
<p>&quot;I think probably the biggest thing they could give them is to say 'We'll work with suppliers and ask them to join the union,'&quot; said Harbour. &quot;Membership is the issue this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Not being the lead-off company has in the past been bad news for the two automakers not selected because of the pattern style of bargaining that imposed terms on them.</p>
<p>But analysts said that is not necessarily the case this time. Unlike prior years, when talks are put on hold at the non-target companies, negotiations are continuing with GM and Chrysler, officials said Wednesday. There are also signs the traditional pattern process is no longer as firm as it used to be.</p>
<p>Bradley noted that by holding out, GM, which is taking a hard stance against outsourcing limitations, has not lost any negotiating power.</p>
<p>&quot;For now, GM is powder-dry. They haven't given up any leverage, which they would have had to do to be first,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
