<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32169" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans end down on FCC estimate, technicals.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans end down on FCC estimate, technicals.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed sharply lower on the bearish influence of a private crop estimate plus follow-through technical selling, traders said.</p>
<p>The soybean market was dropping in late trading Tuesday and spillover selling surfaced Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;FCC set the tone and we continued on that all day,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>Iowa-based Farmers Commodities Corp late Tuesday predicted the U.S. soybean crop would total 2.276 billion bushels, up slightly from FCC's previous outlook for 2.271 billion. USDA's August forecast for U.S. soybean production was 2.3 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a reality check today for the market from FCC,&quot; Lespinasse said.</p>
<p>&quot;Outside of FCC's numbers there wasn't much to trade on. The market was comfortable selling rallies all day,&quot; said Mark Cermak of O'Connor and Co. &quot;Once we broke $7.85, a strong technical area, we couldn't get back over it.&quot;</p>
<p>Also on Wednesday morning, Allendale Inc/Data Transmission Network pegged the U.S. soy crop at 2.090 billion bushels.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed five to 15-1/4 cents per bushel lower, with September down 13-1/4 at $7.97-3/4 and November down 15-1/4 at $7.80-1/4.</p>
<p>Traders said weather remained conducive for crops and pointed to potential rainfall in the eastern growing region as bearish to prices. Hurricane Fran could bring showers into the eastern portions of the soy region.</p>
<p>There was an undercurrent of concern about potential cold weather soon. Meteorologists early Wednesday said cooler weather was expected in the Midwest by Saturday but they differed on how low temperatures would fall.</p>
<p>Joel Burgio, meteorologist with Weather Services Corp said low temperatures on Monday and Tuesday would be in the upper 30s (degrees Farenheit) to low 40s F in the northwest portion of the belt. But Smith Barney meteorologists Basilio Lopez predicted lows in the 50s F and highs in the 70s.</p>
<p>Refco Inc sold seven to eight million bushels of November on the day and LIT America was a late seller of three million November, traders said. The LIT selling plus late local selling drove the market to the day's lows by the close.</p>
<p>Soybean futures volume was estimated at 50,000, up from 44,487 Tuesday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>Soybean options volume was estimated at 22,000, up from 20,7444 Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
