<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32174" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Iraq crisis may cause pain for U.S. consumers.</title>
<headline>Iraq crisis may cause pain for U.S. consumers.</headline>
<byline>Tony McAuley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington's latest confrontation with Baghdad, if it lasts or escalates, may cause pain for consumers in the form of higher gasoline and heating oil prices, analysts and consumer groups said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The U.S. retaliation against Iraq for the weekend blitz on protected Kurdish zones in the north of the Iraq pushed U.S. oil prices up by as much as $2 a barrel.</p>
<p>The oil price spike, in turn, added strength to an already steamy heating oil market and could lead to a reversal in the decline in recent months in retail gasoline prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Gas prices were well on their way to coming back to normal levels before we had this Mideast situation,&quot; said Michael Morrissey, spokesman for the American Automobile Association.</p>
<p>Since hitting a post-Gulf War high of $1.30 a gallon in the spring, the national average price of regular self-serve gas was down to $1.25 just before the Labour Day weekend. Though that was about 7.5 cents a gallon higher than at the same time last year, Morrissey said prices were expected to come down folloing the holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are watching the price situation very closely. What happens with the crisis in the Middle East will determine whether there are any sort of increases in retail prices,&quot; Morrissey said. &quot;Crude prices generally take about a month to show up at the retail pump.&quot;</p>
<p>In the meantime, &quot;We would urge motorists, if they do see increases, to look around and shop at another station,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the situation lasts for a month we might have some price spikes, especially on heating oil as stocks are very low,&quot; said Paulo Nery, an oil industry analyst at Pace Consultants.</p>
<p>Indeed, the heating oil market is much more vulnerable in the current situation because inventories are lean ahead of the coming winter heating season.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been extremely sensitive in the last few days and it hurts,&quot; said Jack Sullivan, chief executive of the New England Fuel Institute, which represents about 1,400 suppliers to retail consumers in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Two things are creating problems for consumers right now: What is going to happen in Iraq and the current inventory levels,&quot; said Sullivan.</p>
<p>With heating oil stocks in the Northeastern market at about half last year's levels, consumers are vulnerable to sharp increases in prices caused by cold-weather demand surges and crises such as the current one in Iraq.</p>
<p>The tight stocks situation already had pushed heating oil futures prices up over the past two months by about 25 percent to as high as 67.50 cents a gallon on Tuesday, the highest level for this time of year since 1991.</p>
<p>The most vulnerable consumers are those that have duel-fuel capacity to switch between natural gas and heating oil, Sullivan noted. Those consumers, accounting for about 15 percent of the New England market, must switch to heating oil below certain temperature threshholds.</p>
<p>But despite the worries, most analysts expect the effect of the Iraqi situation to be shortlived.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this is going to be longlasting, and Saudi Arabia and Venezuela can easily jump in to fill the gap,&quot; said Pace Consultants' Nery.</p>
<p>&quot;I am concerned. But I have seen it before and I am not ready to say there is any panic right now,&quot; said the New England Fuel Institute's Sullivan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
