<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32183" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Perot says U.S. never finished job in Iraq.</title>
<headline>Perot says U.S. never finished job in Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Julianne Basinger</byline>
<dateline>SALT LAKE CITY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Billionaire Ross Perot, campaigning for president under the Reform Party banner, said on Wednesday the United States had failed to complete its mission in Iraq during the Gulf War.</p>
<p>&quot;We must learn from our past mistakes,&quot; Perot told a convention of U.S. war veterans. He told the group the United States had accomplished only one of its three objectives during the Gulf War when it restored Kuwait's sovereignty.</p>
<p>He said the United States failed both to destroy chemical weapons in Iraq and to overthrow President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>&quot;We forgot Winston Churchil's words. 'Never cozy up to tyrants,'&quot; he said referring to Saddam. &quot;If (Perot is) elected president we will never have to fight a war to satisfy a soundbite. If we start it we will finish it.&quot;</p>
<p>Perot's address to the veterans followed by a day a speech by Republican presidential nominee Bob Dole.</p>
<p>Perot won 19 percent of the popular vote in 1992 and was named the candidate of his fledgling Reform Party last month, but most recent polls showed him with less than 10 percent support this time around.</p>
<p>While he was careful not to criticize current U.S. efforts in Iraq while speaking to the veterans' group, he chided past actions in placing U.S. armed forces under United Nations command in Somalia and Bosnia.</p>
<p>In his folksy manner he asked the audience of about 8,000 whether U.S. forces should fight under U.N. commanders and received a resounding &quot;no.&quot;</p>
<p>Perot said if he were in the White House he would have two signs on his desk, one reading &quot;First commit the nation&quot; and the other &quot;Then commit the troops.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The president must always ask if I would send my son or daughter to fight for this cause,&quot; he told the group.</p>
<p>On economic issues, he cautioned against the United States farming its manufacturing to other countries. &quot;We have to be a manufacturing superpower to defend this country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the United States could not rely on Europe and East Asia for steel or the Middle East for oil or Puerto Rico, a U.S. territory, for medical drugs in times of war.</p>
<p>He told the audience he will have another infomercial on television on Sunday night to discuss how he would address U.S. economic problems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALT LAKE CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
