<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32184" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY senator denies seeking higher pay for officials.</title>
<headline>NY senator denies seeking higher pay for officials.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Senate Majority Leader Wednesday denied that he planned to seek pay increases for elected officials, from the governor to state legislators.</p>
<p>Joseph Bruno, R-Troy, was responding to an article in Wednesday's New York Post, which said he was weighing a bill to raise the salaries of the governor, the lieutenant governor, the comptroller and the attorney general.</p>
<p>While saying such pay increases were &quot;justified,&quot; Bruno said the article gave a mistaken impression that he was pressing for such raises, according to a prepared statement.</p>
<p>The governor, George Pataki, now is paid $130,000, which is less than a number of New York City officials, including Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, who earns $165,000 a year, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>Further, Bruno dismissed suggestions that the legislators, whose pay last was increased in 1989, were due for a raise. &quot;As far as legislative pay raises, I have never supported, nor voted for legislative pay increases and I can see no scenario under which I would,&quot; the Senate Majority Leader said.</p>
<p>There had been speculation that after the November elections, the legislators might return for a special session, which would take up the issue.</p>
<p>While Gov. George Pataki in August said he might call for a special session to grapple with the heavy costs the state expects to incur as a result of the new federal welfare reforms, little has been heard since then.</p>
<p>Spokesmen for Pataki and the House Leader, Sheldon Silver, D-Manhattan, were not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>Other issues a special session might consider could include New York City's plan for a new infrastructure authority, an industry source said.</p>
<p>But the source, who requested anonymity, added it was more likely that the legislature would address this issue in the spring of 1997, when the city will be closer to hitting its constitutional limit on debt. The new infrastructure authority is seen as a way to sidestep this debt ceiling.</p>
<p>Legislators now earn a &quot;base salary&quot; of $57,500 a year, as well as additional sums for extra work, the New York Post said. The last raise they received was approved by a lame duck legislature, legislative sources recalled.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
