<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32205" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif water officials unveil $4-$8 bln Delta plans.</title>
<headline>Calif water officials unveil $4-$8 bln Delta plans.</headline>
<dateline>SACRAMENTO, Calif. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>California state and federal water officials have settled on options to improve the hub of California's water distribution system at a cost of between $4 billion and $8 billion, officials said Wednesday.</p>
<p>A portion of the funding could come from a $1 billion water bond that will appear on the November state ballot.</p>
<p>Other funding options were under review, said the Calfed Bay-Delta program, which announced the options to protect and manage California's Bay-Delta. &quot;We are still just starting to work on the financing plan,&quot; said Mary Kelley, spokeswoman for the program. &quot;We are looking at a variety of funding sources.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Bay-Delta is the 738,000-acre region where the San Francisco Bay meets the Sacramento-San Joaquin River Delta. It supplies drinking water for 20 million people in northern, central and southern California, irrigates four million acres of farmland and supports at least 120 wildlife species.</p>
<p>The options call for extensive habitat restoration, widespread water conservation and reclamation, and measures to protect water quality and stabilize levees.</p>
<p>The first option would use existing Delta channels, while the second proposal calls for significant improvements to the existing system of channels.  </p>
<p>The third option calls for improvements to channels as well as for construction of a new water conveyance facility.</p>
<p>The cost of the improvements would run from $4 billion to $8 billion, Kelley said.</p>
<p>In the summer of 1997, Kelley said the Calfed Bay-Delta Program was expected to recommend one of the options and release a draft environmental impact report for the water project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SACRAMENTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
