<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32208" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends slightly lower.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends slightly lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures ended slightly lower Wednesday, correcting from 18 month highs seen Tuesday on a breakout of a two-month old range.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's action was just a reaction on light volumes to yesterday's sharp gains, though the market remains nervous, after rumors Egypt bought 60,000 tonnes yesterday, in addition to its tender for white sugar today,&quot; Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka said.</p>
<p>CSCE October sugar, which expires September 30, ended off 0.06 cent at 12.12 cents a lb, after trading in a narrow range of 12.02-12.15.</p>
<p>The London white sugar market also slipped back, on position squaring ahead of the expiry of the October London contract on September 13, traders said.</p>
<p>There was also some disappointment with the small tonnage award in the European Union's export licences award, traders said. The EU awarded only 250 tonnes in its weekly export licences tender, after 16,000 tonnes last week.</p>
<p>The backwardation in the CSCE October/March spread widened further to 0.47 cent from 0.45 cent Tuesday and 0.35 cent at Friday's close.  </p>
<p>&quot;We saw some selling (in CSCE world sugar) as producers took advantage of the sharply higher prices seen Tuesday and some selling by funds rolling long positions into March,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we expect 12.00 cents, basis October, to hold as support on scale down trade buying,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures ended sharply higher Tuesday, seeing the highest levels for the October contract since January 1995, after a breakout of a six week 11.40-12.00 cent a lb range.</p>
<p>With the approach of the October futures expiration on September 30, attention will once again focus on the loading pace at the Brazilian port of Santos, where logistical problems have frequently come to the aid of bullish traders, one analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Clive McKeef, New York Commodity Desk +1-212-859-1641</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
