<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32219" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME lumber ends with limit gains on strong cash.</title>
<headline>CME lumber ends with limit gains on strong cash.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME lumber futures closed with limit gains of $10.00 per tbf in the November as well as in January 1997 and March 1997 contracts, in reaction to strong demand for cash lumber, traders said.</p>
<p>Random Lengths quoted cash spruce at $419 per tbf Wednesday, up from $414 Friday and $412 a week ago. Analysts said lumber retailers let inventories run low this summer in anticipation lumber prices would decline. Instead prices rose and now in order to satisfy strong demand from home builders, retailers are forced to pay higher offering prices by sawmills</p>
<p>Active transferring of long CME September positions to November gave an added boost to the latter contract. The September contract expires September 13 and open intereset needs to be pared down. At Tuesday's close, September's open interest was 2,325 contracts and analysts said it should be about 800.</p>
<p>The tranferring out of September into November should narrow the latter's discount. At the close, November lumber settled up $10.00 at $388.30 per tbf compared with the September settlement price, which was up $6.50 at $429.30.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
