<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32211" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMR sees British Air alliance delay.</title>
<headline>AMR sees British Air alliance delay.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>American Airlines, a unit of AMR Corp, said on Wednesday that a delay was likely in implementing its alliance with British Airways PLC. due to problems in reaching a new U.S.-British air agreement.</p>
<p>The two carriers announced earlier this year they wanted to implement their alliance by next April, planning that an agreement in bilateral talks on a new free-market air agreement could be reached by this fall.  </p>
<p>But American Air vice president of government affairs Will Ris told a news conference the delay in reaching a bilateral agreement would most likely hold up implementing the alliance, although both sides remained fully commited to it.</p>
<p>He said that to implement the alliance, the carriers needed U.S. Transportation Department approval for immunity from U.S. antitrust law, and the department has said immunity would not be given unless a free-maket air pact were first in place.  </p>
<p>Separately, American Airlines said a national survey of U.S. international travelers showed overwhelming support for an &quot;open skies&quot; agreement between the U.S. and Britain as well as for its own global alliance with British Airways.</p>
<p>The Fort Worth-based airline said in a statement that 82 percent of travelers surveyed found an open skies agreement with Britain to be a &quot;good idea&quot; and 83 percent backed American's proposed alliance with British Airways.</p>
<p>It said 69 percent said the alliance would help them in making international travel plans.  </p>
<p>The telephone survey of 839 passengers was carried out between August 16 and August 20 by Peter D. Hart Research and Wirthlin Worldwide, it said.</p>
<p>The United States last week called off open skies aviation talks with Britain, saying the two sides were too far apart on key issues for productive talks, but a Transportation Department official said Wednesday that the U.S. government was again ready to resume talks, although an accord might be reached with France first.</p>
<p>Britain has balked at opening London Heathrow airport, the base of British Airways, to more flights by U.S. carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;This survey clearly demonstrates how important a U.S.-U.K. open skies agreement and the American-BA alliance is to international travelers,&quot; Will Ris, Vice President of Government Affairs for American Airlines, said in a statement released with the survey results.</p>
<p>The poll had a margin of error of 3.7 percent, the airline said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
