<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32221" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends weaker, but support holds.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends weaker, but support holds.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended slightly lower Wednesday, pressured by light fund liquidation and commission house selling, traders said.</p>
<p>But trade buying emerged at the lows, limiting losses and keeping the benchmark December contract well above key support at 110.00 cents a lb, dealers said.</p>
<p>December coffee ended down 0.50 cent a lb, to 112.80 cents, after ranging between 114.00 and 111.30. Spot September ended 0.85 cent lower, at 124.20, while the remaining months finished 0.70 to 0.75 weaker.</p>
<p>The market took a downturn at the open on follow-through fund liquidation, traders said. Fund liquidation on Tuesday drove prices down sharply after the CFTC Commitment of Traders report released Friday showed a sharp increase in non-commercial long positions.</p>
<p>&quot;The funds are still long,&quot; one trader said. &quot;They liquidated some, but from what I see they still have a way to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Technically, traders said after 110.00 cents, December's next level of support would be near 106.00-105.00 cents. Resistance was seen at 114.50 cents, followed by 116.00 cents.  </p>
<p>The CSCE reported after Tuesday's close that U.S. certified coffee stocks in the week ended August 30 rose 2,250 60-kg bags, to 41,563 60-kg bags.</p>
<p>But while September's open interest continued to decline, it remained relatively high Tuesday at 1,116 lots, or the equivalent of about 317,045 60-kg bags of coffee. Since September entered notice period August 22, a total of six delivery notices have been issued.</p>
<p>Volume reached an estimated 6,900 lots.</p>
<p>-Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
