<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32237" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas eases with moderate temperatures.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas eases with moderate temperatures.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. September spot natgas prices were steady to slightly softer Wednesday as Hurricane Fran posed no threat to the Gulf Coast and temperatures were near normal throughout most of the U.S., sources said.</p>
<p>Swing prices on the U.S. Gulf Coast pipes began this morning's trading on Transco (Station 65) in the low-$1.70s, down about 10 cents from Tuesday's early prices.</p>
<p>This followed with trading on most of the Gulf pipes in the mid-to-high $1.60s, down about three cents from Tuesday. Traders said there was some late buying interest minutes before nomination deadlines that pushed prices to about $1.70.  </p>
<p>At the New York city-gate, prices were stable in the $2.08-2.12 range as temperatures in the Northeast hovered a couple of degrees Fahrenheit above normal.</p>
<p>Forecasters said Fran, with maximum winds of 115 mph, is expected to crash along the Georgia or South Carolina coast late Thursday.</p>
<p>Swing prices in the Midcontinent were flat to slightly weaker in the mid-to-high $1.50s as forecasters called for more moderate temperatures by Saturday.</p>
<p>In the Permian basin, prices ranged anywhere from the low-$1.60s early to the high-$1.40s late. Most deals were getting done in the mid-$1.50s, which is fairly steady from Tuesday.</p>
<p>The differential to Waha narrowed to about four or five cents as traders reported closing deals in the high-$1.50s to low-$1.60s.</p>
<p>Similarly at the southern California border, prices were steady to slightly softer in the $1.65-1.70 range in anticipation of cooler weather along the West Coast.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
