<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32238" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oregon prepares for first execution in 34 years.</title>
<headline>Oregon prepares for first execution in 34 years.</headline>
<byline>Gisele Lamarre</byline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Ore. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oregon is to execute its first inmate in 34 years shortly after midnight on Friday, marking the latest step in the state's history of alternately embracing and then rejecting capital punishment.</p>
<p>Douglas Wright is scheduled to die by lethal injection for the execution-style 1991 killings of three homeless men, whom he lured into the wilderness with promises of construction work. Wright, who also served time for a double murder in the 1970s, has waived further appeals, saying he has had homicidal tendencies since he was a boy and deserves to die.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no doubt in my mind if you paroled me or released me today, I'd probably do well for a while, then I'd probably start killing people again,&quot; he told the Oregonian newspaper.</p>
<p>Democratic Gov. John Kitzhaber, although he is &quot;personally opposed&quot; to the death penalty, will not prevent the execution, spokesman Jon Coney said. &quot;The voters reinstated it, capital punishment is in the constitution and he took an oath to uphold that constitution. He will abide by that oath and not intervene.&quot;</p>
<p>The only thing that could keep Wright, 56, from becoming the 59th man executed in Oregon since 1903 is appeals filed over his objections, one by the American Civil Liberties Union that will be heard on Wednesday by the state Supreme Court.</p>
<p>David Fidanque, executive director of the ACLU of Oregon, said a prisoner cannot waive his right to appeal in a death penalty case.</p>
<p>&quot;Douglas Wright doesn't feel like spending life in prison,&quot; he said. &quot;So what? When did we start giving convicted murderers the choice of punishment? We have to make sure there haven't been major mistakes made in his case.&quot;</p>
<p>Oregon's collective ambivalence toward capital punishment is unique. It has repealed the death penalty twice by popular vote and brought it back three times the same way.</p>
<p>When the state adopted the death penalty in 1864, county sheriffs had the authority to carry out executions. To restrict public attendance, lawmakers eventually centralized executions at the Oregon State Penitentiary.</p>
<p>After 24 men were hanged there, Oregonians had their first change of heart and in 1914 narrowly repealed the death penalty. It came back in 1920, lasting until 1964 when a vote threw it out again.</p>
<p>In 1978 voters reinstated it again and most experts believe that if a vote were held now it would still have the backing of at least two-thirds of voters.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be a reaction after this first one,&quot; David Schuman, a law professor at the University of Oregon, said. &quot;But people will become accustomed to it as more are carried out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
