<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32247" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton not getting world backing on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Clinton not getting world backing on Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton hopes his showdown with Iraq will demonstrate his foreign policy skills, but so far it has underscored his inability to piece together the kind of world support his predecessor George Bush enjoyed.</p>
<p>Although Republicans generally have been cautious in their reaction to the missile strikes on Iraq ordered by Clinton, House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich publicly raised questions on Wednesday about the administration's failure to generate broad-based support for the unilateral U.S. military action.</p>
<p>&quot;The contrast between Desert Storm and the current level of (allied) support is a concern,&quot; the Georgia Republican told reporters. Echoing the words of Republican presidential challenger Bob Dole, he said Congress would fully support American troops but made it clear that backing for the president would not be automatic.</p>
<p>Back in 1990, then-President Bush used his powers of persuasion to put together a coalition that seemed impossible, uniting most of the Arab world with Israel and much of Europe and Asia to drive Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein's forces from Kuwait.</p>
<p>Bush, whose career was steeped in diplomacy as well as politics, made personal appeals to world leaders to stand with the United States. He worked the telephone.</p>
<p>Clinton, who four years ago ousted Bush in a campaign that made scant mention of foreign policy as an issue, comes from a different background. Politics was his life as governor of Arkansas and has consumed much of his attention in Washington.</p>
<p>In the latest showdown with Iraq -- the most violent clash since the Gulf War -- Clinton too has made personal telephone calls to world leaders. But thus far only British Prime Minister John Major has embraced the U.S. actions with any public enthusiasm. The French have distanced themselves from the American strikes and the Russians have been critical, as have the Chinese and many Arab leaders.</p>
<p>In Brussels, the European Union postponed issuing a joint statement on the U.S. attacks on Iraq, underlining the division in Europe over the American action. Diplomats said Britain had pushed for a strong statement of support for the missile strikes but that others, notably France, resisted.</p>
<p>EU statements on matters of foreign policy are normally routine. They are supposed to reflect the 15-nation bloc's common foreign and security policy.</p>
<p>In a rare public sign of the rift the U.S. action has generated, the French went so far as to challenge Washington's freeze on a U.N. plan to permit the sale of oil by Baghdad. It called for new negotiations to ensure that a U.N. resolution allowing Iraq to use the proceeds of oil sales for food and medical supplies could come into force as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Much of the turmoil among U.S. allies stems from the fact that Clinton is in the midst of a re-election campaign that officials in many world capitals believe is driving the escalating pace of the latest showdown.</p>
<p>The military strikes have generated a positive reaction among most Americans, who during the Gulf War heard Bush describe the Iraqi leader with demonic terms. As in other times when a foreign crisis has surfaced, Americans generally rally around their president.</p>
<p>Republicans know that. Dole initially suggested that the &quot;weakness&quot; of Clinton's foreign policy led to the current confrontation, but now the Republican challenger talks respectfully of his love for America's men and women in uniform, a bond that goes back to his own service in the Second World War.</p>
<p>Politically risky questions are being left to Gingrich and others. &quot;We are supporting the American troops in the Middle East. We think it is important to be united in moments of international tension,&quot; Gingrich said.</p>
<p>Republican Sen. John McCain of Arizona, a prisoner of war in the Vietnam War in which Clinton avoided service, said a resolution would be brought before the Senate to address the need to build an international coalition to stand behind actions against the Iraqi leader.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
