<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32244" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Energy Dept needed for energy security - Curtis.</title>
<headline>US Energy Dept needed for energy security - Curtis.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States should keep its Energy Department as a tool to diversify the world's oil supply and increase energy security, an Energy Department official on Wednesday told a Senate panel considering a bill to kill the department.</p>
<p>Testifying before a Senate Energy subcommittee, Deputy Energy Secretary Charles Curtis said a U.S. cabinet-level official is essential to work with counterparts in Russia, the Caucases, the Caspian Sea and the Western Hemisphere to develop oil outside the Gulf.  </p>
<p>&quot;What really counts in determining the world energy balance is what happens in Russia, what happens in the Caspian Sea, the Caucasus and the Western Hemisphere. That's where the world's capacity to diversify its oil supply outside the Persian Gulf exists,&quot; Curtis said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's enormous potential, but to realize that potential requires major and high levels of government ministerial, secretrarial engagement because in Russia, in the Caucasus, in the Caspian, those energy markets are totally controlled by government,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The panel was holding a hearing on a bill to eliminate the Energy Department, and spin off many of its functions to the departments of Defense, Interior and Commerce, and to sell some assets such as the power marketing administrations and the Naval Petroleum Reserves.</p>
<p>Sen. Pete Domenici, a Republican from New Mexico, which has two major Energy Department national laboratories, said: &quot;This bill isn't going anywhere this year,&quot; and blasted the bill's plan to privatize some labs and have the Defense Department take over the nuclear weapons-oriented labs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Transferring the major functions that have to do with maintaining our nuclear stockpile to the Department of Defense would be a wrong thing to do,&quot; Domenici said, adding that narrowing the focus of the government labs just to nuclear weapons would drive off many of the best scientists.</p>
<p>Democrats on the panel also opposed the bill, which was sponsored by Sen. Rod Grams, a Minnesota Republican.</p>
<p>But Grams said the department &quot;has become a patchwork of government initiatives -- haphazardly stitched together, lacking any coherent theme, and tacked collectively into a single, unwieldy mass of bureaucracy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Grams said the bill would save $19-$23 billion in the first five years, and $5-$7 billion annually after that.</p>
<p>But opponents said costs merely would be reshuffled, and questioned whether there would be any savings.</p>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole also has called for eliminating the Energy Department, which he has said is wasteful and unnecessary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
