<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32254" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida aquarium sees worse losses in 2nd quarter.</title>
<headline>Florida aquarium sees worse losses in 2nd quarter.</headline>
<dateline>TAMPA, Fla. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Florida Aquarium suffered its worst losses yet in the quarter ended July 31, putting City of Tampa under added pressure to refinance the $84 million in bonds used to build the attraction.</p>
<p>The aquarium lost $2.3 million in the second quarter, more than half of the $4 million deficit incurred during its entire disappointing first year of operations, Tampa Tribune reported Wednesday.</p>
<p>Attendance was off 40 percent from last year and individual and corporate donations dropped to $511,286 during the quarter, a third the amount received during the same period last year.</p>
<p>The aquarium was forced to dip into reserves to make its $3.2 million debt service payment in May. It has another $3.2 million payment due Nov 1 but had only $12,818 in cash at the end of July.</p>
<p>Tampa is considering a bond refinancing that would reduce annual debt service by up to $800,000 a year but the plan is still being drafted, Tampa chief accountant Ron Ibarra said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Tampa bond issue was backed in part by a $10 million letter of credit from the Tampa Port Authority, which owns the land the aquarium was built on. Under the proposed refinancing, the city would take over the land and forgive the port of its $10 million obligation if the appraisers deem the facility worth at least $10 million.</p>
<p>Ibarra said city and port officials would meet with appraisers later this week to &quot;talk dollar values.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Either way, we're on the hook,&quot; Ibarra told Reuters. &quot;It's conduit financing but our name is on the bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year's attendance of just under 1 million fell nearly 50 percent below projections. Although public aquariums traditionally see attendance fall after the first year, Florida Aquarium officials budgeted for an increase to 1.2 million visitors.</p>
<p>Aquarium President John Racanelli told the Tampa Port Authority board last week that annual attendance could be as low as 750,000 if current trends continue.</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAMPA, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
