<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32260" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY Yankees pick Merrill as stadium adviser.</title>
<headline>NY Yankees pick Merrill as stadium adviser.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Yankees baseball team said Wednesday it chose Merrill Lynch &amp; Co Inc to help it analyze and develop financial strategies for &quot;various stadium options.&quot;</p>
<p>The owner of the baseball team, George Steinbrenner, has made it plain that he is disatisfied with the team's historic stadium in the Bronx Borough of New York City, saying the location cuts attendance.</p>
<p>While Merrill Lynch presumably will evaluate whether to modernize the current stadium or move the team to a new site that was proposed on the West Side of Manhattan, no details about what options will be considered were disclosed.</p>
<p>And the officials, who are expected to consider potential locations in New Jersey, also did not disclose a timeframe for their decision.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not a timetable at this point and we cannot be more specific,&quot; said a spokesman for David Sussman, the general counsel for the Yankees, when asked what specific locations would be considered.</p>
<p>&quot;We look forward to working with Merrill Lynch so that we will be in a position soon to address the complex financing issues associated with the project,&quot; Sussman said in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch has been involved in financing several stadiums, including renovations for the Gator Bowl in Jacksonville, Fla., as well as the Ice Palace in Tampa and the MCI Center infrastructure component in Washington.</p>
<p>The Yankees spokesman added that the selection of a financial adviser was not the first step in the team's efforts to improve its location, noting the team helped pay for an initial study of the issue.</p>
<p>New York City last week said it selected its own financial adviser, Public Financial Management, to help it develop plans for new or renovated stadiums for both the Yankees and the New York Mets, the city's other baseball team.</p>
<p>Proposals to build a new stadium for the Yankees on the West Side of Manhattan have proved controversial as a number of local officials have said they would fight such a plan because it would create too much congestion.</p>
<p>While New York City Mayor Rudolph Giuliani has said he would prefer to keep the Yankees in the Bronx, building the team a new stadium on the West Side of Manhattan was seen as preferable to having the team leave New York City.</p>
<p>Still, the mayor of Carlstadt, New Jersey, whose town evidently also was being considered as a possible new site, also has said he would fight such a move by the Yankees, saying the town already has enough development.</p>
<p>The Yankees have held first place in the American League Eastern Division almost all of the season. But because the team lost more than it won durung August, its lead over the second-place Baltomore Orioles shrunk to four games from 10 games when the month began.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
