<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32289" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US natgas stocks seen up 81-91 bcf in weekly AGAs.</title>
<headline>US natgas stocks seen up 81-91 bcf in weekly AGAs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. natural gas storage levels were expected to rise by 81 to 91 billion cubic feet (bcf) when weekly American Gas Association (AGA) data are released later today, industry sources said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Quite a bit of gas was put into storage because of the spreads we could get in and out of. I think the number should be even higher next Wednesday,&quot; said one trader, noting the Labor Day holiday weekend allowed for hefty injections.</p>
<p>Most opinions were fairly consistent this week as compared with previous weeks. Some traders called the report a non-factor at this point as the start of the winter heating season lurked on the horizon and storage inventories continued their steady climb.</p>
<p>The Reuter poll of industry players showed expectations for an overall build ranged from 75 bcf to 100 bcf for the week ended August 30. The four-week average is 84 bcf.</p>
<p>Last week, AGA showed overall stocks rose by 71 bcf, at the low end of expectations, but were still 390 bcf, or 16 percent, below the same year-ago period.</p>
<p>Last year at this time, stocks rose by 51 bcf.</p>
<p>Expectations for this week's build in the Consuming Region East were in the 50 bcf area versus 60 bcf the prior week. Last year at this time, eastern stocks rose by 49 bcf.</p>
<p>Last week, Consuming Region East stocks stood at 70 percent of capacity. The average weekly build in eastern stocks for the last four weeks was 64 bcf.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
