<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32288" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST - US August payrolls could tilt Fed to hike.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - US August payrolls could tilt Fed to hike.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Although no individual economic report can single-handedly push the Federal Reserve into action, economists believe the nervously-awaited August employment report may come close.</p>
<p>As evidence of healthy third quarter economic growth continues to mount, so have doubts about Fed forecasts for a second half slowdown.</p>
<p>The August non-farm payrolls report, due at 0830 EDT/1330 GMT on Friday, September 6, could decisively reinforce these doubts or shatter them completely, economists predict.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Fed is viewed as closer to tightening now than at any time this year,&quot; said Christopher Low, senior economist at HSBC Markets Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously this payroll figure is very important. If it were to come in on the low side the Fed could comfortably stay on hold through the September meeting, but if it comes in on the high side the pressure on the Fed would clearly intensify,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters are calling for a gain of 244,000 non-farm jobs in August compared to an advance of 193,000 in July.  </p>
<p>The average hourly earnings component of the report -- a key gauge of inflation pressures -- is expected to rise at a 0.3 percent pace, while the unemployment rate is seen edging down to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent in the previous month.</p>
<p>Forecasts call for the average workweek to rise 0.2 percentage points to 34.5 hours in August.</p>
<p>With wage inflation and economic capacity issues weighing heavily on the minds of Fed policymakers, market analysts said the hourly earnings and the jobless rate components will be key.  </p>
<p>In the June payrolls report, the unemployment rate sank to 5.3 percent, its lowest level since June of 1990, while average hourly earnings rose 0.8 percent, their largest monthly gain in the history of the report.</p>
<p>A move in the jobless rate back up to 5.4 percent and a 0.2 percent decline in hourly earnings in July sent reassuring signals, but clearly the jury is still out.</p>
<p>&quot;The labor inflation issue is very big so the unemployment rate and average hourly earnings data will be critical to watch,&quot; said Matthew Alexy, chief market strategist at CS First Boston.  </p>
<p>Alexy is expecting a steady unemployment rate of 5.4 percent and a 0.2 percent uptick in earnings -- numbers which would reassure policymakers.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's fear is for a stronger report, but we are not expecting the Fed to move rates this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>According to a Reuters poll conducted on Tuesday, a slim majority of U.S. economists expect the Fed to hike rates at its upcoming policy meeting on September 24.  </p>
<p>At this point, it appears that many within the Fed would prefer to wait until the November policy meeting, when a more complete picture of third quarter growth is available, before making a decision to tighten credit.</p>
<p>With the U.S. presidential election just two months away, economists also believe the Fed would prefer to avoid getting involved in the political fracas.</p>
<p>However, signals from the minutes of the Fed's July meeting suggest that other policymakers may already be leaning toward a tightening.</p>
<p>&quot;Dissension is probably too strong a word, but you clearly have an honest difference of opinion within the Fed,&quot; said Paul McCulley, chief economist at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>U.S. markets will be looking to the August payrolls report on Friday to settle these differences once and for all.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1673</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
