<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32283" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oregon Treasury will not collect investment fee.</title>
<headline>Oregon Treasury will not collect investment fee.</headline>
<dateline>PORTLAND, Ore. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oregon state Treasurer Jim Hill said Wednesday the Treasury would not collect investment fees from state and local government agencies for the remainder of 1996 and the first part of 1997.</p>
<p>Hill said savings from the management of state funds exceeded the projections the state Legislature used when it set the Treasury's budget in 1995. These savings will allow the state Treasury not to collect the investment fees, Hill said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Legislators told the state treasurer to manage the state's $32 billion investment portfolio for an annual fee of 0.03 percent of the portfolio's value.</p>
<p>&quot;We were able to perform our job for significantly less,&quot; Hill said.</p>
<p>Hill said the savings passed along to the Public Employees Retirement System alone would be about $500,000 a month. Other beneficiaries include all 800 participants in the Local Government Investment Pool, including cities, counties, and water and sewer districts, Hill said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTLAND, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
