<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32292" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sees France continuing in anti-Iraq coalition.</title>
<headline>U.S. sees France continuing in anti-Iraq coalition.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defence Secretary William Perry said on Wednesday he expects France to continue to participate in the allied coalition against Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>Asked if the allied coalition against Iraq was weakening, Perry said: &quot;I am confident the coalition is not weakening. If anythiny I think the coalition is strengthening and I fully expect the French to continue participation.&quot; He spoke to reporters at a joint appearance with visiting British Defence Minister Michael Portillo.  </p>
<p>France withheld support from President Bill Clinton's cruise missile raids on Iraq on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Paris also indicated it had not agreed in advance to Clinton's extension of the no-fly zone from the 32nd parallel to the 33rd parallel just south of Baghdad. The United States, Britain and France have policed the no-fly zone since a U.S.-led coalition drove Iraqi forces out of Kuwait in 1991.</p>
<p>Pentagon officials said earlier on Wednesday that French Mirage jets took part in the first day of patrols of the expanded no-fly exclusion zone in Iraq. But French government officials later said in Paris that the Mirages stayed below the 32nd parallel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
