<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32295" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CMS Energy project in India gets approval.</title>
<headline>CMS Energy project in India gets approval.</headline>
<dateline>DEARBORN, Mich. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CMS Energy Corp's independent power unit, CMS Generation Co, said Wednesday its G.V.K. Industries independent power generating project in India received the final major regulatory approval needed to complete international financing.</p>
<p>In addition, the plant's first gas-fueled turbine has begun generating electricity and entered commercial operation on August 6.</p>
<p>The G.V.K. project in Jegurupadu, Andhra Pradesh, becomes the first internationally owned power project to begin operating in India.  </p>
<p>CMS Generation holds a 18.75-percent ownership interest in and operates the 235-megawatt plant.</p>
<p>Construction is continuing on two additional gas turbines and one steam turbine unit of the combined-cycle facility, with full capacity operation scheduled for mid-1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Achieving this milestone paves the way for completing the remaining project financing with international lenders, which we expect to accomplish by year's end,&quot; said Rodney Boulanger, CMS Generation's president and chief executive officer. The G.V.K. power plant will cost an estimated $260 million.  </p>
<p>An expansion of the plant to 470 megawatts of capacity is being planned by the project's partners.</p>
<p>&quot;Being the first of the 'fast track' independent power projects to go on stream, as scheduled, is indeed a landmark in the Indian power sector,&quot; said G.V. Krishna Reddy, chairman and managing director of G.V.K. Industries, which holds a 26.5 percent ownership interest in the project.</p>
<p>The Government of India counter-guarantee will assure international lenders that their loans would be secured despite historic fluctuations in the credit quality of the State Electricity Board.</p>
<p>The counter-guarantee commits the Indian government to guarantee payments for power sales if both the Andhra Pradesh State Government and State Electricity Board fail to meet their payment obligations to the power plant.</p>
<p>The natural gas- and naphtha-fueled, combined-cycle G.V.K. facility will supply its entire electric output to the Andhra Pradesh State Electricity Board.</p>
<p>Other partners in the project include: Asea Brown Boveri Ltd ; International Finance Corp  Asian Infrastructure Fund and the Andhra Pradesh State Electricity Board.</p>
<p>-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEARBORN, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
