<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32307" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chicago Park District plans $120 mln bond issue.</title>
<headline>Chicago Park District plans $120 mln bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chicago Park District officials are readying an approximately $120 million bond issue for this fall to fund a record amount of capital improvements, Ron DeNard, the district's chief financial officer, said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's probably the biggest new money deal we have done,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Proceeds from the combination limited tax general obligation and alternate bond issue would fund capital improvements for fiscal 1996 and 1997, DeNard said.</p>
<p>He added the bond issue would be presented to the district's finance committee Sept 25 and then to the district board for final approval Oct 9. If approved, DeNard said the deal would be priced sometime later in October with EVEREN Securities as the bookrunner and Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co. as the co-senior manager.</p>
<p>The issue will not include substantial funding for two major projects proposed by the district -- converting Meigs Field, an airport on Chicago's lakefront, to a park, and renovating Soldier Field for the Chicago Bears football team.</p>
<p>DeNard said only $400,000 in bond proceeds would be used to fund design work for the airport conversion, which Illinois is fighting.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bears officials have said they will not consider remaining in Soldier Field and instead have been negotiating with state officials for a new $450 million domed stadium.</p>
<p>Planned capital improvements by the district include harbor modernization, renovations to existing park facilities and building new facilities.</p>
<p>Park district officials this week also unveiled a proposed $301 million operating budget for fiscal 1997 that includes no property tax increase. The district's fiscal year begins Jan 1.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
