<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32318" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST - Fed may tighten, Aug jobs data key - survey.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Fed may tighten, Aug jobs data key - survey.</headline>
<byline>Jeff Coelho</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>While a slim majority of U.S. experts expect an interest rate hike later this month, they still view Friday's jobs data as the key factor in any near term move by the central bank, according to a Reuters poll.</p>
<p>Thirteen of 30 economists surveyed on Tuesday predicted a 25-basis point hike in the federal funds rate at the September 24 Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC) meeting, while three expected a 50-basis point jump.  </p>
<p>A stream of robust economic data has prompted experts to revise their forecasts from two weeks ago, when only three of 29 economists called for a September 24 tightening.</p>
<p>Economists who forecast a tightening said the rate of U.S. economic growth remained more vigorous than the Fed had hoped, which could lead to a tightening even before the next meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The question here is not whether&quot; the Fed will tighten, contended Michael Strauss, executive vice president and chief economist at Yamaichi International (America) Inc. &quot;The question is could Friday's number be strong enough&quot; to prompt them to tighten on Friday, ahead of the meeting.  </p>
<p>Last week, U.S. consumer confidence rose to its highest level in more than six years, second-quarter Gross Domestic Product registered the fastest growth rate in two years and July single-family home sales recorded the largest increase since February.</p>
<p>Economists polled last week projected the payrolls report would show 244,000 new jobs were added in August, compared to 193,000 in July. They said the central bank could feel pressure to raise rates in September if the payroll employment number comes in higher than expected, average hourly earnings show a significant increase and the unemployment rate dips.  </p>
<p>&quot;The recent data have been so strong and pointing to higher signs of inflationary pressure,&quot; said Dan Seto, an economist at The Nikko Securities Co International Inc.</p>
<p>He said the strength at this time could lead to nervousness among bond investors, adding that &quot;a large increase in wages would translate into a much worse inflationary scare.&quot;</p>
<p>Although 16 of 30 economists polled expect a Fed tightening, 10 did not see a move before the upcoming meeting. Three, however, did expect a 25-basis-point increase by the November 13 FOMC gathering, and one predicted a move in 1997.  </p>
<p>None of the respondents forecast an easing of credit.</p>
<p>Philip Braverman, chief economist at DKB Securities Inc, said the Fed will probably not move, especially before November's presidential elections.</p>
<p>With the November 5 presidential election looming, the central bank will act with extra prudence, he said. &quot;The last thing the Fed wants to do is firm and have egg on their face.&quot;</p>
<p>Full results of the survey follow.  </p>
<p>Participating     Sept 24    Next Move   Direction   FF/disc</p>
<p>Firm		   Move?</p>
<p>Bank of America	 No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>					 til 97</p>
<p>Bank of Boston	  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>BZW Gov Sec'ties	Yes     Sept 24     tighten     50/--</p>
<p>Bear Stearns	    Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>BT Securities	   Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Chase Securities	No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>					 til Q4 96</p>
<p>CS First Boston	 No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>Daiwa Securities	Yes     Nov 13	tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Dean Witter Reynolds  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>DKB Securities	  No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>Fuji			No	Nov 13	tighten     50/--</p>
<p>Griggs &amp; Santow	 Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>High Frequency	  No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>I.D.E.A. Inc	    Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Kemper		    Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Lanston, Aubrey G.    Yes     Sept 24     tighten     50/--</p>
<p>Lehman Gov Sec	  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>MFR			 No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>MMS International     No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>Nikko Securities	Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Nomura		    Yes     Sept 24     tighten     50/--</p>
<p>Northern Trust	  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>PaineWebber	     No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>PNC Bank Corp	   No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>Sanwa Securities	No	no move	 --	  --/--</p>
<p>Scotia Capital Mkts   Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Smith Barney	    No	Nov 13	tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Stone &amp; McCarthy	Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Technical Data	  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>Yamaichi		  Yes     Sept 24     tighten     25/--</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1639</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
