<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32327" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cleveland Finance Director resigns to join EVEREN.</title>
<headline>Cleveland Finance Director resigns to join EVEREN.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Less than a week after finally completing what proved to be a controversial bond sale, Cleveland's finance director resigned, Mayor Michael White's office announced late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Kathryn Hyer said she is returning to investment banking, joining Chicago-based EVEREN Securities, according to a news release from the city. Hyer had been an investment banker with Kemper Securities Inc, the firm that became EVEREN after an employee buyout last year, before she joined Cleveland as its finance director in February 1994.</p>
<p>In the release, White praised Hyer, saying she had &quot;contributed her investment banking and financial expertise to help Cleveland have a sound financial foot on which we are building our future.&quot;</p>
<p>The last deal to pass through Hyer's office was $82 million of parking facilities refunding revenue bonds that were the subject of two pricings last month. The first, led by Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co. on Aug. 22, failed to be completed when the firm refused to sign a bond purchase agreement.</p>
<p>The deal was finally completed on Aug. 29 with Smith Barney Inc. in the lead spot.</p>
<p>It was unclear whether the controversial deal played a role in Hyer's resignation. Hyer was not available to comment. A spokesman for the mayor said he did not know.</p>
<p>Hyer's resignation is effective Sept 20. White appointed assistant Finance Director Martin Carmody to serve as acting finance director until a national search is completed to find a permanent replacement for Hyer, the release said.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
