<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32332" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Controversy hots up before Pope's French tour.</title>
<headline>Controversy hots up before Pope's French tour.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A myriad of French groups voiced opposition on Wednesday to Pope John Paul's forthcoming tour, which has reawakened anti-clerical sentiments stretching back to before the 1789 Revolution.</p>
<p>Groups ranging from Greens and Freemasons to Trotskyites and birth control organisations called for a protest rally in Paris on September 22 to coincide with the pontiff's visit to Reims in the Champagne region.</p>
<p>The opposition Socialist Party voiced discontent at reports that state and local authorities would spend public funds on helping to organise the Pope's September 19-22 visit to western France and Reims.</p>
<p>The Pope's visit has stirred opposition both from secularists and from liberal Roman Catholicas opposed to his conservative teachings on birth control and AIDS.</p>
<p>Police this week defused a crude bomb in a church the Pope is due to visit in the western town of Saint-Laurent-sur-Sevre. The unidentified attackers had scrawled &quot;Pope-Pope-BOOM&quot; on a wall.</p>
<p>The Archbishop of Paris, Jean-Marie Lustiger, described critics of the Pope's visit as intolerant fanatics.</p>
<p>&quot;The agitation around the Holy Father's visit strikes me as fanatical and intolerant. I am outraged as a Frenchman and as a democrat,&quot; Lustiger, France's most influential cleric, told the Foreign Press Association.</p>
<p>The visit will be the Pope's fifth to France -- more than to any other nation apart from Poland and the United States. The church will pay up to seven million francs ($1.4 million) for religious events while the state will pay for security and provide a fleet of planes and helicopters.</p>
<p>The pontiff will visit Reims to mark the 1,500th anniversary of the conversion of King Clovis to Christianity, an event which nationalists say made him the father of France and Roman Catholics say made France &quot;the church's eldest daughter&quot;.</p>
<p>The Frankish king's conversion is still a matter for controversy 15 centuries on. Some see it as a founding act that prevented France from being Balkanised after the collapse of the Roman empire.</p>
<p>Others say it was merely an act of political shrewdness that helped to secure Clovis powerful allies with the Christian hierarchy for bloody conquests against other tribes.</p>
<p>The Socialist Party said Clovis' baptism, while important for the Roman Catholic Church, was only one event in the lenghty construction of France.</p>
<p>&quot;Contrary to what some would like to make believe, Clovis' baptism was not France's baptism,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
