<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32337" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French ex-ministers to pay Paris for free servants.</title>
<headline>French ex-ministers to pay Paris for free servants.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two French ex-cabinet ministers are to pay the city of Paris a total of more than 700,000 francs ($140,000) for having enjoyed free use of domestic servants on the municipal payroll, an official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The city hall spokeswoman confirmed a report in the well-informed investigative weekly Le Canard Enchaine, the latest twist in a series of scandals involving favours for city officials and their relatives.</p>
<p>The newspaper said Camille Cabana and Robert Pandraud, who both served under President Jacques Chirac when he was prime minister and mayor of Paris, expected the payments to pre-empt possible prosecution.</p>
<p>It said Cabana, a former minister for privatisation, had agreed to pay back 618,000 francs ($124,000), and Pandraud, a former security minister, had already paid back 92,000 francs ($18,000) at the request of mayor Jean Tiberi, who took over city hall when Chirac was elected president last year.</p>
<p>Le Canard Enchaine said the pair had written to Tiberi saying that the use of municipal staff as free servants at their city-owned apartments had been a current practice and they had not realised it could be illegal.</p>
<p>The mayor's office had no immediate comment on the report.</p>
<p>An administrative court is due to rule on Thursday on a request by a taxpayers' association to open legal action against the two former officials.</p>
<p>Paris city hall has been shaken over the past two years by disclosures that it granted low-rent flats to political cronies and relatives, including Tiberi's children and Prime Minister Alain Juppe and his children, as well as by alleged kickbacks said to have funded Chirac's Gaullist RPR party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
