<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32338" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French lender's profit up before Belgian alliance.</title>
<headline>French lender's profit up before Belgian alliance.</headline>
<byline>Penny MacRae</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French public sector lender Credit Local de France (CLF) announced on Tuesday a six percent rise in half year profit ahead of its planned alliance with one of Belgium's biggest banks.</p>
<p>Net attributable profit for the six months to end June rose to 793 million francs ($156 million) from 748 million and the bank forecast its ninth straight increase in full-year profit.</p>
<p>&quot;On the eve of our alliance with Credit Communal de Belgique (CCB), Credit Local de France is displaying its strength,&quot; bank chairman Pierre Richard said in a statement.</p>
<p>The alliance, in which the two banks will take cross-holdings in each other's share capital, comes into effect at the end of the year.</p>
<p>The partnership will create the 22nd largest bank in Europe and the largest European financial institution specialising in loans to local and regional public authorities.</p>
<p>Later at a news conference, Richard said he had the green light from CCB to forecast the Belgian's lender's first half profit would be &quot;very favourable, I could even say excellent&quot;.</p>
<p>The French bank's shares climbed 12.0 francs or nearly three percent to 424.70 francs on the results, outperforming the blue-chip CAC-40 index which finished up just 0.68 percent.</p>
<p>Net banking income jumped nearly 23 percent to 1.81 billion francs while net provisions totalled 87 million francs. That figure included 97 million francs worth of provisions for real estate compared with 136 million in the previous half-year period and a nine million franc clawback from provisions.</p>
<p>Richard called the financial results &quot;very satisfactory&quot; and said commercial activities had been sustained during the first eight months of 1996, especially internationally.</p>
<p>Operating costs rose 15.7 percent mainly due to intergration of four new units, including CLF-Hypothekenbank Berlin and CLF-Suede. Corporate taxes rose 34 percent due to the jump in operating profit and consolidation of companies paying tax.</p>
<p>The bank had said last July it would pay a total exceptional dividend of 626 million francs to shareholders before the alliance went into effect. The payout is aimed at redressing the difference in size between the two banks.</p>
<p>It said on Wednesday the exceptional dividend would work out to a gross payment of 25.50 francs per share or 17 francs net. That was on top of a 20.85 franc gross dividend paid in June.</p>
<p>Despite stabilisation of local government investment, loans to the public sector as of August 31, 1996, were up 10 percent.</p>
<p>The new group's financial clout with total assets of 1,000 billion francs &quot;will enable us to step up European expansion and even go beyond the borders of Europe,&quot; Richard said. ($ = 5.084 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
