<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32346" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti sees PCs in loss for 1996.</title>
<headline>Olivetti sees PCs in loss for 1996.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's troubled information technology group Olivetti said its loss-making personal computer company will not reach break-even in 1996 and will still languish in the red for the year.</p>
<p>Analysts said Olivetti's chief executive Francesco Caio told them at a conference call late this afternoon that the group's PC company will not reach break-even, but he declined to be drawn on any figures or conclusion.  </p>
<p>Olivetti's former chairman Carlo De Benedetti, who resigned late on Tuesday, had promised the PC company would be sold off if it did not reach break-even in 1996.</p>
<p>In 1995, the PC company lost 200 billion lire and, although it made a small profit in the second quarter of 1996, it did show an operating loss of 10 billion lire for the first half of the year.</p>
<p>Analysts said Caio stressed strategic issues rather than operational ones at the conference call, but did point out that two of Olivetti's five companies -- systems and services and Lexikon did make profits in the first half of 1996.  </p>
<p>He said systems and services, which accounts for 65 percent of Olivetti's group sales, made an operating profit of 49 billion lire, while office equipment maker Lexikon made a 39 billion lire operating profit and a four percent margin.</p>
<p>&quot;They wanted to emphasise that 1996 will not be a year of recovery for Olivetti. It's going to reflect the continuing restructuring,&quot; said Michael Pacitti, Italian analyst at brokers James Capel in London. &quot;Despite the fact in the past the previous management has suggested if the PC division did not make a profit or break-even then it would be sold. This is not part of the current management strategy.&quot;  </p>
<p>In addition, to operating result for systems and services, PCs and Lexikon, Olivetti said its Telemedia company made an operating loss of 38 billion lire, other activities lost 21 billion lire, while its Latin American operations made a profit of 10 billion lire.</p>
<p>Olivetti made an adjustment charge for consolidation of 51 billion lire and put the cost of corporate activity at 59 billion lire, bringing the total group's operating losses to 81 billion for the first half of 1996.  </p>
<p>This 81 billion lire loss figures did not appear to include the 90 billion lire operating loss from Olivetti's 41.3 percent holding in mobile telephone group Omnitel.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first half of the year, Olivetti systems and services reported an operating profit of 49 billion lire on sales of 2.7 trillion lire. That's an operating margin of 1.8 percent,&quot; Pacitti said.</p>
<p>&quot;For all of last year, the operating margin in the systems and services division was 3.8 percent. So the margin has more than halved. That is a threat to results for 1996 and it's a bigger threat than 10 billion loss in the PC division.&quot;</p>
<p>Caio added that plans to partly float Lexikon will not be possible for 1996 and analysts added that Olivetti's aim was to wait until next year for the float.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
