<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32347" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bourse watchdog calls meeting on Olivetti.</title>
<headline>Italian bourse watchdog calls meeting on Olivetti.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian bourse watchdog Consob has called a meeting in Rome on Thursday with former Olivetti director general Renzo Francesconi and &quot;the legal representative&quot; of the group, news agency ANSA reported.</p>
<p>No one was available at Consob's Milan or Rome offices to confirm the report although Olivetti was expected to make a statement later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>No time was given for the meeting.</p>
<p>Francesconi resigned earlier on Wednesday, within a day of the stepping down of Olivetti chairman Carlo De Benedetti.</p>
<p>ANSA quoted a Consob spokesman as saying the meeting had been called to obtain &quot;explanations as to the situation which has been created following the resignation of Francesconi and his declarations about the half year data released yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>Olivetti released its half year results for 1996 at the same time as announcing De Benedetti's resignation. It made a 440.2 billion lire pretax loss.</p>
<p>Francesconi was quoted as saying that Olivetti's future looked very difficult and he did not agree with some results released.</p>
<p>Francesco Caio, managing director of the troubled information technology group, said he was surprised both at the content and form of Francesconi's statements.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures at June 30 1996 have a strict accounting base and contain provisions which reflect in a correct and considered fashion evaluations in relation to strategic business decisions and the restructuring carried out by the company,&quot; Caio said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have chosen the method of transparency and clarity which we can only confirm,&quot; Caio said.</p>
<p>The Consob spokesman said the markets division of the stock market commission &quot;is evaluating the situation&quot; with regard to any possible action on the share on the bourse.</p>
<p>He said a decision would be taken after a statement requested from Olivetti and expected later.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
