<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32349" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. may adpot Iraq resolution Thursday - Envoy.</title>
<headline>U.N. may adpot Iraq resolution Thursday - Envoy.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German ambassador to the United Nations Tono Eitel said on Wednesday that he expects the Security Council to agree a resolution on the Iraqi crisis by Thursday, though with some of the 15 members abstaining.</p>
<p>&quot;I assume we will have something tomorrow but you never know,&quot; said Eitel, who also chairs the U.N. sanctions committee on Iraq.</p>
<p>He said he did not expect a full reconciliation between the opposing Russian and British draft resoltuions, noting that the majority of Security Council members back the British version with a few abstentions.  </p>
<p>Britain produced a draft resolution on Tuesday condemning Iraq for its actions and demanding that it pull out its troops from the northern Kurdish regions immediately, but not making any mention of the U.S. retaliatory attacks in the last two days.</p>
<p>It also calls on Iran to stop military actions in the area and for the rival Kurdish groups to resume talks.</p>
<p>Russia's version was milder in condemning Iraq and asked for all parties to cease using force.</p>
<p>On Wednesday President Clinton said U.S. military objectives had been achieved and said Iraqi troops had begun withdrawing from the area.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Eitel said a final vote on the resolution will include the abstentions. A resolution can be passed by the Security Council with nine out of the 15 members voting in favor and no veto from the five permanent members.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Connole, United Nations, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
