<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32344" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN Sec Council to vote Thurs on Iraq resolution.</title>
<headline>UN Sec Council to vote Thurs on Iraq resolution.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations Security Council will vote Thursday on a formal resolution on Iraq's military action last weekend into internationally-protected Kurdish zones in the north of the country, a spokesman for the British delegation said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will circulate a text later this evening on the results of today's discussions (and) the resolution will go forward tomorrow in a formal meeting of the council,&quot; the British spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It certainly expresses the international community's concern on the Iraqi actions in northern Iraq,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Separately, Germany's ambassador to the United Nations, Tono Eitel, said Wednesday that the Security Council was seeking ways to ensure that the current crisis in Iraq does not unduly delay implementation of Iraq's oil-for-food deal with the U.N.</p>
<p>Implementation of the oil deal (U.N. resolution 986), which would allow Iraq to sell up to $2 billion of oil over six months to pay for badly needed food and medicines for ordinary Iraqis, was suspended at the weekend by U.N. secretary-general Boutros Boutros-Ghali.</p>
<p>&quot;The concensus emerging within the council is that 986 should be implemented when the security situation on the ground will allow that,&quot; said Eitel.</p>
<p>&quot;The last hour of discussions was spent on how to deal with the common desire to make sure 986 did not suffer from whatever is going on now in Iraq and how to integrate 986 into the draft resolution or deal with it separately -- and that is still going on,&quot; the German envoy said after leaving Wednesday's Security Council debate.</p>
<p>British deputy ambassador to the U.N., Stephen Gomersall, said: &quot;The assumption is that a return to the status quo before the last actions of Iraq will be restored&quot; before the oil-for-food deal will be put back on track.</p>
<p>Neither diplomat gave any timeframe for implementation of the deal, which was agreed on May 20. Before the current crisis Iraqi oil was expected to start flowing sometime in September.</p>
<p>Gomersall also said that the resolution which is expected to be adopted will not mention Iran by name but will refer to interference in the region by neighboring states.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
