<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32341" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Russia and NATO still far apart on enlargement.</title>
<headline>Russia and NATO still far apart on enlargement.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov committed Moscow on Wednesday to a dialogue with the West about Europe's new security structures, but said Russia remained opposed to NATO's expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position (on extending NATO) has not changed. But we also think it is necessary to have security talks to establish the relations between NATO and Russia,&quot; he told a news conference after meeting German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel.</p>
<p>Primakov, making first bilateral visit to the West since taking office in January, was due to meet Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Thursday.</p>
<p>Kinkel had billed Wednesday's meeting as the start of a period of intensive talks between Russia and the West to agree a formal charter or treaty governing their relations. Kohl is due to meet Russian President Boris Yeltsin in Mocsow on Saturday.</p>
<p>NATO is likely to decide in principle early next year to admit Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic, all formerly part of the Soviet-led Warsaw Pact, as members.</p>
<p>Russia remains opposed to seeing the Western alliance extend to its borders. But Primakov appeared to soften this stance in June when he suggested a limited expansion might be acceptable if no troops or weapons were stationed on the territory of new members.</p>
<p>While NATO has insisted it will not grant Russia a veto an newadmissions, Germany is pushing for a formal framework which would ensure Russia is involved and consulted on such decisions.</p>
<p>Primakov, stressing the confidence existing between Germany and Russia, said: &quot;I am glad to say we agreed that there can be no European security without Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>Kinkel said both countries agreed on a need to strengthen the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe by giving it new conflict-prevention powers at an OSCE summit in Lisbon in December.</p>
<p>But they differed sharply on their assessment of the U.S. air strikes against Iraq, intended to punish Baghdad for sending its forces to attack against Kurds in a U.N.-implemented no-fly area in the north of the country.</p>
<p>Bonn has said the attacks are appropriate, but Primakov criticised them sharply for the third time in two days. &quot;It's a very dangerous situation, a precedent for the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If... we have a superpower, be it the United States, Europe or Russia, acting on its own initiative to use violence in a region without consulting an international organisation, in this case the U.N. Security Council, there will be conflict.&quot;</p>
<p>Kinkel said his talks with Primakov also covered the health of Yeltsin, seen in public only once since late June.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's aides say his low profile is not a sign of failing health or a lack of control over policy, but that he needs rest and is limiting his meetings and calls.</p>
<p>&quot;We wish for him that he will soon again find the strength -- and I am sure he will, we talked about that -- to take on government business in the way that we jointly hope for,&quot; Kinkel said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
