<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32350" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Angry Kurds charge French &quot;double-talk&quot; on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Angry Kurds charge French &quot;double-talk&quot; on Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kurdish rebels warned France on Wednesday that withholding support from  U.S. missile strikes against Iraqi targets was tantamount to backing Iraqi leader Saddam Hussein and would jeopardise its interests there.</p>
<p>&quot;If French policy persists in its double-talk, the future democratic regime in Iraq will not be able to guarantee the protection of French interests,&quot; the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) said in a statement issued in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;Some statements and acts entail such serious consequences that they are not easily forgotten,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Washington fired cruise missiles at Iraq after Baghdad's forces and guerrillas of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) captured the city of Arbil from their PUK rivals.</p>
<p>Paris, which fought in the coalition which ejected Iraqi forces from Kuwait and was a driving force behind the imposition of a no-fly zone over the Kurdish area of northern Iraq, has expressed concern at the situation and called for dialogue.</p>
<p>It said it had not agreed in advance to President Bill Clinton's decision to extend the no-fly zone imposed after the 1991 Gulf War from the 32nd to the 33th parallel, and its planes stayed well clear of the new exclusion zone on Wednesday.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary Willam Perry said he expected France would continue to participate in the allied coalition.</p>
<p>The PUK said France had saved millions of lives by pushing through the United Nations the right to intervention to &quot;protect civilians against dictators having until then the right to life and death over their own population within borders considered inviolable.</p>
<p>&quot;Does the French government have the right today to renounce the ideals which have made France great?&quot; it asked.</p>
<p>The PUK said France was asking the Iraqi leader to watch over the security of the civilian population, &quot;as if one asked the wolf to watch over the health of the lamb&quot;.</p>
<p>The KDP has said it had allied itself with the Iraqi army to combat aggression by Iran and &quot;treachery&quot; by the PUK.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
