<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32352" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Naples gets back to nature.</title>
<headline>Naples gets back to nature.</headline>
<byline>Claudia Parsons</byline>
<dateline>NAPLES, Italy</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trees may not solve all southern Italy's problems but city officials in Naples think the key to economic development is to convert a former factory site into the biggest public park in the city centre.</p>
<p>Bagnoli in the west of Naples was the largest industrial centre in southern Italy with a workforce of 10,000 in the 1960s, but the state-controlled former steel works was shut down four years ago after decades of decline.</p>
<p>Thousands of jobs disappeared with the closing of the Ilva steel plant and other factories in the complex, helping to push unemployment in the Campania region, of which Naples is the capital, to 26.2 percent -- the highest rate in Italy.</p>
<p>Nearly 90 years of industry has also left a legacy of pollution on land and sea that authorities estimate will cost more than 260 billion lire ($170 million) to clean up.</p>
<p>City officials say they will be tackling both problems by converting the entire 742-acre Bagnoli site into a park surrounded by hotels, restaurants, a clean beach, a tourist marina and quality housing.</p>
<p>&quot;Until Naples starts the difficult process of bringing its standard of living up to the level of other major European cities, it cannot have any prospect of economic development and tackling unemployment,&quot; said Vezio de Lucia, the city official who has devised the Bagnoli development.</p>
<p>He said the project could employ up to 8,000 people over the next decade during construction, and would provide several thousand permanent jobs when it is up and running.</p>
<p>De Lucia's plan is part of a drive by Naples' dynamic mayor and former communist, Antonio Bassolino, to clean up the city's image, tackle crime and boost the economy.</p>
<p>Elected in December 1993, he rapidly won public favour for clearing traffic-clogged streets and rejuvenating public buildings and squares ahead of a Group of Seven (G7) summit held in the city in 1994.</p>
<p>Campania, which boosts top tourist attractions like the ancient Roman city of Pompeii and the glamorous island resort of Capri, is the most popular holiday destination in southern Italy. It saw a 25.3 percent increase in foreign visitors in 1994 and a further 10.6 percent climb in 1995.</p>
<p>But Naples itself is rarely on the tourist itinerary, and crime remains a major factor despite a tough campaign against the Camorra (Naples-area Mafia), which has seen the arrest of several important bosses over the last few years.</p>
<p>A recent report by the Association for Industrial Development in the Mezzogiorno (South) said the capture of so many mob bosses had actually led to an increase in petty crime and murder because of infighting between the dozens of clans striving to fill the gap left by the big arrests.</p>
<p>The crime clampdown, however, means the Bagnoli development may escape a problem that has cursed so many infrastructure projects since the war -- the Mafia traditionally dominated the construction industry, siphoning off cash into their pockets.</p>
<p>A substantial chunk of the more than $115 billion ploughed into developing Italy's poor south since the end of World War II is thought to have ended up in the coffers of organised crime.</p>
<p>One of De Lucia's first actions when he took up his position with Bassolino in 1993 was to start tearing down some of the thousands of buildings constructed illegally -- and often dangerously -- in the decades of chaos and inefficiency.</p>
<p>So far the only visible evidence that Bagnoli is returning to its previous role as a holiday town is the small band of intrepid bathers who have started to brave the waters off the short strip of sand where Ilva used to unload iron ore.</p>
<p>The authorities say it still takes courage to swim there.</p>
<p>Layers of pollution have settled deep down into the sand on the sea bed and shore.</p>
<p>Ilva is due to start dismantling the vast factory and cleaning up the area in September, but De Lucia said that process will take at least three years.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Naples is looking to secure private investors to stump up the estimated $1.3 billion for the rest of the project.</p>
<p>De Lucia said he expects around 10 percent to come from European Union funds, and several private investors are interested, both in Italy and abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;My conviction is that money is not the problem -- you can always find the money,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>What may be the problem is time. The most optimistic estimate is that the project will take at least 10 years, and that prediction relies on Naples' ability to maintain its current mood of optimism and efficiency.</p>
<p>As with everything in Italy, only time will tell.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPLES, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
