<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32353" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: CDC offer for Credit Foncier accepted.</title>
<headline>CDC offer for Credit Foncier accepted.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Noble</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French stock markets authority said on Wednesday state-owned bank Caisse des Depots et Consignations's (CDC) offer for distressed property lender Credit Foncier de France was acceptable.</p>
<p>The decision brings the government within sight of closing the file on a costly and embarrassing bank failure that has plagued the government for months.</p>
<p>The takeover, which will cost in the neighbourhood of 2.5 billion francs ($491.4 million), has yet to be executed and requires acceptances covering two-thirds of the shares in the group.</p>
<p>Government plans call for a &quot;managed wind-down&quot; of the bank under which its commmercial activities and low-cost housing loan portfolio would be spun off. It would be reduced to a shell company and placed in a state holding firm that would ensure that billions of bonds issued in its name were honoured.</p>
<p>But the decision was likely to prompt an appeal by disgruntled shareholders of Credit Foncier who on Tuesday stepped up their fight against terms of a state-orchestrated takeover of the property lender to the courts.</p>
<p>Colette Neuville, head of the French shareholders' action lobby ADAM, said on Tuesday the group had asked a Paris commercial court to order an independent evaluation of the worth of CFF, once France's second-largest bond issuer.</p>
<p>ADAM's members are nursing big losses on shares that once traded around 450 francs per share and want CDC to boost its offer to at least 100 francs.</p>
<p>She also said that if the CBV stock market regulator gave a green light for the bid, the group would challenge the decision.</p>
<p>She said the commercial court would rule on Thursday on its call for an independent assessment of CFF's worth and decide on September 19 on the demand to annul the 1995 accounts.</p>
<p>Neuville said ADAM's toughened stance was triggered by CFF's surprise announcement last Friday of a 402 million franc first-half profit, compared with a 12 million franc loss for the same year-earlier period, and its forecast of a &quot;positive&quot; full year result barring a fresh real estate downturn.</p>
<p>ADAM said the half-year earnings statement showed that the 1995 provisions totalling 13.6 billion francs had been too big.</p>
<p>CFF's woes stemmed from a collapse of property prices and the end of its lucrative monopoly on low cost mortgages. ($1=5.087 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
