<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32359" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French government budget plans - summary.</title>
<headline>French government budget plans - summary.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following gives key details of France's 1997 budget and tax reform plans. The budget is due to be presented officially to the cabinet on September 18, although Prime Minister Alain Juppe is expected to give broad outlines of plans for the budget and a separate tax reform bill earlier.</p>
<p>TOTAL PUBLIC DEFICIT</p>
<p>This is to be reduced to three percent of gross domestic product in 1997 from a targetted four percent in 1996 and five percent in 1995.</p>
<p>It comprises the following areas of spending:  </p>
<p>-- Central government budget. The government said earlier this year that it planned to cut the deficit on this to around 248 billion francs, or three percent of GDP, from a forecast 288 billion this year.</p>
<p>-- Social security accounts. These cover healthcare, pensions and familiy benefits and are financed mainly through payroll taxes. The government originally intended to return these to balance next year, but has since conceded they may run up a small deficit. This year's welfare deficit has been estimated by the national health insurance fund at 50 to 55 billion francs.  </p>
<p>-- National unemployment fund UNEDIC. It said in July that it saw a surplus next year of 22.5 to 25.8 billion francs after a surplus of 10.5 to 10.9 billion in 1996.</p>
<p>-- Local authorities. These are expected to run up a small deficit.</p>
<p>-- Other contributions. The government may seek additional revenue from other areas under state control, including surpluses from state-owned bank Caisse des Depots et Consignations.</p>
<p>One such contribution under consideration is a 37.5 billion franc transfer of funds due from France Telecom when the state assumes its pension liabilities ahead of partial privatisation.  </p>
<p>CENTRAL GOVERNMENT BUDGET - SPENDING</p>
<p>Spending is to be frozen at 1996's 1,552 billion francs.</p>
<p>But since spending on some areas will increase automatically by around 60 billion francs -- to cover inflation, debt service charges and pre-agreed civil service promotions, spending cuts of at least 60 billion francs will have to be made elsewhere.</p>
<p>Spending cuts are expected to include:</p>
<p>-- A reduction in 6,500 to 7,000 civil service jobs, saving some one billion francs</p>
<p>-- A cut in job subsidies, saving 15 to 20 billion francs</p>
<p>-- A reduction in housing aid subsidies.  </p>
<p>Defence, health, education, justice and labour spending are expected to increase next year.</p>
<p>REVENUES</p>
<p>Finance Minister Jean Arthuis said the budget should forecast growth of 2.25 to 2.5 percent next year, slightly lower than the 2.8 percent forecast earlier this year. The government has given no figure for expected 1997 revenues for the budget.</p>
<p>TAX REFORM</p>
<p>This will be contained in the budget bill itself and in separate bills on a five-year reform of taxation and on financing for the social security system.  </p>
<p>The key aims of the reforms are to reduce payroll charges and thus the cost of labour and shift savings into longer-term products and shares, notably through the introduction of private pension funds. There may be a separate bill on pension funds.</p>
<p>INCOME TAX REFORM</p>
<p>The government has promised tax cuts of at least 20 billion francs next year and a reduction in all income tax rates -- including the top rate of tax of 56.8 percent -- over five years. It has said people will feel real benefits in 1997, implying the cuts will apply to 1996 income, payable in 1997.  </p>
<p>A government-commissioned report suggested in June that tax cuts should apply to 1997 income, payable in 1998, saying the state of public finances prevented significant reduction in 1997.</p>
<p>Financial daily Les Echos said income tax cuts would total 25 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>The government is planning to make some 75 billion francs in income tax cuts altogether over the next five years, Francois Leotard, president of France's UDF parliamentary party, said on Wednesday after a meeting with Juppe.  </p>
<p>The government may tighten a range of tax breaks, including on income from savings, scrap special tax allowances applicable to about 100 professions and tax some benefits, including family allowances, although has so far declined comment on this.</p>
<p>TAXES ON SAVINGS</p>
<p>The government has pledged to tighten the current highly favourable tax regime for life assurance policies. In 1995 it introduced taxation for contributions to new policies over a certain amount, but left untouched tax exemptions on earnings from such policies.  </p>
<p>It is expected to introduce a favourable tax regime to encourage contributions to pension funds, which Finance Minister Jean Arthuis has said should be introduced by the start of 1997.</p>
<p>OTHER TAXES</p>
<p>Increases in Value Added Tax (sales tax) and wealth tax made in 1995 are expected to remain in place at least through 1997.</p>
<p>Taxes on tobacco will be raised. Newspapers have said taxes on alcohol and gasoline could also be increased.</p>
<p>HEALTH CARE TAX REFORM</p>
<p>The scope of the generalised social contribution (CSG), a flat 2.4 percent tax on most income, is expected to be widened to offset a reduction in payroll charges to cover healthcare.</p>
<p>The government earlier this year introduced a new flat 0.5 percent tax, the RDS, to pay off accumulated welfare deficits.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
