<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32361" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France, Egypt want results from PLO-Israel talks.</title>
<headline>France, Egypt want results from PLO-Israel talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt and France welcomed Wednesday's first talks between Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat and said they hoped they would lead to progress in the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;I saw in news agency dispatches that Mr Arafat and Mr Netanyahu shook hands. I am delighted. Shaking hands is good, but making progress is better,&quot; French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette told reporters after talks in Paris with his Egyptian counterpart Amr Moussa.</p>
<p>Moussa agreed that the meeting was &quot;a positive step in the interests of both parties and of peace if it leads to practical and positive results&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a question of a simple handshake, but of genuine results which must be cast in concrete,&quot; Moussa said.</p>
<p>De Charette and Moussa said they broadly agreed on the Middle East and other world issues and pledged to continue to work together in search of peace.</p>
<p>&quot;It is urgent that the peace process get back on track, and that it do so on the basis of agreements that have already been signed and promises that have already been made,&quot; de Charette said.</p>
<p>The two also discussed the crisis in Iraq and Egypt's bid for an association agreement with the European Union, de Charette said.</p>
<p>Moussa was in France on the first leg of a three-day diplomatic tour intended to try to get the Middle East peace process moving again.</p>
<p>One of his key concerns is whether to go ahead with plans for a Middle East economic summit in Cairo in November. Egypt has set five conditions to be met by Israel for the conference to be held.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is entirely clear,&quot; Moussa said when asked about the conference. &quot;The summit and its success are tied to the peace process.&quot;</p>
<p>After leaving Paris, Moussa was to visit Norway and perhaps Britain, Egyptian officials said.</p>
<p>Britain has been under attack in Egypt because it has not prevented Islamist militants from holding a conference in London on September 8.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
