<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32362" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Experts reaffirm gene-altered soybean safety.</title>
<headline>Experts reaffirm gene-altered soybean safety.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Health and environmental risks from genetically-modified U.S. soybeans could be excluded, experts said at a seminar organised by the local American Soybean Association (ASA) office here.</p>
<p>The seminar was aimed at informing farm feed advisors and the press ahead of the arrival of U.S. imports in late 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;A separation of the new soybeans and those produced traditionally is impossible both financially and logistically,&quot; said ASA managing director Dieter Kundrun.</p>
<p>&quot;But it won't be necessary because health and safety procedures have tested the products and found no risks.&quot;  </p>
<p>Importers and feed mixers are worried about consumer reaction as there has been too little time to carry out information campaigns.</p>
<p>The EU Commission in April approved the imports of herbicide-resistant beans names &quot;Roundup Ready,&quot; which are expected to account for one or two percent of the total U.S. soybean crop this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The beans enable farmers to use herbicides more selectively and sparingly,&quot; said Andreas Amann, a field development coordinator at producer firm Monsanto Co.  </p>
<p>&quot;Roundup Ready beans allow herbicide use to be cut by one third and to fight erosion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Biochemist Hans Guenter Gassen of Darmstadt University said the minute traces of modified protein in the soybeans were destroyed by heat as the beans were crushed into soy oil or meal.</p>
<p>Armin Salweski of Bingen University said feeding experiments showed the modified soybeans were the same in nutrition, composition and feed value as other soybeans.</p>
<p>Consumer organisation Greenpeace today circulated a press release in Hamburg saying a poll carried out on its behalf showed two-thirds of consumers opposed genetically-altered soybean products.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
