<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32378" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal's BCP, J.Martins launch new bank.</title>
<headline>Portugal's BCP, J.Martins launch new bank.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal's largest private bank Banco Comercial Portugues (BCP) and second biggest retailer Jeronimo Martins said they had signed an agreement to launch a new bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;BCP and Jeronimo Martins (JM) have signed an agreement to launch a new bank that will sell financial services to the consumer through in-store branches located in JM's supermarkets and 'cash and carry' outlets,&quot; a statement said.</p>
<p>It said BCP and JM would set up a joint venture that would be owned equally by the two groups and would operate under the existing banking licence for Banco Comercial de Macau (BCM), a subsidiary of BCP.  </p>
<p>&quot;Although the new bank will be primarily based on its network of in-store branches, it may also use other complementary channels, such as the telephone,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The joint venture is subject to the approval of the Portuguese regulatory authorities, it added.</p>
<p>BCP, listed on the Lisbon, New York and Frankfurt stock exchanges, has total assets of 5.3 trillion escudos, total deposits of 4.1 trillion escudos and total loans of 2.1 trillion escudos. It has a market capitalisation of about 246 billion escudos.</p>
<p>JM's total turnover was more than 256 billion escudos in 1995. The group, listed on Lisbon stock exchange, has more than 130 outlets, including supermarkets, hypermarkets and &quot;cash and carry&quot; shops. It has a market capitalisation of about 184 billion escudos.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +351-1-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
