<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32374" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Israelis, Palestinians met on Jerusalem - weekly.</title>
<headline>Israelis, Palestinians met on Jerusalem - weekly.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Academics close to the Israeli and Palestinian governments drafted a blueprint for the future of Jerusalem at secret talks in Paris last year, but the murder of Israeli prime minister Yitzhak Rabin ended the initiative, a French Jewish weekly reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Tribune Juive said the plan stipulated that the holy city, while remaining under overall Israeli control, would be the capital of both Israel and a future Palestinian state.</p>
<p>The Palestinian government would administer Arab East Jerusalem but would reside outside the city, possibly in nearby Ramallah, it said.</p>
<p>A charter guaranteed by the United States and Russia would outline the rights of both sides over holy sites while Israel's recognition of Palestinian rights would open the way for foreign embassies in Israel to move to Jerusalem, the weekly said.</p>
<p>Tribune Juive identified participants at the meeting as Yair Hirschfeld, Dan Seidemann and Yitzhak Relter of Israel and Mahdi Abdul Hadi, Sari Nusseibeh and Bernard Sabella for the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Hirschfeld, close to former Israeli prime minister Shimon Peres, was a key figure in the initial secret talks that led to the Israel-PLO Oslo peace agreements.</p>
<p>The weekly said the meeting was held on May 14-15, 1995 in the offices of the French Institute for International Relations, and that the think-tank's deputy director, Dominique Moisi, attended along with two French Foreign Ministry observers.</p>
<p>Questioned by Reuters, Moisi declined to confirm or deny the meeting took place.</p>
<p>However, one participant who asked not be to identified confirmed there had indeed been such a meeting but said none of the parties had an official government mandate and no firm agreement was reached.</p>
<p>In May, Israelis elected a hardline government led by Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who rejects any sharing of Jerusalem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
