<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32372" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish neo-nazi radio to be closed down.</title>
<headline>Danish neo-nazi radio to be closed down.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Local radio authorities in south Copenhagen are to close Denmark's neo-Nazi radio station because to broadcast excerpts from Hitler's &quot;Mein Kampf&quot;, the Danish Ritzau news agency reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In our opinion the radio station has been broadcasting despicable statements,&quot; a spokesman for the local radio authority told the agency.</p>
<p>Radio Oasis went on the air in late February after being grudgingly granted a licence under Denmark's liberal freedom of speech laws.</p>
<p>The spokesman said licence was granted on condition that the station did not incite racial hatred among listeners, but it had broadcast extracts from &quot;Mein Kampf&quot;, a book outlining the Nazi philosophy of the superiority of the Aryan race over Jews.</p>
<p>Danish neo-Nazi leader Jonni Hansen told Reuters: &quot;The passage of 'Mein Kampf' which caused offence was in book two where Hitler likens negros to monkeys.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I have not yet received any written notice of the closure from the local radio committee but I am sure we will. We are going to appeal against the closure. We plan to continue broadcasting.&quot;</p>
<p>Radio Oasis -- &quot;an oasis in the media desert&quot; according to Hansen -- broadcast from the headquarters of Denmark's National Socialist Movement in the blue-collar community of Greve, 20 km (12 miles) south of Copenhagen.</p>
<p>It used a 30-watt transmitter so its reception area was limited to Greve and the surrounding suburbs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
