<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32387" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Gle des Eaux aims to be telecoms giant.</title>
<headline>France's Gle des Eaux aims to be telecoms giant.</headline>
<byline>Denis Thomas</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French diversified utility Generale des Eaux said on Wednesday it aimed to take advantage of deregulation to become the country's second largest telecommunications operator after state-owned France Telecom.</p>
<p>&quot;The competition will be very useful for mobile telephone users and tomorrow for the entire range of telephone services,&quot; company chairman Jean-Marie Messier told a news conference.</p>
<p>Messier's comments came as he announced the creation of a new holding company to group the utility's telecommunications activities, to be known as Cegetel.</p>
<p>The holding company is being set up ahead of legislation due to come into effect on January 1, 1998, deregulating the French telecommunications market.</p>
<p>Under the act, telephone users will be able to choose their suppliers for both local and long distance calls.</p>
<p>&quot;This date (January 1, 1998) will mark an opening of the telecommunications market without precedent on a world scale...in the fact that in one step, 90 percent of the market that today is inaccessible will open up to competition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux, which already has a wide portfolio of mobile telephone licences, said it would invest four billion francs ($786.3 million) annually in telecommunications between 1997 and 1999 of which 2.3 billion francs would be earmarked for mobile telephones.</p>
<p>The utility valued the telecommunications market in 1995 at 117 billion francs, of which six billion represented the market for mobile telephones.</p>
<p>It forecast the telecoms market would grow to 187 billion francs by 2003 of which 55 billion would be in mobile phones.</p>
<p>Messier, who will serve as chairman of the new holding, forecast Cegetel would generate a net profit as of 1999.</p>
<p>Its flagship mobile telecommunications unit, Societe Francaise de Radiotelephone (SFR), would become profitable in 1998 after achieving breakeven in 1997, he said.</p>
<p>Messier said competition in the telecommunications sector would allow the group to create &quot;during the coming years undoubtedly 10,000 direct jobs, without counting the indirect jobs which could represent two or three times that amount.&quot;</p>
<p>Generale des Eaux will hold &quot;strong, majority control&quot; of Cegetel reflecting &quot;the group's attachment to its independence,&quot; Messier said.</p>
<p>But Cegetel's capital will also be open to Generale des Eaux's &quot;strategic partners&quot; which have already expressed interest, Messier said.</p>
<p>These partners are notably Southwestern Bell of the U.S. and Britain's Vodafone which hold stakes in Generale des Eaux's telecommunications unit Cofira which will come under Cegetel's umbrella. ($1=5.087 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
