<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32381" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Diplomats see signs of thaw in Cuba trade row.</title>
<headline>Diplomats see signs of thaw in Cuba trade row.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Efforts by a U.S. envoy to win international support for controversial anti-Cuba laws were dismissed by EU officials on Wednesday but diplomats saw signs that the potentially damaging trade row could be defused.</p>
<p>European Union Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan, speaking to the European Parliament, said the Helms-Burton Act was &quot;misguided&quot;, &quot;repugnant&quot; and &quot;the worst possible basis on which to contruct a dialogue&quot;.</p>
<p>But officials from the Commission -- the EU's executive -- said special envoy Stuart Eizenstat's proposals for a global effort to bring democracy to Cuba would be treated seriously.</p>
<p>Eizenstat -- who in an interview with Reuters conceded the near-impossibility of winning international support for the act -- is concentrating his efforts on coordinating and increasing global opposition to the government of Fidel Castro.</p>
<p>Following meetings with senior EU officials and European business and trade union organisations, he said he was very encouraged by the response he had received to U.S. proposals for a three-pronged campaign to isolate the Cuban government.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't stop the opposition (to the act),&quot; Eizenstat said. &quot;But what I am asking for is more effort, more willingness, more desire to bring democracy to what is the last truly oppressive regime in the Western Hemisphere.&quot;</p>
<p>Eizenstat called on U.S. allies to join &quot;a first, genuine, multinational effort&quot; similar to Washington's support for European desires for democracy in the former Eastern bloc.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton Act -- an amalgamation of decades of anti-Cuba legislation -- was passed in July to a chorus of indignant opposition from many U.S. allies.</p>
<p>Among other things, the act allows American citizens to sue in U.S. courts foreign companies that have benefited from investments made in property confiscated by Havana since the communist revolution of 1959.</p>
<p>Although the practical implications of this part have been suspended until next year, the EU -- along with Canada and Mexico -- are concerned that liability is accruing.</p>
<p>Brittan told parliament that even after a meeting with Eizenstat on Tuesday, he was convinced the EU should continue with steps to retaliate against laws which affect its interests.</p>
<p>In July EU foreign ministers gave the Commission a mandate to pursue four measures they believed would best protect European interests.</p>
<p>These were to forbid EU individuals or companies to comply with any U.S. court action; allow them to counter-sue to recover any damages awarded; prohibit individuals from litigant U.S. companies from travelling to the EU and compile a &quot;watch list&quot; of American companies or individuals involved in any litigation.</p>
<p>The EU has also to decide whether to escalate a dispute on the matter within the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>The new U.S. proposals are aimed at co-ordinating international activity at government, non-government and private sector level to ensure aid and assistance to Cuba helps the people rather than the government.</p>
<p>Diplomats said while opposition to the Helms-Burton Act would remain, opponents were prepared to show willingness to support these proposals.</p>
<p>This, they said, could be enough to help U.S. President Bill Clinton -- should he win the November election -- persuade Congress that there were good grounds to extend the suspension.</p>
<p>Eizenstat said Washington had no &quot;10 Commandments&quot; for the rest of the world to observe before it would consider further suspension of the act.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not saying what must be done and what must not be done,&quot; he said. &quot;We are seeking cooperation for what can be a genuine multinational effort to bring change.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
