<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32383" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Danone reports higher first-half profit.</title>
<headline>Danone reports higher first-half profit.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food giant Danone on Wednesday reported that first-half profit rose as a surge in its business outside Europe helped offset a rise in French taxes.</p>
<p>The company, best known for its yoghurts but also a seller of mineral waters, biscuits, pasta and beer, said its net attributable profit increased 2.3 percent to 1.73 billion francs ($340.3 million) from 1.70 billion in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>Operating profit rose 4.3 percent to 3.70 billion francs, while sales climbed 4.1 percent to 41.59 billion.</p>
<p>The comparison between Danone's first-half net income and the prior-year result is skewed by a rise in French taxes last year which applied to the full year but were recorded only in the second half, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;After adjustment for this factor, net income for the first half of 1996 showed a 5.1 percent increase,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Danone confirmed its previous forecast for a six percent full year profit rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating income from business outside western Europe rose 26.4 percent to make a significantly larger contribution to the consolidated total,&quot; said Danone, whose foreign activities range from biscuit factories in China to dairy firms in Argentina.</p>
<p>Within Europe, operating income rose in Danone's dairy products, biscuits, mineral water and containers activities in the first half but declined in grocery products, pasta and beer. ($ = 5.084 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
