<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32392" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish building materials firm CRH buys Tilcon.</title>
<headline>Irish building materials firm CRH buys Tilcon.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN, Ireland</dateline>
<text>
<p>CRH Plc said Wednesday it was buying U.S. construction materials company Tilcon from British conglomerate BTR Plc for $332 million in the largest acquisition deal in its history.</p>
<p>The Irish building materials firm said it would dispose of some parts of Tilcon and the effective cost of the acquisition would be about $254 million.</p>
<p>&quot;At an effective net cost to us of $254 million we have exceptional value, superb quarries and a most amazing fit with our present operations with pretty unique synergies,&quot; CRH Chief Executive Don Godson said in an interview.</p>
<p>Tilcon, one of the largest construction materials firms in the northeastern United States, would combine with CRH's U.S. operations to create &quot;an unassailable position in the northeast,&quot; Godson said.</p>
<p>BTR sold Tilcon as part of a major strategic overhaul involving the sale of non-core businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a situation where we had quite a motivated seller working to a different agenda, and we were a dispassionate and patient negotiator,&quot; Godson said. &quot;We got excellent value.&quot;</p>
<p>CRH announced the acquisition at the same time as reporting its half-year results. Pre-tax profits were 64.1 million punts ($103.6 million) in the first six months of 1996, 13 percent up on the same period the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;Increases in underlying profits in Ireland and the U.S. together with contributions from recent acquisitions were partly offset by declines in the UK and mainland Europe,&quot; Godson said.</p>
<p>He said the outlook for the rest of the year was generally positive, with Ireland and North America continuing to perform strongly.</p>
<p>Godson said CRH's policy of actively seeking smaller acquisitions would continue, helped by a stock offering that will raise a net 101 million punts ($164 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Our acquisition policy has been the secret of our success, and we'll keep following it,&quot; Godson said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN, Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
