<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32398" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bonds seen drifting to Friday.</title>
<headline>Belgian bonds seen drifting to Friday.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds, which ended a quiet but well supported Wednesday barely changed from overnight levels, are likely to continue drifting at least until Friday's U.S. jobs figures, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tuesday's NAPM was disappointing for the bears, but if you look at the breakdown it is by no means certain that a rate hike in the U.S. is necessary either,&quot; one trader said. &quot;So people are waiting for the August non-farm payrolls on Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For now the market is pretty strong because there are no sellers. There are a lot of locked-in profits that no one wants to take yet,&quot; he added. &quot; But when it moves it will be quick.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;As long as this enormous carry is there, the market will stay where it is,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Traders noted some slight steepening of the yield curve for short maturity paper, and some selling interest in very long maturities.</p>
<p>But they noted that few domestic players were involved and there was no real volume.</p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO ended the day yielding 6.63 percent against 6.64 on Tuesday, with the premium over Bunds an unchanged 24 basis points. The front month futures contract was up eight bps at 116.42. -- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
