<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32407" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian shares sluggish, Olivetti stands out.</title>
<headline>Italian shares sluggish, Olivetti stands out.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian stocks ended largely steady in sluggish trading on Wednesday, with the focus on Olivetti shares which bounced around violently after the surprising resignation late Tuesday of group chairman Carlo De Benedetti.</p>
<p>Olivetti rocked higher to be suspended early up 10 percent before the trading ceiling was widened to 15 percent and hit a high of 820 lire, up almost 13 percent, but then slipped back as dealers digested the sharp first-half loss, more restructuring and soaring debt. The shares ended up 3.31 percent at 750 lire.</p>
<p>All-share Mibtel ended up 0.03 percent up at 9,339 and the blue-chip Mib30 index off 0.15 percent at 13,861.</p>
<p>After the shock news of De Benedetti bowing out after a reported clash with chief executive Francesco Caio, many operators decided to go short of the stock, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the problems have not been addressed, a lawyer has taken over as chairman, CIR is still a big shareholder, and the the results were awful,&quot; said one share trader in Milan.</p>
<p>He added that it was still too early to say if Olivetti had turned the corner after reporting five years of losses with 1996 likely to make it a sixth year after a 440.2 billion lire pretax loss for the first half of 1996.</p>
<p>Overall, the market slipped after a slightly positive start following an early fall on Wall Street and continuing background worries over the 1997 Italian financial budget.</p>
<p>Among other stocks, Fiat continued to slide, off 0.53 percent at 4,464 lire and Montedison was down 0.97 percent at 945 lire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
