<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32410" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: High prices may curb German wheat exports - merchant.</title>
<headline>High prices may curb German wheat exports - merchant.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German hopes of exporting up to two million tonnes of wheat from its 18-million-tonne 1996 crop will only be achieved through price cuts or exceptional demand for German qualities, a country merchant said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports at the same rate as in previous years will only be placed if there is demand for our protein levels and blending qualities,&quot; said Hans-Joerg Rautenberg, who trades in the northern Schleswig-Holstein and Mecklenburg states.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise, the price is too high,&quot; said Rautenberg, who was addressing a regional harvest seminar.</p>
<p>Only 40 percent of harvests in the two states, which are key exporters, had been brought in.</p>
<p>Yields and volumes were fair to good but the share of premium wheat with 13-14 percent protein had fallen and relatively more feed wheat was being harvested.</p>
<p>Export brokers are asking 280-320 marks a tonne for fob Baltic wheat for 1996 shipping dates, the highest in the EU.</p>
<p>Fob Rostock wheat with 12.5 percent protein cost 285 marks while comparable qualities in the same lot size in Denmark cost 265, in Britain 260 marks and in France 270 marks.</p>
<p>Rautenberg said Germany would be competing with France in wheat import markets in the Benelux countries, which in recent years had regularly absorbed 800,000 tonnes of German wheat.</p>
<p>France, which achieved untypically high proteins about 13 percent, would also compete with Germany in Italy.</p>
<p>Protein and falling numbers at German suppliers in Bavaria state were lower than expected and transport of northern German qualities via the Baltic Sea to Italy expensive.</p>
<p>Britain and Ireland had reasonable domestic crops and might be turning to U.S. supplies, which was also true for Spain.</p>
<p>But Rautenberg still saw export chances in all of these EU countries, as well as in Greece and Portugal.</p>
<p>Although France had seen some exceptional qualities this year, they may turn out not to be widespread, he added.</p>
<p>German traders placed their biggest hopes on Poland -- which needed wheat imports as its own crop was sharply down after a harsh winter -- and former Soviet Union republics such as Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>But success in third countries depended on the export policy stance taken by the EU Commission.</p>
<p>On-farm feeding of wheat was likely to increase in the 1996/97 season under any export scenario.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
