<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32411" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Gas Natural, Pryca pull Madrid stocks down sharply.</title>
<headline>Gas Natural, Pryca pull Madrid stocks down sharply.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks closed sharply lower on Wednesday despite gains on other European bourses, with sharp losses in a few selected stocks dragging the indices lower, dealers said.</p>
<p>The general index fell 2.69 points, 0.76 percent, to 349.32 and the Ibex fell 37.78 points, 0.94 percent, to 3,966.22.</p>
<p>Gas Natural plummetted almost 10 percent in heavy trade after the government approved a much lower than expected increase in gas prices this year, and a fall in the tariff next year.</p>
<p>Repsol, which has an around 45 percent stake in Gas Natural, was relatively resilient, dropping 35 pesetas to 4,035.</p>
<p>Pryca shed 130 pesetas to 2,825 on expectations of poor second half sales, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in Gas Natural ended up affecting the whole market and now there seem to be more and more companies where there are reasons to sell,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Despite this, Telefonica rose 10 pesetas to 2,350, helped by upbeat full year forecasts and recommendations, dealers said.</p>
<p>The market seemed largely able to bypass initial jitters on news of a second U.S. air raid on Iraq, dealers said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
