<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32418" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Sweden presents proposal on openness at IGC.</title>
<headline>Sweden presents proposal on openness at IGC.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden, proud of its long tradition of open government and sexual equality, has put forward proposals aimed at boosting openness and equality between men and women in the European Union.</p>
<p>The two proposals on amending the EU treaty were presented at a two-day meeting of the inter-governmental conference (IGC) which ended on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Sweden's chief negotiator to the IGC, foreign ministry state secretary Gunnar Lund, said the idea of giving the public better access to EU documents had received mixed initial reactions from other EU countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We are presenting a proposal which amounts to writing into the treaty the principle of access to documents...the basic rule is that documents are public,&quot; Lund told journalists.</p>
<p>Under the Swedish proposal, EU documents would be available to the public unless they fell within the scope of certain &quot;strictly defined criteria&quot; for secrecy, Lund said.</p>
<p>If the proposal went through, it could be &quot;revolutionary for the culture which is cultivated in the EU's institutions,&quot; he told journalists.</p>
<p>The Swedish ideas on openness are spelled out in proposals to include articles 192a-c in the Treaty of Rome.</p>
<p>Sweden wants article 192a to state that any person shall have a right of access to documents held by Community institutions &quot;in conformity with the principles and within the limits determined by the Council pursuant to Article 129b.&quot;</p>
<p>But, the proposed text added, &quot;The right of access applies to internal working documents only if they have been handed out by the institution concerned.&quot;</p>
<p>According to the proposal for article 192b, the Council shall decide on the procedural rules for granting access to documents, limits on this right, rules obliging institutions to register documents and to keep public registers and rules obliging the institutions fo file documents.</p>
<p>&quot;The Council shall decide on limitations in accordance with the previous paragraph when this is necessary in order to satisfy interests that may be considered more important than the public right of access to documents,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The proposal for article 192c says that the Council may adopt provisions which empower the Court of Justice to accept appeals from people who have been denied access to a document.</p>
<p>Lund said several member states were open to the idea of having &quot;something of this character&quot; in the EU treaty.</p>
<p>But there had also been several question marks and some countries were markedly unresponsive to the idea.</p>
<p>The proposal on amending the treaty to boost equality between men and women would, among other things, include the promotion of equality as one of the Union's objectives in the EU treaty.</p>
<p>Lund said his impression was that a clear majority of countries wanted to strengthen the treaty in this regard but there were different opinions on how this should be done.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
