<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32427" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bund futures steady ahead of slew of data.</title>
<headline>Bund futures steady ahead of slew of data.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bund futures were little changed in dull trade on Wednesday as traders readied for a slew of German and U.S. data coming later this week.</p>
<p>The September Bund future was up three basis points to 97.26 in late trade, near its low for the day of 97.25.</p>
<p>Analysts said Bunds will likely continue to trade in uneventful ranges ahead of German unemployment and GDP data due Thursday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Of the two unemployment could have the greatest impact,&quot; said Craig Shute, economist at Bear Stearns in London. &quot;Jobs figures are more current and harder to predict.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Bundesbank will also hold a regular council meeting on Thursday, but all 10 economists surveyed by Reuters expect the central bank to keep rates on hold and six of the 10 said the Bundesbank will not make any further rate cuts in this cycle.</p>
<p>But the big event of the week is U.S. unemployment data due at 1230 GMT on Friday. Traders expect the figures to help clarify the near-term direction of U.S. interest rates which hold significant sway over Bunds.</p>
<p>The Bund/T-note spread narrowed to minus 62 basis points from minus 69 basis points. Analysts said Bunds have recently had trouble widening the spread beyond minus 70 basis points.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom + 49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
