<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32422" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SPD attacks Waigel's 1997 budget plans.</title>
<headline>SPD attacks Waigel's 1997 budget plans.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats (SPD) attacked Finance Minister Theo Waigel's 1997 budget plans on Wednesday, saying economic sluggishness and high joblessness have rent an 18 billion mark ($12.12 billion) gap between income and spending.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must say before budget discussions begin how it intends to cover this hole: through higher taxes, lower spending, more borrowing?&quot; said Karl Diller, fiscal policy spokesman of the SPD parliamentary faction.</p>
<p>The cabinet approved a draft of the 1997 budget in July, but the SPD-dominated upper house of parliament is expected to drag its heels when debate and voting take place in autumn. In the end, however, only lower house approval is required.</p>
<p>The first reading of the draft budget in the lower house is slated for next week but no vote is due until November.</p>
<p>Irmgard Karwatzki, state secretary at the finance ministry, said the main risk to the budget is the &quot;blockade politics&quot; of the SPD.</p>
<p>The draft 1997 budget provides for a federal deficit of 56.6 billion marks. The 18 billion marks cited by Diller would be over and above this sum.</p>
<p>Diller said the government was in danger of violating the constitution by raising the level of government borrowing above the level of public investment.</p>
<p>The goal of reducing the deficit to three percent of gross domestic product, as required for participation in the single European currency, was also at risk, he said.</p>
<p>Government spending in 1997 would be 10 billion marks more than in the draft budget, Diller said. Outlays for unemployment benefits and jobs creation schemes alone could see 8.7 billion in cost overruns.</p>
<p>The SPD also thinks the planned rise in child benefit and the minimum taxable income will be passed despite government opposition, reducing tax revenues by eight billion marks.</p>
<p>Diller made no proposal on how to fill the gap, saying it was up to the finance minister.</p>
<p>Karwatzki said the SPD had for years been obstructing government efforts to curb spending, but the government had no choice but to pursue this policy course.</p>
<p>Coalition budget experts are due to meet with Waigel over the weekend to hammer out further savings measures.</p>
<p>The federal government's 1996 deficit is now seen at 70 billion to 75 billion marks, compared with a budgeted figure of 60 billion marks.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 26097150 ($1=1.4846 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
