<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32425" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bombing of Iraq &quot;dangerous precedent&quot; -- Primakov.</title>
<headline>Bombing of Iraq &quot;dangerous precedent&quot; -- Primakov.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov said on Wednesday the U.S. missile strikes on Iraq were setting a dangerous precedent.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very dangerous situation, a precedent for the future,&quot; he told a news conference after meeting his German counterpart Klaus Kinkel.</p>
<p>&quot;If... we have a superpower, be it the United States, Europe or Russia, acting on its own initiative to use violence in a region without consulting an international organisation, in this case the U.N. Security Council, there will be conflict.&quot;</p>
<p>It was the third time in two days that Primakov had voiced strong public criticism of the U.S. action.</p>
<p>In Vaduz, Liechtenstein, earlier in the day he had sounded a warning that the strikes could unleash &quot;catastrophic consequences&quot; and &quot;anarchy&quot; on the world scene.</p>
<p>At the Bonn news conference, he said the U.S. action, intended to punish Baghdad for sending its forces to attack Kurds in a U.N.-implemented no-fly area in the north of the country, was not covered by any U.N. resolution.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to keep to a system where force (against a sovereign country) is used only by the Security Council,&quot; Primakov said, citing examples such as Yugoslavia where joint international efforts had dealt with conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;There are plenty of other regions where we are working for stabilisation jointly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>in Moscow, President Boris Yeltsin's chief-of-staff, Anatoly Chubais, said Yeltsin viewed the U.S. raids on Iraq as &quot;very dangerous&quot;, and that further strikes would be &quot;impermissible&quot;.</p>
<p>For years under the old Soviet system, Primakov was an academic specialist on the Middle East who frequently met Iraqi President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>Speaking in Berne on Tuesday, shortly after the first wave of U.S. missile strikes, he had suggested that they had been launched in part to help President Bill Clinton's re-election bid.</p>
<p>The attacks, he said, &quot;cannot be supported by anyone at all, except those who put domestic politics, including pre-electoral questions, above all else.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
