<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32438" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU divisions on Iraq cast shadow over meeting.</title>
<headline>EU divisions on Iraq cast shadow over meeting.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Divisions among European Union countries over Washington's actions in Iraq are expected to overshadow a weekend meeting of EU foreign ministers in Ireland, called in part to find common ground on matters of diplomacy.</p>
<p>The meeting -- on Saturday and Sunday in Tralee, County Kerry -- is also expected to discuss Bosnia, the flagging Middle East peace process and trade relations with the United States.</p>
<p>There are no formal plans to discuss Iraq at the long-scheduled meeting. But EU officials said the U.S. missile attacks this week and Europe's failure to agree a joint position on them had thrust the issue on to the agenda.</p>
<p>EU heavyweights Britain and Germany have strongly supported America's cruise missile strikes on targets in Iraq to punish the government of Saddam Hussein for attacks into the so-called Kurdish safe havens in the north.</p>
<p>But France, Spain and Italy have studiously withheld endorsement.</p>
<p>Senior EU diplomats failed on Tuesday to agree a joint position for the 15-nation bloc, leaving the matter to the ministers at the weekend.</p>
<p>The Tralee meeting is a twice-yearly informal gathering without a formal agenda at which theoretically no decisions can be taken.</p>
<p>But these informal meetings are often used as a way of setting EU policy.</p>
<p>Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring, host in Tralee, has told his colleagues he wants to discuss what response the EU should have to the September 14 elections in Bosnia.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody knows they won't be fair and free but they will be moderately democratic,&quot; said one diplomat, adding that the main task afterwards would be to build up Bosnian institutions.</p>
<p>Carl Bildt, the international community's Bosnia moderator, will brief ministers on Saturday. Policy on other parts of the former Yugoslavia will also be discussed.</p>
<p>Spring has also asked his colleagues to consider the EU's role in the Middle East peace process. &quot;We will need to consider, in particular, how we can best encourage Israel to re-engage in the peace process,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>Diplomats said there was some frustration in the bloc over the policies of the new Israeli government. Israeli Foreign Minister David Levy was to meet Spring in Dublin on Thursday.</p>
<p>The ministers will also consider what steps, if any, the EU needs to take to respond to U.S. trade laws designed to punish Cuba, Iran and Libya.</p>
<p>The laws, known as the Helms-Burton and D'Amato acts, have infuriated the EU and America's trading partners because of provisions threatening sanctions on non-U.S. companies doing certain types of business with the three companies.</p>
<p>Retaliation measures, drafted by the European Commission at the ministers request, will be presented at the meeting, diplomats said.</p>
<p>In internal EU matters, the ministers will discuss the status of the inter-governmental conference (IGC), the bloc's review of its treaties.</p>
<p>Spring is expected to push for a date to be set for a special EU summit, due in October. Although EU leaders asked for the meeting, they have been unable to agree on a date, providing EU presidency Ireland with a logistical headache.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
