<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32436" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian BBL sees FY96 pft growing 18 pct.</title>
<headline>Belgian BBL sees FY96 pft growing 18 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank Bruxelles Lambert SA confirmed analysts expectations on Wednesday about the health of Belgian bank profits in 1996, reporting earnings jumped 18 percent in the six-months to June 30 and predicting similar growth for the whole year.</p>
<p>&quot;These results tell us a lot about what will happen this year,&quot; chief executive officer Daniel Cardon de Lichtbuer told journalists.</p>
<p>BBL, the first of Belgium's big banks to release interim 1996 earnings, said half-year net profit rose to 5.07 billion Belgian francs ($165.9 million) from 4.30 billion in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>Analysts polled by Reuters earlier this week predicted a profit in the range of 4.9 to 5.1 billion francs.</p>
<p>BBL said it was helped by a favourable interest rate environment and sharp rise in trading and other income.</p>
<p>Net interest income -- the difference paid on deposits and income received on longer-term loans -- rose 12 percent to 26.40 billion from 23.58 billion Belgian francs.</p>
<p>Trading and commission income rose 32 percent to 17.83 billion francs, with the biggest rise being recorded in forex and securities trading, up 56 percent to 4.93 billion francs.</p>
<p>Cardon said that without increased provisions, in part to prepare for the arrival of Europe's single currency, and higher taxes the rise in earnings would have been stronger.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profit was up 25 percent at 9.31 billion francs, he noted. Depreciation, write-downs and provisions -- which included a first 500 million franc charge for the introduction of the euro -- rose 42 percent to 8.63 billion francs.</p>
<p>Cardon predicted BBL would have to spend about 1.4 billion Belgian francs, plus an additional two percent-a-year in operating costs over four years to update accounting and computer systems and train staff to handle the euro.</p>
<p>Cardon -- who retires at the end of this year -- said BBL had now fulfilled the financial targets he set when he took over as chief executive four years ago at the end of a battle for control over the bank between shareholders Groupe ING and Groupe Bruxelles Lambert.</p>
<p>The bank, as expected, named director Michel Tilmant, a former JP Morgan executive, as his successor.</p>
<p>Cardon admitted, however, he would probably leave the bank before steering it to an alliance with a domestic or foreign partner -- a goal he made public in a newspaper interview in August 1995.</p>
<p>It emerged earlier this year that ING had blocked a possible link between BBL and Generale Bank, Belgium's biggest bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything for the moment is at a standstill, certainly for the coming months and perhaps years. Everybody is looking at the future...(but) there's no obvious solution,&quot; Cardon said.</p>
<p>He repeated however his belief that Belgium was overbanked and that some form of shakeup would come, either before or after the introduction of the euro in 1999.</p>
<p>Belgium's other main banks - Generale Bank, Credit Communal de Belgique/Gemeentekrediet (CCB) and Kredietbank - publish their results on September 10, 11 and 12.</p>
<p>The head of French Credit Local de France - with whom CCB plans to link later this autumn - said on Wednesday CCB would report &quot;very favourable, I could even say excellent profits.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Nick Antonovics, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6817, Fax +32 2 230 7710 ($ = 30.56 Belgian Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
