<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32431" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy budget spending cuts, revenue mix unchanged.</title>
<headline>Italy budget spending cuts, revenue mix unchanged.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>After two days of talks among government ministers preparing Italy's 1997 budget, the budget's target blend consisting of two-thirds reduced spending and one-third greater revenue remains unchanged.</p>
<p>Budget ministry undersecretary Giorgio Macciotta told reporters nothing had emerged at the meetings so far to suggest a different blend.</p>
<p>Meetings continued on Wednesday with talks between Treasury and Budget Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi and Health Minister Rosy Bindi.</p>
<p>Ministers in charge of drafting the package have been holding talks with cabinet colleagues on how to pare spending.</p>
<p>The team of troubleshooters, led by Ciampi, has already met Labour Minister Tiziano Treu and state pensions fund chief Gianni Billia.</p>
<p>Under Italian law, the budget package must be presented to parliament by September 30. Both chambers then have until December 31 to approve it.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left government is aiming to cut the public sector borrowing requirement by 32.4 trillion lire in 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
