<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32437" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU defuses Volkswagen subsidies row.</title>
<headline>EU defuses Volkswagen subsidies row.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a typical EU face-saving compromise, the European Commission agreed on Wednesday to end momentarily a bitter dispute with Germany over subsidies paid to Volkswagen AG VW, some of which the Commission had ruled illegal.</p>
<p>In practice, this means the case could take at least two years to be finally settled by the European Union courts.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the agreement announced by European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert, Volkswagen will keep 91 million marks in subsidies it received recently from the German eastern state of Saxony despite the Commission's negative ruling in late June.</p>
<p>In return, the German government pledged early on Wednesday to block an equivalent amount of federal aid that had been authorised by the Commission but not yet paid to the car manufacturer, Van Miert told a news conference.</p>
<p>Van Miert, whose main priority was to put an end to the &quot;blatant illegality&quot; created by the Saxony move in July, said the illegal aid would thus be &quot;neutralised&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;At the federal level there is a commitment to freeze an amount which is equivalent or parallel to that (contested) amount,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he warned that if this did not happen, the Commission would seek to have the illegal money repaid immediately by filing an injunction with the European Court.</p>
<p>&quot;We took the decision today that the Commission will take an injunction if need be,&quot; Van Miert said. He thought, however, that the federal government was firmly determined to put some discipline in subsidies paid in the former east Germany.</p>
<p>The compromise was welcomed by Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision is an important contribution to bringing back onto a quieter track the discussion over VW's Saxony investments and the protection of needed help for the building of the eastern states,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Commission cleared in late June 540 million marks ($363.7 million) federal and Saxony aid, of a proposed 780 million marks, in support of Volkswagen investments at its plants of Mosel and Chemnitz. The powerful manufacturer counter-attacked by threatening to end its investment in the region already plagued by high unemployment.</p>
<p>The European Court of First Instance, the EU's lower court, will have to decide on the substance of the case. Saxony has already filed a complaint against the Commission, while the Commission will lodge a separate complaint in the coming days.</p>
<p>Court actions usually take up to two years, but a final decision could take even longer given that both parties could appeal to the European Court of Justice.</p>
<p>At the centre of Saxony's defense is the highly contested article 92 (2c) in the EU treaty which allows subsidies to be paid to the former east Germany &quot;to compensate for the economic disadvantages&quot; caused by the division of the country until 1990.</p>
<p>The Commission consistently refused to consider the Volkswagen subsidies under such provisions, citing instead strict guidelines on aid to the car industry designed essentially to avoid adding to the overcapacity in the sector.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the general sentiment at the Commission is that the rules have already been excessively bent to cater for the German problem and that enough subsidies have been channeled eastwards.</p>
<p>The fight over the subsidies paid to Volkswagen in Saxony has been going on since 1994 when the Commission first approved an aid package to the carmaker. It reopened the file in 1995 following evidence that the investment for which the money was agreed had not been completed.</p>
<p>Van Miert said on Wednesday that there had been suspicions about another 16 million marks, but the German authorities had confirmed on Tuesday that this amount was a legal loan granted under market conditions. ($1=1.4846 mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
