<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32435" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: LCAG says may increase ex-Sweden capacity.</title>
<headline>LCAG says may increase ex-Sweden capacity.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo AG Northern Europe said on Wednesday its Boeing 747 freighter from Stockholm airport was running at 95 percent capacity, and it may increase the frequency of the once-weekly flight.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo Northern Europe director Martin Schlingensiepen said in an interview that apart from during the quiet summer months, the airline was filling its Boeing 747 freighter from Stockholm to Frankfurt to 95 percent capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;Our flights, export-wise, are basically always full and we are also looking at expanding this once-weekly service in the future,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said no major rate increases were planned for the autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;For Scandinavia in general I don't see major changes for this October. There might be some touch up to some destinations, but basically we will remain stable,&quot; Schlingensiepen said.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason why we are not increasing rates is because the competitive environment is strong and we are traditionally on the upper end of the scale of rates compared with our competitors.&quot;  </p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo said on Monday that its prices from Germany to various destinations would increase by up to 10 percent. It said prices to Scandinavian capitals Copenhagen and Oslo would increase by between five and 10 percent.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo, an autonomous unit of German carrier Deutsche Lufthansa AG, said earlier on Wednesday it had agreed with Singapore Airlines to add two freighter services between Frankfurt and Singapore.</p>
<p>These new services will link with the Lufthansa cargo hub at Sharjah in the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>Schlingensiepen said he was considering ways to expand capacity from Sweden, which could include a direct link to Lufthansa's hub at Sharjah.</p>
<p>&quot;The first step is to strengthen the feeder capacity from Arlanda to Frankfurt and from there to the worldwide network.</p>
<p>&quot;Our next idea is to maybe offer a direct link from Sweden to Sharjah directly, to bypass Frankfurt which saves time and then in Sharjah (where) we relocate the shipments on other freighters,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be very fast and efficient to Southeast Asia, Australia and the Middle East.&quot;  </p>
<p>In April, Lufthansa launched an all-freight Stockholm-Frankfurt-Sao Paulo weekly service using a Boeing 747 freighter version with 108 tonne capacity.</p>
<p>Otherwise the airline flies a DC-8, with a capacity of 48 tonnes, on Saturdays to Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Schlingensiepen said he agreed with the view of other market players that there was little if any room for more capacity on the ex-Sweden market.</p>
<p>&quot;There are limits to freighter capacity and I think the maximum has been reached. Otherwise yields will go down and we will fight for cargo and that is unhealthy for the whole industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;There is a good market if you compare Sweden with other European countries. There is still lot of cargo trucked to mainland Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>Regarding Lufthansa Cargo's cooperation with its Scandinavian partner's SAS Cargo, Schlingensiepen said working groups were currently discussing ways to interlink networks and work together on marketing, sales, quality and handling.</p>
<p>&quot;(There is) a major focus on network planning of our freighters, which will also include the new SAS 747 freighter, and then having access to each others' networks, so special pro-rate agreements for both companies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important point, if we get those basics done, is definitely on the sales side. Both companies should enter the market in a similar way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Abigail Schmelz, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
