<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32442" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Rescuers find 17 bodies in India house collapse.</title>
<headline>Rescuers find 17 bodies in India house collapse.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rescue workers searching through the debris of a building that collapsed in the heart of India's commercial capital found 11 more bodies on Wednesday, taking the death toll to 17, fire brigade officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have pulled out 17 bodies from the debris,&quot; a fire brigade spokesman said. He said the number of injured remained at 10 on Wednesday, a day after the three-storey office and residential building collapsed.</p>
<p>Officials said they were continuing their search through the rubble, although reports still were confused over the number of people believed to have been inside when the building collapsed shortly after noon on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect there will definitely be two or three more bodies, at least,&quot; said D.E. Billimoria, a relief worker.</p>
<p>A lawyer's black coat flapped forlornly in the breeze as it hung from a nail on a third-floor wall. Stacks of legal briefs tied in red tape were scattered among the debris.</p>
<p>Firemen said a law professor with offices on the third floor was among the first few pulled out of the wreck and taken to hospital.</p>
<p>Officials had initially estimated more than 25 people had been trapped.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a printing press on the ground floor, and a kind of dormitory and club on the first floor,&quot; Chief Fire Officer D.J. Kulkarni of the Bombay Fire Brigade told Reuters. &quot;None of the tenants can say exactly how many people were there.&quot;</p>
<p>The building, Tawadia Chambers, was in the centre of a dense cluster of old buildings close to the heart of Bombay's business district.</p>
<p>Billimoria said police, firemen and home guards had worked through the night to clear the rubble by hand. The narrow lane to the building prevented relief workers taking in heavy lift machinery to help remove it.</p>
<p>&quot;It is about three-fourths removed,&quot; he said. &quot;We will work through the night today as well and clear it.&quot;</p>
<p>Residents said the building was more than 40 years old. But neither they nor the authorities could say why it collapsed. The landlord was among those who died, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no sound when it fell. We just heard a small thud, &quot; said Gaffar who works in a building nearby.</p>
<p>&quot;It looked in good shape. There were no props or anything,&quot; said Amarnath Dubey, the civic official in charge of the area.</p>
<p>Civic authorities have given the three families who lived in the building temporary homes till they find new accommodation.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been given a room nearby,&quot; said Hazel Furtado, a teenage resident whose father Dennis, 62, died when his home fell in on him. &quot;But it's dark, and small, and there's no electricity. It's nothing like home.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of Bombay's buildings are poorly maintained because the city has frozen rents at 40-year-old levels, and landlords have no financial incentive to maintain them. Weakened by wind and heavy rains in the monsoons, many of them collapse each year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
