<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32440" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Ex-Frankfurt rates slump ends, autumn recovery seen.</title>
<headline>Ex-Frankfurt rates slump ends, autumn recovery seen.</headline>
<byline>Paul Needham</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air cargo rates at Germany's export gateway stabilised in August after falling for several months and look set for gradual recovery in the autumn, Reuters' research shows.</p>
<p>The widespread spring and early summer spot pricing prompted by stagnating volumes at Frankfurt airport and falling market rates has clearly decreased, industry sources said.</p>
<p>They said business was unusually healthy in August given the holiday season after total ex-Germany volumes rose 5.4 percent in July and the average yield fall slowed to 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>Reuters average market rates, reflecting official tariffs, discounts and spot rates, thus show a slight August rise although most standard rates have not changed.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo plans to raise rates to selected destinations from October 1 have prompted mixed reactions with some carriers quick to follow suit and others maintaining status quo.</p>
<p>Miguel Herter, Iberia cargo manager Germany, said Lufthansa generated the summer rates fall through discounting and ad hoc rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The national carrier has gone on to the market with prices which we must follow. The market is collapsing and it is a buyers' market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ulf Steinmann, Swissair cargo manager Germany, said he had lost clients to Lufthansa this summer and had no plans for rates rises this autumn apart from on some African and east European routes. He said he foresaw no exports upswing this autumn, adding that the market remains plagued by over-capacity.</p>
<p>Martinair central Europe cargo sales director Heiner Sass said: &quot;I think the market will stabilise in the winter with a slight rise but things are dependent on the dollar rate and political development.&quot;</p>
<p>He highlighted the Far East, Australasia and possibly the USA as destinations where higher prices could be achieved.</p>
<p>Joachim Brouwer, Sabena cargo manager Germany, said he foresees stable ex-Germany market rates this autumn but would follow any Lufthansa price hike instantly.</p>
<p>Dirk Steiger, Alitalia cargo manager Germany, said: &quot;I am hopeful that the market will stabilise but I do not see a good chance to raise rates because competition within Europe is too high.&quot;</p>
<p>Cargo volumes to North America improved 2.9 percent in July, the best showing since April, although the average yield has fallen steadily since January to 1.84 marks, the latest CASS figures showed.</p>
<p>Rafael Rivas, Northwest Airlines cargo sales manager, said July and August have been stronger than usual and there was little sign of the traditional summer slump.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope Lufthansa will increase its prices and we would definitely follow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>United Airlines cargo sales manager Robert Blythe added: &quot;The volumes are coming back and rates are stable at present.&quot;</p>
<p>Petra Lentes, TWA cargo sales manager, said she felt her standard rate of 1.50 marks for the daily Boeing 767-200 passenger flight to New York was fairly high.</p>
<p>Asian carriers such as Singapore Airlines, Pakistan International Airways and Kuwait Airways often under-cut market rates on North America-bound flights stopping in Frankfurt, she pointed out.</p>
<p>Swissair's Ulf Steinmann said volumes to Chicago and Atlanta remain high but Miami and Los Angeles are less in demand.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;The prices cannot sink any more because that would be ruinous, although with the fight for market share anything is possible. There will not be price rises in the near future.&quot;</p>
<p>Rates to south-east Asia picked up in August after a continual fall this year but revenue growth is still lagging significantly behind a double-figure tonnage increase, CASS figures showed.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo has now set the rates pace for the autumn by announcing rises of near 10 percent for Singapore and Bangkok.</p>
<p>Singapore Airlines Germany cargo manager Heinz Icha said he has been forced by market pressure to reduce rates this summer but he will now match the Lufthansa rise in expectation of a further rise in demand this autumn.</p>
<p>&quot;We plan a rate increase of about 10 percent. We will increase at about the same level (as Lufthansa),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ingo Zimmer, managing director ATC Aviation Services, gsa for Royal Brunei Airlines, said business for south-east Asia has been good through the summer.</p>
<p>With rising volumes and planned additional capacity, the Far East looks in line for selective rates rises after a steady fall from April to a July average of about four marks for Korea/Japan.</p>
<p>Lufthansa said it will raise Hong Kong rates by up to 10 percent but appears to have left Korea and Japan at current levels.</p>
<p>Alitalia's Steiger said European demand for Korea means the airline plans additional freighter services from Milan to Seoul this autumn.</p>
<p>Market players expect demand for China to rise in the coming weeks leading to higher rates to destinations such as Shanghai and Beijing.</p>
<p>Sass, of Martinair, said he foresaw strong demand for the airline's twice-weekly Amsterdam to Guangzhou B747-200 freighter starting on October 1.</p>
<p>&quot;We are the only European carrier which will fly directly to the southern region of China,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Transport routes will change and go directly to the region. The direct transport volume to China will grow and the influence of Hong Kong will fall in time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Alitalia's Steiger said he believed rates to Shanghai could rise to the 3.50 marks level because of growing project business in China and the accompanying need for main-deck capacity for oversize consignments.</p>
<p>The Italian carrier, one of just three European airlines flying to Shanghai, is seeing very high load factors on its weekly freighter, he added.</p>
<p>Steinmann, of Swissair, noted: &quot;The automobile industry will have to deliver (to China) by air as long as the cheapest way by ship is not organised and the Chinese are not able to do it themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>Demand for South American destinations out of Germany is booming at present although ex-Frankfurt rates are under pressure from cheaper prices obtainable at other European airports, industry players said.</p>
<p>The region saw a 7.3 percent year-on-year tonnage growth to July with a 4.5 percent revenue rise, Cass figures showed.</p>
<p>Iberia's Herter said: &quot;We are fully booked out to Argentina like all other carriers. This market will develop much more with annual growth of 20-30 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>He described ex-Germany rates to Argentina as stable since last summer, but said he had not been able to increase them in line with demand due to competition from Air France and Lufthansa.</p>
<p>Demand for Brazil is exploding, Chile is growing steadily and both Venzuela and Peru have picked up, he added.</p>
<p>Steinmann at Swissair said he expected strong German demand for his 25 tonnes blocked space allotment on the new Swissair freighter to Sao Paulo starting September 23.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is ready. I think the space we have may not be enough if everything comes which has been discussed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The overall African market has slumped massively this year to July, although demand for the top destination, South Africa, remains strong, sources said.</p>
<p>Sabena's Brouwer said: &quot;The African market fluctuates a lot. The tonnages are very variable.</p>
<p>&quot;For South Africa I see a good volume situation but I am worried about the price development due to the over-capacity which has been created since last winter,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Martinair's Sass said he would market the airline's proposed Johannesburg freighter service primarily by price.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a small (price) difference to move into the market, that is legitimate but we have no interest in destroying the price. We will orientate ourselves to the market price,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Swissair's Steinmann added: &quot;The prices gives us concern. We have to react constantly to the price discounts being offered by national carriers and nonstop carriers.&quot;</p>
<p>ATC's Ingo Zimmer, also gsa for Zimbabwean cargo airline Affretair, said there is still over-capacity to South Africa but demand continues to rise. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 8982 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
