<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32447" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - September 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - September 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DAILY STAR</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina said modern infrastructural facilities would be built in the port city of Chittagong to attract foreign investment in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party has accused the ruling Awami League of using the administration to &quot;forcibly&quot; get its candidates returned in the by-election, due on Thursday in 15 constituencies.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>Authorities have withdrawn all officers and constables from a police outpost in central Manikganj district for their connections with drug smugglers.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Some 270 Rohingya refugees were sent to their homeland in Burma on Tuesday, bringing the number of refugees repatriated to 204,565 since the process began in September 1992.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Bangladesh is amending its century-old Trust Act to allow investments of provident and gratuity funds in the securities market.</p>
<p>Turkish ambassador in Dhaka Kemal Ozcan Davas said his country's entrepreneurs were eager to invest in Bangladesh's energy and telecommunication sector. -- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
