<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32454" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - September 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - September 4.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Telephone: 11-3324842, 11-3761233; Fax: 91-11-3351006 Internet : biznis.news@forums.sprintrpg.sprint.com</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>Hindustan Times</p>
<p>U.S. LAUNCHES MISSILE ATTACK ON IRAQ, INDIA CONCERNED</p>
<p>India expressed grave concern over the firing of U.S. missiles against Iraq. U.S forces fired 27 cruise missiles to punish President Saddam Hussein after his forces attacked Kurdish rebels. Iraq said five people were killed and 19 wounded. It claimed the missiles struck population centres and that most casualties were civilians but give no details of targets. India expressed grave concern over the U.S. attack on Iraq and said it could adversely affect peace and security in the region. The external affairs ministry said enforcement actions under U.N. security Council resolutions could only be taken by the Security Council itself.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Economic Times</p>
<p>ATTACK ON IRAQ COULD RAISE INDIAN OIL IMPORT BILL</p>
<p>The U.S. missile attack on Iraq may cause a substantial increase in India's budgeted annual oil import bill of $7.59 billion, oil ministry officials said. In the aftermath of the attack on Iraq, international oil prices rose. Other officials in the oil ministry fear the oil pool account deficit could touch 110 billion rupees by the year-end. The government may take measures to contain the damage by scaling down the increase in excise and customs duties, sources added.</p>
<p>INDIAN OIL CORP MAY LOSE $200,000</p>
<p>Indian Oil Corp (IOC) stands to lose at least $200,000 as a result of the spurt in international oil prices that followed the U.S. missile attack on Iraq. The IOC is the sole canalising agent for the country's entire requirements and imports about two million tonnes of crude oil and petroleum products each month. The current setback has been caused by a rise in international crude prices.</p>
<p>BPL US WEST TO INVEST 30 BLN RUPEES IN 10 YEARS</p>
<p>BPL US West Cellular Telecommunications Services Pvt Ltd is set to launch its cellular phone services from October. BPL US West expects to have a subscriber base in excess of 200,000 by the year 2000. The company is launching its services in a phased way in the three areas, Maharashtra, Goa, Tamil Nadu-Pondicherry and Kerala. The overall investment proposed by the company, over the 10-year frame, is pegged at around 30 billion rupees. The company's investment by March 1997 will be in the region of seven billion rupees.</p>
<p>AIG SEEN SHYING AWAY FROM STAKE IN FASCEL LTD</p>
<p>The American International Group (AIG), one of the leading investment funds of the US, has deferred plans to buy 19.6 percent equity in Fascel Ltd. Fascel Ltd is the cellular telecommunication company of the Himachal Futuristic Communications Ltd (HFCL) group. Sources said the board of directors of AIG, which met 10 day ago in New York, rejected the plan to invest $20 million in Fascel. AIG's decision came in wake of recent events in India and suspicion cast on HFCL in the the scandal involving former communication minister Sukh Ram.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Times Of India</p>
<p>GUJARAT DY SPEAKER RECOGNISES DISSIDENT GROUP</p>
<p>The deputy speaker of the legislative Assembly in Gujarat has recognised the breakaway faction of the ruling Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), led by Sankersinh Vaghela. The rebel group claimed to have the support of 46 legislators out of BJP's original strength of 120. The ruling faction, on the other hand, claimed to enjoy the support of 94 legislators. This has given a new turn to the political crisis in the state that arose from a recent split in the ruling party. The BJP government had earlier asked the state governor to convene an assembly session so that it could prove its majority on the floor of the House.  </p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NEW COMPANIES ACT TO CURB ISSUE OF DUPLICATE SHARES</p>
<p>The Companies Act of 1956, currently being redrafted by a seven member committee, may restrict the issue of duplicate shares by companies to protect investor's interest. The redrafting committee plans to bring about changes in the share transfer and registry norms for corporates by allowing computerised data storage facilities. The period for which share registry data has to be maintained by companies may also be cut down.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>TATA SONS TO PAY ONE BLN RUPEES FOR UNISYS STAKE</p>
<p>Tata Sons Ltd, the holding company of the Tata group, is buying a 40 percent stake of the US company Unisys in the joint venture Tata Unisys Ltd (TUL). Tata Sons will pay Unisys a sum of one billion rupees at approximately 400 rupees per share for the purpose. While the central bank had already cleared the deal, the bourse regulator's approval was still awaited, sources said. With this, the stake of Tata Sons in TUL will now go up to 80 percent.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOMBAY BOURSE INDEX LOSES 78 POINTS</p>
<p>Share prices witnessed an across-the-board collapse as the news about the U.S. attack on Iraq hit the stock market. The market sentiment was also affected by the postponement of the Finance Minister's budget speech in the Parliament. The Bombay Stock Exchange sensitive index closed at 3484.68, showing a net loss of 78.3 points over the previous close. The 50-share National Stock Exchange index fell 13.64 points to a provisional 1,023.36.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>BOURSE REGULATOR ASKED TO PREPARE POLICY ON SHORT SELLING</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has asked the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI), the bourse regulator, to prepare a policy framework for short selling in shares. The ministry has, however, ruled out a total ban on short selling. SEBI has been asked to define short selling, as it is not clear under any act of law, including the stock exchange bylaws, the Securities Contracts (Regulations) Act and SEBI regulations. SEBI has been asked to work out parameters and fix permissible limits for short sales, after consultations with the bourses.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>INDIAN TELECOM FIRMS TARGET US RETAIL INVESTORS</p>
<p>Lured by the U.S. capital market, the country's telecommunications (telecom) firms were opting to raise equity by issuing American Depositary Receipts (ADRs), investment bankers said. Telecom companies including Hutchison Max Telecom, Bharati Telecom and a BPL group firm planned to raise some $500 million through ADRs. An ADR requires a higher standard of accounting and disclosure than a GDR (global depository receipt) and it undergoes an extensive due diligence process. That is why the ADR is seen as an investment that is more attractive, explained the bankers.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>QUICK PREPAYMENT OF DEMAND LOANS MAY BE PERMITTED</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) may for the first time allow corporates to pre-pay demand loans after six months and extend the repayment tenure to 18 months from the current 12 months. Until now, prepayment was allowed only in term loans. RBI also plans to raise the loan component of the maximum permissible bank finance to 80 percent from the current 60 percent level. In another development, corporates availing of consortium advances are likely to be barred from accessing funds from banks outside the consortium.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>TELECOM COMPANIES REFUSE TO ACCEPT INTERCONNECT PACT</p>
<p>Four holders of letters of intent (LoI) for basic telecommunication services have refused to accept the interconnect agreement of the Department of Telecommunications (DoT). These telecommunication companies include HFCL, RPG-NTT, Essar and Koshika. DoT had set a September 12 deadline for these LoI holders to sign the licence agreement and pay up the first installment of licence fees. Major operators in the telecom sector believed that DoT was trying to gain undue advantages and arbitrary powers by imposing its interconnect agreement on the private companies.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
