<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32457" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Bhutto warns opponents of her street power.</title>
<headline>Bhutto warns opponents of her street power.</headline>
<byline>Raja Asghar</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto warned political opponents on Wednesday of her populist support when she again rejected opposition demands for early elections under a caretaker government.</p>
<p>In a hard-hitting speech in parliament, Bhutto called the demand for a caretaker government as a brainchild of &quot;exploiters, fortune seekers and adventurers&quot;.</p>
<p>In an earlier speech on Wednesday to a public rally at Dargai in the North West Frontier province, she urged opposition parties to have talks with her on national issues rather than threatening agitation to oust her 34-month-old government.</p>
<p>&quot;The poor people of the country are with me, the street power is with me, the silent majority is with me, they are not with you,&quot; Bhutto said while addressing herself to opposition parties now campaiging against her.</p>
<p>The opposition parties accuse Bhutto's government of corruption and misrule and want her to step down. Alternatively, they want President Farooq Leghari, a member of Bhutto's Pakistan People's Party, to sack the prime minister and appoint a neutral caretaker government to hold elections.</p>
<p>Bhutto denies the corruption charges and says she will complete her five-year tenure until October 1998.</p>
<p>The corruption charges against the government are being levelled by &quot;those people who themselves are most corrupt and want to resist the tightening noose of law&quot;, Bhutto said in an interview with a local television channel shown on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In her speech to parliament's lower house, Bhutto seemed particulary angry with an opposition deputy's suggestion for forming a consensus caretaker government excluding both Bhutto and her arch-rival, former prime minister Nawaz Sharif.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of a consensus government,&quot; she said about the proposal from Mehmud Khan Achakzai, leader of Pashtunkhwa Milli Awami Party based in the the southwestern province of Baluchistan.</p>
<p>&quot;What sort of consensus government they are demanding -- a consensus government of vested interests, a consensus government of Satans?&quot; she asked.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't agree with the member from Baluhcistan who says we should now say no to both Benazir Bhutto and Nawaz Sharif,&quot; the prime minisrter said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the right of the people of Pakistan to choose their representatives and in a Moslem state whosoever tries to snatch this right is a usurper and Jihad (holy war) must be waged against him.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
