<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32475" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani Hubco rated long-term buy.</title>
<headline>Pakistani Hubco rated long-term buy.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's Hub Power Company Ltd (Hubco), which began production in July, is a high-yielding, undervalued stock to be viewed as a long-term buy, HSBC James Capel said in a research report received on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The private Hubco power project commissioned the first of four 323-megawatt oil-fired units in July.</p>
<p>&quot;Prior to this, Hubco was valued as a quasi-equity due to guaranteed returns, but commencement of production will now unlock the upside potential for investors,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>It added that Hubco's many contractual agreements minimised risk and guaranteed earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;If valued as a bond, Hubco currently gives a nominal dollar yield of 13 percent. However, on an equity valuation basis, the present value of Hubco's free cash flow is 64 rupees, after commencement of operations on July 1,&quot; James Capel said.</p>
<p>&quot;Hubco provides a good long-term buy for investors looking for a high-yield Pakistani stock with minimum downside.&quot;</p>
<p>The brokerage said Hubco provided an excellent hedge against rupee devaluation as its returns were indexed to the dollar.</p>
<p>The power plant, near the southern port of Karachi, is due to be completed by April 1997 and construction has been on schedule so far.  </p>
<p>&quot;Pre-completion risk is decreasing as Hubco successfully reaches each construction milestone,&quot; the report noted.</p>
<p>It said Pakistan had a shortage of 2,000 megawatts at peak demand, and that demand was growing by eight percent a year. Hubco, Pakistan's only independent power producer listed locally and abroad, offered an exceptional chance to take part in the energy sector's growth, it added.</p>
<p>James Capel forecast Hubco's net profit at 5.516 billion rupees on sales of 17.392 billion rupees in calendar 1997, rising to 9.797 billion on sales of 25.589 billion in 1998, and easing to 6.523 billion on sales of 22.866 billion in 1999.</p>
<p>It forecast earnings per share in nominal dollars at $0.13 in 1997, $0.22 in 1998 and $0.13 in 1999.</p>
<p>Britain's National Power is the main equity sponsor and operator of Hubco, with a 24.4 percent stake, followed by Saudi Arabia's Xenel, with 14.5 percent.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
