<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32480" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan's Dhan Fibres to verify shares.</title>
<headline>Pakistan's Dhan Fibres to verify shares.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Karachi Stock Exchange (KSE) has asked Dhan Fibres Ltd to verify its shares after the company found counterfeit share certificates in circulation, a KSE official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to start reverification of Dhan Fibres shares in the next 15 days,&quot; KSE vice-president Amin Parekh told Reuters.He said verification process would take at least 45 days.</p>
<p>Parekh said a similar exercise had been done in the past for Pakistan Telecommunication Company Ltd shares.</p>
<p>Maqsood Ali, head of Dhan Fibres share department, said the company had detected the existence of fake shares towards the end of July and had written to Pakistan's three stock exchanges on August 5 to explain how they could tell the difference between real and counterfeit shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Somebody has printed fake shares of our company and there are no estimates available how many have been circulated in the market,&quot; Ali said by telephone from Lahore.</p>
<p>A newspaper report about the problem on Wednesday further depressed the price of Dhan Fibres shares, already trading below par value. The scrip closed 0.35 rupees down at 3.10, according to provisional figures from the Karachi bourse.</p>
<p>It was a new year-low for Dhan Fibres shares, which have dropped from a year-high of 11.00 rupees.</p>
<p>Dhan Fibres Ltd was registered at the Karachi exchange in 1994 and has a paid-up capital of 2.968 billion rupees.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I26000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
