<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32481" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Delhi shares bounce off lows on fund buying.</title>
<headline>Delhi shares bounce off lows on fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Late session buying by domestic financial institutions offset the dampening effect of U.S. missile strikes on Iraq and drove share prices to a higher close in Delhi, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Delhi Stock Exchange's sensitive index closed 2.37 points higher at 792.05. At mid-session the index was 788.87.  </p>
<p>Brokers said foreign institutional investors stayed on the sidelines following the news of further U.S. missile attacks on Iraq.</p>
<p>The United States fired a second round of missiles at targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday and enforced a wider no-fly zone, pursuing one of its most serious confrontations with President Saddam Hussein since the Gulf War in 1991.</p>
<p>Iraq said one person was killed and seven were wounded.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries edged up 0.30 rupee to 209.15, while TISCO dropped 0.35 rupee to 195.35.</p>
<p>State Bank of India was up 0.75 rupee to 278.50 while Oriental Bank of Commerce gained 0.10 rupee to 90.90.</p>
<p>TELCO quoted 3.50 rupees higher at 506.</p>
<p>The Delhi Stock Exchange will remain closed on Thursday for the Hindu festival of Janmashtami, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
