<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32486" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India rice exports seen dipping despite good crop.</title>
<headline>India rice exports seen dipping despite good crop.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>India anticipates a good rice crop, helped by plentiful monsoon rains, but exports are likely to dip from record levels due to a fall in world demand and uncompetitive prices, officials and analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Rice exports are not going to pick up due to a fall in international demand,&quot; Anil Adlakha, executive director of the All India Rice Exporters Association (AIREA), told Reuters.</p>
<p>Harvesting of the new rice crop will start in October.</p>
<p>Adlakha said demand for rice on the international rice market is expected to fall to less than 18 million tonnes in fiscal 1996/97 (April-March) from nearly 20 million tonnes in 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, India will also have to lose a share in the world market,&quot; Adlakha said.</p>
<p>Analysts said India was expected to harvest around 70 million tonnes of rice in October, the same as last year.</p>
<p>India produced around 81 million tonnes of rice in the 1995/96 (July-June) crop year, with most of it covering domestic needs. The government has set a target of nearly 80 million tonnes for 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;Indian exports this year will be a maximum of three million tonnes as Indian prices are much higher than Vietnam's prices,&quot; said Prem Garg, a leading foodgrains exporter.</p>
<p>India exported a record five million tonnes of rice in the year that ended in March. It was largest exporter of rice in the year after Thailand.</p>
<p>Officials said substantial quantities of rice were sold to Indonesia and Bangladesh in the year.</p>
<p>Exports to the two countries are expected to fall this year because their domestic production has improved, Adlakha said.</p>
<p>One Bombay-based commodity analyst said: &quot;Exports are not going to pick up unless prices fall by about 20 dollars.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said Vietnam was selling average quality non-basmati rice at $255 per tonne but Indian prices were around $275.</p>
<p>India, a net foodgrains importer until the early 1980s, has become almost self-sufficient in agriculture since a so-called &quot;Green Revolution&quot; that began in the 1960s.</p>
<p>It has emerged as a net exporter of rice and wheat over the past two years.</p>
<p>Analysts said Indian rice export prices were likely to fall when the new crop arrived. But they said it was too early to say if the drop would be substantial.</p>
<p>Traders said Indian five percent broken long grain, non- basmati rice was quoted at $310 per tonne free on board, 10 percent broken long grain at 300, 15 percent at 280 and 25 percent at 250.</p>
<p>&quot;The monsoon has been very favourable for the rice crop,&quot; Adlakha said.</p>
<p>The Indian Meteorological Department (IMD) said rainfall in most parts of the country had been normal or above average levels during the four-month southwestern monsoon which started in June.</p>
<p>It was ninth consecutive year of good monsoon rains.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
