<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32498" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Japan's All Nippon Airways to fly to India.</title>
<headline>Japan's All Nippon Airways to fly to India.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's All Nippon Airways (ANA) will launch its services to India from Thursday with a twice-a- week flight between Bombay and Osaka, company officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This service not only marks ANA's first service to India, it will be the first service ever between Bombay and Osaka and the first non-stop flight between Bombay and Japan,&quot; ANA's Managing Director Yuzuru Masumoto told reporters.</p>
<p>From October 4, ANA plans to launch similar twice-weekly services between New Delhi and Tokyo, he added.</p>
<p>ANA officials said they wanted to take advantage of the growing Japanese traffic to India.</p>
<p>Currently, state-run Air India is the only airline to operate regular flights between the two countries.</p>
<p>Passenger traffic between India and Japan has grown at the rate of 17 percent annually over the last five years. In 1995, arrivals in India from Japan were 4.3 percent of all arrivals.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1995, the number of Japanese visiting India increased by 23 percent to 52,000,&quot; Masumoto said.</p>
<p>&quot;In our first year of operation on Bombay-Osaka, we are hoping to carry 22,000 passengers and 945 tonnes of cargo,&quot; he added. Officials said passenger projections in the first year for the Delhi-Tokyo route were 33,000.</p>
<p>He had no cargo forecast figures for the Delhi-Tokyo route.</p>
<p>ANA expected to see cargo business on the Bombay-Osaka route growing as India's five-year-old programme of economic reforms accelerated, Masumoto said.</p>
<p>&quot;We see potential for our cargo business as the amount of imports from Japan grew by two percent while goods flowing in the opposite direction from Bombay to Japan grew by 16 percent,&quot; Masumoto said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that this trend will continue and intensify as India's economy develops further,&quot; Masumoto added.</p>
<p>ANA operates 252 flights each week to 21 destinations worldwide with a fleet of 126 aircraft. Last year it carried 2.3 million passengers on international flights.</p>
<p>In Japan it operates 98 routes with 530 flights each day, carrying over 100,000 people daily, officials said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
