<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32492" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian state row causes uproar in parliament.</title>
<headline>Indian state row causes uproar in parliament.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's parliament broke up in disarray for the second straight session on Wednesday after opposition Hindu nationalists protested against political wrangling in the western state of Gujarat.</p>
<p>Officials said both the upper and lower houses adjourned after sitting for less than one hour. They will not reopen until Friday because Thursday is a Hindu holiday.</p>
<p>Wednesday's adjournment, and a similar curtailment on Tuesday, delayed a reply by Finance Minister P.Chidambaram to a debate on the federal budget for 1996/97 (April-March).</p>
<p>On Wednesday, members of the opposition Hindu Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) approached the speaker's chair in the lower house and shouted protests at what they said was a conspiracy by other leading parties to oust the BJP-led government in Gujarat.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a murder of democracy,&quot; they shouted, while facing angry retorts from members of ex-Prime Minister P.V. Narasimha Rao's Congress party, who joined them near the speaker's chair.</p>
<p>Congress leaders had said the BJP government in Gujarat had lost its majority after a split in the ranks of the BJP.</p>
<p>The row erupted when the deputy speaker of the Gujarat state assembly, a Congress member, adjourned the assembly indefinitely on Tuesday when the BJP-led government was expecting to prove its majority after the party split.</p>
<p>The BJP split in Gujarat last month after it expelled a powerful caste chieftain, Shankarsinh Vaghela, following a clash with other senior leaders.</p>
<p>The state asembly's deputy speaker was filling in for the speaker, a BJP member who was ill. He recognised 46 breakaway BJP members as a separate political group in the assembly before adjourning the house.</p>
<p>BJP leaders say the deputy speaker violated democratic norms by not allowing Chief Minister Sureshbhai Mehta to prove his majority on the floor of the house. They say the BJP has 94 state lawmakers in the 182-member assembly after the split.</p>
<p>BJP leaders in the federal parliament and in Gujarat said Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's United Front coalition, ruling India with support from the Congress, was party to the moves to oust the Gujarat state government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a conspiracy of the Congress and the United Front,&quot; senior state BJP leader Kashiram Rana told Reuters in parliament in New Delhi on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The BJP won most seats in the federal parliament in general elections in April and May but lost power after 11 days when it failed to prove a majority in the 545-member house.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
