<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32496" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian firms' 1st half profit growth seen slowing.</title>
<headline>Indian firms' 1st half profit growth seen slowing.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian firms will see a sharp slowdown in profit growth in the first half of the fiscal year ended March 31, 1997, but strong results from auto, banking and telecom stocks could soften the blow, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're looking at a profitability growth of an average 15-20 percent in the first half of 1996/97 over the year ago,&quot; said Vinay Kamat, head of research at J.M. Share &amp; Stock Brokers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a sharp fall when you compare it to the previous year's growth, which was closer to 30 percent,&quot; Kamat said.</p>
<p>Analysts slashed earnings forecasts for top index stocks such as Reliance Industries, TISCO and SAIL after India introduced a 12.9 percent minimum alternate tax (MAT) -- which affects non tax-paying firms -- in its 1996/97 budget in July.</p>
<p>But some analysts said infrastructure problems and a recent liquidity crunch -- which were also likely to slow growth -- had not been factored into forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of the lowering in forecasts was budget-related,&quot; said an analyst at a U.S. investment bank. &quot;Economic issues like the tight money situation from last year and lots of logistical problems relating to transportation, fuel and power didn't show up in 1995/96.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They will bleed through in this year's results and start showing up in the first half,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, processed foods maker Nestle India -- which is 51 percent owned by Switzerland's Nestle SA -- said its first-half 1996 net profit was little changed at 223 million rupees ($6.2 million) against 222 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Nestle said its profit was squeezed by rising interest costs and higher depreciation due to the capitalisation of projects.</p>
<p>A recent report by ICICI Securities and Finance (I-Sec) said the earnings growth of Bombay's recast 30-stocks index was seen at 18 percent in 1996/97, down from 31 percent in 1995/96. The Bombay Stock Exchange revamped its benchmark index last month.</p>
<p>I-Sec said earnings growth in the recast index would be higher than for the &quot;old&quot; index due to the lower weight given commodiities and cyclical stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The forecast for the reconstituted index is slightly better than for the old because you have heavyweights like State Bank of India and MTNL (Mahanagar Telephone Nigam Ltd) holding the index up,&quot; said Bharat Iyer, strategist at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>Analysts said auto, banking, telecom and power utilities were the safest bets because they were least affected by MAT.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has discounted the budget proposals to a large extent, but recently there have been a lot of expectations of MAT being revised and we could see a further downside of five percent if nothing happens,&quot; Iyer said.</p>
<p>Newspaper reports said Finance Minister P. Chidambaram may dilute the impact of the MAT when he replies to an ongoing parliamentary budget debate on Friday.</p>
<p>($1=35.74 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
