<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32497" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian Congress sets key clash with Deve Gowda.</title>
<headline>Indian Congress sets key clash with Deve Gowda.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's three-month-old government faced a potential crisis on Wednesday after the Congress Party said it was having problems shoring up the minority alliance.</p>
<p>Former prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao has been under pressure from his Congress Party colleagues to distance it from Deve Gowda's United Front alliance due to assembly polls in the state of Uttar Pradesh, where their interests clash.</p>
<p>Rao, who has said his support to the United Front government was not a life-long commitment, told a rally in India's most populous state late on Tuesday: &quot;We are extending this support with great difficulty.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Congress' support for the United Front was a defensive move against the rightist Hindu Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP), which won the most seats in parliament in the April/May general elections and is a dominant force in Uttar Pradesh, from where it received 52 of its 160 deputies.</p>
<p>Rao's aides said his first public statement since Congress lost the national poll was his clearest warning yet of the potential for Congress to ditch Deve Gowda for political expediency.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, the state's top Congress leader issued a more direct threat.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to fight the elections to win an outright victory. It doesn't matter what effect it has on the central government,&quot; Congress president for Uttar Pradesh, Jitendra Prasada, said in a television interview.</p>
<p>Uttar Pradesh has announced a three-phased poll in late September and October that pits the United Front against Congress and the BJP.</p>
<p>Deve Gowda formed a minority government in June after Rao promised to support him following the inconclusive general elections. The Indian leader depends heavily on Congress to survive the BJP's unceasing challenge in parliament.</p>
<p>The polls in northern Uttar Pradesh state will test that equation, analysts say. Seven of India's 10 prime ministers have come from Uttar Pradesh, which a 1991 census found had a population of 140 million out of India's 920 million people.</p>
<p>Uttar Pradesh was the main support base of the Congress until 1989 when its fortunes began to slide there in successive polls against the BJP and the regional Samajwadi Party of socialist Defence Minister Mulayam Singh Yadav.</p>
<p>The Samajawadi Party won 16 of the state's 85 seats in parliament, the most after the BJP's 52. Deve Gowda's Janata Dal won two seats and Congress five, a far cry from 1984 when it captured all 85.</p>
<p>The BJP also emerged as the largest party in parliament. Most analysts say the BJP, which won 34 percent of the votes in Uttar Pradesh in this year's general elections, looked likely to win a majority in the state assembly.</p>
<p>The Congress, which won eight percent of the votes in the general polls in Uttar Pradesh, has struck an alliance with the Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP) of mostly low caste Hindus.</p>
<p>The state was put under New Delhi's direct rule last year after the BSP ditched Yadav and formed its own government, then was unable to prove its majority and the government resigned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
