<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32493" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian money market sees steady rates, dull trade.</title>
<headline>Indian money market sees steady rates, dull trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money ended Wednesday in the 5.50-5.75 percent range in dull trade against the day's opening 5.50-6.25 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said most of the day's deals were done between 5.50 and 5.75 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected the Reserve Bank of India to relax the existing guidelines on bank investments to allow them to trade in the secondary market for public sector bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the decision to be announced shortly, maybe the next two days,&quot; a dealer at a state-run bank said.</p>
<p>Yields on treasury bills fell on buying pressure, dealers said. The treasury bill maturing on September 14 was traded at yields of 6.40 percent and 6.50 percent against Tuesday's 6.90 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>Yields on government securities were mostly steady in moderate trade, dealers said. &quot;Long-dated securities remain unpopular as bankers are not ready to take positions beyond a few months,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite all the talk of liquidity easing, bankers are uncertain of the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 13.50 percent 1997 government of India stock was traded at a yield of 13.03 percent against 13.08 on Tuesday. The 13.50 percent 1998 stock was unchanged at 13.51 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said three-month commercial paper was placed by top-rated firms in private deals with banks at 13.50 percent.</p>
<p>Rates on inter-corporate deposits were steady at 17.0-19.0 percent for top-rated borrowers.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
