<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32502" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's oil bill not seen hit immediately by Iraq.</title>
<headline>India's oil bill not seen hit immediately by Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Hari Ramachandran</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strengthening oil prices following U.S. missile attacks on Iraq are not expected to hurt India's import bills for crude and products immediately, petroleum officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But they said the petroleum ministry was assessing the longer-term impact of rising prices on imports. This was unlikely to become clear for at least several days.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, there are no problems on the oil supplies. The imports necessary for September have already been contracted,&quot; one official quoted Vijay Kelkar, secretary in the ministry, as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a comfortable stock of products and crude oil,&quot; the official told Reuters.</p>
<p>India's annual oil import demand of some 22 to 23 million tonnes of crude and 16 million tonnes of refined products cost around $6.5 billion last year. This accounted for around 20 to 22 percent of the country's total import bill.</p>
<p>Officials said India bought much of its crude and products from the Middle East but gave no breakdown.</p>
<p>The U.S. launched a second wave of missiles against military targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday in retaliation for Iraqi military intervention in the country's Kurdish north.</p>
<p>India's oil pool deficit, effectively the net subsidy for petroleum products, for the year to next March 31 is 55 to 60 billion rupees ($1.54 billion to 1.68 billion).</p>
<p>On the longer-term impact of developments in Iraq, an Indian Oil Corp (IOC) official said: &quot;The (long-term) impact cannot be assessed at the moment. Only in the next few days can the trends be ascertained.&quot;</p>
<p>The IOC is the sole agent for imports of crude oil.</p>
<p>&quot;India will be floating tenders for October POL (Petroleum Oil and Lubricants), buying only in late September. Buyings for September have already been firmed up,&quot; one ministry official said.</p>
<p>He said the government was keeping a close watch on the supply situation and monitoring the market.</p>
<p>India buys product both on spot markets as well as term contracts, while crude is largely purchased on term.</p>
<p>&quot;Every one dollar increase in oil price will lead to additional payment of about $340 million a year by India, which will go out of the oil pool account,&quot; said P. Dhileepan, an analyst at Crosby Ltd, a securities company.</p>
<p>This would mean an impact of $180 million for the remaining seven months of the current fiscal year ending next March, presuming price increases were maintained, he said.</p>
<p>Dhileepan estimated the oil pool deficit would widen to around 56 billion rupees from the current 50 billion rupees under this scenario.</p>
<p>Rajendra Pachauri, of Tata Energy Research Institute, an independent think-tank, said: &quot;I don't think it (the U.S. action) will have much of impact, maybe one billion rupees if it lasts two or three weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>He said India had made sizeable oil purchases in recent weeks and did not have to rush for more.</p>
<p>&quot;We should really play it cool,&quot; he said. &quot;The scenario is not alarming.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = 35.70 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
