<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32501" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian brokers lower expectations for Chidambaram.</title>
<headline>Indian brokers lower expectations for Chidambaram.</headline>
<byline>Ranjit Gangadharan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's fragile stock markets still hope Finance Minister P. Chidambaram will steer them out of troubled waters, but brokers are lowering their expectations for his economic policies, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts say the internal politics of the 13-party coalition government will likely prevent Chidabaram from making major changes to his budget proposals.</p>
<p>&quot;People have high hopes of market-friendly measures,&quot; said broker Maulik Sharedalal of Vipin Chinubhai &amp; Maulik. &quot;Those hopes could be belied.&quot;</p>
<p>The market was waiting for the finance minister to ease a controversial minimum tax on high-growth firms and announce incentives to lure investors back by scrapping double taxation on company dividends.</p>
<p>Chidambaram was expected to make a statement on the 1996/97 (April-March) budget this week, but on Wednesday parliament was adjourned until Friday because of a row over political developments in Gujarat state.</p>
<p>Chidambaram was expected to spell out any amendments to tax legislation when he speaks for a second time just before parliament votes on the finance bill, which was supposed to be passed by the end of the September 13 session.</p>
<p>But now the session could be extended due to this week's delays.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, say any changes are still unlikely to cure the ills of the local share market, which has been hit by a lack of retail investors and declining foreign interest while being brushed aside by cash-starved domestic funds.</p>
<p>&quot;I really don't think he'll give (the market) a boost. He might make some token changes -- and that will be bad,&quot; said Kamal Kabra, a top broker and former president of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE).</p>
<p>The 30-share BSE index was up 14.08 points at 3,498.76 in mid-afternoon trading on Wednesday. The market has plunged 570.5 points, or 14 percent, since June 18, nearly three weeks after Deve Gowda was sworn in.</p>
<p>&quot;An upsurge will be short-lived,&quot; Sharedalal said. &quot;Ground realities will catch up. Basically it's a problem of huge supply.&quot;</p>
<p>The potential excess supply came from budget proposals like the issue of non-voting shares and divestment of state holdings.</p>
<p>The government plans to raise funds through divesting its holdings in some firms, while Indian companies plan to raise more than $1.5 billion through issue of global depositary receipts listed overseas.</p>
<p>Sharedalal said there was a need for government policies that would encourage a stronger inflow of funds into the system to absorb the supply.</p>
<p>Such policies could include public provident funds to invest in stocks, he said. The government could also recognise bank investments in divested stocks for statutory liquidity reserve requirements.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
