<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32516" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India bourses lower hopes of tonic from Chidambaram.</title>
<headline>India bourses lower hopes of tonic from Chidambaram.</headline>
<byline>Ranjit Gangadharan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shaky Indian stocks markets are banking on Finance Minister P. Chidambaram to steer them out of trouble, but brokers said on Wednesday they were scaling down hopes that the minister will deliver a substantial tonic.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to watch the finance minister today and for the rest of the week,&quot; said Kamal Kabra, top broker and former president of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE).</p>
<p>&quot;I really don't think he'll give a boost. He might make some token changes -- and that will be bad,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The market expects the finance minister to ease a controversial minimum tax on high-growth firms and give some sops to lure investors back by scrapping double taxation of company dividends.</p>
<p>Chidambaram is expected to make a statement on the 1996/97 (April-March) budget on Wednesday, but any amendments to the tax proposals are likely to be announced only early next week before the finance bill is passed by parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;People have high hopes of market-friendly measures,&quot; said broker Maulik Sharedalal of Vipin Chinubhai &amp; Maulik. &quot;Those hopes could be belied.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say the changes will not address the ills of the bourses which have been hit by the near total absence of retail investors, falling foreign portfolio inflows and cash-starved domestic funds.</p>
<p>The 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) index was up 14.78 points at 3,499.46 in late morning trading after sliding to 3,456.42 in early trade.</p>
<p>&quot;An upsurge will be short-lived,&quot; Sharedalal said. &quot;Ground realities will catch up -- basically it's a problem of huge supply.&quot;</p>
<p>The potential excess supply came from budget proposals like the issue of non-voting shares, divestment of state holdings and Euroissues.</p>
<p>The government plans to raise 50 billion rupees through divestment of its holdings in some firms while Indian companies plan to raise more than $1.5 billion through issue of global depositary receipts listed overseas.</p>
<p>Sharedalal said there was a need to inject more funds into the system to absorb this supply like allowing public provident funds to invest in stocks. The government could also recognise bank investments in divested stocks for statutory liquidity reserve requirements.</p>
<p>--Bombay Newsroom +91-22-265-9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
