<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32525" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: FEATURE-Pakistan prisons pamper rich, fetter poor.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Pakistan prisons pamper rich, fetter poor.</headline>
<byline>Saeed Shah</byline>
<dateline>LAHORE, Pakistan 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was a sumptuous meal by Pakistan prison standards, brazenly ordered from outside by one of Lahore's biggest arms dealers.</p>
<p>The prisoner ate at the deputy superintendent's desk and told Reuters he spent thousands of rupees a day to ensure his creature comforts.</p>
<p>Under rules inherited from British colonial days, upper-class inmates get better treatment in Pakistan jails than their less exalted brethren, but anyone can buy privileges.</p>
<p>A lawyer told how he had sneaked a mobile telephone into jail and triumphantly offered it to his well-off client. &quot;No thanks,&quot; replied the prisoner, producing one from his pocket.</p>
<p>Money can smooth hardship for a wealthy minority, but there is no such relief for most of Pakistan's prisoners, many of whom spend long periods in overcrowded jails awaiting trial.</p>
<p>Lawyers and human rights activists blame the packed jails on a painfully slow and often corrupt criminal justice process.</p>
<p>One ex-prisoner said inmates commonly had to bribe police to be brought to the court hearing their case.</p>
<p>The Human Rights Commission of Pakistan (HRCP) says at least 28 percent of inmates are drug users, jailed for possession of small amounts of banned narcotics under 1979 Islamic laws.</p>
<p>The superintendent of Lahore's Camp Jail, Nasir Warriach, said that 2,200 of the 3,300 prisoners in his charge were drug addicts. The prison has an authorised capacity of 994.</p>
<p>In one barrack, 300 addicts huddle in two clean, but crowded dormitories. Lines of miserable faces stare into space. They get three hours of religious instruction daily.</p>
<p>&quot;These people should be sent to rehabilitation centres, not prisons,&quot; said Muhammad Hussain Cheema, inspector general of prisons in Punjab. &quot;Overcrowding is the mother of all our problems, leading to poor sanitation or violation of prison rules.&quot;</p>
<p>Lawyer Nisar Mujahid said many addicts were jailed because of personal feuds or by police boosting their arrest figures.</p>
<p>&quot;I went to stay with some friends,&quot; said Abbas, an inmate at Camp Jail. &quot;There was a raid and I was arrested with the others as drugs were found there. My friends paid 4,000 rupees ($112) to the police to be set free, but I had no money, so here I am.&quot;</p>
<p>Conditions vary, but officials say space is so short in some jails that inmates have to sleep in shifts or even in toilets.</p>
<p>Courts are buckling under a backlog of cases and a shortage of judges, lawyers say. About a million cases have been brought under Islamic laws, clogging and confusing the judicial system.</p>
<p>More than 2,500 juveniles languished in Punjab prisons in December, including 91 on death row. In Camp Jail, two scared and bewildered boys aged no more than 10 said their parents did not know they were in prison. They were caught stealing.</p>
<p>The clang of fetters is a common and unsettling sound. In Camp Jail, those awaiting trial on multiple charges are automatically put in fetters. A prisoner may be chained throughout his detention, regardless of behaviour.</p>
<p>In 1993 the Sindh High Court ruled that fetters offended human dignity, guaranteed by the constitution. The Supreme Court is considering a government appeal against the judgment.</p>
<p>A recent HRCP report on the penal system said warders often inflicted illegal and degrading punishments on inmates, including beating naked prisoners, hanging them upside down, denying them sleep and keeping them in solitary confinement beyond authorised limits.</p>
<p>It said most prisons were filthy and infested with rats and insects. Several lacked fans and clean drinking water.</p>
<p>Pakistan has not ratified the U.N. Convention Against Torture or the U.N. Minimum Standard for Prison Rules.</p>
<p>Cheema acknowledged that malpractices existed.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot depute a watchman to supervise each watchman, so abuses by the guards are bound to take place,&quot; he said. &quot;However, reports greatly exaggerate the amount of abuse that goes on.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=35.50 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAHORE, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
