<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32527" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: FEATURE - Bonds seen overtaking Indian equities markets.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bonds seen overtaking Indian equities markets.</headline>
<byline>Giri Venkatesan</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A series of successful bond issues bucking depressed equity offerings have made analysts sit up and wonder if this is the dawn of a vibrant Indian debt market.</p>
<p>In the past few months new bond floats have mopped up 55 billion rupees ($1.54 billion), and their ready acceptance by equity-shy investors has had a dramatic effect on companies.</p>
<p>New bond offers in the final stages total 50-60 billion rupees, with more issues in the pipeline, analysts say.</p>
<p>The secondary market for debt instruments is in its infancy with little activity. Debt trades are limited to government securities, or gilts, and are done mainly on the National Stock Exchange (NSE), a fully-automated screen-based trading system operating from 24 centres across India.</p>
<p>But the winds of change are making things happen. The Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE), one of Asia's oldest bourses, plans to begin a dedicated segment for debt trading in September.</p>
<p>&quot;The shift was expected,&quot; said NSE managing director R.H.Patil.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian equity market is getting increasingly liberalised and is beginning to resemble the sophisticated markets of the west,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The earlier days of a steep jump in (share) prices upon listing are now gone.&quot;</p>
<p>Cash raised through primary equity issues fell 47 percent to 48.76 billion rupees in the six months ended June 1996 against 91.17 billion rupees in the same period last year, according to Prime database.</p>
<p>Before India embarked on market reforms in 1992, new share offers by companies were priced ridiculously low by the government, giving subscribers huge returns on listing.</p>
<p>In the first flush of reforms, companies got the right to price new equity floats at market rates, but unscrupulous firms rigged up their stocks and gullible investors were saddled with worthless paper when the big premiums vanished overnight.</p>
<p>Some analysts believe the current fad for debt was a reaction to the depressed stock markets and may fizzle out.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonds are looking more attractive because the equities market is down,&quot; said K.R. Bharat, deputy managing director of securities firm Peregrine Capital.</p>
<p>Returns on debt have been better than returns from equities based on the benchmark BSE index, said ICICI Securities and Finance Company (I-Sec).</p>
<p>&quot;The vagaries of the equity markets are driving away investors to debt,&quot; said Aashish Pitale, I-Sec debt analyst. &quot;Retail investors are choosing assured returns over higher risk investments which may offer greater returns.&quot;</p>
<p>I-Sec said a study of the movement of the BSE index and returns from debt over a 42-month period from January 1993 revealed that the annualised return on the index-linked stocks has been lower than fixed income investments.</p>
<p>The current returns on debt instruments at over 16 percent a year compared to an estimated 13.55 percent on equity.</p>
<p>&quot;In the short term, I see bonds cutting into the funds available (for equities market),&quot; said Ramdeo Agarwal, research head at brokerage Motilal Oswal Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Money tends to fly to safety zones. I don't see the appetite for bonds petering out in the short term,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Most of the debt raised so far in calendar 1996 was by state-run financial institutions, but this is changing.</p>
<p>For the first time some of India's leading manufacturing companies such as steel major Tata Iron and Steel Company and engineering and construction giant Larsen &amp; Toubro are raising long-term funds through an issue of deep-discount bonds.</p>
<p>Both firms are planning bond issues of five billion rupees each. The issues are expected very shortly.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a perceptional change towards bonds because these offer better yields,&quot; said analyst Kanu Dave. &quot;Too many investors have burnt their fingers in stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the shift to debt could divert investible funds from equities and further slow down the process of a revival in the equities market.</p>
<p>The depressed state of the equities market is clearly visible from the movement of the BSE benchmark index which closed on August 27 at 3,438.80 against a record 4,628.57 on September 12, 1994.</p>
<p>Some market observers feel the trend is not permanent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a cyclical phenomenon,&quot; said P.H. Ravikumar, senior vice-president at ICICI Banking Corporation. &quot;We have shifted from the equity cycle to the debt cycle which should last for the next four to five years.&quot; (One$ = 35.73 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
