<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32526" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Unitech eyes infrastructure boom.</title>
<headline>India Unitech eyes infrastructure boom.</headline>
<byline>Narayanan Madhavan</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>As India seeks to catch up with fast-growing East Asian &quot;Tiger&quot; economies, Unitech Ltd is seeing opportunities where others see bottlenecks -- real estate and infrastructure.</p>
<p>The company has lined up a series of foreign collaborations on its home turf, marking a change from the days when it saw its fortunes in exporting construction services to the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;When the (Indian) economy opened up five years ago, real estate became more liberal,&quot; Unitech director G.R. Bahri told Reuters in an interview. &quot;We thought a lot was going to happen in infrastructure, especially in roads and power.&quot;</p>
<p>Unitech, which has its roots in a modest consultancy started 25 years ago by Bahri and three other engineers, is now building towns, power transmission towers, a highway and a hotel with a total investment of 30 billion rupees ($857 million).</p>
<p>With real estate prices skyrocketing in cities like Bombay and Delhi, Unitech is building suburban townships, including office buildings, near Delhi, Bombay, Bangalore and Lucknow.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect that corporate relocation will take place,&quot; Bahri said, pointing to a recent decision by multinational PepsiCo to buy an office building outside Delhi.</p>
<p>Unitech this month starts work on Signature Towers, a 325,000 square-foot (29,545 square metre) commercial complex in the middle of Unitech's 325-acre (130-hectare) South City township near Delhi in the state of Haryana.</p>
<p>The &quot;world class&quot; building designed in Singapore and costing 2.0 billion rupees would be built by a consortium that includes Unitech, expatriate Indians and Singapore's First Capital Corp, Bahri said.</p>
<p>Unitech has another venture with First Capital and Technology Parks Ltd to build an industrial complex in Haryana.</p>
<p>Another joint venture, in which Unitech holds 75 percent, is building a five-star hotel close to Delhi airport affiliated to the Radisson group.</p>
<p>Unitech's main projects are in Haryana which is becoming a haven for developers and customers looking for a way out of Delhi's high real estate prices.</p>
<p>Across the state that surrounds Delhi on three sides, Unitech is building a 2.42 billion rupee four-lane highway in collaboration with South Korea's LG (Lucky Goldstar) group.</p>
<p>Seeing opportunity in India's chronic power shortage, Unitech is also building a facility to make power transmission towers with South Korea's Hyundai Engineering and Construction Company. It eventually plans to erect the towers as well as build them.</p>
<p>Unitech also has a plant to make ready-to-use concrete in a venture with Singapore's Resources Development Corp.</p>
<p>Total income was expected to grow by about 40 percent in 1996/97 (April-March) from 2.6 billion rupees ($74 million) in 1995/96, Bahri said.</p>
<p>The four engineers who founded Unitech, along with their associates, hold more than 50 percent of the company's 125 million rupee ($3.5 million) share capital, Bahri said.</p>
<p>As much as 24 percent is held by foreign institutional investors and expatriate Indians. Under Indian regulatory laws, foreign portfolio investors cannot hold more than 24 percent of an Indian company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
