<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32540" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon cuts Chrysler rating.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Salomon cuts Chrysler rating.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Salomon Bros analyst Jack Kirnan said he cut his investment rating on Chrysler Corp to hold from buy because of expected margin erosion in the U.S. light truck market.</p>
<p>-- Kirnan, in a research report, said he cut his 1997 earnings per share estimate for Chrysler to $4.00 from $4.75, which is well below First Call's $4.55 consensus estimate.</p>
<p>-- He continues to project 1996 Chrysler earnings of $4.70 a share.  </p>
<p>-- Chrysler shares were trading off 5/8 to 28-1/8.</p>
<p>-- Kirnan said he expects the shares to trade in a range of $25 to $30 over the next nine to 12 months, although they carry &quot;fairly strong downside risk.&quot;</p>
<p>-- He said the minivan market has essentially peaked and is more characteristic of a replacement-driven market.</p>
<p>-- &quot;It is difficult to envision how current minivan margins can be sustained in the face of several new models from competitors, including General Motors Corp's new trio of vans and two new U.S.-produced minivans from Toyota and Honda in 1997,&quot; Kirnan said.</p>
<p>-- He also said he expects more incentive activity in the sport/utility vehicle market. Chrysler began a lease incentive program in late June on its Grand Cherokee, following a GM lease program on its Blazer and Jimmy models in May. Kirnan said he expects Ford Motor Co to follow suit on its Explorer soon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
