<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32587" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Workers okay 5-year RJR Nabisco pact.</title>
<headline>Workers okay 5-year RJR Nabisco pact.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The union representing 5,700 workers at RJR Nabisco Holding Corp.'s Nabisco Biscuit Co. said Wednesday its members approved an unprecedented five-year pact that improves compensation and labor-management relations.</p>
<p>The Bakery, Confectionary &amp; Tobacco Workers International Union said the pact, which was ratified overwhelmingly on August 31, adds $4.61 to each member's hourly pay and benefits, including $2.60 in across-the-board wage hikes, $1.25 in health benefit gains and 77 cents in pension increases.</p>
<p>The new contract also sets up procedures for workers to redesign their jobs to improve efficiency and provides pay incentives for them to acquire additional skills, said BC&amp;T Secretary-Treasurer Gene McDonald.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a document that incorporates a partnership that we've been working on for many years,&quot; said McDonald, whose 110,000-member union is based in Kensington, Md.</p>
<p>The contract, which took less than two weeks to negotiate in San Diego last month, also sets up joint union-management task forces on health benefits and overall labor relations, the union said.</p>
<p>McDonald said the union and company management have been in a &quot;partnership relationship&quot; since 1987 and had agreed previously on the need to improve productivity to keep Nabisco competitive with other baking companies, including lower-paying non-union firms.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not ever going to compete with them on wages, so we have to do it in efficiency,&quot; said McDonald.</p>
<p>Nabisco's union-represented bakery production employees are in 10 plants: Pittsburgh, Denver, Atlanta, Buena Park, Calif., Buffalo and Niagra Falls, N.Y., Houston, Chicago, Richmond, Va., Portland, Ore., Philadelphia and Fair Lawn, N.J.</p>
<p>The contract raises hourly wages by 40 cents in the first year, 50 cents the second, 60 cents the third, 50 cents the fourth and 60 cents the fifth, the BC&amp;T said. It also contains improvements in family and medical leave provisions, dental and &quot;in-network&quot; medical coverage, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
