<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32619" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. interest rate swap spreads soften slightly.</title>
<headline>U.S. interest rate swap spreads soften slightly.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spreads on U.S. swaps softened slightly, but most still held within last week's tight ranges, brokers and dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets in general are softer, because dealers needed to receive fixed rates due to swap issuance,&quot; one broker at a large Japanese bank said.</p>
<p>He said that one Japanese bank bought $200 million of three-year swaps at 21.5 basis points, and said that dealers were receiving three- to 10-year swaps throughout the day.</p>
<p>Another three-year swap traded at 22 basis points on the annual money rate, he said.  </p>
<p>Spreads on three-year swaps were quoted at 20 basis points bid, 24 basis points offered.</p>
<p>Spreads on 10-year swaps were quoted at 33 basis points bid, 36 basis points offered.</p>
<p>Several traders noted that overnight one Japanese bank sold $100 million 10-years at 35 basis points to a U.S. bank.</p>
<p>One analyst said several bond issues could be priced this week and possibly widen swap rates this week. He said, however, there was little reaction to Kansai Electric Power's $500 million 10-year bond issuance overnight in London.  </p>
<p>Spreads on two-year swaps were at 19 basis points bid, 23 offered, while five-year swaps were at 25 basis points bid, 28 basis points offered.</p>
<p>&quot;The two- to five-year sector represents a lot of value,&quot; a dealer at a U.S. bank said, adding that the two-year swap tested a support level at a bid of 13 basis points last week.</p>
<p>Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuter.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
