<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32620" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. foreign crudes ample despite robust runs.</title>
<headline>U.S. foreign crudes ample despite robust runs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. foreign crudes were amply supplied into the Gulf Coast for September arrival, offsetting otherwise bullish high refinery runs, traders said.</p>
<p>A major was seen offering Brent into the U.S. Gulf at Oct West Texas Intermediate parity for Oct 1-10 delivery.</p>
<p>Last week, a European trader sold half a cargo to a Gulf Coast refiner at Oct WTI minus 10 cents cif, but one parcel was believed still available.</p>
<p>A European seller also sold a million barrels of Troll to two other refiners for mid Oct arrival last week at WTI minus 25 cents, which includes the cost of lightering.</p>
<p>Traders said this confirmed the trans-Atlantic arbitrage was open to the U.S. helped by weak European refining margins.</p>
<p>Latin American supplies were also abundant with Mendinitos reportedly sold at WTI minus $1.65 fob, and thought likely to head for Puerto Rico.</p>
<p>Argentine YPF, negotiating a six-month contract for Canadon Seco starting in November, was rumored to have closed a deal for 15,000 barrels per day (bpd). Traders pegged the value of Canadon Seco around WTI minus $2.40-45 fob.</p>
<p>Other exotic crudes from Asia and some from Canada were also being marketed in the U.S. Gulf, traders said.</p>
<p>A combination cargo of Indonesian grades, including Attaka and Minas were said to be partly sold. The same seller was rumored to be sourcing for some outlets for Canadian light sour crude, but this could not be immediately verified.</p>
<p>In the aftermarket, Brent intermonth Oct/Nov traded at 69 and 72 cents, a shade above earlier levels, and partials of Oct Brent moved at $22.06 and $22.11.</p>
<p>--Jacqueline Wong, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
