<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32623" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Brady market soporific as all eyes watching U.S.</title>
<headline>Brady market soporific as all eyes watching U.S.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market debt prices were confined to narrow ranges Wednesday as liquidity dried up ahead of the U.S. payrolls report on Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Latins there is nothing going on except trading along with Treasuries,&quot; one Brady bond trader said. &quot;Everyone is waiting until Friday.&quot;</p>
<p>But the Brady market held on to its gains as the U.S. long bond closed 1/2 point lower to yield 7.10 percent.</p>
<p>Brady traders also offered little reaction to confirmation that Argentine government was exploring options for issuing a 30-year bond, perhaps as a global bond.  </p>
<p>Another financing option would be to reopen the 20 year 350 million mark Eurobond launched on Tuesday, an Argentine official said.</p>
<p>Argentine FRBs picked up 1/4 for a bid price of 79, while discounts were unchanged 69-1/8.</p>
<p>Walter Molano, director of Latin American Research at Swiss Bank, said he anticipated FRBs would maintain a strong bid tone as the stock of paper declines.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been resilient to volatility in the region and in the country,&quot; Molano said.  </p>
<p>As countries develop their own capital markets and start buying back their Brady debt, the emerging debt markets would likely perform much more smoothly, Molano said.</p>
<p>Some Wall Street bankers may not be warming to the prospect of diminished Brady liquidity, but the trend of refinancing could only be positive for Argentina, said one analyst at a major U.S. pension fund.</p>
<p>&quot;As trader you may not like it, but from a fundamental point of view it is definitely good news,&quot; the analyst said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The bottom line is that the country needs financing and the longer term financing it can raise the better,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;From a debt management point-of-view it would be the right thing to do.&quot;</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
