<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32634" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McDonald's Arch Deluxe burger adds to sales.</title>
<headline>McDonald's Arch Deluxe burger adds to sales.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonald's Corp said Wednesday its new Arch Deluxe hamburger, launched in the United States in May, continues to add to sales in the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We think Arch Deluxe added incrementally to sales in the second quarter, and we believe that continues to be true,&quot; Mary Healy, director of financial communications, said.</p>
<p>But analysts said the Arch Deluxe has not helped offset declines in McDonald's U.S. same store sales in July and August. Same-store sales have been hurt by the fast-food chain's rapid pace of expansion, they added.  </p>
<p>Analysts said they estimated that same-store sales, which measure revenues from units open at least a year, fell by between two percent and four percent in July and did not improve in August. They blamed intense competition in the United States and the addition of new units.</p>
<p>&quot;With virtually every new opening, you're encroaching on an existing unit,&quot; Schroder Wertheim analyst Wayne Daniels said. &quot;They (McDonald's) would tell you that cannibalization (of sales of existing restaurants) costs about one percentage point&quot; on same store sales.  </p>
<p>Daniels added that McDonald's U.S. same-store sales have been flat to down since mid-1995.</p>
<p>Healy declined to comment specifically on U.S. sales and profits in the third quarter. But she reiterated McDonald's stance that comparable store sales are not the only measure of performance.</p>
<p>&quot;McDonald's strategy is to go after market share on an aggressive basis,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>McDonald's has been trying to lure in more customers, especially adults, with its Arch Deluxe, a hamburger with lettuce, tomato and mustard-mayonnaise sauce on a soft roll.  </p>
<p>Healy said that Oak Brook, Ill.-based McDonald's is pleased overall with Arch Deluxe, but did not give any sales figures.</p>
<p>&quot;Customer acceptance is very high,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Some analysts have questioned Arch Deluxe's abilty to draw new customers into McDonald's, adding the new hamburger may simply replace purchases of other menu offerings.</p>
<p>&quot;We never suggested that we thought one product could make a...difference in the competitive U.S. environment,&quot; Healy said.</p>
<p>However, McDonald's has called the Arch Deluxe its biggest product introduction. In May, the company said it hoped the hamburger would reap $1 billion in sales the first year.</p>
<p>McDonald's said it continues to test deluxe versions of its chicken and fish sandwiches, focusing on the Fresno, Calif., and Cincinnati, Ohio markets.</p>
<p>&quot;At some point there may be some more menu news,&quot; McDonald's spokesman Chuck Ebeling added, &quot;but that's as far as we can go.&quot;</p>
<p>Patricia Commins, Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
