<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32658" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mitchell sets Louisiana Chalk pipeline.</title>
<headline>Mitchell sets Louisiana Chalk pipeline.</headline>
<dateline>THE WOODLANDS, Texas 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mitchell Energy &amp; Development Corp said it and Chesapeake Energy Corp plan to build a natural gas pipeline and gathering system in south-central Louisiana to move natural gas from Chesapeake's Austin Chalk Trend wells to Enron Corp's Eunice Plant in Acadia Parish.</p>
<p>Mitchell said it and Chesapeake agreed in principle to form a joint venture to build a 40-mile, 20-inch pipeline and a 40-mile gathering system capable of handling up to 250 million cubic feet of natural gas daily.  </p>
<p>In a separate action, Chesapeake and Enron have reached an agreement whereby Enron will expand its Eunice natural gas processing facility to handle Chesapeake's gas.</p>
<p>Mitchell said construction of the pipeline is expected to be completed in the spring of 1997, with the first operational section completed by the end of this year.</p>
<p>It said the expected cost of the first phase pipeline and gathering facilities is $25 million and has been named the Louisiana Chalk Gathering System.</p>
<p>The completed pipeline will have sufficient capacity to move natural gas from wells drilled by Chesapeake and other third-party producers in Rapides, Allen, Evangeline, Avoyelles and St. Landry parishes to the Eunice area.</p>
<p>&quot;Based upon our agreement with Chesapeake, we will immediately proceed to de-bottleneck Enron's Eunice Gas Processing Plant and Fractionator to accommodate the large increase in NGL volumes to be recovered from Chesapeake's gas,&quot; said Enron Liquid Services Corp.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE WOODLANDS, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
