<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32660" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corporate bonds end slow day lower,spreads firm.</title>
<headline>US corporate bonds end slow day lower,spreads firm.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. high-grade corporate bonds inched steadily lower throughout Wednesday's session to close modestly weaker, along with Treasuries, in thin trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>Junk bonds shed 1/8 to 1/4 of a point, also in soporific trade, despite a tick up in the U.S. equity markets.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrial Average ended up 8.51 at 5656.90 while the 30-year long bond traded off 13/32 at 95-24/32 to yield 7.09 percent in late trade.  </p>
<p>Investment-grade spreads across most maturities were quoted unchanged except that for Continental Cablevision Inc debt, which dealers said tightened two basis points on the long end.</p>
<p>In high-yield, ValuJet Inc notes continued to push higher after news last week the discount airline's fleet will return to the skies in two to three weeks.</p>
<p>ValuJet 10.25 percent paper due 2001 was offered at 88 bid, 89-1/2 offer, up 1/4 from Tuesday's close on the offer side. The paper traded up 3/4 of a point in Tuesday trade after gaining a little over a point last Friday, traders said.  </p>
<p>&quot;ValuJet paper has steadily gone up since the news,&quot; one high-yield trader said.</p>
<p>In the grocery sector, performance was mixed. Brunos paper lost 1/2 point at 100-1/2 bid while Ralphs Grocery 11.0 percent paper fell 1/8, high-yield traders said.</p>
<p>However, Pathmark Stores 9.625 percent paper traded up 1/2 at 95-1/4 bid and Grand Union paper was unchanged, traders said.</p>
<p>Moving to gaming, Stratosphere Corp's 14.25 percent paper traded up 1/4 at 81-3/4 bid, 82-1/2 offer after gaining 2-1/2 points in Tuesday trade.  </p>
<p>Stratosphere notes shed over four points last Friday after news the company suspended construction on its new hotel tower due to an anticipated cash shortfall, dealers said.</p>
<p>The new issue market came back to life Wednesday with two issues pricing after a long hiatus .</p>
<p>Associates Corp of North America, a Ford Motor unit, priced $400 million in two-year notes via lead manager Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. The AA3/AA-minus, 6.50 percent notes were priced at 99.954 to yield 6.525 or 17 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasuries.  </p>
<p>Also, Capital One Financial unit Capital One Bank priced $200 million in 10-year, Baa3/BBB- bank notes at 99.953 to yield 7.167 or 60 basis points over the comparable Treasury.</p>
<p>The notes have a three-year put option and are noncallable for life, lead manager JP Morgan Securities Inc said.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, primary and secondary corporate bond activity is seen muted ahead of the critical U.S. employment report due out Friday, dealers added.</p>
<p>In a Reuter poll, U.S. economist predicted an increase of 244,000 in nonfarm payrolls and expect the unemployment rate to dip slightly to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>--Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
