<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32669" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends down in US, focus shifts to jobs data.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends down in US, focus shifts to jobs data.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar closed lower, especially against the mark, as the market focus veered away from the conflict in Iraq to American economic fundaments and Friday's release of U.S. jobs data, traders said.</p>
<p>The market shrugged off news of a second round of U.S. missile strikes against Iraq.</p>
<p>The dollar skidded to the day's low of 1.4783 marks in the afternoon, before recouping some losses as President Bill Clinton announced the U.S. mission in Iraq had been achieved.</p>
<p>&quot;The flurry of dollar buying we saw over the past two days has dissipated,&quot; said Elliott Dix at Signet Bank.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market had already priced in an early cessation of hostilities,&quot; Dix, assistant vice president of foreign exchange at Signet, added.</p>
<p>The dollar ended down at 1.4801/08 marks and 108.76/81 yen after opening at 1.4853/56 and 108.95/00.</p>
<p>Overnight, option-linked dollar selling and resistance at 109.50 yen and above 1.4900 marks stalled the dollar's rise, setting the stage for today's declines, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;You've had a lot of reasons to buy dollars recently and it just hasn't traded very well,&quot; said Mark Gargano, chief dealer at First Union National Bank.  </p>
<p>Even before Clinton's announcement, market focus had shifted to upcoming economic data from the United States and its implication for U.S. interest rates, traders said.</p>
<p>U.S. August unemployment numbers, due out Friday, will be key in determining whether the Federal Reserve hikes official interest rates this month, analysts said.</p>
<p>Traders said caution ahead of the jobs data had spurred dollar sales against the mark and the yen.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts on average expect non-farm payrolls to rise by 224,000 in August compared with July's 193,000 gain.  </p>
<p>The August unemployment rate, meanwhile, is seen edging lower to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The jobs data has surprised the market more often than not this year, and the market is duly cautious about it,&quot; said Marc Chandler, senior currency analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>The mark was firm against the French franc after news that French gross domestic product contracted by 0.4 percent in the second quarter, traders said.</p>
<p>Mark/French was around 3.4286/87 late on Wednesday, compared with 3.4269/74 in early trade.  </p>
<p>&quot;There's an ongoing concern that the French are not going to be able to make the (Maastricht treaty) budget target of three percent. That kind of spooked the market a little bit,&quot; Chandler said.</p>
<p>The yen recouped some of its earlier losses against sterling and the mark as jitters over rising oil prices in the wake of U.S. military intervention in Iraq receded.</p>
<p>Mark/yen closed at 73.47 compared with 73.59 in late New York trade on Tuesday. Sterling/yen dropped to 170.40/55 late in the New York session, down from 171.50 overnight in Asia.  </p>
<p>In other trading, the dollar eased to 1.2060/70 Swiss francs against 1.2094/99.</p>
<p>It was Canadian $1.3693/98 versus C$1.3695/00.</p>
<p>Sterling ended slightly higher at $1.5667/77 compared with $1.5657/67.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar was $0.7916/21.</p>
<p>-- Daniel Rosenblum, 212-8559-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
