<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32696" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lithuania rating may broaden investment - US experts.</title>
<headline>Lithuania rating may broaden investment - US experts.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>By granting Lithuania the first credit rating to a republic of the former Soviet Union, Moody's Investors Service may have ushered in a new era for international investment across the Baltics, U.S. analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Moody's, a New York-based credit rating agency, Wednesday assigned a Ba2 rating to Lithuania's foriegn currency debt, and a Ba3 to the country's bank deposits.  </p>
<p>Lithuania's rating at the speculative grade level affirmed its transition to a market economy and may open the door to further investment, experts said.</p>
<p>Supporting Lithuania's rating, Moody's cited the country's low external debt burden, the strength of its economic stabilization program and the pro-reform stances of the main political parties.</p>
<p>But Moody's pointed to problems in the energy sector, which may require external funding to overhaul and consolidate, and the banks, which remain undercapitalized and have a significant amount of non-performing loans.  </p>
<p>The Moody's action was an investor initiated rating, according to Sosi Vartanesyan, senior analyst at Moody's.</p>
<p>Vartanesyan said the success of the transformation, the reformist attitude of the goverment and the successful macro-economic stabilization were factors in the Ba2 rating.</p>
<p>U.S. analysts said that, given Lithuania's modest borrowing needs, they did not expect the country to bring much paper before the international capital markets. Still, the credit rating should improve Lithuania's financing options.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's the first former Soviet economy with a rating and it has come as a surprise,&quot; said Richard Segal, head of fixed income research at Santander Investment. &quot;That in itself should generate some interest.&quot;</p>
<p>The Lithuanian rating also provided a benchmark around which Latvia and Estonia would be measured, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It enables investors to place Lithuania on the map and also to derive what the rating will be for the others,&quot; said Luis R. Luis, head of emerging market research at Scudder, Stevens and Clark, a Boston-based mutual fund company.  </p>
<p>&quot;As far as foreign investment, I think this rating will help,&quot; Luis said, adding that interest was likely to come from so-called &quot;buy-and-hold&quot; investors.</p>
<p>Lithuania has two outstanding Eurobond issues, and is set to initial a $75 million syndicated loan in September to be led by JP Morgan and Co Inc. Last week, the finance ministry said that Merrill Lynch would underwrite a $50 million domestic bond issue.</p>
<p>But some U.S. analysts said that few investment banks or portfolio managers paid close attention to Lithuania.</p>
<p>Eric Neilsen, senior economist at Goldman, Sachs and Co Inc, said the Ba2 rating was slightly higher that he would have expected. He also expressed surprise that Lithuania received the rating ahead of parliamentary elections in October.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
