<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32699" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures finish near lows amid softer cash.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures finish near lows amid softer cash.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended significantly lower Wednesday as softer aftermarket cash prices tugged at the front months and traders awaited the release of the weekly storage data, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Some late technical selling pushed October near its $1.73 per million British thermal units contract low before settling at $1.764, down 5.7 cents on the day. November finished 4.2 cents lower at $1.937.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see much to support it. It needs a hurricane in the weather,&quot; said one trader, noting a storm in the Gulf could stop a retreat in the October contract.  </p>
<p>Technically, traders said October support was at the $1.73 contract low. Resistance was seen first at $1.85, then at $1.955.</p>
<p>&quot;The settlement for 9/5/95 was $1.701 for the October contract. So the current storage deficit of 390 bcf is currently valued by the market to be worth roughly eight cents,&quot; said Tim Evans at Pegasus.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true that this deficit has been eroding, but this still seems rather cheap, especially in light of where prices went last winter,&quot; Evans added.</p>
<p>The cash market pulled on the strings of the futures market. Prices at the U.S. Gulf Coast were talked close to $1.70 in late trading, still down one to three cents from Tuesday. Midcontinent prices held fairly steady in the mid-to-high $1.50s.</p>
<p>NYMEX said an estimated 23,275 Henry Hub contracts traded, up from Tuesday's revised tally of 16,946.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip lost 3.5 cents to $1.96.</p>
<p>Shortly after the release of the American Gas Association's storage report, which showed a build of 94 billion cubic feet to 67 percent of capacity, October fell 2.4 cents to $1.74 in the ACCESS session.</p>
<p>NYMEX's October Permian contract settled four cents lower at $1.52. An estimated 21 lots traded.</p>
<p>Physical Permian prices were fairly stale in the low-to-mid $1.50s.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, October finished down five cents at $1.55 after some late technical selling. Other front months were down two to four cents. The East/West spread narrowed by 0.7 cent to 21.4 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>Physical prices at Waha were also lower in the high-$1.50s.</p>
<p>At 1400 EDT, Hurricane Fran was about 445 miles southeast of Charleston, S.C., and heading northwest at 12 miles per hour. The storm, which may pick up more steam as it nears land, is expected to reach the Georgia and South Carolina coastlines by late Thursday.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
