<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32706" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Limited pre-payrolls action.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK - Limited pre-payrolls action.</headline>
<byline>Noah Barkin</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pre-payrolls nerves should keep price movement limited on Thursday, barring a big shocker in weekly jobless claims figures, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the fact that Thursday's (claims) number is far away from the payroll survey week it will give you hardly any information at all about Friday's number,&quot; said Anthony Chan, chief economist at Banc One Investment Advisors Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very very difficult to get much activity so close to the (payrolls) number unless claims are signficantly above or below expectations.&quot;  </p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters are expecting a slight rise in jobless claims for the week ended August 31 to 335,000 from 331,000 in the previous week.</p>
<p>Claims have risen for four consecutive weeks after reaching a low of 294,000 in late July, while the closely-watched four-week moving average for claims has advanced two weeks in a row.</p>
<p>Economists said claims have probably troughed and are likely to trend even higher in the coming weeks. Therefore, a sizable drop would come as a surprise.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we were to get a drop in jobless claims I think it would be important because it's highly unusual at this late stage in the cycle to see claims go lower,&quot; said Mary Dennis, senior economist at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>&quot;But I would not expect much on Thursday -- if anything maybe a little short-covering ahead of Friday,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Friday's payrolls report will shed more definitive light on third quarter economic strength and could push the Federal Reserve into hiking short-term interest rates at its upcoming September 24 meeting, economists said.  </p>
<p>Anticipation of this pivotal release should hamper any major position reshuffling on Thursday.</p>
<p>In addition to the claims report, the tail end of July car sales data will be released as well as individual companies' chain store sales reports for August.</p>
<p>Neither event is likely to produce much price action, economists said.</p>
<p>In late trading on Wednesday, the benchmark 6.75 percent 30-year bond was off 14/32 at 95-23/32 to yield 7.10 percent.</p>
<p>The federal funds rate is expected to open at 5-1/4 percent, in line with the Fed's target rate.</p>
<p>-- N.A. Treasury Desk 212-859-1673</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
