<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32707" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast spot power lower as Fran approaches.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast spot power lower as Fran approaches.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot electricity prices of the southeastern U.S. were mostly lower Wednesday ahead of the forecasted arrival of Hurricane Fran to South Carolina late Thursday or early Friday, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Anticipation of lower electricity demand because of stormy conditions subdued buying interests, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;They'll lean more to their own reserves,&quot; said one East Coast trader, referring to southern utilities that serve the coastal territories in the Southeast.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, peak power for Thursday was pegged in the mid-$20 range, down from Tuesday's $30 area.</p>
<p>Within the Southeastern Electric Reliability Council (SERC) district, next-day prices for non-firm, peak electricity were quoted at $18.00-$21.50, down from Tuesday's $19.00-$22.50 range.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, spot power prices in the Florida remained strong amid continued outages of two nuclear stations.</p>
<p>In the Florida pennisula, electricity prices for peak hour delivery Thursday were quoted in $36.00-$37.00 per megawatt hour (MWh), near unchanged from Tuesday's levels.</p>
<p>Florida Power &amp; Light Co's 839 megawatt (MW) St Lucie 1 nuclear power plant on Hutchinson Island remained shut after being taken off line Aug 31, but was expected to resume service later this week.</p>
<p>Florida Power Corp still did not set a restart date for its 825 MW Crystal River 3 nuclear unit at Red Level after shut the unit Monday night due to an lube oil leak.</p>
<p>Moreover, Carolina Power &amp; Light Co's 880 MW Harris nuclear plant in New Hill, N.C., was tripped off line Tuesday after the unit's water pumps failed. The utility did not have a schedule when it would return the plant to service.</p>
<p>The SERC district includes Alabama, Georgia, Florida, the Carolina, and parts of Virginia, Tennessee and Mississippi.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
