<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32712" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Apache Egyptian find tests 2,119 bbl/day.</title>
<headline>Apache Egyptian find tests 2,119 bbl/day.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apache Corp said Wednesday the second discovery in a month has been made on the Khalda Concession in Egypt's Western Desert.</p>
<p>The Salam SW-1X well tested at a combined rate of 49 million cubic feet (MMcf) of gas and 2,119 barrels of condensate per day from 47 feet of net pay in two separate zones, the Alam El Bueib 5A and 5B sands.</p>
<p>Apache owns 40 percent of the contractor interest in the Khalda Concession, Repsol SA is operator of the group and owns 50 percent, and Samsung Co owns the remaining 10 percent.  </p>
<p>The Khalda Concession is operated by Khalda Petroleum Co, an Egyptian corporation owned jointly by the contractors and the Egyptian General Petroleum Corp, the national oil company.</p>
<p>In a related development, Apache said, Khalda recently recompleted the Salam SE well in the Bahariya formation which is now producing at a rate of 1,000 barrels of oil per day.</p>
<p>This is the first Bahariya production established in this fault block, Apache pointed out.</p>
<p>It said evaluation is under way to determine the timing of appraisal and development drilling in the latest find, located about four miles southwest of Salam Field.  </p>
<p>Apache said negotiations are in progress for a long-term sales contract for the area's natural gas reserves.</p>
<p>It said the Salam SW-1X is the third consecutive successful exploratory well drilled during the past year in the fault block between Salam Field to the north and Hayat Field to the south, both of which were discovered in the mid- 1980s.</p>
<p>The company said the new well's 5A zone flowed at a daily rate of 21 million cubic feet of natual gas and 990 barrels of 46.5 gravity condensate daily when tested on a one-inch choke with 1,233 pounds per square inch of flowing tubing pressure from perforations between 10,756 feet and 10,788 feet.  </p>
<p>The 5B zone flowed at a daily rate of 28 million cubic feet of natural gas and 1,129 barrels of 46.7 gravity condensate through a one-inch choke with a flowing tubing pressure of 1,564 psi. It was perforated between 10,839 feet and 10,854 feet.  -- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
