<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32724" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot power steady in thin talk.</title>
<headline>U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot power steady in thin talk.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Mid-Atlantic spot power prices held steady in relatively thin discussion Wednesday as warmth continued to blanket much of the area, brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it's certainly not hot, it is pretty warm for September,&quot; one East Coast physicals trader said.</p>
<p>Some traders were skeptical about the continued price strength, particularly with the possibility of Hurricane Fran bringing clouds and showers to the East Coast.</p>
<p>Latest forecasts called for Hurricane Fran to hit South Carolina late Thursday or early Friday.</p>
<p>Despite the possibility of a hurricane, forecasts of normal to above-normal temperatures in the Mid-Atlantic held sway.</p>
<p>Next day, peak electricity prices in the Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Maryland (PJM) Interconnect power pool were said to be trading in the $23.75-24.75 range with unconfirmed reports of trades at $24.50, steady from discussion near $24.50 per megawatt hour (MWh) on Tuesday, brokers and traders said.</p>
<p>Peak power for the remainder of this week was said to be discussed near $24.00 from remainder of the week discussion at $23.75-24.50 on Tuesday, the sources said.</p>
<p>Peak electricity for the remainder of September was talked steady in the $21.20-22.40 range with one unconfirmed trade at $21.90 per MWh.</p>
<p>October PJM prices, under the same delivery conditions, were discussed in a range of $20.30-20.55 from a range of $20.35-20.40 per MWh on Tuesday, the brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>Peak PJM power for the fourth quarter was pegged at $22.30-22.60 from a Tuesday range of $22.25-22.50 per MWh, the sources said.</p>
<p>-- Chris Reese, New York Power Desk 212-859-1627</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
