<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32721" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends lower in choppy trading.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends lower in choppy trading.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper settled lower, dragged down in a thin, choppy market by heavy selling in London.</p>
<p>COMEX copper opened some three cents lower to move in line with a weaker LME which had been dragged down by heavy selling overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;Since then the market tried to make a comeback,&quot; a trader said. New York pared some of its losses by the close. &quot;The fundamentals look strong and the market is going to go higher,&quot; the trader added.</p>
<p>December copper settled 1.45 cents lower at 94.40 cents per pound, traded 95.20 to 92.60 cents. Spot September went out 1.50 cents weaker at 95.15 cents. Volume was estimated at 7,000 lots compared to Tuesday's official 8,751 lots. COMEX stocks on Wednesday were unchanged at 22,104 short tons.</p>
<p>Phelps Dodge and labor unions at the company's Chino mine in New Mexico appeared headed towards a stalemate in renewing a labor contract which expired on June 30.</p>
<p>Phelps said it was not willing to renegotiate its final offer made last month. A union official said many of the terms in the offer were unacceptable. The mine is operating normally.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
