<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32730" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT--Stg rally may have run course -US experts.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT--Stg rally may have run course -US experts.</headline>
<byline>Alden Bentley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling's advance met key technical targets near $1.57 and 2.33 marks on Tuesday and analysts said recent bullishness could soon unravel.</p>
<p>&quot;The rally from 1.4900 back at the beginning of May is in the process of ending within $1.5700/$1.5735, and we're looking for weakness to reemerge on the British pound against all its crosses and against the dollar,&quot; said Darren Spain, currency analyst at Credit Suisse.  </p>
<p>At 1530 EDT/1930 GMT on Wednesday, sterling was trading at $1.5671/76 and 2.3205/15 marks, off from Wednesday's early highs of $1.5687 and 2.3289 marks.</p>
<p>Analysts said near-term sterling support comes into play at 1.5630 and then 1.5610.</p>
<p>Some chartists point out that technical studies on the pound may cloud the picture.  Against the dollar, weekly stochastics and the Relative Strength Indicators (RSIs) are suggesting a higher pound, said Ture Johnson, technical analyst at Bank of America.  </p>
<p>In addition, the average directional index is very contracted. &quot;That should suggest a very dynamic move,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Johnson said his bias was for a powerful move lower, with a break below $1.5600/10, confirming a near-term top at Tuesday's $1.5695 peak.</p>
<p>However, a puncture and close above $1.57 would negate a short-term bearish scenario and suggest a &quot;near vertical move&quot; to the $1.5950 to $1.60 area.  Such a rally should terminate the longer-term advance, Johnson said.</p>
<p>Confirmation of a sterling/mark top would come on a move back below 2.3150 at any stage, Spain said.</p>
<p>But there is an alternate scenario with a rosier resolution in sterling/mark.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm still pretty favorable here,&quot; said Pete Grant, senior foreign exchange analyst at MMS International.</p>
<p>&quot;The first resistance level is 2.3333 marks, which is the low from July 18; if we break above it, the next stop would be our 2.34 mark target.&quot;</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1667</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
