<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32741" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMM currency futures finish mostly higher.</title>
<headline>IMM currency futures finish mostly higher.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMM currency futures finished mostly higher in a day of consolidative trade, rebounding from losses on Tuesday.</p>
<p>September yen led the gains, rebounding from seven-week lows that were set on Tuesday after the U.S. launched a Cruise missile attack against Iraq. A second U.S. attack later was largely brushed off, although some contracts strengthened a bit more near midday on Wednesday when reports surfaced of explosions and anti-aircraft fire in Baghdad. But the U.S. denied involvement in that episode, and most contracts came off their highs.  </p>
<p>Traders tied mounting U.S. Treasury bond weakness more to technicals than to tensions in the Middle East. Overall, traders said the U.S.-Iraq situation had a minimal effect on the currency markets, allowing September yen to easily recapture Tuesday's losses and others to rebound.</p>
<p>September sterling retreated from the highest price all year it set on Tuesday in sync with an oil rally. As traders downplayed the magnitude of Middle Eastern tensions, sterling backed off on Wednesday.</p>
<p>One analyst said it may be difficult to get a move in currencies until Friday's U.S. August jobs report.  </p>
<p>U.S. August non-farm payrolls were forecast to rise 244,000. German second-quarter gross domestic product was due on Thursday and forecast to rise 1.1 percent. Also on Thursday is a Bundesbank council meeting.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, ranges could reign.</p>
<p>September sterling, Swiss francs and Canadian dollars all posted inside days on daily bar charts on Wednesday, signs of consolidation. Technicians pegged support in September yen at Tuesday's session and seven-week low of $0.009170. Resistance was seen at $0.009256.  </p>
<p>September yen settled up $0.000040 at $0.009210, marks gained $0.0016 to $0.6758, Swiss fr rose $0.0010 to $0.8297, sterling fell $0.0008 at $1.5668, Canadian dollar rose $0.0004 to $0.7306, Aussie dollar rose $0.0001 to $0.7914, Mexican peso fell $0.000100 to $0.130875. --Derivatives Desk 312-408-8750 E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
