<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32744" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST - Distillates still the star of API data.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Distillates still the star of API data.</headline>
<byline>Harry Milling</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The conflict in Iraq has crude oil in the limelight, but when it comes to the American Petroleum Institute's weekly inventory data to be released Wednesday evening distillates are still the star.</p>
<p>&quot;Distillates are definitely the first place to look,&quot; said Peter Beutel, analyst and president of Cameron Hanover.</p>
<p>Heating oil led NYMEX oil prices sharply higher this summer on concerns of historically low distillate inventories. A Reuters survey estimates a build in distillate stocks for the week ended August 30 of a mere 1.70 million barrels.  </p>
<p>Industry analysts said heating oil stocks should build about two million to three million barrels on a weekly basis at the end of summer to prepare for winter.</p>
<p>Meanhwile, crude oil stocks could build slightly less than one million barrels after a surprisingly large build of 10.4 billion barrels posted in the last API report, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be just a correction from the week earlier,&quot; said a trader of the smaller build expected in crude.</p>
<p>Analysts expected gasoline stocks to show a draw of a little more than one million barrels reflecting motorists enjoying the U.S. Labor Day weekend holiday.  </p>
<p>Still, the expected draw in gasoline, as draws in previous weeks, was characterized as lackluster despite summer traditionally being the period of highest demand for gasoline.</p>
<p>With the gasoline season having ended and winter just months away, refineries are shifting their slates to boost distillate stocks. For the latest week, however, analysts expect refinery utilization rates to have remained steady.</p>
<p>At August 23, API showed total distillate stocks down 15 percent over year ago levels.  </p>
<p>In that report, distillate stocks grew in PADD 1 (the northeastern United States), the world's largest market for heating oil, but analysts said the growth was not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;We just have not been able to build stocks in PADD 1 and diesel demand has been strong,&quot; Dean Witter analyst Steve Platt said.</p>
<p>However, he said crude stocks are ample enough to easily feed the high refinery runs that will be required to make sure heating oil stocks catch up with winter demand.</p>
<p>&quot;Crude stocks have been showing continued improvement, and we are not looking at anywhere near the tighteness we saw last year,&quot; said Platt.</p>
<p>&quot;If this (the Iraqi conflict) had happened last year, there would have been more of a panic,&quot; he said of crude's price move on the Iraqi conflict.</p>
<p>Despite an expected bullish API report for distillates, the data in general may be overshadowed by the market due to political tensions in Iraq, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers are not going to make much of a difference to the market tomorrow because the Iraq conflict eclipses it,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, + 1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
