<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32742" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Grigsby declines to name problem on Cleveland deal.</title>
<headline>Grigsby declines to name problem on Cleveland deal.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of Grigsby Brandford &amp; Co declined Wednesday to say what the problem was that forced the firm to drop out of completing a $82 million Cleveland bond issue last month.</p>
<p>Calvin Grigsby, president and chief executive officer of the San Franscisco-based minority-owned firm, would say only that it had nothing to do with the firm's ability to take down bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not related to our ability to take down bonds,&quot; Grigsby said.</p>
<p>According to Kathryn Hyer, Cleveland's finance director, Grigsby Brandford's initial pricing of the parking facilities refunding revenue bonds resulted in oversubscription in some maturities. The firm then repriced the issue higher losing some orders.</p>
<p>Hyer said Tuesday that Grigsby Brandford then failed to extend a written offer for the bond purchase agreement, forcing the city to scrap deal, which was insured by MBIA Insurance Corp.</p>
<p>The bond issue was subsequently priced Aug 29 with Travelers Group Inc's Smith Barney Inc as bookrunner and Grigsby reduced to a co-manager. By that time, market conditions had worsened and $500,000 was shaved off of the $7.5 million present value savings the city realized on the refunding.</p>
<p>Rumors of disclosure or other technical problems that spread about the issue proved to be unfounded as Hyer confirmed that documents for the deal were virtually identical for both the Aug 22 and Aug 29 pricings.</p>
<p>She has said that only Grigsby officials could say why they chose not to sign a bond purchase agreement.</p>
<p>But Calvin Grigsby would not comment on why the firm dropped out of the deal.</p>
<p>Instead, he took issue with market speculation that some minority-owned firms are too thinly capitalized to weather market downturns and protect their clients from losses.</p>
<p>He said his firm proved that it could carry unsold bonds last week when it priced a $187 million Dade County deal with three other firms. He said the market dropped a point and the firm was forced to take down $100 million of bonds.</p>
<p>Cleveland's Hyer has said she would be reluctant to use Grigsby Brandford as senior manager again. However, her stance on using the firm appeared to be moot as her resignation as the city's finance director was announced late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hyer, who leaves the city post Sept 20, will join Chicago-based EVEREN Securities as a managing director in a new healthcare initiative at the investment banking firm.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
