<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32747" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY precious metals end lower on light volumes.</title>
<headline>NY precious metals end lower on light volumes.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York precious metals futures ended lower Wednesday on light volumes, after some disappointment over the lack of reaction by gold prices to the latest tensions in the Middle East, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some funds look to be going off gold and probing for weakness, with the tensions in Iraq failing to cause a bounce,&quot; Chase Manhattan managing director, Dinsa Mehta said.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is really very little activity, one week historical volatility is around two percent only, and there is solid physical demand and even producer buyback interest at only slightly lower levels,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>COMEX December gold ended down 80 cents at $389.70 an ounce, after trading in a $391.00-$389.40 range.</p>
<p>In New York bullion trade, spot gold was quoted $385.50/386.00, from a London afternoon fix Wednesday at $385.60, compared to a Tuesday close in New York at $386.15/386.55.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some stops hit around $390.00, basis December gold, and some scattered fund selling but the trade has been a net buyer,&quot; Pell Brothers floor trader Don Tierney said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But silver has been holding up, with deliveries of the September contract down to only 400 contracts from 2,800 Friday and 11,000 on the first day of delivery back in July,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COMEX December silver ended up 2.2 cents at $5.230 an ounce, after trading in a $5.250-5.195 range.</p>
<p>With the September silver delivery period underway, most of the shorts have already rolled out of their positions, suggesting prices could come off further in the days ahead, analysts said.</p>
<p>The platinum metals group was weaker though, in line with gold, with NYMEX October platinum ending down $1.50 an ounce at $397.20 and YMEX December palladium closing down 50 cents at $126.50.</p>
<p>--Clive McKeef, New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
