<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32758" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Group says Reading deal &quot;unacceptable&quot;.</title>
<headline>Group says Reading deal &quot;unacceptable&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group led by Libra Advisors Inc said Wednesday it had reviewed a proposed capital restructuring of Reading Co and considers terms of the plan &quot;unacceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>Under a letter of intent announced last month, Craig Corp and Citadel Holding Corp would transfer assets and cash valued at about $88 million in exchange for preferred and equity stock of a still-to-be-formed holding company for Reading.  </p>
<p>The Libra group, which holds a 6.4 percent stake in Reading, said in a Securities and Exchange Commission filing that it had notified Reading of its position in a letter sent on August 28.</p>
<p>In the letter, a copy of which was attached to the filing, the group said that if the deal were consummated as currently contemplated, it would breach the Reading board's fiduciary duty to minority shareholders.  </p>
<p>Given that Reading's book value as of June 30 was in excess of $14 a share, with $8 per share represented in cash, &quot;it would appear not to be in the shareholders' best interests to exchange stock in the company at a conversion price representing a discount to book value for assets of questionable value,&quot; the group said in the letter.</p>
<p>The group also criticized the premium on the convertible preferred stock to be issued by Reading, saying such a premium &quot;should be significantly higher.&quot;  </p>
<p>It said Reading has identified its business as theater development and said it sees no legitimate business reason for the company to buy stock of the supermarket chain, referring to Craig.</p>
<p>It said if the transaction is completed as currently structured, it intends to avail itself of all remedies to challenge the alleged breach of fiduciary duty to minority shareholders by Reading's board.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Craig said it owned a 50.7 percent stake in Reading, while Craig and Reading together held 40 percent of the outstanding voting power in Citadel and a warrant to buy from Citadal additional shares equal to 11 percent of Citadel's common.</p>
<p>Citadel's business is in real estate, a company spokesman said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
