<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32755" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Transports seen re-testing July lows.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Transports seen re-testing July lows.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Transportation shares, under pressure even before the U.S. attack on Iraq sent oil prices surging, appear headed for a retest of the lows set during July's sharp selloff, analysts said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the Dow Jones Transportation index fell nearly 20 points to 2025.70 as oil prices surged to four-month highs on news of the assault on Iraq.  It fell again on Wednesday, dropping 13 points to 2013 by early afternoon, and technicians held out little hope for a rebound soon.  </p>
<p>&quot;Oil prices are working their way through the stocks right now and my sense is we'll probably retest the July lows at around 1950,&quot; said Gruntal &amp; Co technical analyst Peter Green.</p>
<p>Green said the index could find its next support near 1900, where it troughed in January, if it broke 1950.</p>
<p>During the stock selloff in July, the index closed in the 1960's three times, with the lowest close of 1965.70 coming on July 24, some 14 percent off its peak 2296.20 close on May 22.</p>
<p>Since then, the industrials rebounded to just short of their all-time highs, while the transports languished below their 200-day moving average.  </p>
<p>&quot;Since the market peaked in May, you've seen a real divergence,&quot; said Ricky Harrington, technical analyst at Interstate/Johnson Lane.  &quot;The transports, more or less like what has happaned to secondary stocks, haven't been able to recover like the Dow (industrials).&quot;</p>
<p>Technicians said the subdued performance relative to the industrials had broader market implications.</p>
<p>&quot;It tells me you're in a secondary corrective phase,&quot; said Ralph Acampora, director of technical research at Prudential Securities, &quot;and this was a pre-Iraq problem that happened in and of itself from market forces.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Now you couple that with the cost of oil and the Iraqi situation and I think it means the transport index goes back and retests the July lows,&quot; Acampora said.</p>
<p>Analysts said they saw little hope of an upside breakout without a meaningful fall in Treasury yields but they also stressed the transports' weak performance of late was not enough on its own to call for a bear market.</p>
<p>&quot;The divergence in the transports is an indicator to consider but it's only one of a dozen possible indicators,&quot; said Harrington.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
