<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32752" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Manufactured Home bid expected to succeed.</title>
<headline>Manufactured Home bid expected to succeed.</headline>
<byline>Susan Nadeau</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manufactured Home Communities Inc's hostile takeover bid for Chateau Properties Inc will likely prove successful, analysts specializing in real estate investment trusts (REITs) said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Despite a flurry of merger offers, they see few alternatives for the Chateau board of directors, which may even face lawsuits if the proposal is rejected, analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think he (Manufactured Home Chairman Samuel Zell) probably has a pretty good shot at it,&quot; said William Acheson, an analyst for Smith Barney. &quot;It's difficult for a board to nix an all-cash deal that is very attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday, the company launched a $26 a share tender offer for Michigan-based Chateau. The bid follows a similar offer last month to which Chateau did not respond.</p>
<p>&quot;They've said all along that if the board sends signals that it's not going to be accommodating, they would take it straight to shareholders,&quot; said BT Securities analyst Kevin Comer.  </p>
<p>Chateau officials were not immediately available for comment. In the past Chateau has said that its articles of corporation prohibit any entity or person from owning more than seven percent of its outstanding common shares without board approval.</p>
<p>Analysts, however, said the seven percent rule was designed to assure the company maintains its tax-preferred status as a REIT. In order to be considered a REIT, five entities cannot own more than 50 percent of the company, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The intention is to keep the tax-preferred REIT status, and it is not intended to be a defense mechanism whatsoever,&quot; said one REIT analyst who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Chateau's board members are mainly holders of operating partnership units. Although Manufactured Home's offer includes those board members, capital gains tax would keep the $26 cash offer from being attractive, analysts said. Manufactured Home's earlier stock offer is valued at about $21 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the board's hiding behind the seven percent (rule) would subject them to some legal ramifications,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;I think it's a good deal.&quot;  </p>
<p>The tug-of-war in the REIT industry began in July when Chateau and Colorado-based ROC Communities Inc agreed to merge into one company, Chateau Communities.</p>
<p>MHC, based in Chicago, followed with an offer of $26 a share in cash, or 1.15 MHC shares per Chateau share, worth about $21 a share. And just days later Sun Communities Inc offered 0.892 share per Chateau share, currently valued at about $25 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;Originally, it was prompted by the willingness of Chateau to merge with another company, which wasn't there before,&quot; the analyst said.  </p>
<p>The four companies operate sites for pre-fabricated homes. Most of the high-quality properties have already been taken up by one of them, analysts said. And it is difficult to secure zoning for manufactured housing, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so few large portfolios left out there,&quot; Smith Barney's Acheson said.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home said it has received overwhelming support from Chateau shareholders, but it is still hoping for a friendly deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We'd still like to work out a deal,&quot; Manufactured Home Chief Executive David Helfand said in an interview. &quot;We're committed to this because it makes sense.&quot;</p>
<p>Nonetheless, not everyone is sold on the company's offer.</p>
<p>&quot;The action by MHC will accelerate the process but I still think it's too early to tell,&quot; who will ultimately capture Chateau, said Jim Sullivan, a REIT analyst for Green Street Advisors, pointing out that on a stock basis the Sun offer is higher than Manufactured Home's.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
