<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32769" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mondale sees U.S. trade deficit with Japan falling.</title>
<headline>Mondale sees U.S. trade deficit with Japan falling.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Ambassador to Japan Walter Mondale said Wednesday he expects the U.S. trade deficit with Japan to decline to below $60 billion this year.</p>
<p>Mondale told the National Press Club that U.S. exports to Japan are rising faster than imports and that will help cut the huge bilateral trade imbalance this year after hitting about $67 billion.</p>
<p>He said U.S. exports had been helped in part by a strong yen, but that the 21 bilateral trade agreements between Washington and Tokyo have helped open markets in Japan to U.S. products.</p>
<p>The U.S. Commerce Department last month reported  that despite a 23.1 percent drop in the U.S. overall trade deficit in June compared with May, the U.S. trade shortfall with Japan reached $3.24 billion in June, up 3.6 percent from May.</p>
<p>The Commerce Department also reported at that time that the U.S. trade deficit with China surpassed the U.S. trade shortfall with Japan for the first time.  The U.S. trade deficit with China rose to $3.33 billion in June, up 8.8 percent from May.  </p>
<p>Mondale also said the dispute between Washington and Tokyo over deregulation of Japan's insurance market is proving to be difficult to resolve.</p>
<p>&quot;I am really worried about the insurance issue because we have an agreement and those agreements should mean something when they are signed,&quot; Mondale told a National Press Club luncheon in Washington. &quot;Normally they do, but this one is proving to be very difficult.&quot;  </p>
<p>Mondale said the move would put pressure on foreign companies in the third sector, which represents about five percent of Japan's $382 billion insurance market.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of them would be driven out,&quot; he said. &quot;This is not good for Japanese insurance consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>Efforts to resolve the dispute by July 31 failed after a round of marathon negotiations in Vancouver, British Columbia, ended in no agreement.</p>
<p>The United States hopes a new round of negotiations can be set, and Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Japanese Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau, and U.S. Trade Representative senior negotiator Ira Shapiro met in Washington to discuss a possible schedule for negotiations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
