<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32787" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ramtron rise continues on fabrication deal.</title>
<headline>Ramtron rise continues on fabrication deal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ramtron International Corp shares continued their sharp rise on Wednesday, extending gains sparked yesterday by news of a semiconductor fabrication agreement with Rohm Co Ltd, traders said.</p>
<p>In unusually heavy Nasdaq trade, the stock added almost 11 percent, or 7/8, to 8-1/2. Its intraday high was 8-7/8.</p>
<p>Ramtron rose 1-11/16 on Tuesday, a 28.4 percent increase that topped the Nasdaq percent-gainers list. The stock's year-high is 12-3/4, while its low is 4-3/4.</p>
<p>Rohm will produce memory products based on Ramtron's ferroelectric random access memory technology this month.  </p>
<p>According to Ramtron Chairman David Sikes, Rohm's intitial capacity will be about 1,000 semiconductor wafers per month, worth $2 million per month in sales to Ramtron. Rohm will ramp to 10,000 wafers per month, worth about $250 million in annual sales, he said.</p>
<p>As part of the agreement, about one-third of that capacity will be returned to Ramtron for sale to original equipment manufacturers, Sikes said.</p>
<p>Currently, Ramtron produces small amounts of prototype FRAM chips at its Colorado Springs, Colo., facility, which amounts to about $500,000 in sales per quarter, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We did $29 milllion in sales last year and we see $34 million next year, and in 1997 we see significant revenue growth with the ramp-up in FRAM production,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Concurrent with the Rohm announcement, Ramtron said it had reached fabrication deals with Hitachi Ltd, Toshiba Corp and Fujitsu Ltd under similar arrangements that provide licensing and royalty revenue to Ramtron.</p>
<p>Hitachi is the next manufacturing partner to come on-line with a 256-kilobyte device that will be in in full production in 1997. Fujitsu and Toshiba will begin production in 1997 and 1998, Ramtron said.</p>
<p>-- Brendan Intindola, Wall Street Desk 212-859-1734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
