<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32783" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Commercial Intertech sees strong Q4 results.</title>
<headline>Commercial Intertech sees strong Q4 results.</headline>
<dateline>YOUNGSTOWN, Ohio 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Commercial Intertech Corp said Wednesday it foresaw strong fourth-quarter results for itself and its subsidiary, CUNO Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain optimistic that both Commercial Intertech and CUNO Incorporated will report strong fourth-quarter results,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Commercial Intertech, a multinational company with 27 manufacturing plants in eight countries, makes metal products as well as hydraulic and building systems.</p>
<p>CUNO, with eight plants in six countries, makes filtration and purification systems to remove contaminants from gases and fluids like water.</p>
<p>Commercial Intertech said it expected its operating income to be the same this year as it was in 1995.</p>
<p>Net income would be &quot;somewhat&quot; lower than last year due to higher tax rates and interest expenses, it added.</p>
<p>The company said it expected fourth quarter and fiscal year operating income for Astron Building Systems to exceed by &quot;a wide margin&quot; the amount it reported for the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Business conditions remain relatively strong for Astron,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company said it foresaw U.S. Metal Stamping units improving their performance.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe full-year performance should approximate the strong results posted last year,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>The company said Hydraulic Systems was expecting a better fourth quarter as it began to receive more bookings.</p>
<p>&quot;Operating income for the fourth quarter will exceed income for the same 1995 period,&quot; it said. &quot;For the full-year, Hydraulic Systems peformance should be near the record level achieved in 1995.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32830">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YOUNGSTOWN, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
