<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32797" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MK Rail's locomotive unit restructuring.</title>
<headline>MK Rail's locomotive unit restructuring.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>MK Rail Corp said Wednesday its locomotive parts distribution subsidiary, Power Parts Co, has begun a restructuring plan that includes annualized cost reductions of about $1 million, and expansion of its product line and service capabilities.</p>
<p>The plan will result in a work force reduction at Power Parts of about 25 percent, or 25 people, through increased efficiency, elimination of redundant management functions and the planned sale of a non-core product line, MK Rail said.  </p>
<p>Based in Elk Grove Village, Ill., Power Parts has historically provided replacement parts primarily for General Motors Corp locomotives. Power Parts now plans to supply components for General Electric Co  locomotives, as well as freight car parts.</p>
<p>In addition, Power Parts will expand into other segments of the rail and transit industries, distributing parts for maintenance of way equipment, and providing warehousing services for railroads and other MK Rail subsidiaries, the company said.</p>
<p>Power Parts also plans to provide selected components for marine, industrial, mining and electrical applications.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already providing warehousing services for Class I railroads, and we have had some initial successes with new products and markets,&quot; the company explained.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Power Parts is positioned to respond to this demand in both domestic and Mexican markets because we recently moved into a modern warehouse that has increased our capacity, productivity and efficiency.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
