<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32813" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. not considering oil market intervention - DOE.</title>
<headline>U.S. not considering oil market intervention - DOE.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Clinton administration is not considering attempting any types of market intervention, such as tapping government oil reserves, in the wake of an oil price spike after U.S. military action against Iraq, Energy Deputy Secretary Charles Curtis said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no consideration that the government's going to try to manage these markets either by action in the SPRO (Strategic Petroleum Reserve) or otherwise by seeking to require specific inventory levels to be maintained&quot; by oil companies, Curtis told reporters after testifying to a Senate Energy subcommittee.  </p>
<p>But Curtis said he expected a &quot;price spike of some dimension&quot; because he expected Iraq would not be allowed to sell oil in a food-for-oil deal for at least 60 days, and because crude and product stocks are at 20-year lows.</p>
<p>&quot;So introducing any instability into the market or perception of instability is a concerning circumstance when stocks are this low. There's obviously a considerable buy-pressure coming into the market to replenish those stocks and it being now apparent that Iraqi oil is not going to flow for at least 60 days and so this is going to produce a price spike of some dimension,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>But Curtis said, &quot;I see no evidence right now that we have a circumstance that would warrant a withdrawal or a distribution of oil from the strategic reserves.&quot;</p>
<p>Curtis also said he knew of no talk of requiring oil companies to keep higher inventories to try to reduce market volatility. And he said given the market situation, &quot;Those with low stocks are going to get the opportunity to rebuild the inventory at significantly higher prices.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked how long he expected the military action to delay the United Nation's plan to allow Iraq to sell $2 billion of oil to raise money for humanitarian needs, Curtis said, &quot;I think everything depends, as has been the case, on Saddam Hussein's actions. If we get responsible actions, then I expect the sale can take place, but we're in a situation now where responsibility needs to be demonstrated.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
