<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32848" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubbermaid shares drop on Q3 warning.</title>
<headline>Rubbermaid shares drop on Q3 warning.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of Rubbermaid Inc fell sharply after the company warned that third quarter earnings would be hurt by rising prices for raw materials.</p>
<p>The Wooster, Ohio-based company said it now expects third quarter sales and earnings to be flat with year-ago levels of $0.32 per share versus Wall Street expectations of about $0.40.</p>
<p>&quot;People were expecting that the quarter could be up 15 to 20 percent,&quot; said Eric Bosshard of Midwest Research-Maxus Group.</p>
<p>Rubbermaid stock was down 2-3/8 at 24-1/8 in morning trade.  </p>
<p>Another analyst who did not want to be identified said he had anticipated third quarter sales to rise about six percent from year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Rubbermaid blamed the weaker outlook on rising prices for resins, the raw material used in plastics production. It said resin costs have risen more than 50 percent in the past five months.</p>
<p>Analysts said the impact of higher resin prices is likely to carry into the fourth quarter, which typically is weaker than the third quarter. First Call Co. pegged analysts' fourth quarter estimates at $0.36 per share.</p>
<p>Rubbermaid sought to dampen the bleak outlook by also announcing the acquisition of privately held Graco Childrens Products Inc for $320 million cash. Analysts said the purchase of Graco is positive for Rubbermaid, but is not substantial enough to offset concerns about earnings -- Robin Sidel, 212/859-1723</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I48000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
