<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32895" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vitalink, GranCare pharmacy unit to merge.</title>
<headline>Vitalink, GranCare pharmacy unit to merge.</headline>
<dateline>NAPERVILLE, Ill. 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vitalink Pharmacy Services Inc and GranCare Inc said Wednesday they entered into a definitive merger agreement under which GranCare's institutional pharmacy business, TeamCare, would merge with Vitalink.</p>
<p>Vitalink is an 82 percent-owned subsidiary of Manor Care Inc.</p>
<p>After completion of the the merger, Vitalink would have about $400 million in annual revenues, they added.  </p>
<p>The merger, valued at approximately $370 million, would be accounted for under the purchase method of accounting and would be treated as a tax-free exchange of shares, they added.</p>
<p>As part of the transaction, GranCare would spin off its skilled nursing operations in a tax-free distribution to shareholders.  The company's remaining indebtedness then would total approximately $107 million.</p>
<p>Under the proposed merger, Vitalink would issue about 11.6 million shares in exchange for all outstanding shares and stock options of GranCare and would assume the $107 million in debt.  </p>
<p>The skilled nursing operations would retain the GranCare name.</p>
<p>The transaction was approved by the board of each company but remains subject to approval of GranCare shareholders, regulatory approval and other customary closing conditions.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close on or before December 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Following the merger, Vitalink would serve 166,000 beds, or approximately 10 percent of total skilled nursing facility beds in the United States, through 54 pharmacy locations in 29 states nationwide, the companies said.  </p>
<p>It is estimated that on a pro forma basis, the combined companies would have total assets of approximately $450 million. Pro forma long-term debt would be approximately $107 million, or 15 percent of total market capitalization, based on Vitalink's current $23 per share price.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to realize significant operating savings through purchasing leverage and the elimination of duplicate functions in our organizations,&quot; Donna DeNardo, Vitalink president, said in a state.</p>
<p>After the merger, Stewart Bainum Jr, chairman of Manor Care, would become chairman of Vitalink.  Gene Burleson, GranCare chairman, would be Vitalink's chief executive officer. The board would consist four Vitalink and four TeamCare board members.</p>
<p>Bainum said the merger of Vitalink and TeamCare would create a market-leading institutional pharamcy company that is well-positioned for internal growth and further acquisitions as the industry consolidates.</p>
<p>&quot;Our expanded customer base and geographic presence will allow us to capture a greater share of the growing subacute nursing and assisted living facilities markets,&quot; Burleson added.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPERVILLE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
