<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32903" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Manufactured Homes renews Chateau bid.</title>
<headline>Manufactured Homes renews Chateau bid.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Manufactured Home Communities Inc said on Wednesday that it has started a cash tender for the 6.1 million outstanding shares of Chateau Properties Inc at $26 per share.</p>
<p>The bid comes after an earlier, similar offer by Manufactured Communities chairman Samuel Zell to which Chateau did not respond, it said.</p>
<p>It said that it remained willing to enter into negotiations with Chateau at any time.  </p>
<p>Manufactured Home's bid for Chateau competes with Sun Communities Inc's $372 million unsolicited stock offer for the firm.</p>
<p>Michigan-based Chateau has previously agreed to merge with ROC Communities Inc in a tax-free stock swap.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home's proposal, first made August 16, offers Chateau shareholders $26 a share in cash or 1.15 Manufactured Home shares for each Chateau share, or a combination of both.</p>
<p>Manufactured Home said it believes its offer provides a &quot;substantially greater&quot; value to Chateau's shareholders than the proposed ROC transaction or Sun Communities' bid.  </p>
<p>&quot;The combination of Chateau and (Manufactured Home) will unite the two highest quality portfolios in the industry,&quot; David Helfand, chief executive officer of Manufactured Home, said in a statement.  &quot;The new entity would have superior financial strength, significant liquidity and unparalleled access to capital.&quot;</p>
<p>Zell added in a statement that Manufactured Home was &quot;determined to take every appropriate action to successfully consummate this transaction.&quot;</p>
<p>Manufactured Home said its tender offer is not subject to any financing contingencies. The offer is subject to certain conditions, including the tender of at least two-thirds of the outstanding shares.</p>
<p>The tender offer is scheduled to expire October 1.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010022">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
