<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32919" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Sept 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Sept 4.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Matt Damon has landed the lead lawyer role in &quot;The Rainmaker,&quot; the Francis Ford Coppola-directed adaptation of the John Grisham bestseller, Daily Variety reported on Wednesday.,</p>
<p>Damon, who was last seen in &quot;Courage Under Fire,&quot; will play Rudy Baylor, a young lawyer who finds that the job he worked so hard to land has disappeared along with the firm.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported:</p>
<p>* Jack Lemmon is one of the five Kennedy Center honorees this year at a Dec 8 ceremony, as are playwright Edward Albee, composer-musician Benny Carter, country's Johnny Cash and dancer Maria Tallchief.</p>
<p>* A TV movie based on the America's Most Wanted franchise, a pop-culture quiz show for Generation Xer's, and a special about aliens and monsters in Hollywood are part of Twentieth Television's beefed-up development and production slate for 1997.</p>
<p>* Producer Robert Altman and director Alan Rudolph, who last collaborated on 1994's &quot;Mrs. Parker and the Vicious Circle,&quot; will reteam to make &quot;Afterglow.&quot;</p>
<p>The film stars Nick Nolte, Julie Christie, Lara Flynn Boyle and Johnny Lee Miller. It begins shooting in Montreal Saturday.</p>
<p>Written by Rudolph, the film follows two couples, one in their late 40s, the other in their 20s, whose troubled marriages become entwined.</p>
<p>* The summer 1996 moviegoing season closed with a record $2.19 billion -- a boost of about three percent from the prior seasonal high set last year.</p>
<p>It's also the second straight year in which there was modest box office growth but a decline in admissions. The season recorded roughly 488.6 million torn stubs, a dip of about 0.5 percent in ticket sales.</p>
<p>* Marc Platt, former TriStar Pictures president, has joined Seagram Co's Universal Pictures as president of production. Platt replaces Hal Lieberman, who exited the studio two weeks ago after nine years.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
