<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32921" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tacoma council repeals tax on Internet providers.</title>
<headline>Tacoma council repeals tax on Internet providers.</headline>
<dateline>TACOMA, Wash. 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tacoma City Council members voted on Tuesday to exempt Internet service providers from a 6 percent telecommunications tax that had attracted nationwide attention.</p>
<p>With only one dissenting vote, the council approved the exemption at the urging of Mayor Brian Ebersole, who said Tacoma's reputation as a good place to do business outweighed the estimated $200,000 in annual revenue the city stands to lose.</p>
<p>The tax had been imposed on Internet companies in March by Tacoma's tax and license department as part of a broader levy that affects users of cellular telephones, pagers and other equipment who get billed at addresses within the city, about 30 miles south of Seattle.</p>
<p>Ebersole called the decision, which affected all major online service providers including America Online and Compuserve &quot;ill-advised&quot; and argued that exempting the companies would benefit the city.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we will gain revenue through this measure because so much of our economic activity is determined by image -- what people think about Tacoma as a place to do business,&quot; Ebersole said.</p>
<p>Tacoma will provide refunds to Internet service providers who already paid the tax.</p>
<p>Tacoma is one of many cities and states who have seized on the rapid growth of the Internet as a potential for raising needed tax revenues.</p>
<p>West Virginia, Tennessee, Texas, New York and Ohio have similar taxes in place, and California, Florida, New York and Washington state are considering them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TACOMA, Wash."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
