<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32927" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices shave gains as Iraq withdraws troops.</title>
<headline>Oil prices shave gains as Iraq withdraws troops.</headline>
<byline>Karen Matusic</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil markets reacted calmly on Wednesday to news of more U.S. missile strikes on Iraq but analysts said nervous traders were reluctant to take profits amid continuing tension in the Middle East.</p>
<p>Oil futures in London ended lower after seesaw trade when U.S. President Bill Clinton said missile attacks in Iraq had achieved their aim and Iraq had withdrawn its forces from northern Kurdish safe havens.</p>
<p>Markets earlier shrugged off news of a second U.S. strike on Iraqi defence equipment but then shot back up on news of a third hit on a radar station in the expanded no-fly zone in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>October futures for international benchmark Brent Blend ended down 10 cents on the day at $22.11 after shooting up $1.40 in two days.</p>
<p>The market would be prone to knee-jerk reactions resulting in price spikes as long as the standoff between Baghdad and Washington continues, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a perceived supply disruption which is causing commercial oil operators to rethink their autumn stock situation. Volatility has returned to the oil market,&quot; said Peter Gignoux, head of the London energy desk at Smith, Barney.</p>
<p>Analysts said any real or perceived threat to vital oil supplies in the region, combined with already strong demand at a time when inventories are low, should keep oil prices firm through the end of the year.</p>
<p>Despite the earlier pullback, Brent has gained more than $1 in reaction to Iraq's military Kurdish incursion and U.S. retaliation and is nearly $6 above levels seen this time last year.</p>
<p>Baghdad's attacks on Kurdish strongholds have prompted an indefinite delay in the implementation of a United Nations agreement allowing Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil to pay for food and medical supplies.</p>
<p>Without the expected 600,000 to 700,000 barrels per day (bpd) of Iraqi crude, analysts wonder if there will be enough oil around to meet peak winter demand in industrialised countries.</p>
<p>Iraq has been banned from exporting oil since it invaded neighbour Kuwait in August 1990 but traders had expected its return sometime this month before the deal was put on hold on Sunday by U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros-Ghali.</p>
<p>Low stocks of heating fuel going into the peak winter demand period and general uncertainty in the Middle East have resulted in a radical switch from bearish to bullish sentiment, analysts say.</p>
<p>Energy consultancy Cambridge Energy Research Associates (CERA) has revised up by $1 to $19.25 its forecast for average Brent prices in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We have moved the price forecast up because we just do not expect Iraqi oil back on the market this year and the market could use that oil to fill growing demand,&quot; said Peter Bogin, an associate director at CERA.</p>
<p>Although the cat-and-mouse game between the United States and Iraq should keep a floor under prices for some time, other supply-demand fundamentals have sparked the analysts' change of heart.</p>
<p>Bogin said the low level of stocks of heating oil and diesel in both the United States and Europe and the prospect of a return of last winter's deep freeze were more influential on the oil price than Iraqi President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at a 40 percent increase in the price of gas oil (heating oil) in Europe heading into the fourth quarter, compared to last year. If the stock situation is not corrected soon, consumers are going to pay considerably more to heat their homes,&quot; Bogin said.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Sept 4	 Sept 3</p>
<p>						   (close)	(close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $22.16	 $22.30</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$22.11	 $22.21</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)     $23.18	 $23.40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
