<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32928" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British authorities keep markets guessing on rates.</title>
<headline>British authorities keep markets guessing on rates.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's monetary authorities held a short half-hour meeting on Wednesday, keeping financial markets on the hop and unsure if Chancellor Kenneth Clarke will deliver another rate cut before the next general election.</p>
<p>Analysts said short meetings generally imply Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke and Governor of the Bank of England Eddie George agreed on the path of monetary policy in the month ahead.</p>
<p>Since it is well known George wants no further cuts, that could mean rates will be left on hold at 5.75 percent.</p>
<p>But Clarke may have cut the cost of borrowing again to give the economy one last push before the government calls an election, due by May 1997.</p>
<p>He is under intense pressure from his Conservative Party colleagues to deliver a robust economy and a national sense of well-being before they go to the polls.</p>
<p>And the widely expected pick-up in growth in the second half of the year will rob him of an excuse to ease monetary policy if he waits much longer.</p>
<p>&quot;Time is running out. Clarke would like another rate cut and here is one of the last chances he has,&quot; said Paul Mortimer-Lee, chief economist at Paribas Capital Markets.</p>
<p>The meeting ended at 1535 GMT, too late to put any rate changes into effect, so markets will have to wait until Thursday's Bank of England money market operations.</p>
<p>The Financial Times index of 100 leading shares closed 16.8 points up on the day at 3,872.7. The pound lost ground against the mark and ended European trade at 2.3219/29 marks compared with 2.3282/89 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In Britain, where two-thirds of households own their own home, low interest rates are a political imperative.</p>
<p>The ruling Conservatives still trail opposition Labour by over 20 points in the opinion polls.</p>
<p>But the economic grounds for a rate cut are shrinking fast.</p>
<p>The manufacturing sector is still stagnant and inflation pressures dormant, but the consumer sector is forging ahead with high street sales and consumer credit ratcheting upward.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll conducted on Monday found that 13 of 20 economists questioned forecast rates will stay on hold, but seven dissenting voices said Clarke will bite the bullet and cut rates for the fifth time since December.</p>
<p>Minutes of the July monetary meeting show Clarke expected a strong pick up in activity in the third quarter. But he hinted that if he did not get it he would cut rates again.</p>
<p>The first official measure of output at the beginning of the third quarter is not due until Friday, but was in the hands of the authorities before they met.</p>
<p>The data is forecast to show manufacturing output rose 0.3 percent in July after June's 0.3 percent fall, but will be up only 0.1 percent on the year.</p>
<p>If he presses for another cut, Clarke could also argue that the inflation outlook is very benign.</p>
<p>Underlying inflation, which excludes volatile mortgage costs, fell 0.5 percent in July to stand at 2.8 percent year-on- year.</p>
<p>This is still some way above the official target of 2.5 percent or below, but falling upstream prices have yet to feed through fully and retail prices should creep lower this year.</p>
<p>But another interest rate will lead Clarke into a full- blown argument with Bank of England Governor Eddie George.</p>
<p>He strongly opposed the last rate cut in June and since then, the Bank has hardened its line further.</p>
<p>At the time of the July inflation report, the Bank's chief economist Mervyn King said the next move in rates should be up and said Bank officials will be discussing the merits of a pre-emptive rate rise before this week's meeting.</p>
<p>Some economists said the key question surrounding the meeting is how far the Chancellor is prepared to push his view against the Governor's.</p>
<p>Arguments have never bothered Clarke too much in the past. As well as overruling George in June, he dismissed the Bank's advice in May 1995 and kept rates on hold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
