<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32925" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast crudes stay firm, buyers sidelined.</title>
<headline>US West Coast crudes stay firm, buyers sidelined.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crude prices continued rising with a strong spot market late Tuesday, following news the U.S. launched missile attacks against Iraq in response to the country's attack on a U.N. protected zone.</p>
<p>WTI cash for October delivery rose around $1.10 a barrel to $23.30/40 in the wake of the NYMEX-fuelled rally, which saw October values jump $1.15 to $24.25.</p>
<p>But the rise frightened off Alaska North Slope (ANS) crude buyers, who waited for prices to drop before re-entering the market. The last deal was done at $2.05 under October WTI.  </p>
<p>A major seller offered ANS at $2 off October WTI, while a buyer bid at $2.45 under.</p>
<p>Outright prices rose to $21.15/21.45 a barrel, up $1.10 from Friday levels.</p>
<p>Values for Kern River reacted to Tuesday's higher posted prices, edging up 10 cents to end $14.10/14.60 a barrel.</p>
<p>Wilmington stayed $16.10/16.20 a barrel.</p>
<p>Line 63 differentials were unchanged at WTI minus $2.60/2.50 a barrel, with little trading seen ahead of mid-September.</p>
<p>BP, a major ANS producer, bought part of an unusually large spot volume of Alberta crude last week, traders said.</p>
<p>One buyer speculated BP may have purchased the grade, a competitor to ANS, to ease the undermining effect of excess Canadian crudes. The grades have come West in September because of maintenance on a large Canadian pipeline.</p>
<p>But another trader said it was only a &quot;fair buy&quot; for BP.</p>
<p>Texaco last week purchased a large piece of the Canadian offering, at a slight premium to ANS.</p>
<p>One trader said the price for the grade -- a lighter, more lucrative crude to process -- was the cheapest it had been for months.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
