<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32933" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vitalink to buy GranCare pharmacy unit for $370 mln.</title>
<headline>Vitalink to buy GranCare pharmacy unit for $370 mln.</headline>
<dateline>NAPERVILLE, Ill.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vitalink Pharmacy Services Inc. said Wednesday it will acquire GranCare Inc.'s institutional pharmacy business -- TeamCare -- in a $370 million deal that would create a giant provider of drugs to the nursing home industry.</p>
<p>Vitalink is an 82 percent-owned unit of Manor Care Inc., which owns 180 nursing homes throughout the country.</p>
<p>Following the merger, Vitalink will serve 166,000 beds, or 10 percent of the nation's nursing homes, through 54 pharmacies in 29 states, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to realise significant operating savings through purchasing leverage and the elimination of duplicate functions in our organisations,&quot; said Donna DeNardo, Vitalink president.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Stewart Bainum Jr, chairman of Manor Care, will become chairman of Vitalink and Gene Burleson, GranCare chairman, will be Vitalink's chief executive officer.</p>
<p>&quot;Our expanded customer base and geographic presence will allow us to capture a greater share of the growing subacute nursing and assisted living facilities markets,&quot; said Burleson.</p>
<p>The transaction has already been approved by the board of each company but is still subject to approval of GranCare's stockholders.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to be completed before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Grancare's stock jumped $2.50 to $20.25 in early trading on the New York Stock Exchange, while Manor Care was off 50 cents at $34. Vitalink was unchanged at $23 on the Nasdaq market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAPERVILLE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
