<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32931" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares up on Iraqi relief, trading subdued.</title>
<headline>German shares up on Iraqi relief, trading subdued.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's blue chip DAX index gained nearly one percent in bourse trade on Wednesday amid relief at the mild global market response to the Iraqi crisis.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX closed up 21.62 points, or 0.9 percent, at 2,532.39 following the turnaround which sent Wall Street to a higher close on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It was good to see that the U.S. has taken a relaxed approach to the Iraq situation, which seems to me just a bit of pre-election ammunition,&quot; said one Frankfurt dealer.</p>
<p>But the IBIS DAX index, which tracks all-day electronic trade in German shares and had as such already reflected the mood of relief from late Tuesday, ended the day down 2.55 points at 2,526.18 as trading remained subdued.</p>
<p>Although sentiment on the market was largely favourable, the upside potential was limited because of a lack of strong buying interest, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very clear that Germany is not top of the buying list for investors at the moment,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Investors were also seen holding off ahead of economic data due from the U.S. later this week, particularly Friday's employment data.</p>
<p>Carmaker Volkswagen AG gained 9.50 marks to 546.50 after the European Commission ruled that it did not have to repay controversial subsidies it received to help it develop business in east Germany. In post-bourse trade, however, it edged back to 541.90 marks.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, Germany's leading commercial bank, remained lower after this week's news that three funds at its London Morgan Grenfell asset management unit had been suspended. After staging a brief recovery to 72.70 during bourse trade, it finished 18 pfennigs lower at 72.52 on IBIS.</p>
<p>Airline Deutsche Lufthansa AG also rebounded mildly to end up 2.30 marks at 201.50, partly making up losses suffered after its chief executive called in an interview for a wage freeze to secure the airline's future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
