<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32930" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Gold weakens despite fresh U.S. raid on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Gold weakens despite fresh U.S. raid on Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold prices turned lower on Wednesday as the market, disappointed that U.S. missile strikes on Iraq failed to spark a serious rally, sold off positions.</p>
<p>Bullion closed at $385.65 an ounce, down $1.30 from Tuesday's London close.</p>
<p>&quot;The general tone is quite bearish,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Gold blipped up 50 cents yesterday when the first missiles went out and people went long. But they started getting out when they saw the (Mideast) Gulf had no effect on gold.&quot;</p>
<p>Otherwise business was fairly quiet and likely to remain so until mid-September when the seasonal lull ended, dealers said. Gold had edged higher early on Tuesday on news of the first U.S. cruise missile attack on Iraq. But prices then drifted back to previous levels during the European trading day.</p>
<p>The second U.S. missile attack early on Wednesday morning had elicited little initial reaction in Asian markets, before prices started easing in European trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Time and time again the market expects gold to soar on political, economic or financial crises,&quot; analyst Nick Moore of Flemings Global Mining Group said in a commentary.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations of such a response hark back to the good old days, which were probably the anomaly, rather than to gold's more measured role in today's world markets,&quot; Moore added.</p>
<p>Some dealers said they suspected a further easing in gold prices near term, with $383-$384 as the target.</p>
<p>&quot;My heart of hearts says it's going to go lower. I'm not saying it's going to dump, but we could see it a dollar lower,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Silver, an industrial metal, was holding up better, ending unchanged in London at $5.18 an ounce.</p>
<p>But platinum was weaker, finishing down $1.85 against Tuesday's close at $384.40 an ounce. &quot;There doesn't seem to be anything special behind it, it's still in the summer doldrums,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
