<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32934" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: U.S. halt to oil deal sends Iraqi prices soaring.</title>
<headline>U.S. halt to oil deal sends Iraqi prices soaring.</headline>
<byline>Hassan Hafidh</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraqis, seeing the value of their currency plunge and prices soar, cursed U.S. President Bill Clinton on Wednesday for suspending their country's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations.</p>
<p>Stunned shoppers saw prices of some essential commodities more than double in under 24 hours. By the afternoon it took 1,750 dinars to buy a U.S. dollar, from 1,500 in the morning and as little as 450 earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Clinton's missiles are hitting every Iraqi in the heart and we the ordinary people are the victims. I hate him, hate him, hate him. Why is he taking our food away,&quot; said Um Marwan.</p>
<p>Um Marwan came to Shorja to buy sugar, but went home empty handed when told that the price of a kilogram (2.2 lb) of sugar had shot up from 600 dinars two days ago to about 1,300.</p>
<p>The latest U.S.-Iraqi confrontation began last weekend when Iraqi troops pushed into the north to back one group of Kurdish rebels against their rivals.</p>
<p>In retaliation, Clinton has hit Iraq with two waves of cruise missiles and extended a zone closed to Iraqi aircraft to the edge of Baghdad.</p>
<p>Of wider impact for average Iraqis, the U.S. leader also froze Iraq's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations. It would have allowed Iraq to export oil to pay for food and medicine for a population that has been under severe trade sanctions for six years.</p>
<p>The imports funded by the sale of $2 billion of oil over six months would have been used to augment an Iraqi ration system that now meets barely a third of the needs for essential foodstuffs - rice, sugar and flour.</p>
<p>One shopper said: &quot;All this military confrontation I think is meant to destroy the (oil-for-food) agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraqi oil exports had been expected to begin by mid-September and news of the halt sent Iraq's volatile currency down and prices of essential foodstuffs up.</p>
<p>A kilogram of rice doubled to 1,000 dinars from 500 and a tray of 30 eggs jumped to about 3,250 dinars from 2,500, almost half the official monthly salary of a civil servant in Iraq.</p>
<p>Despite the blow, there was little visible discontent on Baghdad streets outside of shoppers and few would give views on the U.S. missile strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;They can give an explanation for their rocket attacks but what would they say to the world when they block food reaching hungry Iraqis and milk reaching malnourished children,&quot; said Asim Darweesh, a government employee.</p>
<p>At Shorga, Baghdad's main commercial centre, traders said business was almost at a standstill as shoppers shunned goods that were now beyond their reach.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really unfair,&quot; one trader said of the halt to the oil-for-food deal. &quot;I feel sorry for these people because most of them cannot afford to buy even a kilogram of sugar.&quot;</p>
<p>Early this year Iraq's talks with the United Nations on the oil-for-food plan produced spectacular gains for the dinar, pushing it from about 3,000 to the dollar at the start of the year to a high of 450.</p>
<p>&quot;I am expecting it to slip more and more until it reaches the levels before the oil talks if the U.S. does not change its stand,&quot; a money changer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
