<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32945" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: U.S. strike on Iraq diverts pressure from Iran.</title>
<headline>U.S. strike on Iraq diverts pressure from Iran.</headline>
<byline>Barry May</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran is staying on the sidelines of the Iraqi crisis, happy to see the attention of its declared enemy the United States diverted to neighbouring Iraq.</p>
<p>Only last month, Middle East analysts openly discussed the possibility of a U.S. military strike on Iran in retaliation for what Washington called state sponsorship of terrorism.</p>
<p>But now the scale of President Bill Clinton's &quot;dual containment&quot; policy against Iran and Iraq -- enforced by U.S. warships and aircraft in the Gulf -- has again shifted heavily towards Baghdad.</p>
<p>&quot;Washington's confrontation with Baghdad gets Tehran off the hook for now,&quot; a Middle East analyst said. &quot;For the last few months the Iranians have been under full American pressure. Now that (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein is once again the chief villain, they can take a breather.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States has been waging an international campaign to isolate the Islamic republic for its alleged involvement in terrorist acts against the West. Iran denies all such charges and says Washington is bent on toppling its Islamic government.</p>
<p>Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani on Wednesday criticised the United States for the attacks but said the Iraqis had provided the pretext.</p>
<p>Asked during a state visit to Kenya whether there was anything he could do to avert further violence, the Iranian leader told Reuters through an interpreter: &quot;We are trying, but it is very difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>State-run Tehran radio said the United States was pursuing far-reaching objectives in Iraq which included a justification for maintaining a permanent presence in the Gulf.</p>
<p>&quot;With this action, Clinton not only takes personal advantage of developments in Iraq, he also paves the way for the advancement of the long-term U.S. strategy for maintaining a permanent presence in the Persian Gulf region,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The United States has dozens of warships in and around the Gulf with 20,000 armed forces personnel on board and stationed at land bases, mainly in Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>The radio accused Clinton of taking advantage of the situation to prove he was a strong leader.</p>
<p>&quot;During the last four years Clinton has been criticised repeatedly by opponents for his failures and weaknesses in foreign policy,&quot; the radio said.</p>
<p>Military action against Iraq &quot;shows Clinton's determination to push U.S. foreign policy forward for campaigning purposes&quot;.</p>
<p>The radio commentary was consistent with Iran's condemnation of meddling by powers outside the region in Gulf conflicts.</p>
<p>Iran was at war with Iraq from 1980 to 1988 and remained neutral in the 1990-1991 Gulf conflict over Iraq's invasion of Kuwait. Tehran denounced Baghdad's invasion as well as the U.S.-led Gulf War.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry, asked in Washington what message Iran was supposed to get from Tuesday's raid, said &quot;We have separately warned Iran not to meddle in this conflict in northern Iraq&quot;.</p>
<p>Tension between the United States and Iran mounted after comments by Perry in August that Tehran might be behind a fuel truck bomb in Saudi Arabia in June which killed 19 U.S. airmen, and that Washington might retaliate.</p>
<p>Perry quickly clarified that his comments did not signal imminent military action against Iran. Tehran complained to the United Nations about what it saw as a U.S. threat.</p>
<p>Middle East analysts said they expected neither a move by the Islamic republic to take advantage of the U.S. attack against Iraq nor an American move against Iran, which Washington has accused of interfering in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>But some Western analysts said Iran could soon return to the top of Washington's agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus is all on Saddam. That's good enough for now. They'll worry about Iran in due course,&quot; said Rosemary Hollis, head of the Middle East programme at the Royal Institute of International Affairs in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Possibly the American analysts told Washington when Iran made its incursions that it was not as dire as we're now hearing it was. In other words, they've made some infiltrations but this doesn't amount to a major operation.&quot;</p>
<p>Iranian troops in July attacked positions of an Iranian Kurdish opposition group in northern Iraq after Tehran accused the rebels of cross-border attacks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
