<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32941" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iraq pulls planes out of extended no-fly zone.</title>
<headline>Iraq pulls planes out of extended no-fly zone.</headline>
<byline>Ashraf Fouad</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq on Wednesday pulled some 30 tactical fixed-wing aircraft from the south of the country shortly before the enforcement by the United States and Britain of a new extended no-fly zone in the area at 0800 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Iraqi President Saddam Hussein) pulled out about 30 aircraft from the area 30 to 90 minutes before the enforcement of the expanded zone took effect,&quot; said a Western military source close to Operation Southern Watch.</p>
<p>Western military sources said Iraq was seen flying Russian MiG and Sukhoi warplanes out of the area.</p>
<p>They also said the United States had not in recent days sent any pilotless aircraft over Iraq. Baghdad's al-Jumhouriya newspaper earlier reported that Iraqi anti-aircraft gunners shot down a U.S.-made &quot;hostile pilotless plane&quot; over its southern province of Missan.</p>
<p>U.S. Lieutenant-Colonel Andy Bourland, Public Affairs Director for the Joint Task Force Southwest Asia, told Reuters more than two hours after the exclusion measure up to the 33rd parallel took effect that no Iraq violations were reported and that the operation has so far proceeded unchallenged.</p>
<p>Any Iraqi air activity beyond the 33rd parallel as of 0800 GMT &quot;would be considered a violation,&quot; he earlier warned.</p>
<p>The United States has fired 44 cruise missiles at southern Iraq since early on Tuesday, mainly to disable key defence installations such as surface-to-air missile sites and radars.</p>
<p>The attacks were aimed at limiting Iraq's ability to challenge Western warplanes in the new zone which, along with a similar one in the north, limits Iraq's ability to fly training missions, military experts said.</p>
<p>The United States decided on Tuesday to extend the zone in the south to the outskirts of Baghdad from the 32nd parallel where it was fixed after Iraq's defeat in the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>France and Britain are also part of Southern Watch but it was not immediately clear if their warplanes in the region were taking part in enforcing the wider zone.</p>
<p>Western military sources said Britain had no objections but France, which has not supported the cruise missile attacks, appeared reluctant to go beyond the original exclusion zone of the 32nd parallel. This could not be immediately confirmed.</p>
<p>London has voiced strong support for Washington's latest attacks against Iraq and said that the Gulf War's Western allies had decided to extend the zone to within 30 miles (50 km) of the Iraqi capital from the border with Kuwait.</p>
<p>Bourland said U.S. sea and land-based warplanes in the region were enforcing the new limitations but he did not specify what kind of aircraft were taking part. Some of the American aircraft involved in the operation fly out of Kuwait and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>Iraq has declared both the northern and southern air- exclusion zones null and void and President Saddam Hussein has urged his pilots and anti-aircraft gunners to shoot down any Western plane entering the zones.</p>
<p>The southern zone is also a &quot;no-drive&quot; one for Iraqi troops, banning Baghdad from sending forces by land into the Shi'ite Moslem-dominated area to reinforce units originally deployed there.</p>
<p>Washington says the wider zone is aimed at further restricting Iraq's ability to pose a threat to neighbours.</p>
<p>Saddam still commands one of the region's largest war machines with a 400,000-man army which has 2,200 tanks despite losing 2,600 in the war. He also has a variety of fixed-wing aircraft -- 150 to 350 of which are operational.</p>
<p>The latest confrontation with Iraq was triggered by Saddam's sending of troops on Saturday into Iraq's Kurdish north in support of one Kurdish faction against a rival group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
