<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32942" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France cool on U.S. raid, wants oil-for-food deal.</title>
<headline>France cool on U.S. raid, wants oil-for-food deal.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>France said on Wednesday the situation in Iraq remained worrying after a second U.S. missile attack and urged rapid implementation of a U.N.-brokered deal allowing Baghdad to sell oil for food and medical supplies.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt, speaking after Washington launched a second missile attack on northern Iraq, told reporters: &quot;The development of the situation remains worrying.&quot;</p>
<p>His remark reinforced previous French comments pointedly refraining from any support for the missile raids which followed an Iraqi attack on Kurdish rebels. Only dialogue could restore calm and prevent an escalation of the conflict, he said.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Alain Lamassoure, speaking after a cabinet meeting, said Washington's response to Iraqi troops attacking Kurdish rebels had remained &quot;limited&quot;.</p>
<p>Rummelhardt declined to say whether France would join the United States and Britain in patrolling an enlarged no-fly zone in southern Iraq, saying French planes in the Gulf had not taken off for a few days.</p>
<p>Asked whether President Bill Clinton's decision to extend the exclusion zone was legitimate, Rummelhardt said: &quot;Its legitimacy is that it was decided unilaterally by the United States and it was supported by Britain.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, Lamassoure told Europe 1 radio that France wanted the rapid enforcement of the oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aims are first to ensure peace in the region and to ensure that the Iraqi leaders are no longer in a position to harm their neighbours or their own people.</p>
<p>&quot;After long negotiations, Iraqi leaders and the international community had agreed on the oil for food resolution...We call for dialogue to ensure that the accord is brought into force as fast as possible,&quot; Lamassoure said.</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department said on Tuesday that the U.N. plan to let Iraq sell some oil to raise hard currency for food and medical supplies was off &quot;for some time&quot;.</p>
<p>United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Sunday postponed implementation of the oil-for-food plan, expected later this month. He said he could not send U.N. staff to monitor it because he feared for their safety.</p>
<p>Under the plan, Iraq was to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to buy food, medicine and other supplies for its citizens.</p>
<p>France, one of the 1991 Gulf War allies, is one of four nations -- along with Britain, Turkey and Washington -- that has been enforcing a no-fly zone in northern Iraq intended to protect Kurds living there from Iraqi attack.</p>
<p>Paris withheld support for a first U.S. missile attack on Iraq on Tuesday, saying Baghdad had not breached U.N. resolutions by sending its troops into northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;The United Nations has stated that Iraqi troops have left the northern region and we note at the same time that the American reaction has remained limited,&quot; Lamassoure told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything must be done to restart a dialogue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Washington launched a second U.S. missile strike on Iraqi air defence positions in southern Iraq on Wednesday to neutralise possible resistance to its decision on Tuesday to extend a southern Iraq air-exclusion zone.</p>
<p>As Iraq's biggest Western creditor and erstwhile arms supplier, France is keen to ease the U.N. economic embargo against Baghdad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
