<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32944" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIECHTENSTEIN: Russia slams U.S. strikes in Iraq, warns of anarchy.</title>
<headline>Russia slams U.S. strikes in Iraq, warns of anarchy.</headline>
<byline>Michael Shields</byline>
<dateline>VADUZ 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov renewed Moscow's criticism of U.S. missile strikes against Iraq on Wednesday and warned they could unleash &quot;catastrophic consequences&quot; and &quot;anarchy&quot; on the world scene.</p>
<p>No country could be allowed to use force that promotes its own interests without the express approval of the U.N. Security Council, he told reporters in the Liechtenstein capital after talks with his counterpart in the tiny Alpine principality.</p>
<p>&quot;We view the renewed attacks in Iraq very negatively. Such a system could lead to catastrophic consequences. I am speaking not only about regional affairs, but about the world order,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;No single country can take action that could disrupt the world order. There is the U.N. Security Council, and only this can decide on using force.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking after signing a cultural accord with Liechtenstein Foreign Minister Andrea Willi, Primakov stressed the importance of coordinating action through the Council, on which Russia and the United States are two of the five permanent members.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the basis for world order after the end of World War Two, and it should be the basis for world order after the end of the Cold War,&quot; he said. &quot;No one can disrupt this order or it could lead to anarchy in international relations.&quot;</p>
<p>In Moscow, Deputy Foreign Minister Vasily Sidorov accused Washington of having ignored Russia's opinion when it delivered a second missile strike against Iraq, Interfax news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is up to the Americans to listen (to our position) or not,&quot; he said in comments that appeared to reflect Moscow's secondary role in the crisis.</p>
<p>Washington unleashed a second wave of cruise missiles against military targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday in retaliation for Iraqi military intervention in the Kurdish north. It first hit Iraqi targets on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sidorov reiterated Russia's opposition to a draft resolution discussed by the Security Council which condemned Iraq and demanded it pull its troops out of the northern Kurdish region immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a one-sided draft aimed at justifying U.S. action and we cannot agree to it,&quot; Interfax quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>After the first strikes, Primakov urged Washington on Tuesday to halt the assault that he said could boost tension across the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope that this action will not be repeated and that good sense will prevail,&quot; he said in the Swiss capital Berne after talks with Swiss Foreign Minister Flavio Cotti.</p>
<p>Primakov, who for years under the old Soviet system was an academic specialist on the Middle East who frequently met Iraqi President Saddam Hussein, also suggested on Tuesday that the strikes had been launched in part to help re-elect U.S. President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>The attacks, he said in Berne, &quot;cannot be supported by anyone at all, except those who put domestic politics, including pre-electoral questions, above all else.&quot;</p>
<p>After those comments, the Russian government in Moscow also condemned the strikes, saying they were unacceptable and calling for an end to &quot;all military actions in Iraq threatening its sovereignty&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIECHT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VADUZ"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIECHTENSTEIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
