<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32958" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran says its north Iraq incursions hit own rebels.</title>
<headline>Iran says its north Iraq incursions hit own rebels.</headline>
<byline>Firouz Sedarat</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani has denied U.S. and Iraqi charges of meddling in northern Iraq, saying Iran only targeted its own rebel Kurds based there.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran only pursues and targets (Iranian) anti-revolutionary elements...Iraqi Kurdish groups should not think this is directed at them,&quot; Rafsanjani said in remarks quoted by state-run Tehran radio on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We defend our borders against any intrusions to keep out lawlessness,&quot; he said. The president was speaking on Tuesday during a state visit to Kenya.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani was reacting to claims by Iraq and the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) that Iran had sent troops into northern Iraq to back the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>Baghdad has said its attack on Arbil in northern Iraq on Saturday, which prompted two waves of U.S. missile strikes on Iraq, was aimed at backing the KDP against the PUK and Iran.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said on Tuesday Washington had warned Tehran not to meddle in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Tehran's troops in July attacked positions of an Iranian Kurdish opposition group in Kurdish-run northern Iraq after Iran accused the rebels of cross-border attacks.</p>
<p>Iranian Kurdish rebels have waged a low-intensity guerrilla struggle against Tehran since government forces drove most of them into Iraq after major offensives in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>Both the KDP and the PUK cooperated with Iran's armed forces against Baghdad in various stages of the 1980-88 Iran-Iraq war.</p>
<p>But since the Iraqi Kurds took control of northern Iraq after the 1991 Gulf War, Tehran has expressed concern over Iranian rebel Kurds' activities in the region where they have bases and radio stations broadcasting to Iran.</p>
<p>Iranian officials have accused the United States and Israel of backing the groups to destabilise Iran. The rebels deny the charge and stress that they are fighting for basic political and cultural rights for Kurds in Iran.</p>
<p>Middle East analysts said Iran was pressuring Iraqi Kurdish groups to stop sheltering Iranian rebels, making any assistance conditional on their cooperation on this issue.</p>
<p>The KDP and Iranian opposition groups said the PUK allowed Tehran's troops to pass through its lines on their July raid.</p>
<p>But London-based Middle East analyst Hazhir Teimourian said the PUK's ties with Iran were the result of dire necessity.</p>
<p>&quot;PUK's leadership is secular and has little in common with Iran's Islamic leaders. If PUK has become dependent on Tehran it is because the only link between areas it controls and the outside world is through Iranian territory,&quot; Teimourian said.</p>
<p>&quot;The best outcome for Iran would be for anti-Saddam forces to lose hope over getting Western backing. Then they would have no alternative but to become dependent on Tehran.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran's long-term worry is over Iranian Kurds becoming inspired by the self-rule experience of Iraqi Kurds,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Iran -- which like Iraq, Turkey and Syria has a big Kurdish minority -- has in recent years intensified economic development efforts in its Kurdish-populated western border regions.</p>
<p>But opposition groups say Tehran has not altered its policy of denying basic cultural and political rights to Kurds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
