<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32953" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Labour Party denies broadcast tax plan.</title>
<headline>UK Labour Party denies broadcast tax plan.</headline>
<byline>Keith Weir</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party denied on Wednesday that it was considering a special new tax on broadcasters if it wins the next general election.</p>
<p>The report, in Wednesday's Financial Times, hurt shares in satellite broadcaster BSkyB, which would have been the big loser under the plan. Rupert Murdoch's News Corp is the main BSkyB shareholder, with a 40 percent stake.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know where the Financial Times got this story from,&quot; said a Labour spokesman, dismissing the report. A general election is due by next May.</p>
<p>BSkyB shares, which had opened 12.75p lower at 557.75p, bounced back to a day's high of 573p after the Labour denial. They had drifted down to 567p by 1200 GMT.</p>
<p>The report said that the tax could be pitched as high as 14 percent of revenue. It was being considered as a possible solution to anomalies resulting from a 1991 auction for ITV commercial television licences, the report added.</p>
<p>Companies competing for ITV licences had to offer an annual cash payment as part of the auction process.</p>
<p>Central Television, unopposed in its bid for the English Midlands licence, offered a nominal 2,000 pounds ($3,135). Carlton Communications, which now owns Central, has to pay an annual sum of almost 45 million pounds to operate the weekday licence for the London area.</p>
<p>The ITV companies must also hand over a percentage of their revenue to the Treasury as the second part of their licence payment. The percentage ranges from zero to 11 percent.</p>
<p>The Financial Times said that Labour was looking at ways of extending the system to all commercial broadcasters including BSkyB, the dominant force in British pay television. The idea was first championed by ITV's Yorkshire-Tyne Tees Television.</p>
<p>&quot;What Yorkshire are trying to do is offer part of BSkyB's cash flow in place of money from ITV,&quot; said one share analyst.</p>
<p>The Financial Times said that the plan would, as at present, raise roughly 400 million pounds annually for the Treasury.</p>
<p>But it calculated that BSkyB would have to cough up around 134 million pounds while the bill for the ITV companies would fall to 237 million pounds.</p>
<p>BSkyB, which has a market capitalisation of almost 10 billion pounds, last month reported record pre-tax profit of 257 million pounds.</p>
<p>The satellite broadcaster does not pay mainstream UK corporation tax as it still has substantial tax losses stemming from the start-up of the venture in 1989.</p>
<p>(1=.6382 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
