<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32956" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Olivetti drama sends governance warning.</title>
<headline>Olivetti drama sends governance warning.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Brothers</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Carlo De Benedetti's ousting as head of Italy's Olivetti could sound a warning bell that &quot;Anglo-Saxon&quot; standards of corporate governance are on the march across continental Europe, fund managers say.</p>
<p>Olivetti, the information technology group headed until Tuesday by flamboyant tycoon De Benedetti, has been majority-owned by non-Italian shareholders since a rights issue last December.</p>
<p>Its share price has fallen by more than 40 percent this year and it reported a first-half pre-tax loss of almost $300 million. Angry shareholders pressing for months for changes at the top finally saw some action when De Benedetti quit.</p>
<p>British fund managers say the Olivetti drama is evidence that foreign shareholders are starting to succeed in imposing Anglo-Saxon (British and U.S.) practices of accountability and management on seemingly wayward firms in the rest of Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say that that is true -- the pressure will definitely be there,&quot; said Anita Skipper, corporate governance manager at Norwich Union.</p>
<p>Corporate executives in continental Europe have often considered how they run their companies as a reflection of their particular culture, seeing no need to appease foreign demands.</p>
<p>But with more than $40 billion in new privatisation issues slated for the market in the next few years, and increasing global competition for the U.S. investment dollar, European firms will have to change to satisfy extremely demanding mutual funds and their clients across the Atlantic, fund managers say.</p>
<p>Finance rather than principle is driving the changes, a fund manager at a major U.K. investment house said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is we are under pressure to make a decent economic return for our clients and we are putting more pressure on companies to run their businesses better.</p>
<p>&quot;Our expectations of returns are probably tougher than they once were -- it is that that is driving corporate governance,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Shareholders in Britain get exercised over instances of apparent boardroom greed, requiring &quot;fat cat&quot; managers to justify six-figure salaries with improved corporate performance.</p>
<p>But Anglo-Saxon investors in continental European firms are more worried about variable voting rights on company shares and the failure of managers fully to realise shareholder value.</p>
<p>Valuations of company assets and the disclosure of holdings also top U.S. investor demands.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign shareholders are used to estimating returns on their investments and are starting to ask questions,&quot; Skipper said.</p>
<p>French, Swiss and Swedish investors are starting to form interest groups and an international corporate governance network is being set up to defend shareholder interests.</p>
<p>However, the fund manager at the major U.K. investment house said the Olivetti incident was unusual.</p>
<p>&quot;Most financial investors would rather not get involved in ousting a senior member of management,&quot; she said. &quot;They would rather vote with their feet.&quot;</p>
<p>But Olivetti's need for cash, which domestic investors would not provide, meant that it had to look abroad, raising the proportion of foreign shareholders who are used to stricter standards.</p>
<p>Larger companies operating in markets that are too small to absorb a large issue on their own would be vulnerable to such a scenario, she added. -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 2734</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
