<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32955" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Blair says UK Labour not a &quot;one-term wonder&quot;.</title>
<headline>Blair says UK Labour not a &quot;one-term wonder&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Richard Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British opposition leader Tony Blair made a spirited pitch for support from business leaders on Wednesday, saying the success of a Labour government would hinge on its ability to produce a healthy climate for them to work in.</p>
<p>The party, which is well ahead of the ruling Conservatives in opinion polls, said it had no plans to raise the top rate of income tax but aimed to halve the basic rate to 10 percent in the long term to help low-paid workers.</p>
<p>At a conference for several hundred business executives, Blair said the traditional divide in British politics between a Conservative party backed by business and a Labour party which was primarily the voice of workers was breaking down.</p>
<p>Increasing numbers of business people believed Labour would offer new opportunities for them and the party would listen closely to their views in government.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to get this right,&quot; Blair said. &quot;We do not want or intend to be a one-term wonder as a government. If we fail to provide the right environment for business, we will not succeed as a government.&quot;</p>
<p>Neither Blair nor his senior party colleagues shed any more light on their plans for taxes and public spending, but said details would be made public before the next election, due by May 1997. But Shadow Chancellor of the Exchequer (finance minister) Gordon Brown reaffirmed that his long-term goal was a basic income tax rate of 15 or even 10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an objective which is desirable if we are to have a tax and benefit system which maximises opportunities and rewards hard work and effort,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major dismissed the idea of Labour as a tax-cutting party as &quot;absolutely ludicrous.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The day the Labour Party become tax cutters you will hear cats bark,&quot; Major said during a visit to Buxton, Derbyshire.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, Blair told a radio interviewer that Labour had no plans to increase the top rate of income tax from the present 40 percent. &quot;We have no proposals to raise the top rate of tax,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In his speech, Blair tackled head-on two Labour policies which have caused anxiety among some business leaders -- its plans to sign up to the European Union's Social Chapter on workers' rights and its pledge to introduce a minimum wage.</p>
<p>Blair said the only measures agreed so far under the Social Chapter were employee consultation in Europe-wide companies and voluntary parental leave.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither poses any threat to competitiveness,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Any extension of the Social Chapter would require unanimity among European Union countries. &quot;We will rigorously examine each proposal to make sure it does not damage our competitiveness,&quot; Blair added.</p>
<p>As for the minimum wage, the Labour leader said it would be set at a realistic level after consultation with business.</p>
<p>Current unregulated low pay cost taxpayers around 2.5 billion pounds a year in the form of welfare benefits for people unable to live on their wages, Blair added.</p>
<p>&quot;The case for a minimum wage rests in part on decency and fairness, but it is also about efficiency,&quot; he said, noting that both the United States and Japan had a minimum wage.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
