<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32962" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Arab foreign ministers to have emergency meeting.</title>
<headline>Arab foreign ministers to have emergency meeting.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arab foreign ministers will have an emergency meeting on September 13 to take a united stand on recent developments in Arab-Israeli relations, Egypt's delegate to the Arab League said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Last week Egypt asked the Arab League to call such a meeting to discuss the stalled peace process.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat has also called for an emergency meeting of foreign ministers to implement resolutions adopted in the Cairo summit in June.</p>
<p>The summit told Israel that Arab states might reconsider steps towards peace with Israel if it does not fulfil its agreements or tries to change the basis for talks.</p>
<p>The League has brought forward a regular six-monthly ministerial meeting to September 14 and 15. The regular meetings usually start a week later.</p>
<p>&quot;They will review developments in the peace process and resolutions taken on the stalled peace process in the Middle East,&quot; Mahmoud Mortada, Egypt's delegate, said.</p>
<p>The Arab League secretariat is still contacting member states on the Palestinian proposal, Mortada added.</p>
<p>The ministerial meeting would also be an opportunity for Egypt to sound out Arab opinion on plans to hold a Middle East economic summit in Cairo in November.</p>
<p>Egypt has said the economic conference will be pointless if Israel does not ensure progress towards Middle East peace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
