<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32967" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU Commission split on media domination.</title>
<headline>EU Commission split on media domination.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission was split on Wednesday over the need for new European Union laws to combat domination of the media by moguls like Silvio Berlusconi and Rupert Murdoch.</p>
<p>A preliminary debate on a plan by Commissioner Mario Monti, responsible for the single market, to control media domination by capping groups' audience share revealed differences of approach.</p>
<p>It foreshadowed a protracted debate on one of the EU's most controversial issues.</p>
<p>An earlier plan to control media mega-mergers was rejected by EU governments and Monti, under pressure from the European Parliament to fight concentration in the interests of democracy, is treading carefully to find a plan which is palatable.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone agrees it's very sensitive and we need to take care,&quot; said one EU source.</p>
<p>EU sources said the EU executive was split roughly into three camps over whether and how to approach the problem.</p>
<p>While Germany's Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann and Italy's Consumer Commissioner Emma Bonino were broadly in favour of the plan for legislation, Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert said he favoured even more vigourous legislation.</p>
<p>Van Miert is leading his own campaign under EU competition law to clamp down on EU mega media mergers.</p>
<p>Britain's senior Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan stood out alone against any move to regulate against media concentration, the sources said.</p>
<p>Culture Commissioner Marcelino Oreja, who has responsibility for promoting the EU's ailing television and film industry, said that while steps needed to take taken against over-concentration, legislation was not the answer.</p>
<p>Oreja says binding legislation does not have the backing of the sectors concerned and could run counter to the need to promote the EU's media industry.</p>
<p>Monti, who now faces the difficult task of chewing over the different points of view, argues legislation is needed if only because a plethora of different rules in the EU on media pluralism could hinder the EU's single market.</p>
<p>Under his current blueprint media concentration would be gauged according to audience share -- a novel approach.</p>
<p>Single media -- like newspapers or radio or television stations -- would see their market share limited to 30 percent, while groups crossing more than one media would see each strand limited to an average of 10 percent.</p>
<p>European publishers said this week the plan would strangle them.</p>
<p>&quot;It will inhibit the development of strong European based companies and discriminate against those who have already proved their success in traditional media (TV, radio and newspaper publishing),&quot; the European Publishers' Council said in a statement.</p>
<p>It questionned exactly how the audience share could be measured.</p>
<p>EU sources said on Wednesday commissioners also expressed concerns about the need to take into account new technologies in the plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
