<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32979" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO, Netanyahu tussle over terms ahead of summit.</title>
<headline>PLO, Netanyahu tussle over terms ahead of summit.</headline>
<byline>Nidal al-Mughrabi</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel and the Palestinians tussled on Wednesday over the wording of a document that would commit Israel to existing peace deals and lead to Benjamin Netanyahu's first meeting with Yasser Arafat, PLO officials said.</p>
<p>The officials, maintaining a meeting could come as early as late Wednesday, said Palestinian President Arafat and his negotiators had sent a reply to an Israeli draft of a joint communique submitted earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;We discussed the Israeli paper, and our response with modifications to the document was sent back via the Norwegian mediator Terje Larsen,&quot; a PLO official said. &quot;If they agree to it, the meeting could take place later today.&quot;</p>
<p>Four days of round-the-clock talks have failed to fix a summit between Arafat and Netanyahu, seen as vital to reviving peace talks suspended since Islamic suicide bombers killed 59 people in Israel in February.</p>
<p>Larsen told reporters there might be a meeting on Wednesday and Mahmoud Abbas, Arafat's top negotiator, said: &quot;I hope there will be a meeting today.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu, elected in May on a vow to take a hardline in peace talks with the Palestinians, had said he would only meet Arafat when he deemed it necessary for Israel's security.</p>
<p>Palestine Liberation Organisation officials said Netanyahu was still resisting making a commitment to implementing the 1993 self-rule deal signed with the previous Israeli government.</p>
<p>&quot;They have come up with several drafts, some with vague wordings, but it does not spell out their commitment to carry out signed accords. They still want to renegotiate agreements,&quot; said the official, who spoke on condition he not be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we are getting closer to bridging the gaps,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Palestinians want a clear commitment from Netanyahu that he will honour Israel-PLO peace deals, including a long delayed Israeli troop redeployment from the West Bank city of Hebron.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has said the agreement on Hebron, where Israeli troops are to remain in parts of the city to ensure the safety of 400 Jewish settlers living in enclaves among more than 100,000 Arabs, must be re-examination due to security concerns.</p>
<p>The prime minister's media adviser David Bar-Illan said on Tuesday the sides were edging closer to agreement and expected the two leaders to meet on Thursday.</p>
<p>Arafat and Netanyahu are likely to meet on Israel's side of the Erez crossing leading to self-ruled Gaza, Bar-Illan said.</p>
<p>&quot;The thrust of the meeting between the prime minister and Arafat is to confirm that an agreement has been reached on the agenda of the negotiations and to seal it with a handshake,&quot; Bar-Illan said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
