<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32978" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PLO officials say Netanyahu-Arafat summit imminent.</title>
<headline>PLO officials say Netanyahu-Arafat summit imminent.</headline>
<dateline>GAZA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>PLO officials said Palestinian President Yasser Arafat would meet Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for the first time on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Israel Radio said a meeting could take place at 4.30 p.m. (1330 GMT).</p>
<p>Ahmed Abdel-Rahman, general secretary of the Palestinian Authority, told Reuters: &quot;The meeting will take place soon.&quot;</p>
<p>Chief PLO negotiator Mahmoud Abbas, asked when a summit would be held, advised reporters: &quot;Go to Erez,&quot; the Israeli-Gaza crossing point where a summit could take place.</p>
<p>But Arafat and a spokesman for Netanyahu said a meeting had yet to be set.</p>
<p>Asked when a meeting would take place, Arafat said: &quot;It has not been decided yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked what was delaying the summit, he said: &quot;Many issues. It is better not to mention it. But still there are many attempts.&quot;</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators have been struggling over the past week to find a formula that would enable the two men to meet and for full-fledged peace talks to resume.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, elected in May on a pledge not to swap occupied Arab land for peace, had said originally he preferred not to meet Arafat but softened his position in recent days.</p>
<p>Palestinians have been pressing for a summit and resumed talks to tackle the issue of Israel's long-delayed troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
