<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32981" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt's taxes to come down as evaders get chased.</title>
<headline>Egypt's taxes to come down as evaders get chased.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Egyptian government will cut tax rates in the long term and compensate for the loss of revenue by expanding the tax base and chasing tax evaders, Finance Minister Mohieddin el-Gharib said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The net result will be to keep the government deficit within the rigorous limits of the past two years, at less than 1.5 percent of GDP, he told an investment conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The long-term trend will be towards reducing individual income tax and corporate tax, gradually,&quot; he said. &quot;This is subject to expanding the tax community and reducing evasion.&quot;</p>
<p>Gharib has previously said he is studying a plan to cut the top rate of income tax to 30 percent from 50 percent and the lowest rate to 10 percent from 20 percent.</p>
<p>Tax reform is part of Egypt's draft agreement with the International Monetary Fund, but Egyptian officials said the agreement mainly covers bringing the tax system into line with international norms familiar to foreign investors.</p>
<p>Gharib told the conference that one reform under study included transforming the government's sales tax into a value added tax. &quot;It might take a year or so, and I think it would be welcomed by the business community and the public,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The minister said he hoped his cabinet colleagues would agree to using some of the proceeds from privatisation to reduce the government's domestic debt, which costs the government 10 percent of GDP to service.</p>
<p>He said foreign investors had already shown interest in investing about $400 million in Egypt's forthcoming issue of seven-year treasury bonds, which go on sale from September 8 with a fixed yield of 11 percent. The treasury hopes to sell bonds worth four billion pounds ($1.18 billion)</p>
<p>&quot;This reflects their confidence in fiscal policy and their expectation that the exchange rate will be stable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Wright +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
