<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32980" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Meeting with Arafat an about-face for Netanyahu.</title>
<headline>Meeting with Arafat an about-face for Netanyahu.</headline>
<byline>Jeffrey Heller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first summit between Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and Palestinian President Yasser Arafat on Wednesday represents a climbdown for the Israeli leader, who once said he hoped never to meet &quot;that man&quot;.</p>
<p>But Arafat won a meeting, likely to be followed by a resumption of full-fledged Israeli-PLO peace talks, by talking tough and taking strident action in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;He can't ignore me...I am the most important figure in the MIddle East's dilemma, in the Middle East equation,&quot; Arafat told Israel Television last month.</p>
<p>Arafat captured world headlines last week by saying the Netanyahu government's decision to expand Jewish settlements in the West Bank and Gaza and its tough policy on Jerusalem were tantamount to a declaration of war on the Palestinians.</p>
<p>He also declared a four-hour Palestinian general strike last Thursday, the first such work stoppage in both the West Bank and Gaza in two years.</p>
<p>It was another setback for Netanyahu, who had been trying unsuccessfully to sideline the Palestinians by focusing on the dormant Syrian peace track and dangling the prospect of &quot;Lebanon First&quot; negotiatons on an Israeli pullout from south Lebanon.</p>
<p>Syria, which said what it really wanted was an Israeli commitment to quit the occupied Golan Heights, would not bite.</p>
<p>&quot;I will not meet Yasser Arafat,&quot; Netanyahu said in an interview with Israel's Channel Two Television last February.</p>
<p>&quot;I won't meet that man but representatives of the government of Israel will meet representatives of the (Palestinian) Authority.&quot;</p>
<p>Since taking office in June, Netanyahu -- a former commando whose brother Jonathan was killed leading Israel's 1976 rescue of Israeli air passengers hijacked by Arab guerrillas to Entebbe, Uganda -- softened his opposition.</p>
<p>He said he would consider meeting Arafat if Israeli security concerns dictated a summit was necessary. Foreign Minister David Levy and President Ezer Weizman have been pressing Netanyahu to agree to face-to-face talks.</p>
<p>At 46, Netanyahu is Israel's youngest ever leader -- a &quot;comeback kid&quot; who at one point trailed former prime minister Shimon Peres in opinion polls by more than 20 percentage points.</p>
<p>Only last November, Netanyahu, flattened by a wave of sympathy for Peres after the assassination of Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin, faced accusations he fostered a climate of hate that led to the killing by a nationalist Jew.</p>
<p>Then Islamic suicide bombers killed 59 people in four attacks in February and March, wiping out Peres's lead.</p>
<p>Educated in the United States, Netanyahu has tried to project a White House image, putting his third wife Sara firmly in the spotlight as a First Lady.</p>
<p>In office only three months, Netanyahu -- who feels most at home on American television news programmes -- will be paying a second trip as prime minister to Washington next week, a private visit to attend an American Jewish function.</p>
<p>His promises to expand Jewish settlement in the West Bank and Gaza Strip plays well among the right-wing in Israel, including Ariel Sharon, a former hardline general who Netanyahu grudgingly appointed minister of national infrastructure.</p>
<p>But the policy puts him on a collision course with the Arabs and Washington.</p>
<p>Political analysts say, however, that a showdown with the United States is likely to be put off until after the November presidential election.</p>
<p>Palestinians meanwhile will be pressing Netanyahu to implement outstanding issues of the peace deals signed with the previous Israeli government, mainly a long-delayed Israeli troop redeployment in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
