<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32999" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: RESEARCH ALERT-Osem downgraded.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT-Osem downgraded.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Salomon Brothers said it downgraded Osem Investments Ltd to underperform from hold in light of substantially lower than expected second-quarter operating results.</p>
<p>Salomon reduced its 1996 earnings per share (EPS) forecast to $0.29 from $0.31. Last year Israel's second-largest publicly traded food manufacturer earned $0.30 a share.</p>
<p>&quot;Osem's stock is currently trading at higher price/earnings multiples than the overall Mishtanim Index average: 20.5 times prospective 1996 EPS compared with 12.0 times for the Mishtanim Index,&quot; analyst Victor Halpert said in a report.</p>
<p>&quot;Osem's 1996 growth relies on the overall performance of the Israeli economy, which is rapidly slowing following five very strong years. Latest GDP estimates at 3.0-4.0 percent for 1996 will directly affect Osem's growth potential in its main market, where the company derives more than 90 percent of its sales.&quot;</p>
<p>Nestle SA  owns 39.7 percent of Osem and Salomon Brothers expects the Swiss giant to pursue an active role in management.</p>
<p>In the second quarter Osem introduced a variety of Nestle products to Israeli consumers. &quot;However, total sales of Nestle products in 1996 now appear likely to fall short of our expectations at around $10 million. We estimate that Nestle products sales offer poor profit margins due to their very high advertising and marketing expenses,&quot; Halpert said.</p>
<p>The original founding families own 45.2 percent of Osem. Salomon Brothers said it believes in the long term Nestle may acquire the remaining shares from the founding families and even try to delist Osem's shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Osem may become Nestle's regional manufacturing and distribution base,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
