<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32991" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks maintain pickup despite Iraq attack.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks maintain pickup despite Iraq attack.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian stocks extended gains at end of weekly trade on Wednesday unshaken by renewed U.S. military strikes against Baghdad, dealers said.</p>
<p>The official Amman Financial Market 60-share index rose 0.50 percent to 145.53 points from 144.80 points on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A total of 365,971 shares changed hands in a moderate 563,707 dinar turnover in the cash-squeezed market. Of 42 stocks traded, 13 advanced, 13 fell and 16 were unchanged. Three posted year lows.</p>
<p>&quot;There were minimal fears with the market already discounting the loss of the Iraqi market with the recent economic breakthrough with the Gulf states at the expense of ties with Iraq,&quot; said Nasser al-Amad, general manager of the brokerage firm United for Financial Investment.</p>
<p>The market was buoyed by a 3.50 dinar rise to 238.50 in Arab Bank, a major component of the index, as the market leader continued to attract interest after revived hopes of a bonus share issue once a new companies law is passed.</p>
<p>Some of the industrial companies that could be affected by the suspension of Iraq's $2 billion oil-for-food deal were slightly weaker, dealers said.</p>
<p>Along with strong demand for Arab Bank, trade was underpinned again with some select bluechip interest.</p>
<p>Dealers reported healthy demand for the second week in Livestock and Poultry, bolstered by a Gulf-based investor reported to be gradually building up his stake.</p>
<p>Investment sentiment has slightly picked up since the government announced last week a package of economic reforms in the wake of recent unrest fuelled by the government's doubling of bread prices in line with IMF-agreed economic reforms.</p>
<p>The Pearl Investable Index -- an independent index of the 45 best-performing shares from the official market -- rose 0.25 percent to 81.05 points. It was 15.13 percent down on last year.</p>
<p>In industrials, the leading sector, Livestock and Poultry again dominated with another 20 fils rise to 630 fils on 189,700 dinar turnover.</p>
<p>Jordan Cement Factories, a focus of foreign investor interest, shed 20 fils to 3.36 dinars. Universal Modern Industries shed 70 fils to 1.70 dinars. Jordan Petroleum Refinery rose 20 fils to 9.28 dinars.</p>
<p>In banks, aside from market leader Arab Bank's rise, Islamic Bank and Cairo Amman Bank were unchanged at 3.58 dinars and 4.45 dinars respectively.</p>
<p>In services, Jordan Electric Power was unchanged at 1.55 dinars and National Portfolio shed 10 fils to 1.18 dinars.</p>
<p>Industrials dominated trading on Wednesday, with a 314,141 dinar turnover and an index rise of 0.09 percent. Banks had a 206,500 dinar turnover and an index rise of 1.03 percent while services had a low 42,782 dinar turnover and an index drop of 0.09 percent.</p>
<p>A total of 216,210 shares worth 122,768 dinars changed hands in moderate trade in the parallel market.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom takes queries on +962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
