<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="32992" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish stock index ends 1.48 percent up. [Corrected 14:55 gmt]</title>
<headline>Turkish stock index ends 1.48 percent up. [Corrected 14:55 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish stocks rose by 1.48 percent on Wednesday amid reaction buying following a three percent fall in the past two days of this week. (Corrects from &quot;in the past week&quot;)</p>
<p>Brokers said cheap stock prices and Tuesday's &quot;successful&quot; treasury acution helped prices rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The market digested the U.S. missiles to Iraq. Unless the dispute turns into a war, things will go on its own rhythm,&quot; said Ali Guler, chief analyst at Acar securities.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 index ended at 63,486.46, barely changed from morning close but up 925.45 points from Tuesday. Daily trade volume was nearly six trillion lira versus 4.3 trillion lira.</p>
<p>The upside of the index is seen limited for the coming days, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The two-day fall weakened the market. Thus we may expect a downward movement after today's reaction. The sideway movement of the index between 61,500-65,000 is likely to continue,&quot; Guler said.</p>
<p>Out of the 219 shares traded, 131 shares rose, 53 unchanged and 35 fell.</p>
<p>Textiles firm Akin Tekstil's shares were the most active of the day. It rose 900 lira to 9,700 lira. Department store Carsi ended 1,500 lira up at 28,500 and utility firm Aktas Elektrik 5,000 lira to 455,000 lira. --Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
