<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33008" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Hariri win boosts confidence in Lebanon - bankers.</title>
<headline>Hariri win boosts confidence in Lebanon - bankers.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Tarnowski</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri's election victory has boosted confidence in the Lebanese economy, increasing local investor trust in the currency and stimulating sales of longer-term Lebanese treasury bills, a banking source said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hariri, who has based his economic policies on strengthening the pound in the past four years, triumphed on Sunday when he and his supporters won 14 of Beirut's 19 seats in the 128-member parliament.</p>
<p>His victory was perceived by local investors as a guarantee of political stability and of the Lebanese pound, and they were now selling dollars to buy pounds for investment in two-year t-bills, the banking source said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen after the Beirut election a huge offer of dollars and a very important subscription in two-year t-bills,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lebanese investors, depositors and speculators were selling dollars at a rate of $15 million-$20 million a day, compared with $4 million-$5 million before the election, he said.</p>
<p>Beirut foreign exchange dealers were unable to confirm the scale of dollar sales. One said it was impossible to know how many dollars were sold on a daily basis and another estimated sales at only $1 million-$3 million.</p>
<p>Two-year bills are the longest-term paper offered by Lebanon. They currently yield 21.76 percent a year compared with 17.85 percent for 12-months bills, 16.92 percent for six-months and 14.61 percent for three-months.</p>
<p>The source said investors began switching from shorter-term paper to two-year bills in the week before the Beirut election as the growing likelihood of Hariri's win dissipated any lingering doubts about an eventual devaluation of the pound.</p>
<p>Last week's sales of two-year bills at 117 billion pounds ($75 million) outstripped other denominations for the first time in a long time.</p>
<p>A dealer at a well-known Beirut bank confirmed there was increased confidence in the Lebanese pound and increased demand for two-year bills, but said Hariri's election was not the only factor.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been bullishness in the market for a while for the two-year bills,&quot; the dealer said. &quot;I wouldn't say the election has been the main thing but it has added to the optimism for the Lebanese pound and Lebanese pound involvement.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The market was already positive because reserves are high, the central bank has shown it can overcome a lot of problems in a very effective way, and all the political problems we have had have not affected the market,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>Another dealer said investors were selling short-term t-bills to buy long-term bills because they anticipated a decline in interest rates.</p>
<p>However, the banking source expected a strong post-election trend to switch from dollars and invest in longer-term t-bills to continue, giving the treasury a strong creditor position.</p>
<p>&quot;This regaining of confidence in the economic situation is an important opportunity for the government to re-think its economic and financial policy,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>He suggested that the government could use the opportunity for a dramatic restructuring of Lebanon's soaring public debt and its financial situation by adjusting interest rates and expenditures.</p>
<p>He proposed lowering interest rates to reduce both the treasury's heavy debt-servicing burden and the crowding out of the private sector which has dampened economic activity.</p>
<p>Other suggestions were the introduction of longer-term bonds to extend the maturity of the public debt and a reduction of current expenditures in favour of investment, the source said.</p>
<p>- Beirut editorial (961 1) 864148 353078 861723</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
