<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33006" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan Islamic Bank H1 profits up 49 pct.</title>
<headline>Jordan Islamic Bank H1 profits up 49 pct.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan Islamic Bank on Wednesday said its pre-tax profits for the first half of 1996 rose to 20.7 million dinars, up 49.5 percent against the same period last year.</p>
<p>A bank official told Reuters the jump was partly credited to higher lending activities. Loans stood at 457.3 million dinars, a 9.5 percent rise in the first half of 1996 compared to the same period 1995.</p>
<p>The bank's largest shareholder is Saudi Baraka Islamic financial group, which has to keep within 49.9 percent ceiling for foreign ownership.</p>
<p>The bank wants to raise its capital to 22 million dinars from 15 million by a private placement and public offer to meet a 20 million dinar minimum capital ceiling by mid-1997 under a Central Bank deadline.</p>
<p>Shareholders rights -- capital and reserves -- rose to 41.9 million dinars in the first half of 1996, the bank said.</p>
<p>The bank, the country's only Islamic investment financial institution, is the third largest commercial bank in size of assets after Arab Bank and Housing Bank.</p>
<p>($1=0.7080 dinar)</p>
<p>-- Amman Bureau +9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
