<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33011" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq vows to ignore Western no-fly zones.</title>
<headline>Iraq vows to ignore Western no-fly zones.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq on Wednesday appeared ready to confront a U.S. decision to expand the amount of the country closed to Iraqi aircraft, raising the spectre of an escalating military confrontion.</p>
<p>A U.S. decision to extend the southern no-fly zone to the outskirts of Baghdad went into effect at noon Baghdad time (0800 gmt).</p>
<p>The Iraqi News Agency (INA) reported that President Saddam Hussein met air defence commanders on Wednesday in what seemed to be a review of Iraqi options in defying the U.S. and allied air patrols in the areas closed to Iraqi planes.</p>
<p>Iraq's official newspapers, including Babel which is run by President Saddam Hussein's eldest son Uday, reiterated that Baghdad would ignore restrictions on Iraqi flights.</p>
<p>The prospect of a conflict over the no-fly zones -- areas patrolled by foreign warplanes but closed to Iraqi flights -- followed an Iraqi advance into the northern Iraq Kurdish area last weekend and U.S. retaliation with cruise missiles.</p>
<p>Washington has so far unleashed 44 cruise missiles, 27 on Tuesday and 17 on Wednesday, against Iraqi air defence targets. Iraq said six people died and 26 were injured in the attacks, which it said hit residential areas and military sites.</p>
<p>The strikes were sparked by Iraq's assault on the Kurdish stronghold of Arbil on Saturday, which it said followed a plea by a Kurdish rebel leader who was fighting pro-Iran rivals.</p>
<p>Iraqi President Saddam Hussein, in a fiery response to Tuesday's first U.S. missile strike, declared the air-exclusion zones over his country null and void and urged his forces not to let Western warplanes enter Iraqi airspace.</p>
<p>Iraq has always expressed its anger at the no-fly zones in the north and the south of the country, condemning them as a flagrant violation of its sovereignty,</p>
<p>In 1993 Iraq moved anti-aircraft missiles into the two zones and anti-aircraft gunners fired at the Western planes, prompting retaliation by U.S. and allied forces.</p>
<p>Baghdad has maintained the U.S.-led coalition that drove its troops from Kuwait in 1993 is disintegrating. It noted that France has not supported the strikes and Washington did not attack from bases in neighbouring Turkey, Jordan and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;Once again we say to the ungodly Americans in a loud voice...(that) from today there are no more imaginary parallel lines...from today there will be no (part) of Iraqi territory off limits to us whether in the north or the south,&quot; Babel said in a front-page editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;We shall defend our sovereignty with our nails and teeth,&quot; Babel said.</p>
<p>The official al-Qadissiya newspaper said Iraq's decision not to accept no-fly zones was irrevocable: &quot;Iraq has obliterated forever the damned lines north of the 36th parallel and south of the 32nd parallel.&quot;</p>
<p>Newspapers termed President Bill Clinton &quot;a dinosaur&quot; trying to swallow the world with computerised weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;Let the cursed Clinton be humiliated. The roar of Iraqis will not let him sleeep at night,&quot; said Qadissiya.</p>
<p>A military communique on Wednesday slammed Clinton for ordering the strikes, saying &quot;the criminal Clinton...added more crimes to his history which is full of vice and crime.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
