<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33016" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus says economy sound but must be careful.</title>
<headline>Cyprus says economy sound but must be careful.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus has a sound economy compared to other small states but remains vulnerable to unexpected events, the island's finance minister said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Economically we are at a remarkable level compared to other small countries,&quot; Finance Minister Christodoulos Christodoulou told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are still a small, open and very vulnerable economy and that must always be on our minds...we must not rest assured so we are not confronted with anything unexpected,&quot; he added, without elaborating.</p>
<p>Christodoulou, opening a three-day international conference on the effects of economic globalisation and regional integration on smaller countries, said larger countries had the upper hand defining trade trends.</p>
<p>&quot;This meeting will give representatives of small countries the opportunity to define their problems and exchange views on ways for a common approach,&quot; said Christodoulou.</p>
<p>The conference, with 140 participants from 10 countries, is organised by the Cyprus Planning Bureau, a government-controlled think-tank.</p>
<p>Cyprus, predominantly a services economy, had a trade deficit of 1.114 billion pounds ($2.417 billion) in 1995, up 10.8 percent from 1,006.2 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>The European Union, which Cyprus has applied to join, is its main trading partner. It is due to start accession negotiations with the bloc in late 1997 or early 1998.</p>
<p>Dr. Ron Ayres, Principal Lecturer in Econonomics at the University of Greenwich in England, told the conference Cyprus and Malta, also a prospective E.U. member, have benefitted from a series of financial protocols 'but the trade consequences have been ambiguous'.</p>
<p>&quot;Neither country has been constrained by a foreign exchange gap but this was largely because of the growth of tourism which was not subject to E.U. trade preferences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Theodoros Georgakopoulos, of the Athens University of Economic and Business, said Greece's accession carried a high cost from the point of view of the balance of payments. Imports increased more than exports and the Greek trade balance has severely deteriorated.</p>
<p>&quot;Accession to the European Union implies far reaching institutional changes that can affect trade materially, (rather) than the simple realignment of tariffs, which is usually considered in customs union theory,&quot; he said. ($= 0.46 pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
