<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33022" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Gulf Arab papers mixed over U.S. attacks on Iraq.</title>
<headline>Gulf Arab papers mixed over U.S. attacks on Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newspapers in the United Arab Emirates on Wednesday slammed the United States for firing cruise missiles at Iraq but papers in Kuwait and Saudi Arabia blamed Baghdad for tension in the region.</p>
<p>One Kuwaiti daily called on Arab states to support Washington's &quot;noble objective&quot;.</p>
<p>UAE dailies, which went to press before a second barrage of U.S. cruise missiles hit targets in southern Iraq on Wednesday, appeared to reflect Abu Dhabi's objections to the U.S. attack.</p>
<p>&quot;Arbil is not Kuwait, attacking Iraq is an act of aggression directed at the sovereignty of an Arab state,&quot; said the Dubai-based al-Bayan, referring to the Western powers' rallying to save Kuwait after Iraq invaded it in 1990.</p>
<p>Iraqi forces helped a Kurdish faction seize the northern city of Arbil from a rival faction on Saturday, prompting the U.S. missile strikes.</p>
<p>&quot;Suspending oil-for-food is aggression against a nation made to pay the price twice,&quot; it added in reference to the United Nations' decision to put on hold the implementation of a deal allowing Iraq to sell oil to pay for much-needed foodstuffs and medicines and meet some 1990-91 Gulf crisis obligations.</p>
<p>The paper said Arabs declined to provide coverage for the attack despite U.S. attempts to &quot;twist their arms because Iraq has a legitimate right to defend its north.&quot;</p>
<p>The Cairo-based Arab League on Tuesday strongly condemned the first round of missile attacks, a move criticised in Kuwait, where Al-Qabas newspaper said:</p>
<p>&quot;If the United States is resorting to enforce international ligitimacy, then the Arab League should mobilise Arabs to achieve this noble objective or at least side with such a move and not oppose it.&quot;</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia's al-Riyadh described President Saddam Hussein's foray into northern Iraq as &quot;suicide&quot;.</p>
<p>Another UAE daily, al-Khaleej, said the success of U.S. attempts to split Iraq could lead the region and the Arab world into &quot;an endless tunnel of darkness and would spread the fragamentation virus to threaten other states.</p>
<p>&quot;The coordinated campaign failed...to camouflage the reality of the military campaign as a flagrant and rude aggression by the superpower against a semi-crippled state.&quot;</p>
<p>The semi-official al-Ittihad hailed Russian and French calls for dialogue to defuse the crisis.</p>
<p>The English-language Gulf News published in Dubai said: &quot;(U.S. President Bill) Clinton who is seeking re-election in November has acted out of very suspect motives seeking in fact to boost his image...without any concern for the damage he is doing to the region's stability.&quot;</p>
<p>In London, columnist Jihad al-Khazen said in the Arabic-language al-Hayat &quot;the Iraqi president should have calculated that the U.S. president would not have missed the chance to attack Iraq with elections only two months away. Saddam Hussein proved again he is the emperor of wrong decisions.&quot;</p>
<p>The daily's chief editor wrote: &quot;Violations by the Iraqi regime do not justify the violations against Iraq.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
