<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33055" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. missiles hit Iraqi targets again.</title>
<headline>U.S. missiles hit Iraqi targets again.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States launched a second wave of cruise missiles at Iraqi military targets on Tuesday to destroy President Saddam Hussein's ability to attack aircraft enforcing the expanded no-fly zone in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>The Pentagon and the White House said 17 missiles were fired from four U.S. ships in a &quot;mop-up&quot; operation authorized by President Bill Clinton. The second wave was aimed at a number of targets not destroyed in an attack by 27 missiles on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>The cruise missiles were fired from ships in the Gulf at targets such as radars and surface-to-air missile sites. Eight were fired from the destroyer Russell, five by the destroyer Laboon, two by the destroyer Hewitt and two by the attack submarine Jefferson City.</p>
<p>Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon said Clinton authorized the strikes to suppress air defenses over southern Iraq and provide greater safety for U.S. and allied pilots who will police the expanded no-fly zone beginning at noon Baghdad-time (0800 GMT on) Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the second strike) required additional approval and he (Clinton) granted that this afternoon,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an effort to go in and assure that we have done everything possible to suppress air defenses before we start enforcing the expanded no-fly zone ... we want to guarantee that our pilots have every opportunity to fly safely.&quot;</p>
<p>Defense Secretary William Perry told PBS's &quot;Newshour with Jim Lehrer&quot; on Tuesday night that damage from the first strike appeared &quot;very considerable.&quot; But he dismissed as &quot;exceedingly unlikely&quot; Iraqi reports that civilians were among the casualties, noting that the target sites were remote.</p>
<p>&quot;What we hope is that Saddam Hussein will cut his losses, put his tail between his legs and retreat to Baghdad,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said of the strikes that drew howls of defiance from Saddam, opposition from the Arab League and only lukewarm backing from U.S. allies.</p>
<p>U.S. officials made clear Washington had decided to retaliate with or without allied approval and warned that Iraq would be hammered again if necessary.</p>
<p>Clinton and his top aides tried to justify the action in terms of sweeping international security concerns, including the vital flow of Gulf oil to the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objectives there are limited but our interests are clear: to demonstrate once again that reckless acts have consequences, to reduce Saddam's ability to strike out again at his neighbors, to increase America's ability to prevent future acts of violence and aggression,&quot; Clinton told the National Guard Association in a speech on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Perry said the issue went far beyond the need to stop an Iraqi attack on the Kurds.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is not simply the Iraqi attack on (the Kurdish town of) Arbil,&quot; he said. &quot;It is the clear and present danger that Saddam Hussein poses to his neighbors, the security and stability of the region and the flow of oil to the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Tuesday's action was the biggest U.S. strike against Iraq since 1993, when 23 missiles destroyed an Iraqi intelligence headquarters in Baghdad in response to its alleged plot to assassinate former President George Bush.</p>
<p>Allied air and naval forces have kept Iraq under surveillance since the 1991 Gulf War to oust Iraq from Kuwait.</p>
<p>U.S., British and French warplanes police no-fly zones north of the 36th parallel in northern Iraq, to protect Iraq's Kurdish minorities from Saddam, and south of the 32nd parallel in southern Iraq to give similar haven to Shiite Muslims.</p>
<p>Clinton said the United States would expand the southern no-fly zone to the north by one degree of latitude to further reduce the Iraqi military's room for movement toward Kuwait and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;This will deny Saddam control of Iraqi airspace from the Kuwaiti border to the southern suburbs of Baghdad and significantly restrict Iraq's ability to conduct offensive operations in the region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Saddam responded defiantly, calling the raids &quot;aggression&quot; and urging his Air Force and anti-aircraft gunners to attack allied planes policing the air exclusion zones.</p>
<p>Clinton also said a recent U.N. decision to let Iraq sell some of its embargoed oil to raise funds for humanitarian supplies could no longer proceed under current circumstances.</p>
<p>Burns said the oil-sale plan would be shelved for &quot;some time&quot; without being more specific.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
