<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33054" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fran strengthens to dangerous Category 3 hurricane.</title>
<headline>Fran strengthens to dangerous Category 3 hurricane.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Zengerle</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Fran became a potentially dangerous storm with winds of 115 mph (185 kph) late on Tuesday and weather forecasters posted a hurricane watch stretching from central Florida to the border of North Carolina.</p>
<p>A hurricane warning was in effect for the sparsely populated northwestern Bahamas as Fran gained strength and edged across the Atlantic toward the United States, the National Hurricane Center said.</p>
<p>At 11 p.m. EDT (0300 GMT on Wednesday), Fran was near latitude 26.0 north and longitude 73.5 west, or about 255 miles (410 km) east of Nassau, Bahamas, and moving west-northwest near 12 mph (19 kph), a path that forecasters said could bring the storm to the United States on Thursday.</p>
<p>The hurricane watch area extended from Sebastian Inlet near Vero Beach, Florida, to Little River Inlet at the border of North and South Carolina.</p>
<p>Although the storm was several hundred miles (kms) east of the Florida coast, at a latitude just south of Miami, forecasters said Fran began a gradual northerly turn, diminishing Fran's threat to the heavily populated southern portion of the state.</p>
<p>&quot;If this (turn) actually is realized, which we think it will, it will lessen the chances of landfall in the southern Florida region and increase the chances in the north Florida to the North Carolina region, and that would be two to three days out,&quot; said Bill Frederick, a meteorologist at the National Hurricane Center.</p>
<p>Fran's maximum sustained winds increased as it moved over warmer water, jumping from a minimal hurricane clocked at 80 mph (130 kph) earlier on Tuesday. That strengthening made Fran a dangerous Category 3 hurricane capable of significant damage.</p>
<p>A hurricane warning was in effect for the tiny islands of the northwestern Bahamas as Fran's path paralleled the island chain. A hurricane watch, indicating hurricane conditions -- maximum sustained winds of 74 mph (119 km) or higher -- was expected within 36 hours, and a tropical storm warning, indicating that winds of 39 to 73 mph (63-117 kph) might arrive within 24 hours, was in effect in the central Bahamas from Acklins Island to Cat Island.</p>
<p>The Club Med in the Bahamian island San Salvador closed its beach as Fran generated high waves and brisk winds. With rough seas, heavy rain and active thunderstorms expected as Fran's edge brushed the islands, residents of Abaco, Cat Island and Eleuthera were advised to stay indoors.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending upon the speed of the storm we're looking to meet sometime Thursday afternoon. If it starts to make funny changes we're going to meet sooner,&quot; said Clarence Skinner, head of the emergency control group in Dare County, North Carolina, noting that Fran would only get stronger as it moved over warm ocean waters.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a high probability of it being a Category 3 when it comes to shore,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Dare County, which encompasses Cape Hatteras on North Carolina's Outer Banks, &quot;no swimming&quot; advisories were lifted at beaches for the first time since Edouard threatened the state late last week.</p>
<p>Edouard was declared extra-tropical before dawn as it moved in the north Atlantic southwest of Halifax, Nova Scotia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
