<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33082" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Midwest seen warm through Friday, turning cool.</title>
<headline>US Midwest seen warm through Friday, turning cool.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cooler weather was expected to supplant this week's above-normal U.S. Midwest readings by Saturday but forecasters differed on how low temperatures would fall after the cold front moved through.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a brief stint, two to three days of cool weather, followed by another warm-up,&quot; said Joel Burgio, meteorologist with Weather Services Corp.</p>
<p>He forecast low temperatures on Monday and Tuesday in the upper 30s (degrees Farenheit) to low 40s F in the northwest portion of the belt. Highs were expected to be in the mid 50s F to low 60s with some 70s to the south.  </p>
<p>But Smith Barney meteorologist Basilio Lopez predicted lows in the 50s F and highs in the 70s. He expected a total rainfall accumulation of 0.30 to 1.50 inches in southern Indiana and Ohio Saturday through Monday.</p>
<p>Temperatures were expected to be above normal through Friday with little precipitation noted, meteorologists agreed. Highs this week should be in the low- to mid-80s F with some upper 80s to the south.</p>
<p>&quot;It does start to cool off on Saturday with the potential for a few light, scattered showers in the west and in the east on Sunday,&quot; Burgio said.  </p>
<p>Hurricane Fran, expected to hit the U.S. East Coast late Thursday, was not expected to bring much precipitation to the corn belt.</p>
<p>But heavy rains were forecast for areas of North Carolina and South Carolina, which would delay corn harvest. Rainfall accumulations could reach two to six inches with locally heavier, Lopez said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is obviously a very poor situation for the crop across South Carolina and North Carolina,&quot; he said. &quot;Corn harvesting will be further delayed as fieldwork operations will come to a halt from Thursday into Saturday.&quot;</p>
<p>Areas of eastern Georgia could see 2.0 to 4.0 inches of rain during that period, he said.</p>
<p>--Emily Kaiser 312-408-8749</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
