<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33098" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stocks seen taking cue from oil outlook, data.</title>
<headline>U.S. stocks seen taking cue from oil outlook, data.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Westhoven</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks were in for a directionless open on Wednesday, as Wall Street awaits a key jobs report due Friday and more information on the future of oil prices.</p>
<p>Construction data, due at 1000 EDT/1400 GMT, could also move stocks and bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;A follow through of yesterday's gains is really a matter of question,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, market strategist at Fahnestock and Co. &quot;The new element in the economic story is the prospect of rising oil prices.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ackerman said stocks would also be battling worries about interest rates, historical weakness during the month of September, and a lack of conviction ahead of the jobs data.</p>
<p>&quot;Should they be strong, its likely to prompt a selloff,&quot; he said. U.S. August payroll and unemployment numbers are due Friday.</p>
<p>This morning's July construction spending figures are expected to fall 0.2 percent compared to a June gain of 1.2 percent. At 0900 EDT/1300 GMT, BTM Schroders releases chain store sales for the week ended August 31 compared to the prior week.  </p>
<p>&quot;I suspect were in for some profit taking at the open, which will hurt the Dow initially, and then another gyration day for stocks,&quot; said Peter Cardillo, director of research at Westfalia Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is going to take a very cautious attitude before the report due Friday. We could see a 20 point range from low to high and maybe some profit taking in oil stocks,&quot; Cardillo said.</p>
<p>&quot;But if construction data is softer than expected or on target, the market could follow yesterday's pattern, when it overcame early losses to close up 32 points,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The real key to the Iraq situation was the fact that the Iraqi oil deal was suspended. That's what hit oil prices and stocks,&quot; Cardillo said.</p>
<p>The long bond was off 8/32 to yield 7.08 percent.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks closed slightly higher, mostly brushing off news of the second U.S. missile attack on Iraq, with the Nikkei 225 index up 4 to 20202.</p>
<p>U.S. shares were narrowly mixed in light and featureless trading in London with U.S. oil companies mostly flat ahead of the market open in the United States.  </p>
<p>The dollar fell slightly against the yen, hovering below the 109 mark in European trading.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's Futures were off 0.60 to 655.25, indicating a slightly lower opening.</p>
<p>McDonald's shares slipped slightly in London trading after the Wall Street Journal's &quot;Heard on the Street&quot; column said the company's new Arch Deluxe burger was not boosting sales.</p>
<p>Stratton Oakmont is still trying to find a public market for E-Net, according to the &quot;Marketplace&quot; column of the New York Times.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
