<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33115" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ex-prostitute fails in bid for U.S. Congress.</title>
<headline>Ex-prostitute fails in bid for U.S. Congress.</headline>
<dateline>CARSON CITY, Nev. 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jessi Winchester, a former prostitute who once worked at the Moonlight Bunny Ranch, a legal brothel in Nevada, fell short of her dream of reaching the U.S. Congress on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Former state Sen. Thomas &quot;Spike&quot; Wilson crushed Winchester in the Democratic primary for Nevada's second congressional district on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Former state Assemblyman Jim Gibbons won the Republican primary and will face Wilson in the November election to choose a successor to U.S. Representative Barbara Vucanovich, a Republican who is retiring after 14 years in Congress.</p>
<p>In the race for Nevada's only other congressional seat, which encompasses the Las Vegas area, state Sen. Bob Coffin easily defeated three opponents in the Democratic primary to earn a shot at Republican incumbent John Ensign, who had no primary opposition.</p>
<p>Winchester retired after six years as prostitute, working at the Moonlight Bunny Ranch and the Mustang Ranch, both legal Nevada brothels. The 53-year-old grandmother drew national attention with her campaign for political office.</p>
<p>Although Winchester distanced herself from her former profession, her candidacy drew criticism from the Nevada Brothel Association, which represents brothels that operate legally in 10 of Nevada's 17 counties.</p>
<p>&quot;Her behaviour flies in the face of a policy our industry tries to maintain of not rubbing our existence in people's faces,&quot; George Flint, a lobbyist for the association, said earlier this year.</p>
<p>With almost 90 percent of precincts reporting, Wilson had about 62 percent of the vote to Winchester's 21 percent, with Mike Martin, a security guard at a Reno casino, trailing on 17 percent.</p>
<p>In her low-budget, heavily-travelled campaign, Winchester derided Wilson, who served 14 years in the state legislature and, most recently, as chairman of the Nevada Ethics Commission, as &quot;a professional politician&quot; and &quot;good old boy&quot;.</p>
<p>By contrast, she said she was &quot;totally in touch with those who work more than 40 hours a week and have to figure out a budget.&quot;</p>
<p>Winchester said her former profession initially caused a stir on the campaign trail &quot;but in the last few months I've had no questions. They saw me as a candidate, not as a hooker.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking on Tuesday evening, Winchester said that political realities had engulfed her earlier optimism to the point where she would likely never seek major office again.</p>
<p>&quot;I was just an average person trying to give some representation to the middle class. What I found was that the average person can't run,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wilson and I didn't run against each other. He had the influence and power of the governor and two (U.S.) senators and their staffs. The average person just can't fight this thing,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARSON CITY, Nev."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
