<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33117" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. fires missiles at Iraq second time.</title>
<headline>U.S. fires missiles at Iraq second time.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Wilson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States used cruise missiles twice to blast Iraqi air defenses and clear a path for U.S. warplanes that were to begin enforcing an expanded &quot;no-fly zone&quot; on Wednesday in southern Iraq against a defiant President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>The expansion of the area in which Iraqi combat pilots are forbidden to fly was to go into effect at 4 a.m. EDT (0800 GMT) but Hussein ordered his pilots to shoot down U.S. airmen who try to enforce it.</p>
<p>After firing 27 powerful cruise missiles from bombers and ships early on Tuesday at &quot;about&quot; 15 southern Iraqi targets, including radar stations and communication centers, the U.S. Defense Department and the White House ordered another wave of missiles to be fired on Tuesday night (early Wednesday Iraq time).</p>
<p>The United States said the second attack included 17 missiles fired from three ships and one submarine and said it was a mop-up operation against targets not destroyed in the first attack.</p>
<p>Pentagon analysts, hampered by thick clouds over Iraq, were unable to make conclusive assessments about the damage done by the first attack.</p>
<p>The targets of the first strike were elements of Iraq's air defense network, including 14 sites which would control any attacks on allied aircraft monitoring the no-fly zone.</p>
<p>After Hussein defied U.S. warnings to keep his troops and warplanes out of Kurdish-held territory in northern Iraq, President Bill Clinton ordered the missile strikes.</p>
<p>Clinton also announced the United States would no longer tolerate any Iraqi warplane flights in an area of southern Iraq extending northward from the Kuwait border to the southern suburbs of Baghdad.</p>
<p>In a statement announcing that a second wave of missiles had been fired, White House spokesman Mike McCurry said, &quot;This operation is designed to eliminate sites not destroyed in Tuesday morning's attack ... tonight's attack is necessary to ensure the safety of aircraft and crews operating in the expanded no-fly zone.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton has not said what Hussein must do to avoid further military action against Iraq.</p>
<p>Clinton administration officials called Hussein a menace to world security, a danger to his neighbors and a threat to the vital flow of oil from the Gulf.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objective is to see him stop this military action, stop him from being a bully ... but I would not want to equate a particular action he must take,&quot; Defense Secretary William Perry said.</p>
<p>It was unclear whether the U.S. would strike again if Hussein pulled his troops out of northern Iraq. U.S. intelligence late on Tuesday had detected the movement of Iraqi forces in the north but called the shift inconclusive. The Pentagon did not rule out additional air strikes even if Hussein pulled out his troops.</p>
<p>&quot;We reserve the right to conduct further military actions,&quot; said Perry. &quot;One factor which would influence whether we conduct those is what he (Hussein) does in the future, but that's not the only factor.&quot;</p>
<p>The first strike was deplored by Hussein who accused the Americans of cowardice in hiding behind the technology of their sophisticated weaponry and ordered his pilots to ignore the no-fly zone.</p>
<p>He said five people had been killed and 19 injured, some of whom were civilians, but Perry disputed that account, saying it was &quot;exceedingly unlikely&quot; that there would have been any civilian casualties because the sites targeted were remote and not near any populated or residential areas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
