<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33128" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: UAW targets Ford in U.S. auto labor talks.</title>
<headline>UAW targets Ford in U.S. auto labor talks.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Auto Workers has targeted Ford Motor Co. to lead labor contract negotiations between union and the Big Three U.S. automakers, a source close to the talks said.</p>
<p>The source, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said the union informed Ford's top management of the decision earlier on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The selection will allow the No. 2 U.S. automaker to negotiate an agreement that will serve as a pattern for rivals General Motors Corp and Chrysler Corp to follow.  </p>
<p>Contracts covering about 400,000 U.S. hourly workers at all three companies expire September 14. As the target company, Ford faces the threat of a national strike if it fails to strike an agreement.</p>
<p>UAW Vice President Ernest Lofton, who is leading the union's Ford negotiations, later confirmed the choice but downplayed the possibility of a strike.</p>
<p>&quot;They are the lead company in regards to resolving our 1996 negotiations,&quot; Lofton said in an interview on WDIV-TV.  </p>
<p>Ford spokesman Jon Harmon would only read the following statement: &quot;We're hard at work negotiating with the UAW at the subcommittee level as well as at the main table...</p>
<p>&quot;Our team is working under the assumption that we will be closely involved in whatever transpires over the next two weeks. And that's been our preference all along.&quot;</p>
<p>The decision marks the second time in a row that the union has chosen Ford to lead its Big Three U.S. negotiations. Ford negotiated the current pact in 1993.</p>
<p>The UAW's top priorities in the 1996 negotiations are improved job security for its workers and restrictions on the automakers' ability to shift work to lower-cost outside suppliers.</p>
<p>Chrysler has been chosen as the Canadian Auto Workers union's negotiating target. The CAW's Big Three labor contract, covering about 53,000 workers, has been extended until September 17.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
