<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33130" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - U.S. says Saddam endangers peace, security.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - U.S. says Saddam endangers peace, security.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States fired 27 missiles at military targets in Iraq on Tuesday, saying Iraqi President Saddam Hussein had re-emerged as a menace to world security and urging him to &quot;put his tail between his legs and retreat.&quot;</p>
<p>Later on the same day, the U.S. launched a second missile attack. Defence department officials said privately that the attack launched earlier in the day had not done the damage expected against Iraqi missile defences in the southern part of the country.</p>
<p>No more details were immedietely available of the second strike.</p>
<p>The unilateral missile attack, earlier on Tuesday, was launched from ships and planes at targets in southern Iraq after Saddam had reportedly ignored demands to cease an assault on Kurds in northern Iraq and withdraw his troops.</p>
<p>Defence Secretary William Perry told PBS's &quot;Newshour with Jim Lehrer&quot; on Tuesday night that damage appeared &quot;very considerable.&quot; But he dismissed as &quot;exceedingly unlikely&quot; Iraqi reports that civilians were among the casualties, noting that the target sites were remote.</p>
<p>&quot;What we hope is that Saddam Hussein will cut his losses, put his tail between his legs and retreat to Baghdad,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said of the strikes that drew howls of defiance from Saddam, opposition from the Arab League and only lukewarm backing from U.S. allies.</p>
<p>U.S. officials made clear Washington had decided to retaliate with or without allied approval. They said Iraq would be hammered again if necessary.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton and his top aides tried to justify the action in terms of sweeping international security concerns, including the vital flow of Gulf oil to the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objectives there are limited but our interests our clear: to demonstrate once again that reckless acts have consequences, to reduce Saddam's ability to strike out again at his neighbours, to increase America's ability to prevent future acts of violence and aggression,&quot; Clinton told the National Guard Association in a speech on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Perry said the issue went far beyond the need to stop an Iraqi attack on the Kurds.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is not simply the Iraqi attack on (the Kurdish town of) Arbil,&quot; he said. &quot;It is the clear and present danger that Saddam Hussein poses to his neighbours, the security and stability of the region and the flow of oil to the world.&quot;</p>
<p>Put that way, the U.S. action assumed the same mantle of international cause as the original allied effort to reverse Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait. Clinton cast the missile strike as a step necessary to avoid more severe military conflict down the road.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want that to happen, and therefore I did what I did today,&quot; he told the Guard.</p>
<p>Jitters swept world petroleum markets on Tuesday. Oil prices hit their highest levels since the Kuwait invasion. Japan is the biggest importer of Gulf oil, followed by Europe and then the United States.</p>
<p>Tuesday's action was the biggest U.S. strike against Iraq since 1993, when 23 missiles destroyed an Iraqi intelligence headquarters in Baghdad in response to its alleged plot to assassinate former President George Bush.</p>
<p>Allied air and naval forces have kept Iraq under surveillance since the 1991 Gulf War to oust Iraq from Kuwait.</p>
<p>U.S., British and French warplanes police no-fly zones north of the 36th parallel in northern Iraq, to protect Iraq's Kurdish minorities from Saddam, and south of the 32nd parallel in southern Iraq to give similar haven to Shiite Moslems.</p>
<p>Clinton, reading a statement in the White House Oval Office on Tuesday morning, said the United States would follow up the attack by expanding the southern no-fly zone by one degree of latitude to further reduce the Iraqi military's room for movement toward Kuwait and Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>&quot;This will deny Saddam control of Iraqi airspace from the Kuwaiti border to the southern suburbs of Baghdad and significantly restrict Iraq's ability to conduct offensive operations in the region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Saddam responded defiantly, calling the raids &quot;aggression&quot; and urging his Air Force and anti-aircraft gunners to attack allied planes policing the air exclusion zones.</p>
<p>Clinton also said a recent U.N. decision to let Iraq sell some of its embargoed oil to raise funds for humanitarian supplies could no longer proceed under current circumstances.</p>
<p>Burns said the oil-sale plan would be shelved for &quot;some time,&quot; but he offered no more precise estimate.</p>
<p>Some U.S. allies including Britain, Germany, Canada and Japan expressed general support for the raid. But others including France withheld such backing. The Arab League and Russia opposed the U.S. intervention.</p>
<p>Burns said Washington was satisfied with the support it got but made clear it was determined to act in any case.</p>
<p>&quot;We engaged in two days of diplomacy, consultations with our European allies, partners in the area and the Middle East, about what should be done, where we clearly indicated that the United States was going to do something,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The move also intruded into U.S. politics. Clinton's presidential election opponent, Republican Bob Dole, had blamed &quot;weak&quot; Clinton policies for the Iraqi situation over the weekend but backed off that criticism on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
