<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33148" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German industry orders up again in July.</title>
<headline>German industry orders up again in July.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German July industrial orders data published on Wednesday showed the second consecutive monthly gain, encouraging economists to predict solid overall economic growth in the third quarter after a robust spring.</p>
<p>Industrial orders grew by a monthly 0.6 percent after a 1.9 percent gain in June, the economics ministry said.</p>
<p>A rise of 0.9 percent in western Germany was undermined by what economists called a worrying 4.7 percent drop in the &quot;new states&quot; of former communist eastern Germany.</p>
<p>They said the picture emerging from early indicators for July, along with last week's business confidence survey by the Ifo institute, pointed to continued growth at a slower pace following a leap during the spring.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is going well, and will do well in the second half,&quot; said economist Holger Schmieding at Merrill Lynch in Frankfurt. &quot;The monthly figures are distorted by major orders, but if you look at the trend it is dramatically upward.&quot;</p>
<p>Second quarter gross domestic product figures are due on Thursday. They are expected by economists to show a gain of 1.0-1.5 percent over the first quarter when Germany suffered from bad winter weather and output fell 0.4 percent.</p>
<p>The industrial orders figures came in above a plus 0.3 percent consensus forecast in a Reuter survey -- but within expectations. They followed industrial output data on Tuesday which also showed a slowdown in month-on-month growth in July from June although the growth trend extended back five months.</p>
<p>The orders figure was &quot;a little better than I thought, but just barely,&quot; said Adolf Rosenstock of the Industrial Bank of Japan in Frankfurt. &quot;Looking at output and orders data, output was below expectations, so this compensates.</p>
<p>&quot;The trend development is rather stable, so this should not have policy or market implications. West Germany seems to have stabilised. We are on a moderate upward trend, but nothing spectacular.&quot;</p>
<p>Pan-German industrial orders were down by 0.1 percent in July on the same month a year earlier, after a two percent rise in June, according to calculations based on Bundesbank data.</p>
<p>Economists said the slump in east German orders could have either been caused by a gap in major orders or problems due to the summer holidays.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement is there, but we are not out of the woods yet. In the east, there are clouds on the horizon,&quot; Rosenstock said.</p>
<p>Gerhard Grebe of Bank Julius Baer said that the poor east German figure meant pan-German orders were below his forecast. But he expected that number to be revised up later and said he was leaving his overall view unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;My outlook is for a strong economic recovery in the second quarter, followed by a continuation at a slower pace in the third quarter,&quot; Grebe said.</p>
<p>Data across the board showed strong growth of over seven percent in foreign orders, while domestic orders were sluggish and slipped back by nearly three percent against June.</p>
<p>The fledgling economic upturn is unlikely to help employment, however. Economists expect August unemployment data due on Thursday to show continued stagnation at close to post-war record highs of just under four million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
