<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33145" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS - Total's profits jump 45 percent.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Total's profits jump 45 percent.</headline>
<byline>Noelle Mennella</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French energy company Total on Wednesday reported a 45 percent jump in first-half profits to 2.63 billion francs ($517 million) on the back of higher crude prices and a 15 percent rise in production in the January-June period.</p>
<p>Total's operating profit surged to 4.96 billion francs from 3.47 billion in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>On a per-share basis, its profit rose to 11 francs in the first half of 1996 from 7.80 francs.</p>
<p>The company said in a statement that oil production levels remained high at the beginning of the second half, but it declined to give a full-year profit forecast.</p>
<p>Chairman Thierry Desmarest told a news conference the group aimed to increase production to between 950,000 and one million barrels per day from 766,000 currently.</p>
<p>&quot;For the year 2005, a level of 1.25 million barrels is not unattainable,&quot; he said. He said the group expects to double production outside the Middle East over the next eight years.</p>
<p>Growth in production and productivity in the medium term -- to the year 2000 -- should boost profitability even if oil prices slipped to around $16 a barrel, the company said.</p>
<p>U.S. attacks on Iraq have boosted the European benchmark, Brent crude, above $23 a barrel in recent days but Desmarest said the current price was not sustainable.</p>
<p>The &quot;situation with Brent above $20 is not representative of a long-term trend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Total said the favourable first-half environment, including higher oil prices, had a positive impact on operating results of around 700 million francs relative to the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>Refining margins were above levels seen in the first half of 1995 but remain volatile, the group said.</p>
<p>The operating result of the energy production activity rose 53 percent to 3.3 billion francs. Total attributed the gain to higher crude prices and production but also to lower costs.</p>
<p>The operating result of the refining-distribution business rose 65 percent to 674 million francs, helped by improved refining margins in Europe and efforts to push down the break-even level at its refineries, Total said.</p>
<p>The chemical business's operating result rose eight percent to 984 million francs on a 14.9 percent rise in sales.</p>
<p>Total's share price, which has risen in recent sessions on expectations that it would show good results and on the recent oil price gains, extended its gains on Wednesday by 0.31 percent to 385.70 francs in late trading.</p>
<p>Shares in rival Elf-Aquitaine, due to report its half-year results on Thursday morning, were 1.1 percent higher at 386 francs. ($1=5.087 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
