<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33154" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Britain and Ireland to discuss N.Ireland violence.</title>
<headline>Britain and Ireland to discuss N.Ireland violence.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Hill</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British and Irish government ministers meet on Thursday to breathe new life into Northern Ireland peace talks whose credibility is threatened by blood feuds among Protestant &quot;Loyalist&quot; militants.</p>
<p>The two governments are expected to tell the Loyalists' political representatives that they face expulsion from the talks when they resume in Belfast on September 9 unless they reaffirm their commitment to non-violent politics.</p>
<p>Their departure would be a major setback for the talks process, already undermined by the absence of the IRA's political wing, Sinn Fein, because of the IRA guerrillas' continued war against British rule of the province.</p>
<p>The IRA ended a 17-month truce in February with bomb attacks against targets in Britain and Germany and shows no sign of reinstating the ceasefire that helped launch the talks.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland Secretary, Sir Patrick Mayhew, and Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring are expected to warn the Loyalists' political representatives that they will be cast into the cold like Sinn Fein unless they condemn the public feud.</p>
<p>The row erupted after the Combined Loyalist Military Command (CLMC), the umbrella group for Protestant guerrilla groups fighting to maintain British rule of the province, ordered wayward militant Billy Wright to leave Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>It said he faced &quot;summary justice&quot; -- which Wright said meant death -- after publicly opposing the CLMC's strategy of maintaining a 23-month-old truce to keep its political spokesmen at the peace talks.</p>
<p>Wright, who has been convicted for security offences, defied an order to leave his native Portadown by last Saturday midnight and claims to have the support of broad sections of the Protestant majority.</p>
<p>The Progressive Unionist Party (PUP), a Loyalist group close to outlawed Ulster Volunteer Force (UVF) guerrillas, has deplored the threat against Wright, a reputed UVF commander, but has failed publicly to condemn the warning against him.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe that there is any room for ambiguity in regard to violence in the political process. There is no way that you can be half a democrat,&quot; Irish Prime Minister John Bruton said on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>He said any expulsion of the PUP or a second Loyalist party, the Ulster Democratic Party (UDP), from the talks was a matter for other participants -- who have already made plain that they regard the Wright affair as grounds for their ejection.</p>
<p>&quot;It should first be discussed by the participants and then reported upon by the chairman to the two governments, who will at that stage, and not previous to that, be in a position to make a balanced decision,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The mainstream Ulster Unionist Party (UUP), the biggest political party, and smaller Democratic Unionist Party (DUP) have both warned the PUP and UDP of possible expulsion.</p>
<p>The talks have been snarled since they started by UUP and DUP mistrust of their chairman, former U.S. Senator George Mitchell, President Bill Clinton's Ireland envoy.</p>
<p>The two parties fear that he sympathises with Irish Republicans and have sought to trim his powers and set an agenda which includes stripping guerrillas of their arms, which neither the IRA nor Loyalists will agree to.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
