<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33156" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Delhaize H1 1996 profits seen climbing.</title>
<headline>Delhaize H1 1996 profits seen climbing.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A firmer dollar and good performance at U.S. unit Food Lion should help Belgian retailer Delhaize show a rise of around 15 to 20 percent in 1996 first half profits, analysts said on Wedensday.</p>
<p>&quot;Since last year the dollar has recovered sharply, and Food Lion has showed accelerated growth,&quot; said Herman Vanderloos, an analyst at Banque Bruxelles Lambert (BBL).</p>
<p>He expected Delhaize - one of Belgium's leading retail groups - to post a first half 1996 group net profit of about 1.85 billion francs, up from 1.62 billion in first half 1995.</p>
<p>Delhaize is due to announce its results on Friday.</p>
<p>Full year 1995 profit slipped to 3.77 billion from 4.02 billion the previous year as a result of severe dollar weakness which affects the groups consolidated accounts in francs.</p>
<p>Maud Watelet at brokers Mignon, Hanart, Declerck forecast a 21 percent rise in profit. &quot;Sales have been good at Food Lion thanks to their commercial strategy - for example 24-hour opening,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Watelet calculated an average dollar rate for 1996 of 30.7 francs, compared to 29.5 last year, when Food Lion accounted for 66 percent of Delhaize's full year consolidated turnover.</p>
<p>Analysts said the contribution of Delhaize's Belgian activities should also show some improvement.</p>
<p>Although there had been no new supermarket openings, and Delhaize appeared to have lost market share slightly to big rivals GIB Group and Colruyt, its smaller outlets looked to be gaining share against other competitors.</p>
<p>&quot;Delhaize says...its expansion is abroad and on small outlets in Belgium, so I'm not worried about it,&quot; BBL's Vanderloos added.</p>
<p>Analysts said while food sales in Belgium had picked up, overall consumption levels remained stagnant.</p>
<p>Several analysts said they were neutral or positive on Delhaize stock, but were generally less bullish about the retail sector than they had been at the start of the year.</p>
<p>Generale Bank analyst Sandra Vandersmissen said she considered the stock a &quot;hold&quot;, and may change her recommendation to &quot;buy&quot; after the results &quot;if there is a positive surprise in their Belgian business.&quot;</p>
<p>She noted the sudden departure of Food Lion's chief financial officer at the end of August had depressed Food Lion stock, in turn hurting Delhaize shares in Brussels. This had made them look &quot;rather cheap&quot;.</p>
<p>Mignon's Watelet said the departure was not likely to affect Food Lion's strategy in the long term. &quot;Maybe this is a buying opportunity -- Delhaize is not very expensive compared to GIB or Colruyt,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>She said it was possible Delhaize could reach 1,700 francs by the end of the year, but noted the retail sector had already gained a lot of ground this year.</p>
<p>Delhaize shares closed five francs up at 1,610 francs on the Brussels bourse on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;For Delhaize we've been on the buy side for a long time. Now we are less tremendously bullish - the story is largely over,&quot; said Philippe Masset, analyst at Vermeulen Raemdonck.</p>
<p>He said Delhaize stock was fairly valued, with a price to earnings ratio on 1996 earnings of around 18 and more than 16 on 1997 earnings.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
