<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33166" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Caio wins Olivetti battle, hard task ahead.</title>
<headline>Caio wins Olivetti battle, hard task ahead.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>It's taken just two months for Olivetti chief executive Francesco Caio to topple the group's chairman of nearly 20 years, Carlo De Benedetti, but his battle to save the struggling group has just begun.</p>
<p>Caio, 39, emerged late on Tuesday as the winner in a battle over the future of Italy's lumbering information and technology giant -- only weeks after De Benedetti had hand-picked his former assistant to take charge of day-to-day management.</p>
<p>Industry analysts speculated that Caio, groomed in the world of U.S. management consultancy McKinsey and the global telecommunications industry, clashed with the autocratic style of De Benedetti, who had already rescued and transformed Olivetti once in the late 1970s.</p>
<p>Caio was appointed sole chief executive in early July following the surprise departure of Corrado Passera and after De Benedetti gave up the joint chief executive role he held with Passera to focus on strategic corporate issues as chairman.</p>
<p>For the previous 19 months, Caio had moulded Olivetti's 41.3 percent-owned cellular phone operator Omnitel into a true force in the Italian mobile phone world and a serious challenger to the dominant state-controlled Telecom Italia Mobile (TIM).</p>
<p>For some analysts, Caio did a good job guiding Omnitel to apparent early success. Others believe most of the credit should go to consortium partners, which included big U.S. telecommunications groups Airtouch and Bell Atlantic.</p>
<p>Caio is seen by analysts as the telecoms man destined to push Olivetti even quicker towards telephony and away from its old business of personal computers, office equipment and banking and retailing automation systems.</p>
<p>Major Olivetti institutional shareholders had become more and more disgruntled with De Benedetti's overbearing style, highlighted by a lack of financial information from the company base in the Italy's northwestern town of Ivrea.</p>
<p>Caio is seen as having an ear open to shareholder voices and being more inclined to allow greater transparency with group financial data.</p>
<p>This situation was highighted last week when shareholders representing 25 percent of Olivetti stock met in London to voice their disapproval of its management and the lack of information coming out of Ivrea.</p>
<p>De Benedetti bought into the loss-making typewriter company in 1978, transformed it into one of Europe's leading computer makers and was trying to turn it into a modern telecoms player.</p>
<p>Olivetti has bled red ink for five years and it is Caio's task to keep it together until its telephony business starts producing profits to sustain the whole group.</p>
<p>Analysts said his main problem would be to persuade shareholders -- 70 percent of them from outside Italy -- to stick with him through the recovery phase as the share price languishes near record lows and with most having seen a loss on their investment.</p>
<p>Caio first worked for Olivetti in 1981 and 1982 in telecoms systems marketing before completing an MBA business degree in France and moving to McKinsey's London offices before returning to Olivetti in 1991 as assistant to De Benedetti.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
