<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33170" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Positive Danish shares rally, more gains up front.</title>
<headline>Positive Danish shares rally, more gains up front.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Danish share prices closed higher on Wednesday after recovering from Tuesday's blues, with dealers seeing the positive undertone persisting and more gains ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The market got off to a good start from the world go, faltering a little in the afternoon on profit-taking in A.P. Moeller paper but recovering again unaffected by the Iraq crisis. We should climb again tomorrow,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index closed 0.80 point higher at 120.20 while the KFX September future rose 0.50 point to 120.20 as well with 179 contracts each worth 100,000 crowns traded.  </p>
<p>The leading banks rallied with Unidanmark finishing 11 crowns better off at 265 and rival Den Danske Bank ending three up at 408, while ISS continued to surprise everyone, climbing five crowns to close at 159 on overseas investor interest.</p>
<p>FLS boomed on too, putting on a solid 40 crowns to 720.</p>
<p>Tele Danmark rose one crown to 282, Novo Nordisk edged three up to 893 while Moeller's two shares went different ways - D/S 1912 B closing 500 crowns higher at 142,500 and D/S Svendborg 2,000 crowns lower at 207,000.</p>
<p>Overall turnover for the day was 902 million crowns.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom, 45-33-969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
