<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33186" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Hungary's gas price rise delay dismays investors.</title>
<headline>Hungary's gas price rise delay dismays investors.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary's decision to delay implementation of a planned increase in natural gas prices has dismayed foreign investors, a conference was told on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Germany's Ruhrgas AG -- which has invested in Hungary's gas distribution sector -- was &quot;very disappointed&quot; by the deferral, from October 1 to at least January 1 and possibly even further, Anne Hessbrugge, Head of Projects Section at Ruhrgas, told the International Energy Agency's third natural gas conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The consequence of the delay will be to delay investments,&quot; said Guillaume Bonhoure, the head of Gaz de France's permanent office in Budapest.</p>
<p>Hungary's oil and gas company MOL Ltd is hoping for a price increase of at least 20 percent.</p>
<p>Despite the price increase delay, Hungary is on the brink of joining the west European gas grid. Next month a $26 million, 70-km pipeline link to the Austrian grid at Baumgarten will be completed, says Gabor Molnar, chief of the Energy Information Centre at MOL.</p>
<p>Ruhrgas has already concluded a contract to supply MOL with 500 million cubic metres (mcm) of gas a year from Germany via Austria and this new pipeline link.</p>
<p>Hungary has been more successful at attracting foreign investment in its gas sector than any other country of the former eastern bloc. At the end of 1995, the country's six gas distribution companies were privatised and all are now controlled by foreign interests, with a shareholding of 50 percent plus one share in nearly every case.</p>
<p>Gaz de France controls two, DEGAZ and EGAZ; a Ruhrgas/VEW partnership controls DDGAZ and holds a 39 percent stake in FOGAZ which supplies Budapest; Italgas controls TIGAZ; and a Bayernwerk/EVN partnership controls KOGAZ.</p>
<p>One of the attractions to foreign investors is gas' penetration of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1995, gas accounted for 34 percent of all energy consumed in Hungary,&quot; said Molnar. &quot;This is second only to the Netherlands in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that this will increase to 35 percent by 2010.</p>
<p>&quot;Already there are 2.3 million residential customers, and we are expecting three million by 2010,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Given Hungary's cold winters and warm summers, there is huge variation in seasonal demand. Seventy percent of demand depends on the temperature, which means more storage capacity is needed, another potential area for foreign investment, said Molnar.</p>
<p>But price remains a critical issue for investors, as it does throughout eastern Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had a new gas law since 1994 which at least channels things in the right direction,&quot; said D. Vasanits, deputy general director of Gas Works of Budapest.</p>
<p>&quot;We used to have very low prices in all sectors, but there was cross financing so public service users got gas extremely cheaply while industrial and commercial users paid more.</p>
<p>&quot;Since then, a new energy authority has equalised the price stucture but absolute values are not yet acceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sebastian Alison, Berlin newsroom</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
