<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33185" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS - U.S. steps up diplomacy on Cuba trade row.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - U.S. steps up diplomacy on Cuba trade row.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Wednesday stepped up its efforts to defuse a potentially damaging international trade row, calling on its allies to join its efforts to isolate the Cuban government of Fidel Castro.</p>
<p>Stuart Eizenstat, the special envoy appointed by President Bill Clinton to win support for Washington's controversial Helms-Burton Act, met senior European Union officials to outline proposals for a multinational effort to isolate Cuba.</p>
<p>But the European Commission, the EU's executive, remained steadfast in its opinion that the act was hindering rather than helping Washington's aims.</p>
<p>EU Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan was due to address the European Parliament later on Wednesday to report on his meeting with Eizenstat and reiterate plans to retaliate against any U.S. laws which punish European companies or individuals doing business with Cuba.</p>
<p>Eizenstat -- who on Wednesday conceded the near-impossibilty of winning international support for the act, an amalgamation of decades of anti-Cuba legislation -- is instead concentrating his efforts on coordinating and increasing opposition to Castro.</p>
<p>He met EU commissioners Manuel Marin and Emma Bonino -- responsible for Latin American affairs and humanitarian aid, respectively -- to outline new U.S. proposals, and plans also to meet senior business and trade union officials.</p>
<p>A Commission spokesman, however, reiterated that the EU believed it was already &quot;very active&quot; in efforts to bring democracy to Cuba.</p>
<p>Brittan, following his meeting with Eizenstat, promised to reflect on the U.S. proposals, which called for inter-governmental, non-governmental and private sector dealing with Cuba to be concentrated on &quot;helping the people rather than the government&quot;.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton Act was passed in July to a chorus of indignant opposition from many of Washington's strongest allies on the grounds that it is extra-territorial -- that is, it imposes U.S. laws on other countries.</p>
<p>Among other things, the act allows American citizens to sue in U.S. courts foreign companies that have benefited from investments made in property confiscated by Havana since the Cuban revolution of 1959.</p>
<p>Although the practical implications of this part have been suspended until next year, the EU -- along with Canada and Mexico -- are concerned that liability is accruing.</p>
<p>The EU has already outlined what form retaliation is likely to take. In July, foreign ministers gave the Commission a mandate to pursue four measures they believed would best counter the laws -- named after its U.S. congressional sponsors, Dan Burton and Jesse Helms.</p>
<p>These were to forbid EU individuals or companies to comply with any U.S. court action; allow them to counter-sue to recover any damages awarded; prohibit individuals from litigant U.S. companies from travelling to the EU; and compile a &quot;watch list&quot; of American companies or individuals involved in any litigation.</p>
<p>The EU has also to decide whether to escalate a dispute on the matter within the World Trade Organisation.</p>
<p>EU officials have repeatedly said their opposition to nations considered undemocratic is already strong. Earlier this year the EU pulled out of a cooperation agreement with Cuba on the grounds that it did not promise enough protection to human rights.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
