<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33187" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: FOCUS - Waterford first half profits gleam.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Waterford first half profits gleam.</headline>
<byline>Jane O'Sullivan</byline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crystal and china group Waterford Wedgwood Plc said on Wednesday that half-year pre-tax profit rose by 28 percent to 9.5 million punts ($15.42 million).</p>
<p>First-half trading was characterised by significant growth in the U.S., Japan and Ireland but slower growth in Britain and more difficult conditions in the rest of western Europe, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>But despite some difficult markets, strong performances by the group's Waterford crystal and Wedgwood china brands saw sales rise by eight percent to 163.2 million punts.</p>
<p>The company said its overall marketing strategy was proving to be globally successful and the international reach of its brands enabled it to cope more easily with localised fluctuations in demand.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very pleasing first half in terms of sales and profits,&quot; chief executive Redmond O'Donoghue told a news conference.</p>
<p>Chairman Tony O'Reilly, who also heads U.S. food group H.J. Heinz Co and chairs three other Irish companies, said Waterford Wedgwood continued to concentrate on a new growth strategy outlined earlier this year and aimed at doubling the company's size by 2000.</p>
<p>The group plans to consolidate its position of leadership in the tabletop industry through organic growth, the strength of its brands, investment to keep it globally competitive and acquisitions should suitable opportunities arise, O'Reilly said in the statement.</p>
<p>On a divisional basis, Waterford Crystal reported a 13 percent increase in operating profit to 5.1 million punts in the first half, on sales of 61.5 million.</p>
<p>At the Wedgwood china division, first-half operating profits also rose by 13 percent to 6.3 million Irish pounds, the highest level for six years, although sales slipped to 101.7 million punts from 104 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>&quot;Measured in sterling and at constant exchange rates, sales overall were up four percent on 1995,&quot; Waterford Wedgwood said.</p>
<p>The group said Wedgwood sales in the Japanese market continued to surge, rising 18 percent to record levels in the first half. Other Far East markets, while still small, are showing great promise, and sales there increased by 69 percent over the comparative period, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Pan-Asia is small but growing like a rocket,&quot; Wedgwood chief executive Brian Patterson told reporters.</p>
<p>The group announced an interim dividend of 0.30 Irish pence. The share price was unchanged from the close at 76 pence by 1240 GMT. ($1=.6159 Punt)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
