<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33184" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: BHF economist calls on Buba to liberalise reserves.</title>
<headline>BHF economist calls on Buba to liberalise reserves.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bundesbank should further liberalise bank reserve requirements to shore up Germany's position as a financial centre as Europe readies itself for currency union, a senior independent economist said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hermann Remsperger, chief economist at BHF Bank in Frankfurt, argued the Bundesbank's reserve requirements are forcing banks to take business abroad, dealing another blow to Germany's efforts to compete head-to-head with London.</p>
<p>&quot;A further easing of the minimum reserve requirement could aid German preparation for the currency union. That is necessary since international competition for German banks will be heightened by the currency union,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Currently the Bundesbank requires banks to hold minimum reserves on short-term borrowings obtained from foreign banks or domestic non-banks in non-interest-bearing accounts at the central bank.</p>
<p>The reserve level is two percent of sight and term deposits and 1.5 percent of savings deposits.</p>
<p>Remsperger said even though the Bundesbank pared back its reserve requirements in recent years, Germany still lacks a functioning securities repurchase market as banks prefer to give such business to foreign units to avoid holding reserves.</p>
<p>&quot;The absence of a functioning domestic repo market is regrettable,&quot; Remsperger said, adding this market gap could be eliminated if the Bundesbank were to abolish requirements that banks hold reserves on these borrowed funds.</p>
<p>&quot;With a minimum reserve requirement reform, investors would have the opportunity to easily bring these funds back to Germany,&quot; Remsperger said.</p>
<p>Several studies have shown that Germany already lags far behind its London rival, not only because of more restrictive financial regulations but also because of language barriers and underdeveloped infrastructure.</p>
<p>German bankers have repeatedly appealed to the Bundesbank to set things right by relaxing regulations, helping Germany gear up for currency union when it loses its hitherto strongest asset, the mark.</p>
<p>Remsperger rejected arguments that the Bundesbank would lose control over monetary policy by abandoning the reserve requirement.</p>
<p>Rather the move would assist German banks' preparations in the runup to Europe's planned currency union, where competition between banks will grow ever more fierce, Remsperger said.</p>
<p>But the Bundesbank has generally stood firm that reserves are necessary and had lobbied hard for the future European central bank to adopt a similar system.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
