<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33190" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Rexrodt welcomes EU compromise on VW subsidies.</title>
<headline>Rexrodt welcomes EU compromise on VW subsidies.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt on Wednesday welcomed a compromise announced by the European Commission in a dispute over subsidies paid by the state of Saxony to auto maker Volkswagen AG.</p>
<p>&quot;This decision is an important contribution to bringing back onto a quieter track the discussion over VW's Saxony investments and the protection of needed help for the building of the eastern states,&quot; Rexrodt said in a statement.</p>
<p>He said the German government and the European Commission shared the same goal of achieving subsidy discipline in the single market.</p>
<p>&quot;That is also of particular interest to the German business sector,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rexrodt said the compromise addressed Germany's need to rebuild its formerly communist eastern states, for which it needs EU help, while continuing on the road to greater European integration.</p>
<p>Earlier in Brussels, European Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert said Germany had agreed to freeze an amount of money due to be paid to VW to neutralise the illegal aid granted by Saxony, and the commission would refrain from taking further action.</p>
<p>The Commission approved 540 million marks ($364 million) of a planned 780 million marks in proposed subsidies, but charged that at least 100 million marks more had been illegally handed over to the carmaker.</p>
<p>VW said late on Tuesday that it would not draw on the disputed funds. On Wednesday, it declined to comment further.</p>
<p>&quot;We have expressed our opinion. There is no more to say,&quot; a VW spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 26097150 ($ = 1.483 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
