<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33197" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway says Israeli-PLO talks big step forward.</title>
<headline>Norway says Israeli-PLO talks big step forward.</headline>
<byline>Rolf Soderlind</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway said on Wednesday it expected Israeli and PLO leaders to discuss a range of issues from Hebron to border closures in their talks over the next few days in a &quot;major and significant&quot; effort to revive the peace process.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu will meet Palestinian President Yasser Arafat at Erez, the Israeli-Gaza crossing point, at 5.30 p.m. (1430 GMT), PLO negotiator Saeb Erekat told reporters in Palestinian-ruled Gaza.</p>
<p>&quot;I just talked to Arafat,&quot; Norwegian Foreign Minister Bjoern Tore Godal told Reuters in an interview. &quot;I see this as a major and significant step forward in the peace process.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, it is not a breakthrough in itself but it is important because it creates a psychological climate betwen the two leaders that is very instrumental in the future negotiations,&quot; the foreign minister said.</p>
<p>Norway, which helped broker the 1993 Israeli-PLO peace pact, has been involved in new diplomatic efforts in recent weeks to ease relations between Israel and the Palestine Liberation Organisation.</p>
<p>&quot;I have reason to believe the agenda in the next few days will be the border closures, the issue of Hebron and the special security issues in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators have been struggling over the past week to find a formula that would enable the two men to meet and for full-fledged peace talks to resume.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, elected in May on a pledge not to swap occupied Arab land for peace, had said originally he preferred not to meet Arafat but softened his position in recent days.</p>
<p>Palestinians have been pressing for a summit and resumed talks to tackle the issue of Israel's long-delayed troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Norway, which hosted 14 secret meetings between Israeli and PLO negotiators in 1993, has again been working behind the scenes, overseeing fresh talks between key Israeli and Palestinian personalities in a private Tel Aviv apartment.</p>
<p>The new discussions have been held under the guidance of United Nations special envoy Terje Larsen, a Norwegian, and his wife Mona Juul, a diplomat at the Norwegian embassy.</p>
<p>&quot;We take pleasure in being used for the benefit of the peace process,&quot; said Godal, who will meet Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussaa on Thursday in Oslo.</p>
<p>Moussa arrives on Wednesday evening for talks with Godal and Prime Minister Gro Harlem Brundtland.</p>
<p>Godal said his Middle East adviser Ambassador Rolf Trolle Andersen found during a visit to Israel and Gaza this summer just after the Israeli election that the new Israeli leaders were very interested in the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;We were positively surprised at the keen interest that representatives of the new Israeli government showed in the nature and psychology of the peace process so far,&quot; he said. &quot;They were not too acquainted with the details, but then they had not been directly involved in the mechanisms and the personalities on the Palestinian side.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
