<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33196" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Paris archbishop slams critics of papal visit.</title>
<headline>Paris archbishop slams critics of papal visit.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Edinger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's most influential cleric, Paris Archbishop Jean-Marie Lustiger, stepped squarely into a controversy on Wednesday over a forthcoming papal visit to France, describing critics as intolerant fanatics.</p>
<p>&quot;The agitation around the Holy Father's visit strikes me as fanatical and intolerant. I am outraged as a Frenchman and as a democrat,&quot; Lustiger told the Foreign Press Association.</p>
<p>&quot;I am also outraged as a Christian but if it is in Christ's name, I am always ready to accept contradiction and persecution,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Pope's September 19-22 visit to France, a close ally of Rome and long seen by traditionalists as the &quot;elder daughter of the Church&quot;, has revived anti-clerical currents stretching back to before the 1789 Revolution.</p>
<p>Local and state authorities have come under fire for using public funds on the visit, mostly to traditonally devout areas of western France, with critics saying the legal separation of church and state was being blurred.</p>
<p>Lustiger accused unnammed leading intellectuals who oppose the visit as engaging in &quot;ideological warfare&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ashamed for my country, which seeks to project itself as a cultural beacon, to hear nonsense being spouted out by people who see themselves as leading lights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He accused both the Right and the Left of rewriting history to satisfy partisan aims and dismissed the efforts as &quot;historical and political nonsense&quot;.</p>
<p>The visit will be the Pope's fifth to France -- more than to any other nation apart from Poland and the United States. The church will pay up to seven million francs ($1.4 million) for religious events while the state will pay for security and provide a fleet of planes and helicopters.</p>
<p>The outspoken Lustiger also accused ultra-leftist groups of having &quot;largely manipulated&quot; African illegal immigrants who sheltered several times in Paris churches this year before being expelled by police.</p>
<p>&quot;The Paris church has been active in helping immigrants in need for decades. We have sheltered other Africans in our parish installations for months without getting involved in the circle of provocation and repression which the leftists want to provoke,&quot; Lustiger said.</p>
<p>He described last month's violent expulsion by police of dozens of Africans from a Paris church as &quot;tragic but inevitably the blame should be laid with the leftists.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
