<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33209" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Engil rises on profit expectations.</title>
<headline>Engil rises on profit expectations.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Portugal's Engil-SGPS rose in heavy volume on expectations that the engineering company will post good half-year results later this month.</p>
<p>By 1225 GMT the stock had risen 10 escudos to 1,380 on volume of 381,600 and was by far the most heavily traded share on the Lisbon bourse. Dealers said buying was mainly domestic but some foreign investors had placed orders.</p>
<p>&quot;The market expects Engil to announce first-half profit of between 600 and 650 million escudos,&quot; said one dealer. He said this would be regarded as a positive result given the slow pace of construction in Portugal in the first half.</p>
<p>&quot;This should allow the company to make a full-year profit of 1.5 billion escudos, in line with its own forecasts, because construction is always more active in the second half,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>In 1995 Engil posted a first-half profit of 586 million escudos.</p>
<p>Dealers said the share price had support at between 1,375 and 1,400 escudos but said it would only get closer to its year high of 1,450 if the half-year results, due around September 15, actually lived up to expectations.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon editorial +(351-1) 353 8254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
