<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33205" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Munich Re sees Amer Re merger hurting 97 earnings.</title>
<headline>Munich Re sees Amer Re merger hurting 97 earnings.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German reinsurance giant Munich Re said on Wednesday its mega-takeover of American Re would pressure its earnings next year but should yield a positive impact on its results from 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;One and one will not make two in this case, but three,&quot; Munich Re management board chairman Hans-Juergen Schinzler told the Boersen Zeitung daily newspaper, referring to his hopes for the merged operations.</p>
<p>Muenchener Rueckversicherungs AG, known as Munich Re, revealed its plans to spend $3.3 billion on third-ranked U.S. non-life reinsurer American Re last month, in a bid to boost its share of the world's biggest insurance market.</p>
<p>Schinzler told the newspaper that the merger would hurt Munich Re's earnings in 1997 but that synergy effects would kick in to improve the group's earnings per share in 1998.</p>
<p>The move would be a &quot;quantum leap&quot; for Munich Re's U.S. business, which has been relatively underdeveloped so far.</p>
<p>The Munich Re chief said he was convinced that American Re had smoothed out longstanding difficulties in its liability cover which helped cause it a net loss of $87.6 million in 1995. He said the U.S. group was expected to post net profit of around $200 million on 1996 business.</p>
<p>Schinzler also said he was confident that the takeover would be completed by year-end. Although he hoped for a 100 percent takeover, a full acquisition was not essential.</p>
<p>Munich Re's $65 per share offer for American Re is backed by the U.S. firm's 64-percent owner, investment firm Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co (KKR).</p>
<p>Schinzler said his strategy for now would be to keep Munich Re's dividend on hold after several years of increasing payouts.</p>
<p>Although full results for its 1995/1996 business year are not yet available, Munich Re has already said its net profit in the period exceeded the previous year's 325 million marks ($219 million) and raised its dividend to 16 marks from 13.50.</p>
<p>Schinzler made no specific forecasts on the impact of the merger on earnings. When the deal was announced, the Bavarian-based giant said American Re would increase its premium income from reinsurance to 22.5 billion marks and its overall income to 37 billion marks.</p>
<p>Schinzler added there were &quot;no viable possibilities&quot; at present for any futher takeovers in the reinsurance industry.</p>
<p>Munich Re's merger with American Re, the latest in a series of shake-outs in the industry, has sparked much talk of more consolidation to come.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.483 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
