<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33208" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FOCUS - Shift to telecoms seen as Olivetti life-belt.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Shift to telecoms seen as Olivetti life-belt.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's troubled Olivetti woke up to life without its chairman Carlo De Benedetti on Wednesday and analysts said its survival rests on moving more rapidly into telephony and away from problem core businesses.</p>
<p>Olivetti announced late on Tuesday that its leader for nearly 20 years was stepping down after a reported clash with new chief executive Francesco Caio. The group also reported a surprising first half loss, deeper debts and slumping sales.</p>
<p>Analysts were busy taking on board the sobering news that the information technology group had made a loss even at the operating level, there were yet more restructuring charges and that trading conditions had taken a turn for the worse.</p>
<p>Olivetti signalled its exit from the personal computer market, but as its other core businesses faltered and its new telephony business continued to absorb cash, analysts fretted over how Olivetti would raise money to keep the company afloat.</p>
<p>&quot;Olivetti is making the right moves, but far too late and far too slowly. I would like to see them out of all their old businesses to focus telephony,&quot; said one industry analyst.</p>
<p>Most analysts were still left puzzling after the brief statement with little detail on the performance of its five separate operating companies and were awaiting a conference call with the company at 1600 GMT.</p>
<p>Olivetti's share price jumped nearly 13 percent in early trade but then subsided to only two percent higher.</p>
<p>Olivetti has put aside 200 billion lire ($132 million) to get out of its PC business, but analysts say it will cost twice that to shut down the operation which employs nearly 2,000 people. They were looking for clarification on whether an actual disposal is planned.</p>
<p>&quot;We are left in the dark, sales have slumped 11 percent, we are seeing operating losses and debt has soared. What are we left to think?&quot; said another industry analyst.</p>
<p>The group reported a first half operating loss of 80.8 billion lire after an operating profit of 114 billion lire in the whole of 1995 -- although then a massive 1.123 trillion lire restructuring charge pushed the group into a 1995 record net loss of 1.589 trillion lire.</p>
<p>Olivetti also reported first half sales slumped 11 percent to 4.224 trillion lire, while debt soared to 1.26 trillion lire at end-June from the 764.8 billion lire level at end-1995.</p>
<p>Analysts said Olivetti should accelerate its exit from its three old core businesses -- PCs, Lexikon, which makes office equipment such as fax machines and printers, and even its core systems and services unit, which is a leader in banking and retail automation systems, to focus on its two new areas.</p>
<p>These are Italy's fast-growing second mobile phone group Omnitel, where Olivetti has a 41.3 percent stake, and Telemedia which includes Olivetti's fixed-line telecoms interests.</p>
<p>Analysts pointed out the problem is that while the three core businesses falter, the two new areas are absorbing cash and making operating losses or just breaking even.</p>
<p>One analyst said with PCs making a small loss in the first half, Omnitel around a 90 billion lire loss and Telemedia just about breaking even, that meant Olivetti's systems and services and Lexikon businesses were probably only making an operating profit of around 25 billion lire in the first half.</p>
<p>But the problems don't end there. If PCs are out of favour and up for sale, who will buy an ailing player in a cut-throat world PC market? Meanwhile, ambitious plans to float 40 percent of Lexikon on the U.S. market seem to have been put on hold.</p>
<p>Even the backbone of the old Olivetti, its systems and services business, is suffering from price competition and profit margins have been trimmed back.</p>
<p>The most optimistic analysts see a small loss for Olivetti in 1996 and many see a lot more red ink.</p>
<p>They are still wary that De Benedetti has not completely severed his links with Olivetti, with his family company CIR still having a stake close to 15 percent, long-standing family lawyer Antonio Tesone taking over the Olivetti chair and one of De Benedetti sons on the board and another still in the company. ($1=1,514 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
