<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33217" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Arafat to hold Vatican talks, meet Jews, in Rome.</title>
<headline>Arafat to hold Vatican talks, meet Jews, in Rome.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat will meet top Vatican officials, Italian leaders and members of Italy's Jewish community during a visit to Rome on Thursday, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Arafat will hold talks with Pope John Paul's two top diplomats, Cardinal Angelo Sodano, Vatican Secretary of State, and Archbishop Jean-Louie Tauran, the Vatican's foreign minister.</p>
<p>One highlight of his 12-hour visit is expected to be a private meeting with Rome community leaders, hosted by mayor Francesco Rutelli at city hall. Rutelli has invited several leading members of Italy's Jewish community to attend.</p>
<p>It is believed to be the first time Arafat will meet members of the Italian Jewish community, which still vividly remembers a 1982 Palestinian guerrilla attack on Rome's synagogue that killed a two year-old boy.</p>
<p>Arafat, who will be stopping in Rome on his way to an international business seminar in northern Italy, will hold talks with Italian President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro, Prime Minister Romano Prodi and Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini.</p>
<p>He has no meeting scheduled with the Pope, whom he has met several times in the past.</p>
<p>Last year Arafat sent a letter to the Pontiff saying he wanted to pray with him in Bethlehem and Jerusalem if the Pope visits the Holy Land.</p>
<p>A main topic at Arafat's talks at the Vatican is expected to be the city of Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The Vatican wants international guarantees protecting Jerusalem as a city sacred to Moslems, Christians and Jews. Israel says the city's holy places are open to all believers.</p>
<p>Israel declared Jerusalem its &quot;united and eternal&quot; capital in 1980, 13 years after its forces captured the city's Arab eastern sector from Jordan in the Six-Day War.</p>
<p>Palestinians view East Jerusalem as the capital of a future state. The city's fate is up for negotiation at final peace talks that have yet to resume under Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Most states, including the Vatican, have not recognised Jerusalem as the Jewish state's capital and keep their embassies elsewhere, mostly in Tel Aviv and its suburbs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
