<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33219" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Markka seen softening vs mark in one month - poll.</title>
<headline>Markka seen softening vs mark in one month - poll.</headline>
<byline>Tuula Franck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The markka is expected to edge down versus the German mark but remain fairly stable against the Swedish crown in the month ahead, according to a Reuters poll.</p>
<p>The range of the DEM/FIM forecasts of 22 dealers, analysts and economists in banks and corporate treasury departments was 2.99-3.06, with 10 participants seeing a level of 3.05 or higher. Only one bank expected the rate to fall to 2.99.</p>
<p>The poll showed an average DEM/FIM rate of 3.04 in early October. It traded just above 3.03 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Also of the 22 polled, eight banks and corporates expected the SEK/FIM rate to stand at 0.68, which was also the mean forecast. SEK/FIM on Wednesday traded at 0.677.</p>
<p>Three months ahead, the DEM/FIM rate was seen trading again at a level of 3.03 on average. Eight participants saw the rate rising to 3.05 or higher, but three large banks and one corporate treasury expected DEM/FIM to fall to 2.98.</p>
<p>The average SEK/FIM forecast in three months was 0.67. Four of the 22 estimated SEK/FIM to rise at least to 0.69.</p>
<p>FORECASTS FOR MARKKA SPOT RATES AFTER ONE MONTH:</p>
<p>			     Mean	Range	  1345/1045 GMT</p>
<p>DEM/FIM		    3.04	2.99-3.06    3.032</p>
<p>SEK/FIM		    0.68	0.67-0.69    0.677</p>
<p>FORECASTS FOR MARKKA SPOT RATES AFTER THREE MONTHS:</p>
<p>			     Mean	Range	  1345/1045 GMT</p>
<p>DEM/FIM		    3.03	2.98-3.08    3.032</p>
<p>SEK/FIM		    0.67	0.66-0.70    0.677 </p>
<p>The quarterly poll was done on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>Forecasts came from Aktia Bank, Bank of America (London), Banque Indosuez (Stockholm), CD Derivatives Ltd, Davy Protos, Den Danske Bank (Copenhagen), Enskilda Banken Helsinki, Enso, Handelsbanken Markets Finland, Huhtamaki Finance, Interbank, IVO, Kemira, Kesko, Merita Bank, Neste, Nokia, OKOBANK, Postipankki, SOK, Unibank (Copenhagen) and UPM-Kymmene.</p>
<p>If you wish to join future polls on markka-related topics, call:</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-0-680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
