<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33211" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Nordic banks adopt softly-softly growth strategy.</title>
<headline>Nordic banks adopt softly-softly growth strategy.</headline>
<byline>Trevor Datson</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The restructuring of the Nordic banking industry has reached an impasse and analysts said on Wednesday organic growth could oust corporate raids as the banks' preferred means of cross-border expansion.</p>
<p>The wave of takeovers and mergers that swept through the Nordic financial markets after a credit crash of the early 1990s has now subsided, leaving the survivors bigger, fitter and hungry for expansion. But where?</p>
<p>Most of the minnows that could be swallowed have been, leaving the bigger fish eyeing each other at a distance.</p>
<p>For example, Sweden's most attractive takover option, Foreningsbanken -- a regional bank, recently rebuffed overtures from Swedbank with the help of its principal owner, farmers' union LRF.</p>
<p>Although Swedbank could have pressed ahead with a takeover bid, its failure to do so highlights what industry analysts call the &quot;jeopardy factor&quot;. Since much of the value of a service company is in the goodwill of its customers, hostile takeovers can erode goodwill are almost inevitably doomed to failure.</p>
<p>Voluntary mergers, such as that between Union Bank of Finland and KOP which created Merita bank in Finland, or the Norwegian UBN's cooperation agreement with five small savings banks are much easier to implement and much more likely to succeed.</p>
<p>Talk in Denmark has been of a merger between second-liners Amagerbanken and Sydbank. In Norway players expect further moves from Fokus Bank and Sparebanken Vest after both took separate 10 percent stakes in Bergens Skillingsbank.</p>
<p>Cross-border ventures are also a theme of market predictions for the future of the industry.</p>
<p>Finland's Merita is tipped to be interested in a tie-up with a Swedish major, but analysts say political reluctance to cede ownership to a foreign player as well as financial conditions rule out such a move.</p>
<p>Even so, few industry sources believe the restructuring of the financial services industry in the region is over, as Swedish Swedbank's recent move into Finland's Aktia Bank shows.</p>
<p>A restructuring of the sector has more or less become a necessity as competition squeezes margins and leading players position themselves for the massive impact on the industry that the third phase of EMU -- currency union -- will bring.</p>
<p>One option is to continue the moves into new areas that began in the early part of the decade as banks began marketing life an pension insurance, and traditional insurers retaliated by setting up niche retail banks.</p>
<p>Danish banks such as Den Danske have pioneered the &quot;financial supermarket&quot; approach, offering one-stop financial service shopping in cooperation with former rivals.</p>
<p>BG Bank has entered into a strategic alliance with insurer Topdanmark and finance company Nykredit, allowing BG to offer a full range of services at post offices and throughout its branch network.</p>
<p>Another softly-softly route to expansion preferred by some Nordic players is to set up representative offices in Nordic capitals and then expand operations into the private market.</p>
<p>This approach, favoured by Sweden's Handelsbanken and Den Danske, could ultimately lead to banks swapping branch offices, banking analyst Keith Baird of Kleinwort Benson said.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the Danes or Norwegians will start buying into Sweden in this way, potentially doing some branch swaps. Logically, it's something that could happen,&quot; he told Reuters, adding that banks have traditionally been too defensive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
