<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33214" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: EU rapeseed losses seen offset by weak demand.</title>
<headline>EU rapeseed losses seen offset by weak demand.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The impact of harvest losses on the European rapeseed market this year will be offset by a lack of demand for vegetable oils, a trader said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Seed crushers were so unhappy with their margins that they were planning plant stoppages, said Bernd Koelln of Deutsche Conti at a seminar organised by grain trade paper Ernaehrungsdienst.</p>
<p>He forecast the 1996/97 EU rapeseed crush at 6.0-6.3 million tonnes compared with 7.8 million in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The EU rapeseed crop this year may fall to 6.9 million tonnes from 8.2 million, the Oil World newsletter said on Tuesday, citing a decline in area and poor weather.</p>
<p>Koelln said cif north European rapeseed oil at $575 was $35-40 too expensive when compared with Latin American sun oil and U.S. soyoil and given the high level of Rotterdam oil stocks.</p>
<p>Rapeseed sellers were asking 465 marks but crushers could operate profitably only if prices were cut by about 25 marks or if product prices rose as a result of a sudden surge in demand.</p>
<p>Koelln said seed crush margins in parts of Europe were just $15 a tonne, compared with crushers' expectations of nearer $40.</p>
<p>But Koelln said EU seed prices may fall under pressure from Canadian canola exports from November onwards.</p>
<p>The EU was also unlikely to export seed to Japan or Mexico as in recent years.</p>
<p>Despite this, farmers were storing rapeseed in the hope of higher prices next year.</p>
<p>He noted that the market could also be affected by higher Asian oilmeal consumption, falling world rapeseed stocks and a depletion of vegetable oil stocks in the U.S. and Latin America.</p>
<p>This in turn would make an impact on European stocks levels.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
