<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33225" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Finnish 10-yr bond yield seen down in 3 mths - poll.</title>
<headline>Finnish 10-yr bond yield seen down in 3 mths - poll.</headline>
<byline>Tuula Franck</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The yield of the 7.25 percent coupon Finnish benchmark bond maturing in 2006 is expected to fall slightly while money market rates would be almost unchanged three months from now, according to a Reuters quarterly poll.</p>
<p>The gap between the ten-year bond yield and Germany's corresponding yield was seen narrowing a few basis points.</p>
<p>The mean of forecasts for the ten-year yield was 7.03 percent. The yield on Wednesday stood at 7.12 percent.</p>
<p>But looking one year ahead, the ten-year yield was expected to rise to 7.20 percent on average.</p>
<p>Eight participants polled expected it to fall below 7.00 percent while three expected a rise above 8.00 percent.</p>
<p>The 10-year gap over Germany was estimated to narrow some ten basis points on average to 63 basis points after a year. Nine banks and corporates saw the spread shrinking to 50 basis points or more.</p>
<p>However, two corporates expected the gap to soar to 125 basis points or more one year from now.</p>
<p>The one-year certificate of deposit (CD) rate was seen at 3.78 percent on average after three months compared to the current 3.80 percent three months from now, but in a year the one-year rate would rise.</p>
<p>The mean of the forecasts a year from now was 4.33 percent. Two banks saw it falling under 4.00 percent by next September, while two participants expected it to jump to 5.00 percent.</p>
<p>In three months, the three-month CD rate was seen nudging down to 3.31 percent on average from 3.36 percent. A year from now, it would have risen to 3.81 percent. </p>
<p>FORECASTS FOR INTEREST RATES AFTER THREE MONTHS:</p>
<p>			   Average   Range	    1200/0900 GMT</p>
<p>3-month rate	   3.31 pct  3.00-3.70 pct  3.36 pct</p>
<p>12-month rate	  3.78 pct  3.50-4.00 pct  3.80 pct</p>
<p>2006-bond yield	7.03 pct  6.50-7.50 pct  7.12 pct</p>
<p>Spread over Germany  67 bps    40-100 bps     74 bps </p>
<p>FORECASTS FOR INTEREST RATES AFTER 12 MONTHS:</p>
<p>			   Average   Range	    1200/0900 GMT</p>
<p>3-month rate	   3.81 pct  3.00-4.65 pct  3.36 pct</p>
<p>12-month rate	  4.33 pct  3.30-5.00 pct  3.80 pct</p>
<p>2006-bond yield	7.20 pct  6.40-8.25 pct  7.12 pct</p>
<p>Spread over Germany  63 bps    20-125 bps     74 bps</p>
<p>The quarterly interest rate poll was conducted on Monday and Tuesday this week. </p>
<p>Forecasts by Aktia Bank, Bank of America (London), Banque Indosuez (Stockholm), CD Derivatives Ltd, Davy Protos, Den Danske Bank (Copenhagen), Enskilda Banken Helsinki, Enso, Handelsbanken Markets Finland, Huhtamaki Finance, Interbank, IVO, Kemira, Kesko, Merita Bank, Neste, Nokia, OKOBANK, Postipankki, SOK, Unibank (Copenhagen) and UPM-Kymmene.</p>
<p>If you want to join future polls on markka-related topics, call:</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358-0-680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
