<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33224" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Wednesday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Wednesday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Wednesday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas confirmed that Stuart Eizenstat, U.S. under-Secretary for Trade and U.S. President Bill Clinton's special envoy on the Helms-Burton trade restrictions, would meet with Commissioners Manuel Marin and Emma Bonino. Spokesmen would be available to brief on the meetings from 1515/1315 GMT, he said.</p>
<p>On the weekly Commission meeting, van der Pas said it had started with a tribute to Emile Noel, former Secretary General of the Commission, who died in August.</p>
<p>Van der Pas said Commission President Jacques Santer expressed some concern on the progress of the intergovernmental conference. No concrete decision has been taken since the latest European Council and the proposals put forward did not go in the direction wished by the Commission, said van der Pas. He used the example of article 113 (trade policy) on which no decision has been taken to extend it to the service sector. Van der Pas said the Commission would hold a special meeting on the IGC in the coming weeks.</p>
<p>He also said the Commission would not change its position on the Helms-Burton Cuban trade restrictions after the meeting between Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and Stuart Eizenstat.</p>
<p>There would be no further briefing for the press on Wednesday, he added.</p>
<p>Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert gave a news conference from 1215/1015 GMT to announce the Commission's decision on the Volkswagen dispute.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Agriculture, forestry and fisheries, 1996-8, Trends in the EU agricultural price indices in 1995.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Agriculture, forestry and fisheries, 1996-9: Slight drop in numbers compared with April 1995. Slight decrease in production forecast for the next few months.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Agriculture, forestry and fisheries, 1996-10: Trends in the EU agricultural price indices in the first quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Consumer price index, 1996-7: prices: EU annual inflation fell to 2.5% in June 1996.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: External Trade, 1996-7: European Union trade with central and eastern Europe countries, results for 1995.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Energy and Industry, 1996-24: Extract from &quot;Industrial Trends - July 1996&quot;.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Energy and Industry, 1996-25: Opinion of European enterprises on the impact of the single market programme.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Energy and Industry, 1996-26: Inland deliveries of petroleum products in 1995.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Statistics in focus: Energy and Industry, 1996-27: Industry statistics.</p>
<p>- Eurostat: Distributive trade, services and transport, 1996-6/7.</p>
<p>- Oil Bulletin No 834.</p>
<p>- European Economy, reports and studies, The CAP and enlargement, No 2, 1996.</p>
<p>- XXVth Report on Competition Policy, 1995.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/204: Opening address at the temporary committee of inquiry into BSE of the European Parliament by Franz Fischler, European Commissioner for Agriculture and Rural Development.</p>
<p>- ME96/4.9: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
