<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33239" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French women's fashion industry back in the red.</title>
<headline>French women's fashion industry back in the red.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French women's clothes industry recorded its second-ever trade deficit in the 12 months to April 1996, industry figures showed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The only other time France imported more women's clothing than it exported was in the 1993-1994 period.</p>
<p>The deficit was largely because of Europe's sluggish economy and the strength of the franc, said Gerard Roudine, president of the French Federation of Women's Ready-to-Wear.</p>
<p>&quot;Internal economic problems in the countries of Europe seems to be the principal factor, along with the strong franc which leads to the loss of certain markets or, at least a modification in sales,&quot; Roudine said.</p>
<p>French exports of clothing were down three percent to 10.3 billion french francs ($2.03 billion) in the 12 months to April. Imports for the same period climbed 8.6 percent to 11.4 billion francs, yielding a deficit of 1.1 billion francs.</p>
<p>This comes after a 124 million franc surplus for the for 1994 to 1995 period.</p>
<p>Exports to EU countries, which account for nearly 50 percent of industry sales, slipped 7.1 percent.</p>
<p>The biggest surprise came from southeast Asia, with an 8.6 percent increase, the only region where imports of French apparel were on the rise.</p>
<p>It was largely due to a 25 percent rise in purchases by Japan, which accounts for well over half of the area's imports of French clothing and has emerged as the industry's largest single customer.</p>
<p>&quot;In a world of economic warfare, Japan has become our first customer, surpassing the Benelux countries and Germany,&quot; Roudine said.</p>
<p>South Korea, also a boom client, saw its imports of French women's clothing soar 31 percent.</p>
<p>Roudine said the United States, where French apparel purchases were up only 1.8 percent, gave a &quot;disappointing performance given the vigour of its recovery&quot;.</p>
<p>Roudine noted a growing trend among French companies towards setting up operations outside the country in order to jump tarif barriers and cut labour costs.</p>
<p>&quot;On basic everyday wear, moving operations can mean survival for a company. But it has also become a strategy for entering new markets where previously it was impossible to export directly from France,&quot; said Roudine, citing China and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Imports from France's 10 main outside suppliers climbed generously, except those from Germany, which tumbled 17.6 percent. Imports from Morocco and Tunisia, France's two top suppliers, rose 17 and 24 percent respectively. ($1=5.087 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
