<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33244" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Die Erste urges common stance on Creditanstalt bid.</title>
<headline>Die Erste urges common stance on Creditanstalt bid.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria's Die Erste on Wednesday indicated it may leave an Austro-Italian consortium of bidders for privatisation candidate Creditanstalt in its present form unless the group agreed on a common stance by Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to continue being part of the consortium, but there are several other possible variations,&quot; a spokeswoman for the savings bank told Reuters.</p>
<p>The consortium, which includes insurer EA-Generali, Germany's Commerzbank and Banca Commerciale Italiana, is deeply split over Die Erste's proposal to set up a joint holding company with Creditanstalt.</p>
<p>The plan would give Die Erste, which is barely a third of the size of Creditanstalt, majority control of the holding.</p>
<p>Commerzbank reportedly has threatened to leave the consortium unless Die Erste backs down. Nobody at Commerzbank was immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Austria's government on Tuesday turned up the heat on the consortium, saying their time was up unless the group came up with a final offer by midnight Friday, one week after the original deadline expired.</p>
<p>&quot;This deadline is significantly more serious than last week's,&quot; Die Erste's spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima said he would reopen the bidding process and invite offers from other interested parties if the consortium failed to comply with the deadline.</p>
<p>The group so far is the only known bidder for the government's 70 percent stake in Creditanstalt, which has been on the privatisation list for more than six years now. -- Vienna newsroom +431 53112 274</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
