<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33246" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Dresdner bond offer could cut its Munich Re stake.</title>
<headline>Dresdner bond offer could cut its Munich Re stake.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dresdner Bank AG's launch on Wednesday of a five-year bond exchangeable into shares in Munich Re could reduce its 11.9 percent stake in the giant reinsurance company.</p>
<p>However the bank said in a statement that it wished to remain a &quot;significant shareholder&quot; in Munich Re.</p>
<p>The bank is offering a five year 500 million mark ($337 million) bond which may be exchanged into Munich Re shares at an indicated premium of 15 percent. The exchange would reduce its stake in the reinsurer but the conditions of issue also allow Dresdner to pay out the equivalent of the Munich Re share value in cash.</p>
<p>Dresdner said: &quot;Dresdner Bank wants to further optimise its shareholding portfolio with the issue of this exchangeable bond. It will also remain a significant shareholder in Muenchener Rueckversicherungs AG (Munich Re).&quot;</p>
<p>Responding to a Reuters enquiry, a Dresdner spokesman said the bank would retain enough shares in Munich to be able to continue to use a tax privilege available on holdings of the first 10 percent in other companies, implying that Dresdner's stake will not fall far below the 10 percent level.</p>
<p>The bank's Dresdner Finance NV unit announced the launch of the bond on Wednesday morning. Dresdner Kleinwort Benson, Frankfurt, will act as lead manager.</p>
<p>The bond will carry a coupon of two to 2.5 percent, Dresdner said. Conditions are to be finalised on September 5.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.483 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
