<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33249" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares stage mild rebound, close with gains.</title>
<headline>Greek shares stage mild rebound, close with gains.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities paused a three-day correction to close with mild gains led by construction in moderate turnover. Brokers said nervous range trading would continue leading up to elections on September 22.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's rebound was led by construction shares as investors expect a new strong government will push ahead with slow-moving infrastructure projects. There is bound to be nervous trading until the elections,&quot; said broker Yannis Kalogerakis at ABN AMRO Axias Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the market has not been affected by the U.S. raids on Iraq and has brushed off fears of higher oil prices. Stocks will hold the 915-950 range until September 22,&quot;he said.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index closed 0.37 percent, or 3.47 points higher at 934.31 from Tuesday's 930.84 close after opening at 930.94 points. Turnover slipped to 6.72 billion drachmas on volume of 4.2 million shares.</p>
<p>Bankers and economists forecast August inflation would ease to 8.5 percent year-on-year from 8.6 percent in July, they told Reuters in an informal poll.</p>
<p>Greece will hold early elections September 22.</p>
<p>Other brokers said the correction had bottomed out around 930 points and the market's uptrend remained intact. Players got jittery on Monday on talk that the gap between the competing socialist Pasok and conservative New Democracy parties seemed to be closing.</p>
<p>Gainers led losers 117 to 89 with 26 issues unchanged on 232 traded. Banks closed flat, up 0.02 percent, industrials firmed 0.38 percent with construction climbing 1.61 percent. Small-caps closed 0.76 percent higher.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 560-578 at the close. Shares of OTE telecom  OTEr.AT, the underlying, ended up 35 drachmas at 4,035 in moderate trade.</p>
<p>The recently launched Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares was quoted higher at 203.50-214.20 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It was in the money at 1025.5.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted at 3,588-3,816 drachmas at the close. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
