<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33255" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: OSCE declines to set new date for Bosnian polls.</title>
<headline>OSCE declines to set new date for Bosnian polls.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-09-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The man charged with organising Bosnia's post-war elections declined to be drawn on Tuesday over when cancelled municipal polls may be allowed to go ahead.</p>
<p>Robert Frowick, head of an Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) team which is organising the Bosnia elections under a UN mandate, said he could not say whether it would be a question of weeks or months.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not have a timeframe,&quot; he told reporters after briefing NATO's 16 ambassadors on the current situation in Bosnia.</p>
<p>Frowick cancelled the municipal polls two weeks ago due to vote-rigging tactics by Bosnian Serbs, but elections for regional and national assemblies and presidencies are still slated for September 14.</p>
<p>Under the Dayton peace accords, the elections have to go ahead to put unified democratic institutions in place and underpin the accords and allow NATO nations to withdraw their 60,000-strong peace mission as scheduled by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana said the alliance's peace force IFOR would retain sufficient strength to help with the organising of any polls, municipal or otherwise, until the end of the year.</p>
<p>He said that if the polls had not been held by then, the position would have to be reconsidered.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement is to maintain enough forces on the ground until the very end of the year, until the end of the mission. If municipal elections are postponed beyond that period of time, then that will be the moment to reconsider the decision,&quot; Solana said.</p>
<p>NATO sources stressed that did not mean an extension of the current one-year mandate would be necessary. Under current withdrawal plans, it could take more than three months for the troops in place to be brought out.</p>
<p>Frowick admitted again the polls would be flawed, but said they would be &quot;reasonably democratic...Balkan-style&quot;. He said the country was at peace and no hostage-taking was occurring.</p>
<p>Human rights groups say the poll will only give a thin veneer of democratic legitimacy to ethnic conquests won in battle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
