<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33251" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Alitalia ups Italy-Korea freight capacity.</title>
<headline>Alitalia ups Italy-Korea freight capacity.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alitalia said it will double capacity to Korea with the launch of two additional Milan-Seoul all-freight flights on September 12.</p>
<p>Alitalia cargo manager Germany, Dirk Steiger, told Reuters in an interview the Italian airline will fly three times weekly non-stop from Milan Malpensa to Seoul in a joint venture with Korean Air Lines.</p>
<p>&quot;The market to Korea is booming. This is primarily Italian market demand for Korea but also export from other European countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The new flights will effectively double capacity to Korea,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The flights, using McDonnell Douglas MD-11F aircraft, will be on Thursdays, Saturdays and Sundays and will replace the currently weekly Boeing 747F flight.</p>
<p>A second weekly joint Alitalia-Korean B747F flight using a Korean aircraft had to be dropped in the summer due to a shortage of Korean equipment, he pointed out.</p>
<p>Space on the freighters is likely to be marketed 50:50 by the two airlines but no decision has yet been made on how much will be made available to each European market, Steiger added.</p>
<p>Rates in Italy for the Far East are at a healthy level due to continuing high demand, he noted. - Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
