<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33269" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kinkel pledges German help to link Russia and West.</title>
<headline>Kinkel pledges German help to link Russia and West.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel, in a newspaper article published on Wednesday, pledged to help bring Russia closer to the West and said he was confident Moscow would take up an offer of cooperation with NATO.</p>
<p>Kinkel, writing in the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung newspaper, said the West still faced uncertainties in dealing with Russia, concerning the stability of its democracy and the health of President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>Kinkel was scheduled to meet Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov on Wednesday hoping to launch moves to draw up a charter formalising Russia's relationship with NATO before the Western alliance admits new members from eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Russia opposes any extension of NATO to include its former communist allies. But it has signalled it might accept the admission of Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic under certain conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;The time has come for NATO and Russia to start an intensive dialogue which should take up Russian suggestions on practical cooperation,&quot; Kinkel wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident Russia will take up NATO's offer of comprehensive cooperation... We want to include Russia, not exclude it.&quot;</p>
<p>Kinkel said Russia should be helped to appreciate the potential of cooperating with the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;If the reform process is continued, as I have no doubt it will be, we will try to bring Russia closer to international financial and economic institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia must become a member of the World Trade Organisation and be included in the discussions of the Group of Seven as soon as possible,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>But Kinkel said Russia's transformation was not complete.</p>
<p>Questions remained on how the constitutional organs would work together, whether stable, democratic parties would become established, and whether social welfare would improve.</p>
<p>&quot;President Yeltsin ran a committed election campaign,&quot; Kinkel added. &quot;How is he? The public in Russia and abroad are wondering. I personally hope he feels healthy enough to meet the challenges which his office now presents.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
