<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33271" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch cocoa trade opposes ICCO reserve fund.</title>
<headline>Dutch cocoa trade opposes ICCO reserve fund.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Dutch cocoa trade is opposed to setting up a buffer stock reserve fund to finance the International Cocoa Organization (ICCO) administrative budget.</p>
<p>A discussion on how to continue financing the organisation -- which has a budget of around 2.7 million stg -- will be one of the key issues at week-long ICCO talks next week in London.</p>
<p>Buffer stock sales make up around 40 percent of revenues but are due to run out in April 1998, prompting the funding debate. Earlier this year the ICCO suggested setting up a reserve fund, from which the interest would used to meet day-to-day expenses.</p>
<p>But Dutch trade sources, who do not reflect the official government position, said buffer stock money should not be used in this way and ought to be returned to individual members.</p>
<p>&quot;We regard this money as belonging to the trade and as such should be given back to members,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>Other options facing the ICCO are pruning expenditure or raising members' contributions. The Dutch trade favours the former.</p>
<p>&quot;The ICCO should cut back on what it spends and focus on what it was set up to do,&quot; the source added.</p>
<p>The Dutch government has not made its position on funding known but regards the proceeds of the buffer stock sales as government money, putting it at loggerheads with the trade.</p>
<p>The financing committee of the ICCO is meeting this week in preliminary talks to sort out details of financing proposals and sources said the most likely outcome of the discussions next week is some sort of compromise between the three options.</p>
<p>&quot;Importing countries are not willing to accept a substantial increase in subscriptions but maybe in tandem with economies made by the secretariat, it will be more acceptable,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Another idea behind the reserve fund is that it could also serve as a liquidation fund, cushioning the blow should the ICCO ever be wound up.</p>
<p>It is not planned that all buffer stock money be used to set up the fund but only a small proportion of it, with the rest distributed to members as already agreed. --David Evans, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
