<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33273" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: First Russia Yamal gas to flow in October - Wingas.</title>
<headline>First Russia Yamal gas to flow in October - Wingas.</headline>
<byline>Sebastian Alison</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The first gas from the Russian-German Yamal Europe gas project will flow in October, the project's operator said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gert Maichel, managing director of Wingas, a joint venture between Wintershall of Germany and Russia's Gazprom, said a connection with the existing Polish gas grid will allow the first Yamal Europe gas to be handed over to customers in Mallnow, Germany next month.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking about weeks, not months,&quot; Maichel told the International Energy Agency's third natural gas conference in Berlin, &quot;and it is on course for completion next month.&quot;</p>
<p>The Yamal Europe project consists of the development of three fields in northern Russia's remote Yamal peninsula -- Bovanenko, Kharasavey and Kruzenshtern -- and the creation of a transport route from the fields to Germany.</p>
<p>The Yamal peninsula has recoverable rserves of 10,400 billion cubic metres (bcm), around 20 percent of Russia's total proven reserves of 49,000 bcm. And the three fields in the Yamal Europe project alone contain 65 percent of Yamal's reserves.</p>
<p>The project's concept is to build the pipeline from the customer to the source. Wingas and EuRoPol GAZ, a joint venture between the Polish Oil and Gas Company, Wintershall and Gazprom, completed the crossing of the river Oder with two 56-inch pipelines in October last year.</p>
<p>EuRoPol GAZ is also well on the way to completing the first 107 km of line from the Oder into Poland, said Maichel. It is from this line that a connection to the Polish grid will be completed next month, he added.</p>
<p>Wingas has also started construction of the JAGAL pipeline taking gas from the Oder south, and the WEDAL line leading towards the Ruhr.</p>
<p>Elsewhere construction work has started in Belarus on the section transitting that country, Maichel said. And Gazprom is working on the link between the Russia/Belarus border and the pumping station at Torzhok, near Moscow.</p>
<p>On the Yamal peninsula itself, construction of a new railway and field works are in progress, Maichel said.</p>
<p>On completion, the pipeline from Yamal to Frankfurt-on-Oder will span 4,107 km, including 2,867 km in Russia, 575 km in Belarus and 665 km in Poland.</p>
<p>The plan is to deliver 52 bcm a year at Frankfurt-on-Oder, with a further 14 bcm for consumption in Poland, seven bcm in Belarus and 10 bcm used as fuel for compressors. So total output at Yamal will be 83 bcm per year.</p>
<p>&quot;The European gas market is growing,&quot; said Maichel. &quot;New big gas resources have to be developed and connected to the European gas grid. Yamal is the number one on the list in this respect.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the original idea to build the pipelines from the customer to the source was still valid and &quot;due to temporary overcapacity in Russia, the project is more viable than ever before.&quot;</p>
<p>This overcapacity means that Russian gas can be sent through the parts of the network already built long before the link to Yamal itself is complete.</p>
<p>Maichel declined to estimate a date by which the project would be completed.</p>
<p>But analyst Stephen O'Sullivan of MC Securities in London said it was unlikely to be finished before 2010. &quot;It depends crucially on how European and Russian gas demand changes over the next 10 years or so,&quot; he said, adding that there will be other competing suppliers, especially from Algeria and Norway.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
