<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33287" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French '97 tax cuts at least 20 bln francs - minister.</title>
<headline>French '97 tax cuts at least 20 bln francs - minister.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French government spokesman and junior budget minister Alain Lamassoure said on Wednesday that taxes would be cut by at least 20 billion francs in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The order of tax cuts for 1997 will be at least 20 billion francs,&quot; Lamassoure told Europe 1 radio.</p>
<p>He declined, however, to comment on newspaper reports of a proposed 25 billion franc income tax cut next year.</p>
<p>The government is scheduled to present the 1997 budget to the cabinet on September 18. Prime Minister Alain Juppe has said he will present the broad outlines of his budget and tax reform plans around September 10.</p>
<p>The newspaper Les Echos reported on Wednesday the government was planning income tax cuts totalling around 75 billion francs over five years and aimed to lower the top rate to below 50 percent from 56.8 percent.</p>
<p>Lamassoure said there would probably be an increase in the tax on tobacco next year.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very likely there will be a rise on tobacco,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The tax reduction will focus mainly on income tax with a key objective being to simplify this system...and reduce taxes for workers and families,&quot; Lamassoure said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal is to lower income tax rates over a period of five years beginning in 1997,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The government is due to present the budget officially to the cabinet on September 18, though Juppe is due to give the broad outlines of the government's plans before that.</p>
<p>It has pledged to cut income tax rates over the next five years and reform taxation to encourage a shift in savings into longer term investment and stocks.</p>
<p>In the 1997 budget it aims to cut both spending and taxes as part of its plans to reduce the total public deficit to three percent of gross domestic product next year in preparation for European monetary union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
