<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33284" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: INTERVIEW-CRH says Tilcon buy &quot;exceptional value&quot;.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-CRH says Tilcon buy &quot;exceptional value&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish-based building materials group CRH Plc said on Wednesday its acquisition of BTR's U.S. unit Tilcon for $329 million represented exceptional value and created significant synergies with its own U.S. operations.</p>
<p>CRH chief executive Don Godson said that despite the purchase of Tilcon CRH's active acquisitions policy would continue unabated, helped by a placing of 17.94 million shares to raise 101 million punts.</p>
<p>&quot;With this acquisition we have exceptional value, superb quarries and a most amazing fit with our present operations with pretty unique synergies,&quot; Godson told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Godson said the acquisition would be immediately earnings-enhancing.</p>
<p>He said CRH had no plans for a rights issue as its share placing had provided enough funds for its acquisitions strategy. Dealers said market talk of a possible rights issue had been holding back the CRH share price in recent weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;We could, and indeed did, fund the Tilcon acquisition from our own debt facilities,&quot; Godson said. &quot;But we did not want to forego other opportunities that we see in Europe, in developing regions and indeed in the U.S. The placing gives us the firepower to avail of other opportunities.&quot;  </p>
<p>The placing also &quot;took a bit of doubt out of the marketplace about an overhang,&quot; Godson said.</p>
<p>He said CRH's ratio of debt to shareholders funds would be around 40 percent at the year-end, compared with 40.3 percent at end-June 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't do any acquisitions the ratio would be below 20 percent at the end of 1997, but of course we hope to be on our bike doing what we do best, which is pulling in mid-size acquisitions from our 12 development teams around the world.&quot;</p>
<p>CRH announced the acquisition at the same time as reporting its half-year results.  </p>
<p>Pre-tax profits for the first half of 1996 were up 13 percent at 64.1 million punts, driven by good growth in Ireland and the U.S., CRH said. Britain and mainland Europe suffered a decline in underlying profits.</p>
<p>Bad weather at the start of the year in Europe and the U.S. had hit profits, CRH said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are quite pleased with 13 percent pre-tax profit growth, given the deep freeze month in northern europe and the eastern U.S., and a fairly sluggish UK market,&quot; Godson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had good perormances out of Ireland and the U.S. and Europe perfomed pretty well overall despite some setbacks.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said CRH was positive about the overall full-year outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;Europe is fighting back in the second half although there is still a fair bit of ground to make up. America has been very strong for us despite the cold start and we see that going forward throughout the year.&quot;</p>
<p>CRH had been eyeing Tilcon for several years, Godson said. BTR said its sale of Tilcon was part of a strategy of repositioning its portfolio of businesses.  </p>
<p>&quot;We had quite a motivated seller working to a different agenda, and we were a dispassionate and patient negotiator. We got excellent value,&quot; Godson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will now be working together with a good management team to weld together our operations in the northeastern U.S. and give us an unassailable position.&quot;</p>
<p>--Andrew Marshall, Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I48100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
