<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33294" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australian Broadcasting Corp Midday Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>MANSFIELD REVIEW FLOODED</p>
<p>More than ten thousand submissions have been received for the review of the ABC, being headed by Bob Mansfield.</p>
<p>Last's Friday's deadline was extended, after people weren't able to get through on the fax machine.</p>
<p>A spokesman says any letter or fax that reaches the review office by the close of business on Friday will be accepted.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NSW REBUTTAL OF FAST TRAIN DELAY CLAIMS</p>
<p>The New South Wales government has flick-passed the blame for delays in the development of the high speed rail link between Sydney and Canberra back to the Federal and ACT governments.</p>
<p>Federal Transport Minister, John Sharp, yesterday accused the New South Wales government of stalling the link, meaning it won't be in place for the Sydney 2000 Olympics.</p>
<p>But Mr Sharp's New South Wales counterpart, Brian Langton, says his government was the first to commit funds to the link's feasibility study.</p>
<p>And Mr Langton says the ACT government deferred the steering committee in mid-May, then reported in June that its officials hadn't been able to complete tasks they'd been allotted.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>KENNETT: ACTU LEADERSHIP TERMINAL</p>
<p>Victoria's Premier, Jeff Kennett, says the ACTU is in danger of self-destructing.</p>
<p>Mr Kennett's told a Melbourne business breakfast the ACTU leadership should have accepted responsibility for the Canberra Parliament House riots.</p>
<p>The Premier says, by refusing to do so, President Jennie George and Secretary Bill Kelty have ensured their leadership is terminal.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>OFFICIAL INTEREST RATES UNCHANGED</p>
<p>The final meeting of the Reserve Bank board with Bernie Fraser as chairman has taken no action on monetary policy, despite speculation official interest rates would be cut.</p>
<p>Predictions the central bank would cut official rates at its monthly board meeting yesterday were hosed down with the release of figures showing a strong increase in retail spending in July.</p>
<p>Citibank's Stephen Koukoulas says he wasn't surprised this morning's deadline for a monetary policy announcement passed without a word from the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NETWORK TO COMBAT GRAFFITI TIPPIED</p>
<p>The first national conference on the control of graffiti has been told action to combat graffiti vandalism has until now happened at a state level, with little sharing of information and ideas.</p>
<p>West Australian Premier, Richard Court, told the Perth conference he's confident it will result in a national network to target graffiti.</p>
<p>Mr Court says W-A is acknowledged as a leader in developing strategies to reduce the level of graffiti, which has fallen by 50 per cent in the state since 1993.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
