<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33290" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASEAN forum agrees on need to police the Net.</title>
<headline>ASEAN forum agrees on need to police the Net.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southeast Asian broadcasters and officials agreed on Wednesday to police the Internet and block off sites that run counter to Asian values.</p>
<p>A statement issued at the close of the three-day Internet forum in Singapore also said there was a need for nations in the West to understand concerns about the Internet in the region.</p>
<p>It said the meeting &quot;affirmed the importance of having safeguards against easy access to sites which ran counter to our cherished values, traditions and culture. ASEAN would encourage other nations, especially the West to understand its concern.&quot;</p>
<p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) groups Brunei, Malaysia, Singapore, Indonesia, the Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, ASEAN information ministers met in Singapore to discuss the darker side of the information technology revolution and agreed to set up a regulatory body to oversee the Internet invasion.</p>
<p>They said their chief concerns were smut in cyberspace and information on the Net that could spark religious and racial tensions in their countries.</p>
<p>At the close of the day forum on Wednesday, the officials agreed that government and industry regulation were important, but parental supervision also played a key role in muzzling the net, the statement said.</p>
<p>But the statement suggested there was no agreement on a uniform approach to policing the Internet.</p>
<p>The ASEAN officials had agreed that regulatory frameworks would depend on each country, and said they would continue to meet regularly &quot;to help each country formulate and fine tune its regulatory approaches,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Policing of the Net in ASEAN varies from Singapore's stance of strict controls by licensing only three Internet service providers who have to screen all material accessed by clients.</p>
<p>Other ASEAN members encourage more self-regulation, and the Philippines says freedom of speech is a critical factor.</p>
<p>&quot;Political control would not be on the Philippines' agenda,&quot; Glenn Sipin, deputy executive director of the Philippines Council for Advanced Science and Technology, told Reuters at the start of the conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
