<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33297" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ share market ends stronger on hefty volume.</title>
<headline>NZ share market ends stronger on hefty volume.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>* NZ share rises on good demand, encouraged by Wall Street</p>
<p>* Telecom strong, and market picked to stay firm</p>
<p>* Sky City rises after well received result  </p>
<p>The New Zealand share market closed stronger on hefty volume on Wednesday and brokers said it was in good shapre for a further rise.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a good solid day,&quot; said Hendry Hay McIntosh broker Tim Koller, adding that expects demand to continue on Thursday.</p>
<p>The strong finish on Wall Street and the U.S. resumption from the long weekend encouraged demand in the leaders, particularly Telecom and the Fletcher stocks.</p>
<p>The top 40 index closed 14.65 ahead at 2,237.73 on volume of $71 million.  </p>
<p>Telecom closed five up at $6.98 and earlier was bid up to $7.00, while Fletcher Paper was up three at $2.82.</p>
<p>There was heavy turnover in Fletcher Building which ended seven cents stronger at $3.32.</p>
<p>Brierley Investments was steady on $1.43 a day ahead of its result which is generally expected to be a $320 million net profit for the year.</p>
<p>Several of the second line stocks peformed strongly.  </p>
<p>Sky City gained 19 cents to $7.11 a day after its result, which was in line with forecasts. Brokers said the company appeared to have taken some one-off costs while profits from its casino slot machines were forecast to do well.</p>
<p>Energy Direct was also up 19 to to $3.19, possibly the beneficiary of a decision by national grid operator Trans Power to charge South Island generators the costs of power transmission across the Cook Strait.</p>
<p>Fisher &amp; Paykel was another middle stock to run well, ending 15 cents up at $5.00.</p>
<p>-- Simon Louisson 64 4 4714 276</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
