<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33291" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Joyce becomes Hugo Boss sole HK retailer.</title>
<headline>Joyce becomes Hugo Boss sole HK retailer.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong fashion retailer Joyce Boutique Holdings Ltd has become German menswear company Hugo Boss AG's exclusive retailer in the territory from August, the two firms said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lane Crawford International Ltd, controlled by Wheelock and Co Ltd, had been the German group's exclusive local retailer for about a decade before the new partnership.</p>
<p>&quot;No other operation in Hong Kong can possibly compete with Joyce and we look forward to a long and successful partnership with them,&quot; Hugo Boss president and chief executive Peter Littmann told a news conference.</p>
<p>The firm had decided to make Hong Kong its headquarters for Asia excluding Japan, he added.</p>
<p>Under the latest agreement, Joyce would be responsible for investment in new Hugo Boss shops and share some advertising costs, Joyce managing director Roberto Dominici said.</p>
<p>With the Hugo Boss sales, menswear was expected to account for 41 to 42 percent of Joyce's sales in Hong Kong in 1997 and 1998, compared with 35 percent at present, he said.</p>
<p>Joyce founder and chief executive Joyce Ma added: &quot;Joyce is marking the (menswear) category for strong growth during the next several years and expects its Hugo Boss retail operations to make a very substantial contribution to that growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Dominici said sales at a Hugo Boss shop opened last month had beaten the target by 40 percent.</p>
<p>The officials gave no further figures.</p>
<p>Another Joyce store is also selling Hugo Boss labels. A new Hugo Boss outlet is planned to be opened this month.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
