<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33293" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Broadcasting Corp Afternoon Update.</headline>
<text>
<p>BLOUNT OUTLINES TELSTRA BLUEPRINT</p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer of Telstra, Frank Blount, says while the partial privatisation of Telstra is desirable, the communications giant will have to improve to make it work.</p>
<p>Mr Blount says Telstra will have to become world class in its operations to guarantee its future.</p>
<p>Mr Blount has outlined his blue-print for Telstra's future at a luncheon in Sydney.</p>
<p>He said while Telstra was branching out into other areas such as Pay-TV, it would never walk away from its core business -- telephony.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>GOVT SENATE LEADER WON'T COMMIT TO COLSTON</p>
<p>Government Senate leader, Robert Hill, won't say if the Government will agree to independent Senator, Mal Colston's conditions over the part sale of Telstra.</p>
<p>Senator Colston's vote is crucial to determining whether the Government will be able to sell a third of Telstra.</p>
<p>Senator Colston is refusing to say if he'll support the partial sale, but wants the Government to ensure that Telstra doesn't shed jobs in regional Queensland if the sales goes through.</p>
<p>Senator Hill says the Government will keep some power over Telstra when it's partially privatised.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>LABOR SUPPORTS U.S. ACTION</p>
<p>Labor's Foreign Affairs Spokesman, Laurie Brereton, says the United States military action against Iraq is completely understandable.</p>
<p>Mr Brereton says Saddam Hussein's record of appalling atrocities against the Kurdish people is a matter of international notoriety.</p>
<p>He says every effort must be taken to ensure that civilians don't pay the price for Sadam Hussein's actions and the U-S strikes appear to have been designed to minimise civilian casualties.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>AUSTRALIAN DEMOCRATS WANT U.S. TO CONSULT</p>
<p>The Australian Democrats want the Federal Government to urge the U.S. to consult other members of the United Nations Security Council before taking further military action.</p>
<p>Foreign Affairs spokesperson, Vicki Bourne, says while she understands the difficulty of coordinating international action, any military activity in a UN safe haven should be carried out by the international community as a whole.</p>
<p>Senator Bourne says unilateral action by the U.S. gives Saddam Hussein another excuse to demonise the United States as the enemy.</p>
<p>She says Australia should consult with other nations about establishing an international Autonomy Commission, to examine how human rights can be ensured for ethnic minorities, such as the Kurds.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>YOUTH LESS IMPORTANT THAN DEFICIT -- CONFERENCE</p>
<p>A youth conference in Brisbane has heard the Federal Government regards the Budget deficit as more important than the lives of Australia's young people.</p>
<p>The Queensland Youth Affairs Conference has met to discuss the problems and challenges young people are facing in the lead up to the 21st century.</p>
<p>Youth Affairs Network of Queensland Spokeswoman, Jenny Gilmore, says young people are often excluded from making decisions affecting them.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>GARRY ABLETT FACES DRIVING CHARGES</p>
<p>Police have confirmed that Geelong footballer Gary Ablett will face charges of speeding and driving while his license was suspended.</p>
<p>The incident occurred early in June this year, when Ablett was pulled over for travelling at 90 kilometres an hour in a 60 zone.</p>
<p>However, the champion goalkicker was ineligible to drive at the time after having his license suspended for accumulating too many demerit points.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
