<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33296" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ bond yields end higher, investors sidelined.</title>
<headline>NZ bond yields end higher, investors sidelined.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>* 11/06 bond yields 8.45 vs 8.38 pct</p>
<p>* Sept bill futures 90.04, vs 90.07. Volume 1,122  </p>
<p>New Zealand government bond yields ended higher on Wednesday after a light session as investors took to the sidelines following a second missile attack by the United States on Iraq.</p>
<p>The upcoming October 12 election was another reason to do nothing.</p>
<p>Some stock returned to the market on Tuesday night and there was one seller in the long end this afternoon, according to one Wellington bond dealer.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think people are convinced yet that we are at the top of the market (in yield) given the Iraqi situation and with the election cmoing up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Which means the institutional end holders are probably sitting in the wings to a certain extent, just waiting to see where things will pan out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the short end of the curve was not so badly off, supported in part by the steady stream of swap, Euro and Samurai activity.</p>
<p>A close watching brief was being kept on U.S. markets.  </p>
<p>Further out, the market turning was turning its attention to next week's fiscal update and the Reserve Bank's economic projections.</p>
<p>Economists expect the Reserve Bank to re-assert its view that conditions need to remain firm to contain inflation.</p>
<p>-- James Gray (64 9 302 1253)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
