<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33301" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FORECAST - Slow growth seen at Goodman.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FORECAST - Slow growth seen at Goodman.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Hickey</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australasian food group Goodman Fielder Ltd is expected to report a slightly higher annual net profit before abnormals early on Thursday, as firmer margins in some areas are seen largely offset by higher grain costs.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll be looking for some margin growth, but also there's been some strong raw materials cost increases,&quot; one Sydney analyst said, adding he was forecasting a pre-abnormals net profit of just under A$100 million.  </p>
<p>The median forecast in BZW Australia's Barceps survey of analysts was for a A$100.0 million pre-abnormals net profit for the year to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>Forecasts ranged from A$97.0 million to A$102.3 million, compared with the A$97.3 million profit posted in 1994/95.</p>
<p>&quot;There'll be a big impact from the grain prices in the second half and going into the first half of this (1996/97 year),&quot; another Sydney analyst said, estimating extra grain costs of about A$60 million.  </p>
<p>But analysts expected the cost of grain, a major input in Goodman's breadmaking and chicken operations, would ease back later in calendar 1996.</p>
<p>The higher grain costs were likely to have been offset somewhat in the second half of 1995/96 by lower packaging and palm oil costs, some analysts said.</p>
<p>Profit expectations are in a tight band in part because of Goodman's own comments about the result in early August.</p>
<p>Goodman chief executive David Hearn said then that the pre-abnormal profit would be around A$100 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're saying that there will be a small increase in pre-abnormal profit in the 0-5 percent range from last year and since we made A$97 million last year, zero to five means somewhere between A$97 and A$102 million,&quot; Hearn said.</p>
<p>Goodman then also announced it would post abnormal losses of up to A$75 million in 1995/96, including a revaluation of its loss-making poultry operations.</p>
<p>This would produce a net profit after abnormals of around A$25 million, Hearn said then.  </p>
<p>Analysts said however most of the interest would be centred on Goodman's strategic plans for recovery from its profit slump of recent years.</p>
<p>Goodman Fielder shares closed down a cent at A$1.31 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
