<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33300" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia launches Indian trade push.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia launches Indian trade push.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia on Wednesday launched its biggest overseas trade promotion aimed at India at the start of a 15-month campaign to upgrade ties with South Asia.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Alexander Downer said the A$6.0 million &quot;Australia India New Horizons&quot; programme was aimed at encouraging trade by correcting outdated Indian perceptions of Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;It will also herald the beginning of a renewed emphasis in the development of Australia's relations with the entire South Asia region, culminating in next year's 'Year of South Asia' initiative,&quot; Downer said at the programme launch in Sydney.  </p>
<p>&quot;Throughout 1997, the government will devote considerable efforts to upgrading ties with all countries in South Asia...&quot;</p>
<p>South Asia groups the countries of India, Pakistan, Sri Lanka and Bangladesh.</p>
<p>Downer said economic reforms in India since 1991 had resulted in seven percent economic growth in 1995/96, opening up a huge market for Australian companies.</p>
<p>Two-way trade between Australia and India was worth A$1.7 billion in 1995/96 and should double by the year 2000, he said, while Australian investment in India was around A$500 million at the end of 1995 from a &quot;negligible&quot; amount in the early 1990s.  </p>
<p>&quot;On current trends India will be amongst Australia's top 10 trading partners within the next three years,&quot; Downer said.</p>
<p>Australian exports to India were primarily coal, wool, metals, machinery, transport equipment and other manufacturers.</p>
<p>But Downer said opportunities existed for Australian trade in financial and educational services, environental technology, computer software, telecommunications and medical technology.</p>
<p>The trade promotion campaign between October 22 and early December would be staged in six Indian cities and consist not only of business leaders, but also farmers, chefs and musicians.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
