<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33307" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Australia dlr breathes easier as rates held.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Australia dlr breathes easier as rates held.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar inched ahead Wednesday after the Reserve Bank held official rates steady in the wake of Tuesday's policy meeting.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market had always thought a cut unlikely this time, but offshore investors could be encouraged by the RBA's silence since it suggested it would hold off until third quarter inflation and wages data were released in late October.</p>
<p>That should help sustain the attraction of A$ samurai's for Japanese investors, and further support was promised by the rise in oil prices following a second round of U.S. strikes on Iraq. All-in-all, a test of US$0.7935 resistance was likely later.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0700 GMT) the dollar had made hard work of a modest gain to US$0.7922/27 from an early US$0.7914/19 and US$0.7913/18 late here Tuesday.</p>
<p>It briefly touched a US$0.7933 high shortly after the RBA's morning money market operation came and went with no change in policy, but ran into heavy offers there. Dealers said the market looked to have gone long in anticipation of just such an RBA decision so was reluctant to take it any higher as yet.</p>
<p>Support had proved to be solid at US$0.7885/90 but a break of last week's US$0.7945 peak was needed to shake the bears off and signal a fresh leg of the uptrend to 80 cents.  </p>
<p>Analysts cautioned there was nothing to prevent the RBA from cutting rates at any time over the next month -- the board may well have voted to give the governor that discretion.</p>
<p>However, the last easing had come a day after the July 30 board meeting and analysts could see little reason why the bank would want to alter the pattern this time.</p>
<p>The next major data on inflation and wages, for instance, was not due until late October and the 1996/97 Federal Budget was expected to take a few weeks yet to fully clear the Senate.</p>
<p>There was also the -- growing -- risk the Federal Reserve would hike U.S. interest rates later this month.  </p>
<p>A run of robust U.S. economic data recently had made it increasingly likely the Fed would tighten at its policy meeting on September 24 and a report in the Wall Street Journal Tuesday suggested the Fed officials were thinking of an aggressive 0.5 point rise rather than the 0.25 point the market favoured.</p>
<p>The RBA had made a point on divorcing ts policy from that in the U.S., but analysts still thought it would be wary of leaving the local dollar exposed by easing while the Fed was hiking.</p>
<p>Some had already scented a possible change in alliegance amongst Japanese investors toward New Zealand and U.S. dollar denominated saumrai bonds.  </p>
<p>Kiwi dollar dual currency samurai bonds offer even higher yields than Australia while a long awaited samurai from IBM turned out to be US$-linked instead of an A$ issue as expected.</p>
<p>The local dollar was also aided by the U.S./Iraq hostilities as it boosted the price of oil, a major export earner for Australia but a major cost for Japan which imports all its oil.</p>
<p>The effect was unlikely to be long lasting unless the crisis developed into a full blown war which many considered improbable given the proximity of the U.S. Presidential election.</p>
<p>It was steady at 86.42/52 yen from 86.43/53 late Tuesday and at 58.1 in trade weighted terms. -- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
