<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33313" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ electricity retailers slam Trans Power pricing.</title>
<headline>NZ electricity retailers slam Trans Power pricing.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand electricity retailers on Wednesday slammed the transmission pricing mechanisms used by state-owned national grid operator Trans Power, calling them a stumbling block to the truly competitive and efficient generation of electricity.</p>
<p>At the annual meeting of the Electricity Supply Association of New Zealand (ESANZ), power companies said they were footing the bill for the bulk of electricity transmission costs, while generators only paid a fee for connection to the national grid.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we've been trying to persuade Trans Power to do is to put the costs of manufactured electrons back on the producers of the electrons,&quot; ESANZ executive director Barrie Leay told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, all those costs fall on the loads, and the loads are small power companies that have got no market power to fight a state monopoly.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Trans Power's recent decision to charge generators for the cost of transmitting power from the South to the North Island was not going far enough.  </p>
<p>&quot;Trans Power have accepted philosophically that what we are arguing is right, and they've now put all the DC costs back onto the South Island generators, but by taking out part of it they've almost compounded the problem, because the real problem is in the North Island,&quot; said Leay.</p>
<p>Power company executives said it was important to charge all generators for transmission costs because it would encourage competition in the generation market and give more appropriate price signals for future investment in generation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one of the key issues in New Zealand,&quot; EnergyDirect managing director Mike Underhill told Reuters.  </p>
<p>&quot;If New Zealand is to make future investment in generation, there needs to be encouragement for generation close to the source of use to avoid transmission costs, or the flipside which is energy efficiency, where you invest in using less energy.</p>
<p>&quot;But while you have market signals being disguised through this incorrect transmission pricing, then you don't see the opportunities for that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Because the majority of New Zealand's electricity is generated by hydro dams located in remote areas, the distances between a generator and the centres it supplies are often large. A percentage of electricity is lost in the transmission.  </p>
<p>A fundamental priciple of the new marketplace is that prices send economic efficiency signals indicating where the next power station should be built.</p>
<p>&quot;Ideally it should be built in the middle of (Auckland's) Queen St,&quot; said Trans Power spokesman Tim Grafton. &quot;As close as possible to Auckland, where a third or more of New Zealand's demand for electricity is.&quot;</p>
<p>He said if South Island generators were not charged for the transmission of their relatively cheap electricity to Auckland, it would distort the economic efficiency signal, &quot;and we end up building generation in the wrong place&quot;.  </p>
<p>But ESANZ argues that the same priciple is applicable in the North Island.</p>
<p>Eastland Energy Ltd chief executive Alistair Taylor said his company, which provides electricity to the Gisborne area, was losing NZ$950,000 a year because it was being charged for a transmission loss factor far greater than it should be.</p>
<p>With Lake Waikaremoana just 80 km down the road, the amount of electricity lost though transmission was about 4.5 percent, compared with the 15 percent Eastland was being charged, simply because the cheapest generator at a given time could be a far greater distance away.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we want to see is that people pay for their true losses. I don't mind paying our actual costs of getting power to Gisborne, but why should I pay more than that?,&quot; Taylor asked.</p>
<p>He agreed that the market pricing mechanism was meant to give signals about whether a region needed a new transmission line or to build a generator.</p>
<p>&quot;Our transmission line is not constrained, and we've got a generator 80 km away that is more than adequate to supply Gisborne, so why are we told there are signals to build a new transmission line? It's just crazy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Trans Power marketing manager Clive Bull said the problem with the retailers' argument was lack of true competition in New Zealand's small market.</p>
<p>&quot;If there was pure competition, that argument could be sustained I guess. But in New Zealand it's virtually a duopoly in terms of energy supplies right now, although that will change over time.&quot;</p>
<p>He said charging generators for all transmission costs would lumber them with &quot;NZ$500-odd million worth of transmission charges&quot;. He said the impact on generators would be of such magnitude that they would be forced to inflate prices, which would distort the market signal.</p>
<p>ESANZ, however, was adament in its call for a change.</p>
<p>&quot;When you can screw the scrum by having generators as remote as you like, and they don't pay the cost of transport, you don't get the right economic signals and answers,&quot; said Leay.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very subtle, but very important issue.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
