<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="33311" id="root" date="1996-09-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian meat not hit by Iraq freeze.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian meat not hit by Iraq freeze.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-09-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian meat exports would not be affected by the suspension of the proposed United Nations' oil-for-food deal, said Australian Meat and Livestock Corp (AMLC) manager, international sheepmeat and livestock marketing Lloyd Beeby.</p>
<p>The AMLC, an Australian meat industry statutory authority, had explored the potential to export meat to Iraq under the UN oil-for-food resolution, Beeby told Reuters.</p>
<p>But it was discovered that meat was not on Iraq's priority list. A fair amount of meat was selling at Iraq's roadside butchers, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It was fairly evident that at (present prices) we would be hard-pressed to even better it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've come away having made all of the contacts, ready to move at a moment's notice, but without any orders or any sign of any orders.</p>
<p>&quot;From what's happening there at the moment, we're not affected at all,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This did not mean that Iraq's market would not improve in future, he said.</p>
<p>Much of Australia's problem was European export subsidies, which left Australia uncompetitive at present rates, he said.  </p>
<p>Iraq was not a large consistent market for Australian meat before the Gulf War, although Australia had exported &quot;helpful&quot; amounts to Iraq in particular years, he said.</p>
<p>Iraq's oil-for-food deal, suspended on Tuesday after the U.S. missile attack on Iraq, would have allowed Iraq to sell US$2 billion worth of oil every six months to buy food and medicine.</p>
<p>Alistair Nicholas of the Australian Trade Commission (Austrade) told Reuters that the effect on Australian exports to Iraq would be negligible because no oil-for-food deals had gone through.  </p>
<p>&quot;But it is a further delay to any opportunities coming to fruition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
